<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="29069190_en">
  <chunk id="29069190_en.c0" text="Moderate and severe household food insecurity in families of people living with HIV/Aids: scale validation and associated factors.">
    <entity charOffset="0-8" id="29069190_en.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012826" text="Moderate" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="13-19" id="29069190_en.c0.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="29069190_en.c1" text="Vulnerable population groups, including people living with HIV/Aids (PLHA), may have a high prevalence of food insecurity (FI). A cross-sectional study evaluated the internal validity of the Brazilian Food Insecurity Scale (Escala Brasileira de Insegurança Alimentar - EBIA) and measured the prevalence of FI in a sample of 796 PLHA in João Pessoa, Paraíba State (PB). The validation was performed using a Rasch analysis. The association of FI with sociodemographic and clinical characteristics was assessed using the chi-square test. Associated variables were included in a Poisson multiple regression model. The EBIA was valid for PLHA with fit values within the expected limits and item severity conforming to the theoretical model. The EBIA identified 66.5% of PLHA with FI in the sample (30.8% mild FI, 18.1% moderate FI and 17.6% severe FI). Moderate FI and severe FI were associated with an age younger than 43 years (prevalence ratio (PR) = 1.49; 95% confidence interval (CI): 1.14-1.86), primary education (PR=1.64; 95% CI: 1.24-2.17), income per capita lower than ½ minimum wage (MW) (PR=1.83; 95% CI: 1.37-2.44), lack of occupation (PR=1.59; 95% CI: 1.16-2.19) and adult-only households with a female reference person (PR=2.19; 95% CI: 1.45-3.31). The PLHA in this study had a high prevalence of FI, worsening their living conditions and potentially exacerbating their health problems.">
    <entity charOffset="690-698" id="29069190_en.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012824" text="severity" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="799-803" id="29069190_en.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012825" text="mild" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="814-822" id="29069190_en.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0012826" text="moderate" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="836-842" id="29069190_en.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="848-856" id="29069190_en.c1.e4" ontology_id="HP_0012826" text="Moderate" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="864-870" id="29069190_en.c1.e5" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
