<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="29211176_en">
  <chunk id="29211176_en.c0" text="The relationship of climate variables in the prevalence of acute respiratory infection in children under two years old in Rondonópolis-MT, Brazil.">
    <entity charOffset="59-64" id="29211176_en.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="65-86" id="29211176_en.c0.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011947" text="respiratory infection" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="29211176_en.c1" text="It is estimated that approximately 30% of childhood diseases can be attributed to environmental factors and 40% involve children under the age of five years old, representing about 10% of world population. This study aimed to analyze the relationship of climate variables in the prevalence of acute respiratory infection (ARI) in children under two years old, in Rondonopolis-MT, from 1999 to 2014. It was used a cross-sectional study with a quantitative and a descriptive approach with meteorological teaching and research data from the database from the health information system. For statistical analysis, it adjusted the negative binomial model belonging to the class of generalized linear models, adopting a significance level of 5%, based on the statistical platform R. The average number of cases of ARI decreases at approximately by 7.9% per degree centigrade increase above the average air temperature and decrease about 1.65% per 1% increase over the average air relative humidity. Already, the rainfall not associated with these cases. It is the interdisciplinary team refocus practical actions to assist in the control and reduction of ARI significant numbers in primary health care, related climate issues in children.">
    <entity charOffset="293-298" id="29211176_en.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="299-320" id="29211176_en.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011947" text="respiratory infection" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="675-686" id="29211176_en.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0012837" text="generalized" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
