<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="30183802_en">
  <chunk id="30183802_en.c0" text="ASSOCIATION OF MENINGITIS AND PERICARDITIS IN INVASIVE PNEUMOCOCCAL DISEASE: A RARE CASE.">
    <entity charOffset="15-25" id="30183802_en.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0001287" text="MENINGITIS" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="30-42" id="30183802_en.c0.e1" ontology_id="HP_0001701" text="PERICARDITIS" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="30183802_en.c1" text="To report a rare case of a child with invasive pneumococcal disease that presented meningitis associated with pericarditis.This report describes the unfavorable clinical course of a previously healthy 6-months-old female infant who initially presented symptoms of fever and respiratory problems. A chest X-ray revealed an increased cardiac area with no radiographic changes in the lungs. After identifying a pericardial effusion, the patient experienced seizures and went into coma. Pneumonia was excluded as a possibility during the clinical investigation. However, Streptococcus pneumoniae was identified in the cerebrospinal fluid and blood cultures. An initial neurological examination showed that the patient was brain dead, which was then later confirmed according to protocol.Purulent pericarditis has become a rare complication of invasive pneumococcal disease since the advent of antibiotic therapy. Patients with extensive pneumonia are primarily predisposed and, even with early and adequate treatment, are prone to high mortality rates. The association of pneumococcal meningitis and pericarditis is uncommon, and therefore difficult to diagnose. As such, diagnostic suspicion must be high in order to institute early treatment and increase survival.">
    <entity charOffset="83-93" id="30183802_en.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0001287" text="meningitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="110-122" id="30183802_en.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0001701" text="pericarditis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="161-176" id="30183802_en.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0031797" text="clinical course" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="193-200" id="30183802_en.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0032322" text="healthy" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="264-269" id="30183802_en.c1.e4" ontology_id="HP_0001945" text="fever" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="454-462" id="30183802_en.c1.e5" ontology_id="HP_0001250" text="seizures" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="483-492" id="30183802_en.c1.e6" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="Pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="497-505" id="30183802_en.c1.e7" ontology_id="HP_0040285" text="excluded" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="792-804" id="30183802_en.c1.e8" ontology_id="HP_0001701" text="pericarditis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="933-942" id="30183802_en.c1.e9" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1081-1091" id="30183802_en.c1.e10" ontology_id="HP_0001287" text="meningitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1096-1108" id="30183802_en.c1.e11" ontology_id="HP_0001701" text="pericarditis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
