<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="30365808_en">
  <chunk id="30365808_en.c0" text="CLINICAL-EPIDEMIOLOGICAL PROFILE OF 106 PEDIATRIC PACIENTS WITH UROLITHIASIS IN RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL."/>
  <chunk id="30365808_en.c1" text="To describe the frequency, clinical profile and treatment of patients with urolithiasis in the Pediatric Nephrology Department of a public state hospital in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.Retrospective study. Data from pediatric patients (age: 1 month - 18 years) with urolithiasis admitted between January/2012 and December/2014 were reviewed from hospital charts. The studied variables were: demographic and anthropometric data, clinical status, family history of urolithiasis, urinary tract infection and use of lithogenic drugs, diagnostic procedures, associated abnormalities, metabolic disorders, treatment and recurrence.The frequency of urolithiasis was 13.6%. Main characteristics of the patients: male gender, white race, eutrophy, aged between 5 and 10 years, family history of urolithiasis, previous urinary infection and spontaneous stone passage. Abdominal and flank pain and macroscopic hematuria were the most common complaints. The most frequent metabolic disorders were hypercalciuria, hyperuricosuria and hypocitraturia. Hypocitraturia was associated with previous urinary infection (p=0.004). Abdomen/urinary tract ultrasonography was the most commonly used diagnostic test. Hydronephrosis occurred in 54.4% of the cases, 81.1% of the stones were in the kidneys, and bilateral stones were associated to a family history of urolithiasis (p=0.030). Recurrence rate was 29.3% (most patients had a metabolic disorder). In 12.3%, the patients underwent lithotripsy, 24.5% were surgically treated (mainly pyelolithotomy), and only 7.6% had their stones analyzed (calcium oxalate was the main finding in the examined stones).The frequency of urolithiasis in these pediatric patients was similar to that reported by the literature. A metabolic evaluation is required and the composition of stones should be better evaluated.">
    <entity charOffset="16-25" id="30365808_en.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0040279" text="frequency" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="440-454" id="30365808_en.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0032316" text="family history" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="624-633" id="30365808_en.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0040279" text="frequency" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="763-777" id="30365808_en.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0032316" text="family history" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="867-877" id="30365808_en.c1.e4" ontology_id="HP_0030157" text="flank pain" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="873-877" id="30365808_en.c1.e5" ontology_id="HP_0012531" text="pain" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="882-903" id="30365808_en.c1.e6" ontology_id="HP_0012587" text="macroscopic hematuria" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="894-903" id="30365808_en.c1.e7" ontology_id="HP_0000790" text="hematuria" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="946-954" id="30365808_en.c1.e8" ontology_id="HP_0040282" text="frequent" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="996-1011" id="30365808_en.c1.e9" ontology_id="HP_0003149" text="hyperuricosuria" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1016-1030" id="30365808_en.c1.e10" ontology_id="HP_0012405" text="hypocitraturia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1032-1046" id="30365808_en.c1.e11" ontology_id="HP_0012405" text="Hypocitraturia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1187-1201" id="30365808_en.c1.e12" ontology_id="HP_0000126" text="Hydronephrosis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1279-1288" id="30365808_en.c1.e13" ontology_id="HP_0012832" text="bilateral" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1317-1331" id="30365808_en.c1.e14" ontology_id="HP_0032316" text="family history" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1634-1643" id="30365808_en.c1.e15" ontology_id="HP_0040279" text="frequency" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
