<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="32491075_en">
  <chunk id="32491075_en.c0" text="Cardiovascular Implications in Patients Infected with Covid-19 and the Importance of Social Isolation to Reduce Dissemination of the Disease."/>
  <chunk id="32491075_en.c1" text="Respiratory symptoms, especially the development of severe acute respiratory distress syndrome, dominate the discussion and initial concerns of the population and health professionals. However, the cardiovascular system is greatly affected by these conditions and is often responsible for complications and mortality of these patients. In order to show the cardiovascular implications in patients infected with COVID-19 and the importance of social isolation as an alternative to curb the spread of the disease, a literature review was carried out based on 37 articles, in English, Portuguese and Spanish, available on Scielo and PubMed. The findings showed that cardiac complications associated with COVID-19 infection are similar to those produced by: severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS), Middle East respiratory syndrome (MERS) and influenza. However, COVID-19 has a much greater and faster contamination and, unlike influenza, there is no vaccine or treatment available yet. In view of this, social isolation becomes a tool that can reduce and flatten the curve of cases and thus protect the people at higher risk, decreasing the chances of serious conditions related to the disease, potential deaths and the collapse of the country's health system.">
    <entity charOffset="52-58" id="32491075_en.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="59-64" id="32491075_en.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="65-85" id="32491075_en.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0002098" text="respiratory distress" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="231-239" id="32491075_en.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0032320" text="affected" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="754-760" id="32491075_en.c1.e4" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="761-766" id="32491075_en.c1.e5" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
