<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="0113b9a8d82039e8474e887038d643853b5fdfeb">
  <chunk id="0113b9a8d82039e8474e887038d643853b5fdfeb.c0" text="Revitalization of integrated disease surveillance and response in Sierra Leone post Ebola virus disease outbreak"/>
  <chunk id="0113b9a8d82039e8474e887038d643853b5fdfeb.c1" text="Background: The Ministry of Health and Sanitation (MOHS) in Sierra Leone partially rolled out the implementation of Integrated Disease Surveillance and Response (IDSR) in 2003. After the Ebola virus disease outbreak in 2014-2015, there was need to strengthen IDSR to ensure prompt detection and response to epidemic-prone diseases. We describe the processes, successes and challenges of revitalizing public health surveillance in a country recovering from a protracted Ebola virus disease outbreak. Methods: The revitalization process began with adaptation of the revised IDSR guidelines and development of customized guidelines to suit the health care systems in Sierra Leone. Public health experts defined data flow, system operations, case definitions, frequency and channels of reporting and dissemination. Next, phased training of IDSR focal persons in each health facility and the distribution of data collection and reporting tools was done. Monitoring activities included periodic supportive supervision and data quality assessments. Rapid response teams were formed to investigate and respond to disease outbreak alerts in all districts. Results: Submission of reports through the IDSR system began in mid-2015 and by the 35th epidemiologic week, all district health teams were submitting reports. The key performance indicators measuring the functionality of the IDSR system in 2016 and 2017 were achieved (WHO Africa Region target ≥80%); the annual average proportion of timely weekly health facility reports submitted to the next level was 93% in 2016 and 97% in 2017; the proportion of suspected outbreaks and public health events detected through the IDSR system was 96% (n = 87) in 2016 and 100% (n = 85) in 2017. Conclusion: With proper planning, phased implementation and adequate investment of resources, it is possible to establish a functional IDSR system in a country recovering from a public health crisis. A functional IDSR system requires well trained workforce, provision of the necessary tools and guidelines, information, communication and technology infrastructure to support data transmission, provision of timely feedback as well as logistical support.">
    <entity charOffset="756-765" id="0113b9a8d82039e8474e887038d643853b5fdfeb.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0040279" text="frequency" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="841-846" id="0113b9a8d82039e8474e887038d643853b5fdfeb.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0030650" text="focal" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="980-988" id="0113b9a8d82039e8474e887038d643853b5fdfeb.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0025304" text="periodic" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
