<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="02bfb4c09489a5f48c23e8441e37b055bf7228ee">
  <chunk id="02bfb4c09489a5f48c23e8441e37b055bf7228ee.c0" text="Chikungunya nsP2 protease is not a papain-like cysteine protease and the catalytic dyad cysteine is interchangeable with a proximal serine OPEN">
    <entity charOffset="123-131" id="02bfb4c09489a5f48c23e8441e37b055bf7228ee.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012840" text="proximal" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="02bfb4c09489a5f48c23e8441e37b055bf7228ee.c1" text="Chikungunya virus is the pathogenic alphavirus that causes chikungunya fever in humans. In the last decade millions of cases have been reported around the world from Africa to Asia to the Americas. The alphavirus nsP2 protein is multifunctional and is considered to be pivotal to viral replication, as the nsP2 protease activity is critical for proteolytic processing of the viral polyprotein during replication. Classically the alphavirus nsP2 protease is thought to be papain-like with the enzyme reaction proceeding through a cysteine/histidine catalytic dyad. We performed structurefunction studies on the chikungunya nsP2 protease and show that the enzyme is not papain-like. Characterization of the catalytic dyad cysteine residue enabled us to identify a nearby serine that is catalytically interchangeable with the dyad cysteine residue. The enzyme retains activity upon alanine replacement of either residue but a replacement of both cysteine and serine residues results in no detectable activity. Protein dynamics appears to allow the use of either the cysteine or the serine residue in catalysis. This switchable dyad residue has not been previously reported for alphavirus nsP2 proteases and would have a major impact on the nsP2 protease as an anti-viral target.">
    <entity charOffset="71-76" id="02bfb4c09489a5f48c23e8441e37b055bf7228ee.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0001945" text="fever" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="311-328" id="02bfb4c09489a5f48c23e8441e37b055bf7228ee.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0008233" text="protease activity" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="02bfb4c09489a5f48c23e8441e37b055bf7228ee.c1.e0" e2="02bfb4c09489a5f48c23e8441e37b055bf7228ee.c1.e1" id="02bfb4c09489a5f48c23e8441e37b055bf7228ee.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="02bfb4c09489a5f48c23e8441e37b055bf7228ee.c2" text="Chikungunya virus (CHIKV) is mosquito-borne, and a major pathogenic agent that causes chikungunya fever in humans. CHIKV originated in Africa and spread rapidly into Asia and Europe. Within the last 10 years, a number of Chikungunya outbreaks have arisen in various parts of the world 1 . Recently, more than a million suspected and confirmed cases have been reported in the Americas 2 . Although many of the reported cases were from travelers who brought back the disease from the affected countries where they had visited, autochthonous infections were also reported 2-4 . This alphavirus is primarily transmitted by Aedes aegypti and Aedes albopictus mosquito vectors and humans are an amplifying host 5 . Patients infected with CHIKV will develop symptoms some 3-5 days after infection. Common symptoms are characterized by joint and muscle pain, rash, nausea and headache. The fever and pain may persist for months and occasional fatalities have been reported. The CHIKV genome is comprised of a positive sense single-stranded RNA which contains two open reading frames encoding the non-structural and structural proteins 6 . The non-structural polyprotein precursor, nsP123 or nsP1234, is translated first">
    <entity charOffset="98-103" id="02bfb4c09489a5f48c23e8441e37b055bf7228ee.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0001945" text="fever" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="482-490" id="02bfb4c09489a5f48c23e8441e37b055bf7228ee.c2.e1" ontology_id="HP_0032320" text="affected" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="845-849" id="02bfb4c09489a5f48c23e8441e37b055bf7228ee.c2.e2" ontology_id="HP_0012531" text="pain" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="857-863" id="02bfb4c09489a5f48c23e8441e37b055bf7228ee.c2.e3" ontology_id="HP_0002018" text="nausea" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="882-887" id="02bfb4c09489a5f48c23e8441e37b055bf7228ee.c2.e4" ontology_id="HP_0001945" text="fever" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="892-896" id="02bfb4c09489a5f48c23e8441e37b055bf7228ee.c2.e5" ontology_id="HP_0012531" text="pain" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="924-934" id="02bfb4c09489a5f48c23e8441e37b055bf7228ee.c2.e6" ontology_id="HP_0040283" text="occasional" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
