<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="0330ede445d96dd0a27f474f945d6ce2e7085f15">
  <chunk id="0330ede445d96dd0a27f474f945d6ce2e7085f15.c0" text="Viperin Targets Flavivirus Virulence by Inducing Assembly of Noninfectious Capsid Particles"/>
  <chunk id="0330ede445d96dd0a27f474f945d6ce2e7085f15.c1" text="Efficient antiviral immunity requires interference with virus replication at multiple layers targeting diverse steps in the viral life cycle. We describe here a novel flavivirus inhibition mechanism that results in interferon-mediated obstruction of tick-borne encephalitis virus particle assembly and involves release of malfunctioning membrane-associated capsid (C) particles. This mechanism is controlled by the activity of the interferon-induced protein viperin, a broad-spectrum antiviral interferon-stimulated gene. Through analysis of the viperin-interactome, we identified the Golgi brefeldin A-resistant guanine nucleotide exchange factor 1 (GBF1) as the cellular protein targeted by viperin. Viperin-induced antiviral activity, as well as C-particle release, was stimulated by GBF1 inhibition and knockdown and reduced by elevated levels of GBF1. Our results suggest that viperin targets flavivirus virulence by inducing the secretion of unproductive noninfectious virus particles via a GBF1-dependent mechanism. This as-yet-undescribed antiviral mechanism allows potential therapeutic intervention.">
    <entity charOffset="124-140" id="0330ede445d96dd0a27f474f945d6ce2e7085f15.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0019058" text="viral life cycle" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="261-273" id="0330ede445d96dd0a27f474f945d6ce2e7085f15.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0002383" text="encephalitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="274-297" id="0330ede445d96dd0a27f474f945d6ce2e7085f15.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0019068" text="virus particle assembly" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="935-944" id="0330ede445d96dd0a27f474f945d6ce2e7085f15.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0046903" text="secretion" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="0330ede445d96dd0a27f474f945d6ce2e7085f15.c1.e0" e2="0330ede445d96dd0a27f474f945d6ce2e7085f15.c1.e1" id="0330ede445d96dd0a27f474f945d6ce2e7085f15.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="0330ede445d96dd0a27f474f945d6ce2e7085f15.c1.e1" e2="0330ede445d96dd0a27f474f945d6ce2e7085f15.c1.e2" id="0330ede445d96dd0a27f474f945d6ce2e7085f15.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="0330ede445d96dd0a27f474f945d6ce2e7085f15.c1.e1" e2="0330ede445d96dd0a27f474f945d6ce2e7085f15.c1.e3" id="0330ede445d96dd0a27f474f945d6ce2e7085f15.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
