<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="058f046fec5eee31c9ed0bdacd37aa22ba485993">
  <chunk id="058f046fec5eee31c9ed0bdacd37aa22ba485993.c0" text="Clinical outcomes among hospital patients with Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus (MERS-CoV) infection"/>
  <chunk id="058f046fec5eee31c9ed0bdacd37aa22ba485993.c1" text="Background: Mortality is high among patients with Middle East Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus (MERS-CoV) infection. We aimed to determine hospital mortality and the factors associated with it in a cohort of MERS-CoV patients. Methods: We reviewed hospital records of confirmed cases (detection of virus by polymerase chain reaction from respiratory tract samples) of MERS-CoV patients (n = 63) admitted to Buraidah Central Hospital in Al-Qassim, Saudi Arabia between 2014 and 2017. We abstracted data on demography, vital signs, associated conditions presented on admission, pre-existing chronic diseases, treatment, and vital status. Bi-variate comparisons and multiple logistic regressions were the choice of data analyses. Results: The mean age was 60 years (SD = 18.2); most patients were male (74.6%) and Saudi citizens (81%). All but two patients were treated with Ribavirin plus Interferon. Hospital mortality was 25.4%. Patients who were admitted with septic shock and/or organ failure were significantly more likely to die than patients who were admitted with pneumonia and/or acute respiratory distress syndrome (OR = 47.9, 95% CI = 3.9, 585.5, p-value 0.002). Age, sex, and presence of chronic conditions were not significantly associated with mortality. Conclusion: Hospital mortality was 25%; septic shock/organ failure at admittance was a significant predictor of mortality.">
    <entity charOffset="416-423" id="058f046fec5eee31c9ed0bdacd37aa22ba485993.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0030645" text="Central" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="589-596" id="058f046fec5eee31c9ed0bdacd37aa22ba485993.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011010" text="chronic" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="968-973" id="058f046fec5eee31c9ed0bdacd37aa22ba485993.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0031273" text="shock" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1070-1079" id="058f046fec5eee31c9ed0bdacd37aa22ba485993.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1087-1092" id="058f046fec5eee31c9ed0bdacd37aa22ba485993.c1.e4" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1093-1113" id="058f046fec5eee31c9ed0bdacd37aa22ba485993.c1.e5" ontology_id="HP_0002098" text="respiratory distress" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1198-1205" id="058f046fec5eee31c9ed0bdacd37aa22ba485993.c1.e6" ontology_id="HP_0011010" text="chronic" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1314-1319" id="058f046fec5eee31c9ed0bdacd37aa22ba485993.c1.e7" ontology_id="HP_0031273" text="shock" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
