<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="060833389f07819960d34c91e0dfdc92e053f6ac">
  <chunk id="060833389f07819960d34c91e0dfdc92e053f6ac.c0" text="Porcine Reproductive and Respiratory Syndrome Virus (PRRSV) Inhibits RNA-Mediated Gene Silencing by Targeting Ago-2">
    <entity charOffset="69-96" id="060833389f07819960d34c91e0dfdc92e053f6ac.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0031047" text="RNA-Mediated Gene Silencing" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="82-96" id="060833389f07819960d34c91e0dfdc92e053f6ac.c0.e1" ontology_id="GO_0016458" text="Gene Silencing" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="060833389f07819960d34c91e0dfdc92e053f6ac.c1" text="Porcine reproductive and respiratory syndrome virus (PRRSV) infection strongly modulates the host's immune response. The RNA silencing pathway is an intracellular innate response to viral infections. However, it is unknown whether PRRSV interacts with cellular RNA silencing to facilitate the viral infection. Here, we report for the first time the interaction between PRRSV and RNA silencing in both the porcine macrophages and African green monkey kidney cell line (MARC-145) cell line, which were derived from African green monkey kidney cells and highly permissive for PRRSV infection. Our data demonstrated that PRRSV suppressed RNA silencing induced by short-hairpin (sh) RNA, double-strand (ds) RNA and microRNA (miRNA) and downregulated the expression of argonaute protein-2 (Ago-2), which is a key protein of the RNA silencing pathway in animal cells. Further, exogenous introduction of siRNA and shRNA downregulated Dicer or Ago-2 proteins of the cellular RNA silencing apparatus in MARC-145 cells and porcine macrophages, which, in turn, increased the viral replication and titers. The viral non-structure protein 1α (nsp-1α) and nsp11 of PRRSV were identified as the suppressors for cellular RNA silencing (RSSs) to downregulate the Ago-2 protein. Our results identify that PRRSV, through its nsp proteins, suppresses the cellular RNA silencing apparatus in favor of viral infection and supports a co-evolutionary process of the virus and the cellular RNA silencing process.">
    <entity charOffset="149-162" id="060833389f07819960d34c91e0dfdc92e053f6ac.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0005622" text="intracellular" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="293-308" id="060833389f07819960d34c91e0dfdc92e053f6ac.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0016032" text="viral infection" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1379-1394" id="060833389f07819960d34c91e0dfdc92e053f6ac.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0016032" text="viral infection" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
