<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="096d707e74acc27426416dacf89d5d134a0b9866">
  <chunk id="096d707e74acc27426416dacf89d5d134a0b9866.c0" text="Immunosuppression of the Trimellitic Anhydride-Induced Th2 Response by Novel Nonanatural Products Mixture in Mice"/>
  <chunk id="096d707e74acc27426416dacf89d5d134a0b9866.c1" text="Many natural dietary products prevent or cure allergic inflammation; however, the ability of mixtures of these natural medicinals to suppress allergic skin inflammation is unknown. We examined the inhibitory effects of nonanatural products mixture (NPM-9), which provides immunoregulatory activation, on Th2-mediated skin allergic inflammation. Oral administration of NPM-9 in mice reduced ear thickness and specific IgE production in trimellitic anhydride-(TMA-)induced contact hypersensitivity (CHS). NPM-9 also suppressed IL-4 and IL-1 production in splenocytes but prevented only TMA-induced IL-1 production in inflamed ears. To characterize the mechanism of this effect, we examined NPM-9 immunosuppression on an OVA-induced Th2 allergic state. Oral administration of NPM-9 inhibited Th2-mediated serum IgE overproduction. NPM-9 also downregulated the polarized Th2 response, whereas it upregulated Th1 response in splenocytes. These data suggest that NPM-9 may be a useful therapeutic agent for allergic inflammatory diseases through its suppression of the Th2-mediated allergic response.">
    <entity charOffset="151-168" id="096d707e74acc27426416dacf89d5d134a0b9866.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011123" text="skin inflammation" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="479-495" id="096d707e74acc27426416dacf89d5d134a0b9866.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0002524" text="hypersensitivity" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="534-549" id="096d707e74acc27426416dacf89d5d134a0b9866.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0032612" text="IL-1 production" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="596-611" id="096d707e74acc27426416dacf89d5d134a0b9866.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0032612" text="IL-1 production" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="096d707e74acc27426416dacf89d5d134a0b9866.c1.e0" e2="096d707e74acc27426416dacf89d5d134a0b9866.c1.e1" id="096d707e74acc27426416dacf89d5d134a0b9866.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="096d707e74acc27426416dacf89d5d134a0b9866.c1.e0" e2="096d707e74acc27426416dacf89d5d134a0b9866.c1.e2" id="096d707e74acc27426416dacf89d5d134a0b9866.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="096d707e74acc27426416dacf89d5d134a0b9866.c1.e0" e2="096d707e74acc27426416dacf89d5d134a0b9866.c1.e3" id="096d707e74acc27426416dacf89d5d134a0b9866.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
