<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="0b9583908e91f87840a0f844e7c4ebb546482c50">
  <chunk id="0b9583908e91f87840a0f844e7c4ebb546482c50.c0" text="Prospective case-control analysis of the aetiologies of acute undifferentiated fever in Vietnam">
    <entity charOffset="56-61" id="0b9583908e91f87840a0f844e7c4ebb546482c50.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="79-84" id="0b9583908e91f87840a0f844e7c4ebb546482c50.c0.e1" ontology_id="HP_0001945" text="fever" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="0b9583908e91f87840a0f844e7c4ebb546482c50.c1" text="Acute undifferentiated fever (AUF) is frequently observed in tropical settings, but diagnosing the cause of AUF is often a challenge for local physicians and the physicians treating returning travellers. We conducted a case-control study in central Vietnam in 2016. A total of 378 febrile adult patients (AUFs) with a fever for ≤21 days, no evidence of localized infection and negative screening tests for dengue and malaria, and 384 afebrile adult patients (Controls) were prospectively enrolled. Whole blood, plasma, eschar swab, throat swab and urine specimens were collected and analysed. Quantitative PCR and RT-PCR were used to test for 55 bacteria, viruses and their subtypes. Serological tests were also used to test for rickettsial agents. The most common aetiology was influenza virus (20.9% in AUFs vs. 0% in Controls), followed by rickettsial agents (mainly Orientia tsutsugamushi and Rickettsia typhi) (10.8% vs. 0.3%), dengue virus (7.7% vs. 0.5%), Leptospira (4.8% vs. 0.8%), adenovirus (4.8% vs. 1.0%), and enterovirus (2.1% vs. 0%) (p &lt; .05). The real proportion of dengue in AUF cases was underestimated because patients with denguepositive rapid diagnosis tests were excluded from the study. The emerging agent Rickettsia felis, which had not been previously observed in Vietnam, was detected in this study. In total, 216 patients (57.1%) were given causative diagnoses, comprising 143 (66.2%) monoinfections and 73 (33.8%) coinfections. The infections caused by these agents should be considered in clinical practice and further studies. Additionally, agents susceptible to doxycycline were detected in 15.6% of AUFs; thus, this drug should be included in the panel used to treat AUF patients.">
    <entity charOffset="0-5" id="0b9583908e91f87840a0f844e7c4ebb546482c50.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="Acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="23-28" id="0b9583908e91f87840a0f844e7c4ebb546482c50.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0001945" text="fever" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="241-248" id="0b9583908e91f87840a0f844e7c4ebb546482c50.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0030645" text="central" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="318-323" id="0b9583908e91f87840a0f844e7c4ebb546482c50.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0001945" text="fever" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="353-362" id="0b9583908e91f87840a0f844e7c4ebb546482c50.c1.e4" ontology_id="HP_0012838" text="localized" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1186-1194" id="0b9583908e91f87840a0f844e7c4ebb546482c50.c1.e5" ontology_id="HP_0040285" text="excluded" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
