<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="0c04a2b5c4c91d76c26736dd05ce6fc6385cc167">
  <chunk id="0c04a2b5c4c91d76c26736dd05ce6fc6385cc167.c0" text="LILRA3 Binds Both Classical and Non-Classical HLA Class I Molecules but with Reduced Affinities Compared to LILRB1/LILRB2: Structural Evidence"/>
  <chunk id="0c04a2b5c4c91d76c26736dd05ce6fc6385cc167.c1" text="Structurally, Group 1 LILR (Leukocyte Immunogloblin (Ig)-Like Receptor, also known as Ig-like transcripts, ILT; Leukocyte Iglike receptor, LIR; and CD85) members are very similar in terms of the HLAIs (human leukocyte antigen class I molecules) binding region and were hypothesized that they all bind to HLAIs. As one of the Group 1 LILRs, LILRA3 is the only secretory LILR and may greatly control the inhibitory immune response induced by LILRB1, LILRB2, and other HLA-binding LILR molecules like LILRA1. Nevertheless, little was known about the binding of LILRA3 to HLAIs. In this report, we present the crystal structure of the LILRA3 domain 1 (D1) and evaluate the D1 and D1D2 (domain 1 and domain 2) binding to classical and non-classical HLAIs using BIAcoreH surface plasmon resonance analysis (SPR). We found that LILRA3 binds both classical HLA-A*0201 and non-classical HLA-G1 but with reduced affinities compared to either LILRB1 or LILRB2. The polymorphic amino acids and the LILRA3 D1 structure support this notion. Citation: Ryu M, Chen Y, Qi J, Liu J, Fan Z, et al. (2011) LILRA3 Binds Both Classical and Non-Classical HLA Class I Molecules but with Reduced Affinities Compared to LILRB1/LILRB2: Structural Evidence. PLoS ONE 6(4): e19245.">
    <entity charOffset="245-252" id="0c04a2b5c4c91d76c26736dd05ce6fc6385cc167.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="413-428" id="0c04a2b5c4c91d76c26736dd05ce6fc6385cc167.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0006955" text="immune response" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="547-554" id="0c04a2b5c4c91d76c26736dd05ce6fc6385cc167.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="705-712" id="0c04a2b5c4c91d76c26736dd05ce6fc6385cc167.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
