<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="0d8784d230453109b9340461f2692f0f2d048927">
  <chunk id="0d8784d230453109b9340461f2692f0f2d048927.c0" text="Role of S-Palmitoylation on IFITM5 for the Interaction with FKBP11 in Osteoblast Cells"/>
  <chunk id="0d8784d230453109b9340461f2692f0f2d048927.c1" text="Recently, one of the interferon-induced transmembrane (IFITM) family proteins, IFITM3, has become an important target for the activity against influenza A (H1N1) virus infection. In this protein, a post-translational modification by fatty acids covalently attached to cysteine, termed S-palmitoylation, plays a crucial role for the antiviral activity. IFITM3 possesses three cysteine residues for the S-palmitoylation in the first transmembrane (TM1) domain and in the cytoplasmic (CP) loop. Because these cysteines are well conserved in the mammalian IFITM family proteins, the S-palmitoylation on these cysteines is significant for their functions. IFITM5 is another IFITM family protein and interacts with the FK506-binding protein 11 (FKBP11) to form a higher-order complex in osteoblast cells, which induces the expression of immunologically relevant genes. In this study, we investigated the role played by Spalmitoylation of IFITM5 in its interaction with FKBP11 in the cells, because this interaction is a key process for the gene expression. Our investigations using an established reporter, 17-octadecynoic acid (17-ODYA), and an inhibitor for the S-palmitoylation, 2-bromopalmitic acid (2BP), revealed that IFITM5 was S-palmitoylated in addition to IFITM3. Specifically, we found that cysteine residues in the TM1 domain and in the CP loop were S-palmitoylated in IFITM5. Then, we revealed by immunoprecipitation and western blot analyses that the interaction of IFITM5 with FKBP11 was inhibited in the presence of 2BP. The mutant lacking the S-palmitoylation site in the TM1 domain lost the interaction with FKBP11. These results indicate that the S-palmitoylation on IFITM5 promotes the interaction with FKBP11. Finally, we investigated bone nodule formation in osteoblast cells in the presence of 2BP, because IFITM5 was originally identified as a bone formation factor. The experiment resulted in a morphological aberration of the bone nodule. This also indicated that the S-palmitoylation contributes to bone formation. Citation: Tsukamoto T, Li X, Morita H, Minowa T, Aizawa T, et al. (2013) Role of S-Palmitoylation on IFITM5 for the Interaction with FKBP11 in Osteoblast Cells. PLoS ONE 8(9): e75831.">
    <entity charOffset="40-53" id="0d8784d230453109b9340461f2692f0f2d048927.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0016021" text="transmembrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="198-229" id="0d8784d230453109b9340461f2692f0f2d048927.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0043687" text="post-translational modification" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="431-444" id="0d8784d230453109b9340461f2692f0f2d048927.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0016021" text="transmembrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1755-1771" id="0d8784d230453109b9340461f2692f0f2d048927.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0009877" text="nodule formation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1862-1876" id="0d8784d230453109b9340461f2692f0f2d048927.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0001503" text="bone formation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="2020-2034" id="0d8784d230453109b9340461f2692f0f2d048927.c1.e5" ontology_id="GO_0001503" text="bone formation" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
