<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="10206d084e0ca2117abdb7f6909d9b857ec89b69">
  <chunk id="10206d084e0ca2117abdb7f6909d9b857ec89b69.c0" text="A global bibliometric analysis of Plesiomonas- related research (1990 -2017)"/>
  <chunk id="10206d084e0ca2117abdb7f6909d9b857ec89b69.c1" text="Plesiomonas shigelloides is an emerging pathogen with damaging effects on human health such as gastroenteritis and extraintestinal infections. Here, we carried out a bibliometric survey that aimed to examine publication trends in Plesiomonas-related research by time and place, international collaborative works, identify gaps and suggest directions for future research. The search term &quot;Plesiomonas shigelloides&quot; was used to retrieve articles published between 1990 and 2017 from the Web of Science database. Only primary research articles were included in the analysis. A total of 155 articles were published within the survey period, with an average of 5.54±2.66 articles per year and an annual growth rate of −0.8%. Research output peaked in 2000 and 2006 (each accounting for 7.7% of the total). The United States ranked first in terms of numbers of articles (n = 29, 18.1%) and total citations (n = 451). Cameroon, Canada, Cuba, Switzerland and Turkey co-shared the 10 th position each with 2 articles (1.3%). Research collaboration was low (collaboration index = 3. 32). In addition to Plesiomonas shigelloides (n = 82, 52.9%), the top Authors Keywords and research focus included lipopolysaccharide and nuclear magnetic resonance (n = 13, 8.4%). Diarrhea (n = 43, 27.7%), Aeromonas species (n = 41, 26.5%) and infections (n = 31, 20.0%) were also highly represented in Keywords-Plus. Authors' collaborations and coupling networks formed two mega-clusters which nodes were shared solely by authors from high-income countries. The common conceptual framework in retrieved articles determined by K-means clustering revealed three clusters with sizes of 7, 16, and 29, representing research responses focused on extraintestinal and gastroenteritis, P. shigelloides lipopolysaccharide structure, and co-infections, respectively. Our bibliometric analysis revealed a global diminishing research in Plesiomonas; greater research outcomes from high-income countries compared to others and low collaboration with developing countries.">
    <entity charOffset="698-704" id="10206d084e0ca2117abdb7f6909d9b857ec89b69.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0040007" text="growth" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="978-986" id="10206d084e0ca2117abdb7f6909d9b857ec89b69.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012830" text="position" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1254-1262" id="10206d084e0ca2117abdb7f6909d9b857ec89b69.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0002014" text="Diarrhea" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="10206d084e0ca2117abdb7f6909d9b857ec89b69.c1.e0" e2="10206d084e0ca2117abdb7f6909d9b857ec89b69.c1.e1" id="10206d084e0ca2117abdb7f6909d9b857ec89b69.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="10206d084e0ca2117abdb7f6909d9b857ec89b69.c1.e0" e2="10206d084e0ca2117abdb7f6909d9b857ec89b69.c1.e2" id="10206d084e0ca2117abdb7f6909d9b857ec89b69.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
