<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="11a3797796973b32b0763f8127b908f4783e5734">
  <chunk id="11a3797796973b32b0763f8127b908f4783e5734.c0" text="Comprehensive Mapping Antigenic Epitopes of NS1 Protein of Japanese Encephalitis Virus with Monoclonal Antibodies">
    <entity charOffset="68-80" id="11a3797796973b32b0763f8127b908f4783e5734.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002383" text="Encephalitis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="11a3797796973b32b0763f8127b908f4783e5734.c1" text="Japanese encephalitis virus (JEV) non-structural protein 1 (NS1) contributes to virus replication and elicits protective immune responses during infection. JEV NS1-specific antibody responses could be a target in the differential diagnosis of different flavivirus infections. However, the epitopes on JEV NS1 are poorly characterized. The present study describes the full mapping of linear B-cell epitopes in JEV NS1. We generated eleven NS1-specific monoclonal antibodies from mice immunized with recombinant NS1. For epitope mapping of monoclonal antibodies, a set of 51 partially-overlapping peptides covering the entire NS1 protein were expressed with a GST-tag and then screened using monoclonal antibodies. Through enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA), five linear epitope-containing peptides were identified. By sequentially removing amino acid residues from the carboxy and amino terminal of peptides, the minimal units of the five linear epitopes were identified and confirmed using monoclonal antibodies. Five linear epitopes are located in amino acids residues 5 AIDITRK 11 , 72 RDELNVL 78 , 251 KSKHNRREGY 260 , 269 DENGIVLD 276 , and 341 DETTLVRS 348 . Furthermore, it was found that the epitopes are highly conserved among JEV strains through sequence alignment. Notably, none of the homologous regions on NS1 proteins from other flaviviruses reacted with the MAbs when they were tested for cross-reactivity, and all five epitope peptides were not recognized by sera against West Nile virus or Dengue virus. These novel virus-specific linear B-cell epitopes of JEV NS1 would benefit the development of new vaccines and diagnostic assays.">
    <entity charOffset="9-21" id="11a3797796973b32b0763f8127b908f4783e5734.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002383" text="encephalitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="173-181" id="11a3797796973b32b0763f8127b908f4783e5734.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="173-181" id="11a3797796973b32b0763f8127b908f4783e5734.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1481-1485" id="11a3797796973b32b0763f8127b908f4783e5734.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0004617" text="sera" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="11a3797796973b32b0763f8127b908f4783e5734.c1.e0" e2="11a3797796973b32b0763f8127b908f4783e5734.c1.e1" id="11a3797796973b32b0763f8127b908f4783e5734.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="11a3797796973b32b0763f8127b908f4783e5734.c1.e0" e2="11a3797796973b32b0763f8127b908f4783e5734.c1.e2" id="11a3797796973b32b0763f8127b908f4783e5734.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="11a3797796973b32b0763f8127b908f4783e5734.c1.e0" e2="11a3797796973b32b0763f8127b908f4783e5734.c1.e3" id="11a3797796973b32b0763f8127b908f4783e5734.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
