<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="12c2a6ee1e3e7cf0f915e5c5454627b7e1ed9db3">
  <chunk id="12c2a6ee1e3e7cf0f915e5c5454627b7e1ed9db3.c0" text="Epimedium koreanum Nakai Displays Broad Spectrum of Antiviral Activity in Vitro and in Vivo by Inducing Cellular Antiviral State"/>
  <chunk id="12c2a6ee1e3e7cf0f915e5c5454627b7e1ed9db3.c1" text="Epimedium koreanum Nakai has been extensively used in traditional Korean and Chinese medicine to treat a variety of diseases. Despite the plant's known immune modulatory potential and chemical make-up, scientific information on its antiviral properties and mode of action have not been completely investigated. In this study, the broad antiviral spectrum and mode of action of an aqueous extract from Epimedium koreanum Nakai was evaluated in vitro, and moreover, the protective effect against divergent influenza A subtypes was determined in BALB/c mice. An effective dose of Epimedium koreanum Nakai markedly reduced the replication of Influenza A Virus (PR8), Vesicular Stomatitis Virus (VSV), Herpes Simplex Virus (HSV) and Newcastle Disease Virus (NDV) in RAW264.7 and HEK293T cells. Mechanically, we found that an aqueous extract from Epimedium koreanum Nakai induced the secretion of type I IFN and pro-inflammatory cytokines and the subsequent stimulation of the antiviral state in cells. Among various components present in the extract, quercetin was confirmed to have striking antiviral properties. The oral administration of Epimedium koreanum Nakai exhibited preventive effects on BALB/c mice">
    <entity charOffset="673-683" id="12c2a6ee1e3e7cf0f915e5c5454627b7e1ed9db3.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0010280" text="Stomatitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="878-887" id="12c2a6ee1e3e7cf0f915e5c5454627b7e1ed9db3.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0046903" text="secretion" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="12c2a6ee1e3e7cf0f915e5c5454627b7e1ed9db3.c1.e0" e2="12c2a6ee1e3e7cf0f915e5c5454627b7e1ed9db3.c1.e1" id="12c2a6ee1e3e7cf0f915e5c5454627b7e1ed9db3.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="12c2a6ee1e3e7cf0f915e5c5454627b7e1ed9db3.c2" text="Viruses 2015, 7 353 against lethal doses of highly pathogenic influenza A subtypes (H1N1, H5N2, H7N3 and H9N2). Therefore, an extract of Epimedium koreanum Nakai and its components play roles as immunomodulators in the innate immune response, and may be potential candidates for prophylactic or therapeutic treatments against diverse viruses in animal and humans.">
    <entity charOffset="219-241" id="12c2a6ee1e3e7cf0f915e5c5454627b7e1ed9db3.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0045087" text="innate immune response" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
