<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="12fe4cca998a403e153ae872595eab2676c77d2f">
  <chunk id="12fe4cca998a403e153ae872595eab2676c77d2f.c0" text="Phenotypic characteristics of human type II alveolar epithelial cells suitable for antigen presentation to T lymphocytes">
    <entity charOffset="83-103" id="12fe4cca998a403e153ae872595eab2676c77d2f.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0019882" text="antigen presentation" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="12fe4cca998a403e153ae872595eab2676c77d2f.c1" text="Background: Type II alveolar epithelial cells (AECII) are well known for their role in the innate immune system. More recently, it was proposed that they could play a role in the antigen presentation to T lymphocytes but contradictory results have been published both concerning their surface expressed molecules and the T lymphocyte responses in mixed lymphocyte cultures. The use of either AECII cell line or fresh cells could explain the observed discrepancies. Thus, this study aimed at defining the most relevant model of accessory antigen presenting cells by carefully comparing the two models for their expression of surface molecules necessary for efficient antigen presentation.">
    <entity charOffset="179-199" id="12fe4cca998a403e153ae872595eab2676c77d2f.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0019882" text="antigen presentation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="666-686" id="12fe4cca998a403e153ae872595eab2676c77d2f.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0019882" text="antigen presentation" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="12fe4cca998a403e153ae872595eab2676c77d2f.c2" text="We have compared by flow cytometry the surface expression of the major markers involved in the immunological synapse on the A549 cell line, the most popular model of type II alveolar epithelial cells, and freshly isolated cells. HLA-DR, CD80, CD86, ICOS-L, CD54, CD58 surface expression were studied in resting conditions as well as after IFN-γ/TNF-α treatment, two inflammatory cytokines, known to modulate some of these markers. Results: The major difference found between the two cells types was the very low surface expression of HLA-DR on the A549 cell line compared to its constitutive expression on freshly isolated AECII. The surface expression of co-stimulatory molecules from the B7 family was very low for the CD86 (B7-2) and ICOS-L (B7-H2) and absent for CD80 (B7-1) on both freshly isolated cells and A549 cell line. Neither IFN-γ nor TNF-α could increase the expression of these classical co-stimulatory molecules. However CD54 (ICAM-1) and CD58 (LFA-3) adhesion molecules, known to be implicated in B7 independent co-stimulatory signals, were well expressed on the two cell types. Conclusions: Constitutive expression of MHC class I and II molecules as well as alternative co-stimulatory molecules by freshly isolated AECII render these cells a good model to study antigen presentation.">
    <entity charOffset="95-116" id="12fe4cca998a403e153ae872595eab2676c77d2f.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0001772" text="immunological synapse" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="109-116" id="12fe4cca998a403e153ae872595eab2676c77d2f.c2.e1" ontology_id="GO_0045202" text="synapse" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
