<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="14c6dff031b3bcf8a7ea8486965b1dd888cf46a4">
  <chunk id="14c6dff031b3bcf8a7ea8486965b1dd888cf46a4.c0" text="A safe and convenient pseudovirus-based inhibition assay to detect neutralizing antibodies and screen for viral entry inhibitors against the novel human coronavirus MERS-CoV"/>
  <chunk id="14c6dff031b3bcf8a7ea8486965b1dd888cf46a4.c1" text="Background: Evidence points to the emergence of a novel human coronavirus, Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus (MERS-CoV), which causes a severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS)-like disease. In response, the development of effective vaccines and therapeutics remains a clinical priority. To accomplish this, it is necessary to evaluate neutralizing antibodies and screen for MERS-CoV entry inhibitors. Methods: In this study, we produced a pseudovirus bearing the full-length spike (S) protein of MERS-CoV in the Env-defective, luciferase-expressing HIV-1 backbone. We then established a pseudovirus-based inhibition assay to detect neutralizing antibodies and anti-MERS-CoV entry inhibitors. Results: Our results demonstrated that the generated MERS-CoV pseudovirus allows for single-cycle infection of a variety of cells expressing dipeptidyl peptidase-4 (DPP4), the confirmed receptor for MERS-CoV. Consistent with the results from a live MERS-CoV-based inhibition assay, the antisera of mice vaccinated with a recombinant protein containing receptor-binding domain (RBD, residues 377-662) of MERS-CoV S fused with Fc of human IgG exhibited neutralizing antibody response against infection of MERS-CoV pseudovirus. Furthermore, one small molecule HIV entry inhibitor targeting gp41 (ADS-J1) and the 3-hydroxyphthalic anhydride-modified human serum albumin (HP-HSA) could significantly inhibit MERS-CoV pseudovirus infection. Conclusion: Taken together, the established MERS-CoV inhibition assay is a safe and convenient pseudovirus-based alternative to BSL-3 live-virus restrictions and can be used to rapidly screen MERS-CoV entry inhibitors, as well as evaluate vaccine-induced neutralizing antibodies against the highly pathogenic MERS-CoV.">
    <entity charOffset="147-153" id="14c6dff031b3bcf8a7ea8486965b1dd888cf46a4.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="154-159" id="14c6dff031b3bcf8a7ea8486965b1dd888cf46a4.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1168-1176" id="14c6dff031b3bcf8a7ea8486965b1dd888cf46a4.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1168-1176" id="14c6dff031b3bcf8a7ea8486965b1dd888cf46a4.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="14c6dff031b3bcf8a7ea8486965b1dd888cf46a4.c1.e0" e2="14c6dff031b3bcf8a7ea8486965b1dd888cf46a4.c1.e2" id="14c6dff031b3bcf8a7ea8486965b1dd888cf46a4.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="14c6dff031b3bcf8a7ea8486965b1dd888cf46a4.c1.e0" e2="14c6dff031b3bcf8a7ea8486965b1dd888cf46a4.c1.e3" id="14c6dff031b3bcf8a7ea8486965b1dd888cf46a4.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="14c6dff031b3bcf8a7ea8486965b1dd888cf46a4.c1.e1" e2="14c6dff031b3bcf8a7ea8486965b1dd888cf46a4.c1.e2" id="14c6dff031b3bcf8a7ea8486965b1dd888cf46a4.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="14c6dff031b3bcf8a7ea8486965b1dd888cf46a4.c1.e1" e2="14c6dff031b3bcf8a7ea8486965b1dd888cf46a4.c1.e3" id="14c6dff031b3bcf8a7ea8486965b1dd888cf46a4.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
