<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e">
  <chunk id="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e.c0" text="Experimental infection of hamsters with avian paramyxovirus serotypes 1 to 9"/>
  <chunk id="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e.c1" text="Avian paramyxoviruses (APMVs) are frequently isolated from domestic and wild birds throughout the world and are separated into nine serotypes (APMV-1 to -9). Only in the case of APMV-1, the infection of non-avian species has been investigated. The APMVs presently are being considered as human vaccine vectors. In this study, we evaluated the replication and pathogenicity of all nine APMV serotypes in hamsters. The hamsters were inoculated intranasally with each virus and monitored for clinical disease, pathology, histopathology, virus replication, and seroconversion. On the basis of one or more of these criteria, each of the APMV serotypes was found to replicate in hamsters. The APMVs produced mild or inapparent clinical signs in hamsters except for APMV-9, which produced moderate disease. Gross lesions were observed over the pulmonary surface of hamsters infected with APMV-2 &amp; -3, which showed petechial and ecchymotic hemorrhages, respectively. Replication of all of the APMVs except APMV-5 was confirmed in the nasal turbinates and lungs, indicating a tropism for the respiratory tract. Histologically, the infection resulted in lung lesions consistent with bronchointerstitial pneumonia of varying severity and nasal turbinates with blunting or loss of cilia of the epithelium lining the nasal septa. The majority of APMV-infected hamsters exhibited transient histological lesions that self resolved by 14 days post infection (dpi). All of the hamsters infected with the APMVs produced serotype-specific HI or neutralizing antibodies, confirming virus replication. Taken together, these results demonstrate that all nine known APMV serotypes are capable of replicating in hamsters with minimal disease and pathology.">
    <entity charOffset="702-706" id="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012825" text="mild" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="782-790" id="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012826" text="moderate" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1067-1074" id="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0009606" text="tropism" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1193-1202" id="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1214-1222" id="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e.c1.e4" ontology_id="HP_0012824" text="severity" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1366-1375" id="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e.c1.e5" ontology_id="HP_0025153" text="transient" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e.c1.e0" e2="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e.c1.e2" id="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e.c1.e1" e2="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e.c1.e2" id="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e.c1.e2" e2="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e.c1.e3" id="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e.c1.e2" e2="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e.c1.e4" id="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e.c1.e2" e2="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e.c1.e5" id="1686765b6847c2b132d0129be10f7263bac5973e.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
