<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="16eb672447620efa83aa59f913d690a95240f488">
  <chunk id="16eb672447620efa83aa59f913d690a95240f488.c0" text="The &quot;sweet&quot; side of a long pentraxin: how glycosylation affects PTX3 functions in innate immunity and inflammation">
    <entity charOffset="42-55" id="16eb672447620efa83aa59f913d690a95240f488.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0070085" text="glycosylation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="82-97" id="16eb672447620efa83aa59f913d690a95240f488.c0.e1" ontology_id="GO_0045087" text="innate immunity" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="16eb672447620efa83aa59f913d690a95240f488.c1" text="Innate immunity represents the first line of defense against pathogens and plays key roles in activation and orientation of the adaptive immune response. The innate immune system comprises both a cellular and a humoral arm. Components of the humoral arm include soluble pattern recognition molecules (PRMs) that recognize pathogen-associated molecular patterns and initiate the immune response in coordination with the cellular arm, therefore acting as functional ancestors of antibodies. The long pentraxin PTX3 is a prototypic soluble PRM that is produced at sites of infection and inflammation by both somatic and immune cells. Gene targeting of this evolutionarily conserved protein has revealed a non-redundant role in resistance to selected pathogens. Moreover, PTX3 exerts important functions at the crossroad between innate immunity, inflammation, and female fertility. The human PTX3 protein contains a single N-glycosylation site that is fully occupied by complex type oligosaccharides, mainly fucosylated and sialylated biantennary glycans. Glycosylation has been implicated in a number of PTX3 activities, including neutralization of influenza viruses, modulation of the complement system, and attenuation of leukocyte recruitment. Therefore, this post translational modification might act as a fine tuner of PTX3 functions in native immunity and inflammation. Here we review the studies on PTX3, with emphasis on the glycan-dependent mechanisms underlying pathogen recognition and crosstalk with other components of the innate immune system.">
    <entity charOffset="0-15" id="16eb672447620efa83aa59f913d690a95240f488.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0045087" text="Innate immunity" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="128-152" id="16eb672447620efa83aa59f913d690a95240f488.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0002250" text="adaptive immune response" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="137-152" id="16eb672447620efa83aa59f913d690a95240f488.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0006955" text="immune response" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="378-393" id="16eb672447620efa83aa59f913d690a95240f488.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0006955" text="immune response" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="825-840" id="16eb672447620efa83aa59f913d690a95240f488.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0045087" text="innate immunity" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1052-1065" id="16eb672447620efa83aa59f913d690a95240f488.c1.e5" ontology_id="GO_0070085" text="Glycosylation" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
