<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f">
  <chunk id="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c0" text="Quercetin Feeding in Newborn Dairy Calves Cannot Compensate Colostrum Deprivation: Study on Metabolic, Antioxidative and Inflammatory Traits"/>
  <chunk id="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1" text="Immaturity of the neonatal immune system is causative for high morbidity in calves and colostrum intake is crucial for acquiring passive immunity. Pathogenesis is promoted by reactive oxygen species accumulating at birth if counter-regulation is inadequate. The flavonol quercetin exerts antioxidative and anti-inflammatory effects that may enhance neonatal health. The aim of this work was to study effects of quercetin feeding on metabolic, antioxidative and inflammatory parameters in neonatal calves to investigate whether quercetin could compensate for insufficient colostrum supply. Twenty-eight newborn calves were assigned to two dietary groups fed colostrum or milk-based formula on day 1 and 2 and milk replacer thereafter. From day 2 onwards, 7 calves per diet group were additionally fed quercetin aglycone (50 mg/(kg body weight × day)). Blood samples were taken repeatedly to measure plasma concentrations of flavonols, glucose, lactate, total protein, albumin, urea, non-esterified fatty acids, triglycerides, cholesterol, insulin, glucagon, cortisol, immunoglobulins, fibrinogen, haptoglobin and serum amyloid A. Trolox equivalent antioxidative capacity, ferric reducing ability of plasma, thiobarbituric acid reactive species and F2isoprostanes were analyzed to evaluate plasma antioxidative status. Expression of tumor necrosis factor, interleukin-1α, interleukin-1β, serum amyloid A, haptoglobin, fibrinogen, Creactive protein, catalase, glutathione peroxidase and superoxide dismutase mRNA were measured in liver tissue on day 8. Plasma flavonol concentrations were detectable only after quercetin-feeding without differences between colostrum and formula feeding. Plasma glucose, lactate, total protein, immunoglobulins, triglycerides, cholesterol, trolox equivalent antioxidative capacity and thiobarbituric acid reactive species were higher after colostrum feeding. Body temperature, fecal fluidity and plasma concentrations of cortisol and PLOS ONE | Competing Interests: The authors have declared that no competing interests exist. haptoglobin were higher in formula-than in colostrum-fed groups. Hepatic mRNA expression of tumor necrosis factor was higher after quercetin feeding and expression of C-reactive protein was higher after formula feeding. Data confirm that colostrum improves neonatal health and indicate that quercetin feeding cannot compensate for insufficient colostrum supply.">
    <entity charOffset="147-159" id="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0009405" text="Pathogenesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1331-1336" id="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0002664" text="tumor" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1337-1345" id="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0001906" text="necrosis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="2149-2154" id="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0002664" text="tumor" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="2155-2163" id="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0001906" text="necrosis" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1.e0" e2="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1.e1" id="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1.e0" e2="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1.e3" id="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1.e1" e2="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1.e2" id="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1.e1" e2="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1.e4" id="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1.e2" e2="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1.e3" id="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1.e3" e2="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1.e4" id="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c1.p5" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="1771673809c10324fde2768ce37d548a5077577f.c2" text="Quercetin Supplementation in Neonatal Calves with Respect to Different Diet PLOS ONE |"/>
</document>
