<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="17cfe7cc0c68b1002bb31a2b2afa988ab9cdc890">
  <chunk id="17cfe7cc0c68b1002bb31a2b2afa988ab9cdc890.c0" text="Characterization of a novel species of adenovirus from Japanese microbat and role of CXADR as its entry factor"/>
  <chunk id="17cfe7cc0c68b1002bb31a2b2afa988ab9cdc890.c1" text="Mastadenovirus have been isolated from various bat species, some of them displaying a wide host range in cell culture. In this study, we isolated two BtAdVs from Japanese wild microbats. While one isolate was classified as Bat mastadenovirus A, the other was phylogenetically independent of other BtAdVs. It was rather related to, but serologically different from, canine adenoviruses. We propose that the latter, isolated from Asian parti-colored bat, should be assigned to a novel species of Bat mastadenovirus. Both isolates replicated in various mammalian cell lines, implying their wide cell tropism. To gain insight into cell tropism of these BtAdVs, we investigated the coxsackievirus and adenovirus receptor (CXADR) for virus entry to the cells. We prepared CXADRknockout canine kidney cells and found that replication of BtAdVs was significantly hampered in these cells. For confirmation, their replication in canine CXADR-addback cells was rescued to the levels with the original cells. We also found that viral replication was corrected in human or bat CXADR-transduced cells to similar levels as in canine CXADR-addback cells. These results suggest that BtAdVs were able to use several mammalian-derived CXADRs as entry factors.">
    <entity charOffset="597-604" id="17cfe7cc0c68b1002bb31a2b2afa988ab9cdc890.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0009606" text="tropism" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="632-639" id="17cfe7cc0c68b1002bb31a2b2afa988ab9cdc890.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0009606" text="tropism" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="17cfe7cc0c68b1002bb31a2b2afa988ab9cdc890.c2" text="Adenovirus (AdV) is a non-enveloped, double-stranded DNA virus, and is divided into five genera: Mastadenovirus, Atadenovirus, Ichtadenovirus, Siadenovirus, and Aviadenovirus. Recently, several novel members of Mastadenovirus were identified, and more than 40 species were registered in the International Committee"/>
</document>
