<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="1843389daffca2a8b5e04048821ce881eb068269">
  <chunk id="1843389daffca2a8b5e04048821ce881eb068269.c0" text="Complementing conventional infectious disease surveillance with national health insurance claims data in the Republic of Korea OPEN"/>
  <chunk id="1843389daffca2a8b5e04048821ce881eb068269.c1" text="Reported to claimed cases ratios (R/C ratio) were evaluated from monthly notifiable disease cases captured by NIDS and NHICS. The relationships between 26 infectious diseases and each surveillance system were analysed using Pearson's correlation analysis and linear regression. There was an overall increase in R/C ratio from 2010-2017 (0.37 to 0.78). In 22 infectious diseases, there was a correlation between NIDS and NHICS. Moreover, claim-based surveillance showed less fluctuating disease incidence rates than report-based surveillance for specific infectious diseases, such as varicella, mumps, and scarlet fever. However, for infectious diseases with episodic outbreaks or low incidence, it was difficult to assess NHICS usefulness. Claim-based surveillance is less affected by limitations of conventional report-based surveillance systems, such as reporting rate. Given delays in claim systems, a claim-based surveillance is expected to be complementary to conventional systems for the detection of various infectious diseases with the advancement of bio-information technology.">
    <entity charOffset="474-485" id="1843389daffca2a8b5e04048821ce881eb068269.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0031914" text="fluctuating" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="658-666" id="1843389daffca2a8b5e04048821ce881eb068269.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0025303" text="episodic" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="773-781" id="1843389daffca2a8b5e04048821ce881eb068269.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0032320" text="affected" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="1843389daffca2a8b5e04048821ce881eb068269.c2" text="Published: xx xx xxxx OPEN Interrupted time series analysis of overall R/C ratio. We conducted an interrupted time series (ITS) 20 to evaluate the changes in the R/C ratio over time and analysed the effect of enhanced report-based surveillance after the 2015 MERS-CoV infection outbreak. The ITS provides a tracking function on the time trend of R/C ratio, and the change in trend and level change after June 2015."/>
  <chunk id="1843389daffca2a8b5e04048821ce881eb068269.c3" text="Correlation between surveillance systems. Pearson's correlation analysis was employed to demonstrate the correlation between reported and claimed cases in both systems, and linear regression analysis was conducted to identify changes in the reporting rate over time and the fitness of the linear model. Two-tailed P-values of &lt;0.05 were considered statistically significant. All statistical analyses were performed using SAS 9.4 (SAS Institute Inc., Cary, NC, USA)."/>
  <chunk id="1843389daffca2a8b5e04048821ce881eb068269.c4" text="Ethical consideration. The study protocol was approved by the institutional review board of Korea University (approval number: KU-IRB-18-EX-51-A-1) and was performed in accordance with the relevant guidelines and regulations. As this study used secondary data obtained from the NHICS and NIDS and contained no personal information, the need for informed consent was waived."/>
</document>
