<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="18a116d870bd24c96d95317418946ce0873f2180">
  <chunk id="18a116d870bd24c96d95317418946ce0873f2180.c0" text="Ocular pathogenesis and immune reaction after intravitreal dispase injection in mice">
    <entity charOffset="7-19" id="18a116d870bd24c96d95317418946ce0873f2180.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0009405" text="pathogenesis" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="18a116d870bd24c96d95317418946ce0873f2180.c1" text="The purpose of the current study was to examine the ocular pathogenesis and immune reaction in mice after intravitreal dispase injection. Methods: Three microliters of dispase at a concentration of 0.2 U/μl were injected into the vitreal cavities of 4-6-weekold mice. Hematoxylin and eosin staining, immunofluorescence analysis, and electroretinograms of the eyes were then performed to assess ocular changes, and enzyme-linked immunospot assays and intracellular staining of single-cell suspensions of the spleens were used to detect immune changes during an 8 week observation period. Results: Neutrophils were the main inflammatory infiltrating cells appearing at the anterior chamber. No cluster of differentiation (CD)3+ labeled T cells, F4/80+ labeled macrophages, or CD56+ labeled natural killer cells were found in the vitreal cavities or retinas in dispase-injected mice within 5 days after injection. Proliferative vitreoretinopathy (PVR)like signs first appeared at 2 weeks, gradually increased thereafter, and reached peak values at 8 weeks. There was a statistically significant difference in b-wave amplitudes between the PVR and saline-control eyes. Enzyme-linked immunospot assays and intracellular staining showed that specific CD4+ and CD8+ labeled T cells were not involved in dispase-injected mice. Conclusions: Our data show that neutrophils in the anterior chamber and PVR-like signs in the retinas were found, and that specific immune reactions were not involved after intravitreal dispase injection in mice.">
    <entity charOffset="59-71" id="18a116d870bd24c96d95317418946ce0873f2180.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0009405" text="pathogenesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="450-463" id="18a116d870bd24c96d95317418946ce0873f2180.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005622" text="intracellular" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="925-942" id="18a116d870bd24c96d95317418946ce0873f2180.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0007773" text="vitreoretinopathy" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1201-1214" id="18a116d870bd24c96d95317418946ce0873f2180.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0005622" text="intracellular" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="18a116d870bd24c96d95317418946ce0873f2180.c1.e0" e2="18a116d870bd24c96d95317418946ce0873f2180.c1.e2" id="18a116d870bd24c96d95317418946ce0873f2180.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="18a116d870bd24c96d95317418946ce0873f2180.c1.e1" e2="18a116d870bd24c96d95317418946ce0873f2180.c1.e2" id="18a116d870bd24c96d95317418946ce0873f2180.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="18a116d870bd24c96d95317418946ce0873f2180.c1.e2" e2="18a116d870bd24c96d95317418946ce0873f2180.c1.e3" id="18a116d870bd24c96d95317418946ce0873f2180.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
