<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="1ca045bd7724943ce8c268353153bd522358625d">
  <chunk id="1ca045bd7724943ce8c268353153bd522358625d.c0" text="Positional Bias of MHC Class I Restricted T-Cell Epitopes in Viral Antigens Is Likely due to a Bias in Conservation"/>
  <chunk id="1ca045bd7724943ce8c268353153bd522358625d.c1" text="The immune system rapidly responds to intracellular infections by detecting MHC class I restricted T-cell epitopes presented on infected cells. It was originally thought that viral peptides are liberated during constitutive protein turnover, but this conflicts with the observation that viral epitopes are detected within minutes of their synthesis even when their source proteins exhibit half-lives of days. The DRiPs hypothesis proposes that epitopes derive from Defective Ribosomal Products (DRiPs), rather than degradation of mature protein products. One potential source of DRiPs is premature translation termination. If this is a major source of DRiPs, this should be reflected in positional bias towards the N-terminus. By contrast, if downstream initiation is a major source of DRiPs, there should be positional bias towards the C-terminus. Here, we systematically assessed positional bias of epitopes in viral antigens, exploiting the large set of data available in the Immune Epitope Database and Analysis Resource. We show a statistically significant degree of positional skewing among epitopes; epitopes from both ends of antigens tend to be under-represented. Centric-skewing correlates with a bias towards class I binding peptides being over-represented in the middle, in parallel with a higher degree of evolutionary conservation.">
    <entity charOffset="38-51" id="1ca045bd7724943ce8c268353153bd522358625d.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0005622" text="intracellular" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="339-348" id="1ca045bd7724943ce8c268353153bd522358625d.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0009058" text="synthesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="515-526" id="1ca045bd7724943ce8c268353153bd522358625d.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0009056" text="degradation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="598-609" id="1ca045bd7724943ce8c268353153bd522358625d.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0006412" text="translation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1228-1235" id="1ca045bd7724943ce8c268353153bd522358625d.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
