<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="1cb0c02329d10e7513faabdc57113172591d5406">
  <chunk id="1cb0c02329d10e7513faabdc57113172591d5406.c0" text="Rapid, Unbiased PRRSV Strain Detection Using MinION Direct RNA Sequencing and Bioinformatics Tools"/>
  <chunk id="1cb0c02329d10e7513faabdc57113172591d5406.c1" text="Prompt detection and effective control of porcine reproductive and respiratory syndrome virus (PRRSV) during outbreaks is important given its immense adverse impact on the swine industry. However, the diagnostic process can be challenging due to the high genetic diversity and high mutation rate of PRRSV. A diagnostic method that can provide more detailed genetic information about pathogens is urgently needed. In this study, we evaluated the ability of Oxford Nanopore MinION direct RNA sequencing to generate a PRRSV whole genome sequence and detect and discriminate virus at the strain-level. A nearly full length PRRSV genome was successfully generated from raw sequence reads, achieving an accuracy of 96% after consensus genome generation. Direct RNA sequencing reliably detected the PRRSV strain present with an accuracy of 99.9% using as few as 5 raw sequencing reads and successfully differentiated multiple co-infecting strains present in a sample. In addition, PRRSV strain information was obtained from clinical samples containing 10 4 to 10 6 viral copies or more within 6 hours of sequencing. Overall, direct viral RNA sequencing followed by bioinformatic analysis proves to be a promising approach for identification of the viral strain or strains involved in clinical infections, allowing for more precise prevention and control strategies during PRRSV outbreaks."/>
  <chunk id="1cb0c02329d10e7513faabdc57113172591d5406.c2" text="2 of 18 against a new introduction from outside the farm indicates a need for enhanced biosecurity, while a re-break of a resident strain suggests better strategies for an elimination or vaccination program are needed. Another big challenge for PRRS control is that PRRSV vaccine is not completely effective at preventing and controlling infection due to the high genetic diversity of the virus, thus outbreaks still occur in vaccinated herds [13] [14] [15] [16] . A diagnostic method which can provide genetic information about the strain causing infection would allow for identification of potential reasons for vaccination failure, such as limited cross-protection due to high genetic divergence from vaccine [17] , or in the case of genetic similarity to vaccine, perhaps a reversion to virulence (escape mutation) of the vaccine itself [18] . In addition to the clinical challenges mentioned above, PRRSV has widely divergent genetic lineages and is a rapidly evolving pathogen with novel variants which seem to be more divergent and virulent than those in the past [10, [19] [20] [21] . The continuous emergence of new virulent strains causes unexpected devastating outbreaks, such as the severe outbreaks of HP-PRRSV in China and MN184 and NADC30 outbreaks in the United States [22] [23] [24] [25] . The increasing incidence of co-infections of multiple strains further complicates PRRS diagnosis and control [26] . Hence, diagnostic tools that can provide more genetic information are extremely important for investigation, prevention, and control strategies for PRRSV outbreaks.">
    <entity charOffset="1195-1201" id="1cb0c02329d10e7513faabdc57113172591d5406.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="1cb0c02329d10e7513faabdc57113172591d5406.c3" text="Prompt detection of pathogens during an outbreak is essential for efficient disease control. Real-time quantitative reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction (RT-qPCR) testing, which has the advantages of short turnaround time and high sensitivity [27, 28] , is currently the primary molecular diagnostic method for PRRSV detection and is performed routinely in diagnostic laboratories. The current PCR methods can quickly detect the presence of PRRSV in general [29] , but cannot identify specific strains unless targeted primers are designed which requires prior knowledge about the strains of interest [26, 30] . Nucleic acid sequencing technologies have been incorporated as a new diagnostic tool in recent years to provide necessary support, such as strain information, for PCR in clinical sample diagnostics [31] [32] [33] . Sequencing approaches have been applied successfully to various fields in virology so far, such as the discovery of novel viruses/strains, whole viral genome sequencing, quasispecies detection, and epidemiological investigations [34, 35] . The fact that sequencing is robust and does not need prior knowledge of the pathogens/strains under detection is particularly important for rapid responses to highly variable pathogens, such as PRRSV [36] . The routine use of viral genome sequencing and genomic surveillance will not only serve as a powerful tool for PRRSV detection [37] , but also provides researchers with a better understanding of PRRSV epidemiology and how the virus transmits, spreads, and evolves, thus facilitating effective prevention and control measures [38] .">
    <entity charOffset="116-137" id="1cb0c02329d10e7513faabdc57113172591d5406.c3.e0" ontology_id="GO_0001171" text="reverse transcription" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="1cb0c02329d10e7513faabdc57113172591d5406.c4" text="Conventional sequencing methods for RNA viruses usually includes reverse transcription and PCR amplification during library preparation which is then followed by amplicon sequencing. These extra steps not only introduce bias, but also increase the sequencing time, making rapid diagnosis difficult [39] [40] [41] . The Oxford Nanopore MinION sequencer allows for sequencing of the RNA molecule directly, in its native format. This feature, together with other characteristics such as low start-up costs, portability, and real-time data streaming, makes the Oxford Nanopore MinION sequencer a good candidate for rapid RNA virus detection, even in resource-limited or remote areas [40, 42, 43] . Influenza virus was the first pathogen to be successfully sequenced in its native RNA format by direct RNA sequencing (DRS) using Oxford Nanopore MinION technology [44] . Since then, studies have been performed for other viruses, confirming the potential of MinION technology to aid in the detection of infectious viral agents [45, 46] . PRRSV whole genome sequencing (WGS) has been carried out previously using traditional Sanger sequencing [10] and next-generation short-read sequencing platforms [47] . Incorporating a bioinformatic approach, we systematically evaluated and standardized third-generation long-read MinION DRS for PRRSV whole genome generation and determined its ability to detect the viral strain present, its analytical sensitivity for strain-level diagnosis of clinical samples, and its feasibility for differentiation of co-existing multiple strains in a single sample. To our knowledge, our study is the first time PRRSV has been sequenced in its native RNA format without amplification.">
    <entity charOffset="65-86" id="1cb0c02329d10e7513faabdc57113172591d5406.c4.e0" ontology_id="GO_0001171" text="reverse transcription" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
