<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="1cbc073d7288259db8f24cd19ee27052c1eece02">
  <chunk id="1cbc073d7288259db8f24cd19ee27052c1eece02.c0" text="Regulation of Cytokine Production by the Unfolded Protein Response; implications for infection and Autoimmunity">
    <entity charOffset="14-33" id="1cbc073d7288259db8f24cd19ee27052c1eece02.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0001816" text="Cytokine Production" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="99-111" id="1cbc073d7288259db8f24cd19ee27052c1eece02.c0.e1" ontology_id="HP_0002960" text="Autoimmunity" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="1cbc073d7288259db8f24cd19ee27052c1eece02.c0.e0" e2="1cbc073d7288259db8f24cd19ee27052c1eece02.c0.e1" id="1cbc073d7288259db8f24cd19ee27052c1eece02.c0.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="1cbc073d7288259db8f24cd19ee27052c1eece02.c1" text="Protein folding in the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) is an essential cell function. To safeguard this process in the face of environmental threats and internal stressors, cells mount an evolutionarily conserved response known as the unfolded protein response (UPR). Invading pathogens induce cellular stress that impacts protein folding, thus the UPR is well situated to sense danger and contribute to immune responses. Cytokines (inflammatory cytokines and interferons) critically mediate host defense against pathogens, but when aberrantly produced, may also drive pathologic inflammation. The UPR influences cytokine production on multiple levels, from stimulation of pattern recognition receptors, to modulation of inflammatory signaling pathways, and the regulation of cytokine transcription factors. This review will focus on the mechanisms underlying cytokine regulation by the UPR, and the repercussions of this relationship for infection and autoimmune/autoinflammatory diseases. Interrogation of viral and bacterial infections has revealed increasing numbers of examples where pathogens induce or modulate the UPR and implicated UPR-modulated cytokines in host response. The flip side of this coin, the UPR/ER stress responses have been increasingly recognized in a variety of autoimmune and inflammatory diseases. Examples include monogenic disorders of ER function, diseases linked to misfolding protein (HLA-B27 and spondyloarthritis), diseases directly implicating UPR and autophagy genes (inflammatory bowel disease), and autoimmune diseases targeting highly secretory cells (e.g., diabetes). Given the burgeoning interest in pharmacologically targeting the UPR, greater discernment is needed regarding how the UPR regulates cytokine production during specific infections and autoimmune processes, and the relative place of this interaction in pathogenesis.">
    <entity charOffset="0-15" id="1cbc073d7288259db8f24cd19ee27052c1eece02.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0006457" text="Protein folding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="23-44" id="1cbc073d7288259db8f24cd19ee27052c1eece02.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005783" text="endoplasmic reticulum" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="318-333" id="1cbc073d7288259db8f24cd19ee27052c1eece02.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0006457" text="protein folding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="608-627" id="1cbc073d7288259db8f24cd19ee27052c1eece02.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0001816" text="cytokine production" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="729-738" id="1cbc073d7288259db8f24cd19ee27052c1eece02.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0023052" text="signaling" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1484-1493" id="1cbc073d7288259db8f24cd19ee27052c1eece02.c1.e5" ontology_id="GO_0006914" text="autophagy" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1737-1756" id="1cbc073d7288259db8f24cd19ee27052c1eece02.c1.e6" ontology_id="GO_0001816" text="cytokine production" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
