<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="1e2493a8e26be4ff934b96dedc32dc7cf5728370">
  <chunk id="1e2493a8e26be4ff934b96dedc32dc7cf5728370.c0" text="Trigger factor assisted soluble expression of recombinant spike protein of porcine epidemic diarrhea virus in Escherichia coli">
    <entity charOffset="92-100" id="1e2493a8e26be4ff934b96dedc32dc7cf5728370.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002014" text="diarrhea" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="1e2493a8e26be4ff934b96dedc32dc7cf5728370.c1" text="Background: Porcine epidemic diarrhea virus (PEDV) is a highly contagious enteric pathogen of swine. The spike glycoprotein (S) of PEDV is the major immunogenic determinant that plays a pivotal role in the induction of neutralizing antibodies against PEDV, which therefore is an ideal target for the development of subunit vaccine. In an attempt to develop a subunit vaccine for PEDV, we cloned two different fragments of S protein and expressed as glutathione S-transferase (GST)-tagged fusion proteins, namely rGST-COE and rGST-S1D, in E.coli. However, the expression of these recombinant protein antigens using a variety of expression vectors, strains, and induction conditions invariably resulted in inclusion bodies. To achieve the soluble expression of recombinant proteins, several chaperone co-expression systems were tested in this study. Results: We firstly tested various chaperone co-expression systems and found that co-expression of trigger factor (TF) with recombinant proteins at 15°C was most useful in soluble production of rGST-COE and rGST-S1D compared to GroEL-ES and DnaK-DnaJ-GrpE/GroEL-ES systems. The soluble rGST-COE and rGST-S1D were purified using glutathione Sepharose 4B with a yield of 7.5 mg/l and 5 mg/l, respectively. Purified proteins were detected by western blot using mouse anti-GST mAb and pig anti-PEDV immune sera. In an indirect ELISA, purified proteins showed immune reactivity with pig anti-PEDV immune sera. Finally, immunization of mice with 10 μg of purified proteins elicited highly potent serum IgG and serum neutralizing antibody titers.">
    <entity charOffset="29-37" id="1e2493a8e26be4ff934b96dedc32dc7cf5728370.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002014" text="diarrhea" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1571-1579" id="1e2493a8e26be4ff934b96dedc32dc7cf5728370.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1571-1579" id="1e2493a8e26be4ff934b96dedc32dc7cf5728370.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="1e2493a8e26be4ff934b96dedc32dc7cf5728370.c1.e0" e2="1e2493a8e26be4ff934b96dedc32dc7cf5728370.c1.e1" id="1e2493a8e26be4ff934b96dedc32dc7cf5728370.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="1e2493a8e26be4ff934b96dedc32dc7cf5728370.c1.e0" e2="1e2493a8e26be4ff934b96dedc32dc7cf5728370.c1.e2" id="1e2493a8e26be4ff934b96dedc32dc7cf5728370.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="1e2493a8e26be4ff934b96dedc32dc7cf5728370.c2" text="Conclusions: In this study, soluble production of recombinant spike protein of PEDV, rGST-COE and rGST-S1D, were achieved by using TF chaperone co-expression system. Our results suggest that soluble rGST-COE and rGST-S1D produced by co-expressing chaperones may have the potential to be used as subunit vaccine antigens."/>
</document>
