<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="207885268ef61365fc89820ecb7c854a3dc23d9a">
  <chunk id="207885268ef61365fc89820ecb7c854a3dc23d9a.c0" text="A novel mechanism of RNase L inhibition: Theiler's virus L Ã protein prevents 2-5A from binding to RNase L">
    <entity charOffset="88-95" id="207885268ef61365fc89820ecb7c854a3dc23d9a.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="207885268ef61365fc89820ecb7c854a3dc23d9a.c1" text="The OAS/RNase L pathway is one of the best-characterized effector pathways of the IFN antiviral response. It inhibits the replication of many viruses and ultimately promotes apoptosis of infected cells, contributing to the control of virus spread. However, viruses have evolved a range of escape strategies that act against different steps in the pathway. Here we unraveled a novel escape strategy involving Theiler's murine encephalomyelitis virus (TMEV) L* protein. Previously we found that L* was the first viral protein binding directly RNase L. Our current data show that L* binds the ankyrin repeats R1 and R2 of RNase L and inhibits 2'-5' oligoadenylates (2-5A) binding to RNase L. Thereby, L* prevents dimerization and oligomerization of RNase L in response to 2-5A. Using chimeric mouse hepatitis virus (MHV) expressing TMEV L*, we showed that L* efficiently inhibits RNase L in vivo. Interestingly, those data show that L* can functionally substitute for the MHV-encoded phosphodiesterase ns2, which acts upstream of L* in the OAS/RNase L pathway, by degrading 2-5A.">
    <entity charOffset="516-531" id="207885268ef61365fc89820ecb7c854a3dc23d9a.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0005515" text="protein binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="524-531" id="207885268ef61365fc89820ecb7c854a3dc23d9a.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="669-676" id="207885268ef61365fc89820ecb7c854a3dc23d9a.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="796-805" id="207885268ef61365fc89820ecb7c854a3dc23d9a.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0012115" text="hepatitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="207885268ef61365fc89820ecb7c854a3dc23d9a.c1.e0" e2="207885268ef61365fc89820ecb7c854a3dc23d9a.c1.e3" id="207885268ef61365fc89820ecb7c854a3dc23d9a.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="207885268ef61365fc89820ecb7c854a3dc23d9a.c1.e1" e2="207885268ef61365fc89820ecb7c854a3dc23d9a.c1.e3" id="207885268ef61365fc89820ecb7c854a3dc23d9a.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="207885268ef61365fc89820ecb7c854a3dc23d9a.c1.e2" e2="207885268ef61365fc89820ecb7c854a3dc23d9a.c1.e3" id="207885268ef61365fc89820ecb7c854a3dc23d9a.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="207885268ef61365fc89820ecb7c854a3dc23d9a.c2" text="Oligoadenylate synthetases (OAS) are a family of enzymes that produce 2'-5' oligoadenylates (2-5A) from ATP. OAS accumulate as inactive enzymes in cells that have been exposed to interferon. When infection of these cells occurs, double-stranded RNA produced during virus replication activates OAS, which produce 2-5A. 2-5A act as second messengers. They bind a cellular endonuclease called RNase L, thereby triggering the dimerization and the activation of this RNase. Active RNase L degrades cellular and viral RNA molecules, ultimately killing the infected cell, thus preventing virus spread. Viruses PLOS Pathogens | https://doi.have developed diverse mechanisms to escape RNase L activity. We report that Theiler's murine encephalomyelitis virus, a virus that produces persistent infections of the central nervous system, evolved a novel mechanism to escape the OAS/RNase L pathway. The L Ã protein produced by this virus binds RNase L very close to the pocket known to sense 2-5A and thereby prevents 2-5A from activating RNase L. This mechanism contrasts with that used by Influenza (flu) virus, which sequesters double-stranded RNA and thereby also inhibits alternative antiviral pathways. We further showed that the RNase L antagonist activity of L Ã is effective in vivo and that L Ã can substitute for 2-5A degrading enzymes produced by coronaviruses.">
    <entity charOffset="802-809" id="207885268ef61365fc89820ecb7c854a3dc23d9a.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0030645" text="central" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="207885268ef61365fc89820ecb7c854a3dc23d9a.c3" text="RNase L antagonism by inhibition of 2-5A binding PLOS Pathogens | https://doi.">
    <entity charOffset="41-48" id="207885268ef61365fc89820ecb7c854a3dc23d9a.c3.e0" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
