<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="21133fab598928cee990ee06d660b1d00f317175">
  <chunk id="21133fab598928cee990ee06d660b1d00f317175.c0" text="Associated Severe Acute Respiratory Illness in South Africa Using a Rapid Assessment Methodology">
    <entity charOffset="11-17" id="21133fab598928cee990ee06d660b1d00f317175.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="Severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="18-23" id="21133fab598928cee990ee06d660b1d00f317175.c0.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="Acute" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="21133fab598928cee990ee06d660b1d00f317175.c1" text="Local disease burden data are necessary to set national influenza vaccination policy. In 2010 the population of South Africa was 50 million and the HIV prevalence was 11%. We used a previously developed methodology to determine severe influenza burden in South Africa.">
    <entity charOffset="228-234" id="21133fab598928cee990ee06d660b1d00f317175.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="21133fab598928cee990ee06d660b1d00f317175.c2" text="Hospitalized severe acute respiratory illness (SARI) incidence was calculated, stratified by HIV status, for four age groups using data from population-based surveillance in one site situated in Gauteng Province for 2009-2011. These rates were adjusted for each of the remaining 8 provinces based on their prevalence of risk factors for pneumonia and healthcare-seeking behavior. We estimated non-hospitalized influenza-associated SARI from healthcare utilization surveys at two sites and used the percent of SARI cases positive for influenza from sentinel surveillance to derive the influenza-associated SARI rate. We applied rates of hospitalized and non-hospitalized influenza-associated SARI to census data to calculate the national number of cases. The percent of SARI cases that tested positive for influenza ranged from 7-17% depending on age group, year, province and HIV status. In 2010, there were an estimated 21,555 total severe influenza cases in HIV-uninfected individuals and 13,876 in HIV-infected individuals. In 2011, there were an estimated 29,892 total severe influenza cases in HIV-uninfected individuals and 17,289 in HIV-infected individuals. The incidence of influenza-associated SARI was highest in children &lt;5 years and was higher in HIV-infected than HIV-uninfected persons in all age groups. Influenza virus PLOS ONE |">
    <entity charOffset="13-19" id="21133fab598928cee990ee06d660b1d00f317175.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="20-25" id="21133fab598928cee990ee06d660b1d00f317175.c2.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="337-346" id="21133fab598928cee990ee06d660b1d00f317175.c2.e2" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="934-940" id="21133fab598928cee990ee06d660b1d00f317175.c2.e3" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1073-1079" id="21133fab598928cee990ee06d660b1d00f317175.c2.e4" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
