<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="21c5b88a655bb1b5b8c3c3cd1dc1aefcf2c75cbd">
  <chunk id="21c5b88a655bb1b5b8c3c3cd1dc1aefcf2c75cbd.c0" text="Porcine Reproductive and Respiratory Syndrome Virus strains with Higher Virulence Cause Marked Protein Profile Changes in MARC-145 Cells OPEN"/>
  <chunk id="21c5b88a655bb1b5b8c3c3cd1dc1aefcf2c75cbd.c1" text="Porcine reproductive and respiratory syndrome is an infectious disease that causes serious economic losses to the swine industry worldwide. To better understand the pathogenesis of the porcine reproductive and respiratory syndrome virus (PRRSV), three PRRSV strains with different molecular markers and virulence were used to infect MARC-145 cells. A total of 1804 proteins were identified, and 233 altered proteins and 72 signaling pathways involved in the proteomic profiling of virus-infected MARC-145 cells increased with the virulence of the PRRSV strain. The three types of viral strains shared a common pathway-the electron transport reaction in mitochondria-in the infected-MARC-145 cells. Moreover, the antisense pathway was the most variable of all significant signaling pathways for the highly virulent SX-1 strain, indicating that this unique pathway may be connected to the high virulence of the SX-1 strain. Our study is the first attempt to provide a proteome profile of MARC-145 cells infected with PRRSV strains with different virulence, and these findings will facilitate a deep understanding of the interactions between this virus and its host.">
    <entity charOffset="165-177" id="21c5b88a655bb1b5b8c3c3cd1dc1aefcf2c75cbd.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0009405" text="pathogenesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="423-432" id="21c5b88a655bb1b5b8c3c3cd1dc1aefcf2c75cbd.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0023052" text="signaling" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="631-640" id="21c5b88a655bb1b5b8c3c3cd1dc1aefcf2c75cbd.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0006810" text="transport" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="771-780" id="21c5b88a655bb1b5b8c3c3cd1dc1aefcf2c75cbd.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0023052" text="signaling" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="21c5b88a655bb1b5b8c3c3cd1dc1aefcf2c75cbd.c2" text="The porcine reproductive and respiratory syndrome virus (PRRSV), the causative agent of porcine reproductive and respiratory syndrome (PRRS), is an important pathogen in the swine industry, and it causes reproductive failure in pregnant sows and respiratory disorders in pigs of all ages 1 . As a member of the Arteriviridae family, PRRSV is an enveloped, linear, single positive-stranded RNA virus, and it is similar to the equine arteritis virus, lactate dehydrogenase-elevating virus, and simian hemorrhagic fever virus 2 . PRRSV can be classified into two distinct genotypes: type 1 (European type) and type 2 (North American type) 3,4 . In vivo, this virus mainly infects pulmonary alveolar macrophages (PAMs) 5-7 , whereas in vitro, MARC-145 cells are a good platform to study viral replication, pathogenesis, and host response [8] [9] [10] [11] .">
    <entity charOffset="432-441" id="21c5b88a655bb1b5b8c3c3cd1dc1aefcf2c75cbd.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012089" text="arteritis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="511-516" id="21c5b88a655bb1b5b8c3c3cd1dc1aefcf2c75cbd.c2.e1" ontology_id="HP_0001945" text="fever" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="21c5b88a655bb1b5b8c3c3cd1dc1aefcf2c75cbd.c3" text="In life cycle of cells, there are some natural antisense transcripts (NATs), which are reverse complementarity with mRNAs 12 . These NATs, also named antisense RNAs or natural regulatory RNAs, are small molecules and non-coding RNAs, mediating regulation and generally inhibiting mRNA transcription and/or translation or inducing their rapid degradation 13,14 . Signals regarding antisense RNA transcription and regulation were named the antisense pathway, in which PSF (Polypyrimidine tract-binding protein-associated-splicing factor), P54 (Non-POU domain-containing octamer-binding protein) and MATR3 (matrin-3) are major proteins 15-17 . PSF is a DNA-and RNA-binding protein, involved in regulation of signal-induced alternative splicing and homologous DNA pairing 18 . The PSF-P54 heterodimer associated with MATR3 may play a role in nuclear retention of defective RNAs 19 . PSF also binds to and represses gene promoter region, such as CTBP1, P53, SMAD3 and P21 20, 21 .">
    <entity charOffset="280-298" id="21c5b88a655bb1b5b8c3c3cd1dc1aefcf2c75cbd.c3.e0" ontology_id="GO_0009299" text="mRNA transcription" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="306-317" id="21c5b88a655bb1b5b8c3c3cd1dc1aefcf2c75cbd.c3.e1" ontology_id="GO_0006412" text="translation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="342-353" id="21c5b88a655bb1b5b8c3c3cd1dc1aefcf2c75cbd.c3.e2" ontology_id="GO_0009056" text="degradation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="380-407" id="21c5b88a655bb1b5b8c3c3cd1dc1aefcf2c75cbd.c3.e3" ontology_id="GO_0009300" text="antisense RNA transcription" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
