<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="225d47cea0dca6f6211b16f9bf8911e2360fb75b">
  <chunk id="225d47cea0dca6f6211b16f9bf8911e2360fb75b.c0" text="Development of real-time recombinase polymerase amplification assay for rapid and sensitive detection of canine parvovirus 2"/>
  <chunk id="225d47cea0dca6f6211b16f9bf8911e2360fb75b.c1" text="Background: Canine parvovirus 2, a linear single-stranded DNA virus belonging to the genus Parvovirus within the family Parvoviridae, is a highly contagious pathogen of domestic dogs and several wild canidae species. Early detection of canine parvovirus (CPV-2) is crucial to initiating appropriate outbreak control strategies. Recombinase polymerase amplification (RPA), a novel isothermal gene amplification technique, has been developed for the molecular detection of diverse pathogens. In this study, a real-time RPA assay was developed for the detection of CPV-2 using primers and an exo probe targeting the CPV-2 nucleocapsid protein gene. Results: The real-time RPA assay was performed successfully at 38°C, and the results were obtained within 4-12 min for 10 5 -10 1 molecules of template DNA. The assay only detected CPV-2, and did not show cross-detection of other viral pathogens, demonstrating a high level of specificity. The analytical sensitivity of the real-time RPA was 10 1 copies/ reaction of a standard DNA template, which was 10 times more sensitive than the common RPA method. The clinical sensitivity of the real-time RPA assay matched 100% (n = 91) to the real-time PCR results. Conclusion: The real-time RPA assay is a simple, rapid, reliable and affordable method that can potentially be applied for the detection of CPV-2 in the research laboratory and point-of-care diagnosis.">
    <entity charOffset="517-520" id="225d47cea0dca6f6211b16f9bf8911e2360fb75b.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0005662" text="RPA" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="619-631" id="225d47cea0dca6f6211b16f9bf8911e2360fb75b.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0019013" text="nucleocapsid" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="669-672" id="225d47cea0dca6f6211b16f9bf8911e2360fb75b.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0005662" text="RPA" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="980-983" id="225d47cea0dca6f6211b16f9bf8911e2360fb75b.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0005662" text="RPA" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1088-1091" id="225d47cea0dca6f6211b16f9bf8911e2360fb75b.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0005662" text="RPA" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1142-1145" id="225d47cea0dca6f6211b16f9bf8911e2360fb75b.c1.e5" ontology_id="GO_0005662" text="RPA" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1230-1233" id="225d47cea0dca6f6211b16f9bf8911e2360fb75b.c1.e6" ontology_id="GO_0005662" text="RPA" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
