<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399">
  <chunk id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399.c0" text="viruses Recombination in Enteroviruses, a Multi-Step Modular Evolutionary Process"/>
  <chunk id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399.c1" text="RNA recombination is a major driving force in the evolution and genetic architecture shaping of enteroviruses. In particular, intertypic recombination is implicated in the emergence of most pathogenic circulating vaccine-derived polioviruses, which have caused numerous outbreaks of paralytic poliomyelitis worldwide. Recent experimental studies that relied on recombination cellular systems mimicking natural genetic exchanges between enteroviruses provided new insights into the molecular mechanisms of enterovirus recombination and enabled to define a new model of genetic plasticity for enteroviruses. Homologous intertypic recombinant enteroviruses that were observed in nature would be the final products of a multi-step process, during which precursor nonhomologous recombinant genomes are generated through an initial inter-genomic RNA recombination event and can then evolve into a diversity of fitter homologous recombinant genomes over subsequent intra-genomic rearrangements. Moreover, these experimental studies demonstrated that the enterovirus genome could be defined as a combination of genomic modules that can be preferentially exchanged through recombination, and enabled defining the boundaries of these recombination modules. These results provided the first experimental evidence supporting the theoretical model of enterovirus modular evolution previously elaborated from phylogenetic studies of circulating enterovirus strains. This review summarizes our current knowledge regarding the mechanisms of recombination in enteroviruses and presents a new evolutionary process that may apply to other RNA viruses."/>
  <chunk id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399.c2" text="Over 20 clinically recognized syndromes have been frequently associated with human EVs. Among the most frequent are pathologies of the central nervous system (CNS): poliomyelitis, encephalitis, and meningitis [3] [4] [5] [6] . More than 90% of viral meningitis cases are caused by EVs. Enteroviral encephalitis and myelitis are less common, but more often have severe manifestations. Following the elimination of wild type PV in most regions of the world, EV-A type 71 (EV-A71) emerged as the most significant neurotropic EV. EVs are also frequently associated with acute pericarditis and myocarditis, hand-foot-and-mouth disease, pleurodynia, or respiratory disease [7] [8] [9] [10] [11] . RVs represent the principal cause of the common cold, a frequent infection both in children and adults, usually limited to the upper respiratory airways [8, 10] . The three types of PV belong to the EV-C species, which also includes many weakly or non-pathogenic coxsackieviruses A (CV-A), such as CV-A13 or CV-A17.">
    <entity charOffset="103-111" id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0040282" text="frequent" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="135-142" id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399.c2.e1" ontology_id="HP_0030645" text="central" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="180-192" id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399.c2.e2" ontology_id="HP_0002383" text="encephalitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="198-208" id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399.c2.e3" ontology_id="HP_0001287" text="meningitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="250-260" id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399.c2.e4" ontology_id="HP_0001287" text="meningitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="298-310" id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399.c2.e5" ontology_id="HP_0002383" text="encephalitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="315-323" id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399.c2.e6" ontology_id="HP_0012486" text="myelitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="361-367" id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399.c2.e7" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="566-571" id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399.c2.e8" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="572-584" id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399.c2.e9" ontology_id="HP_0001701" text="pericarditis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="747-755" id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399.c2.e10" ontology_id="HP_0040282" text="frequent" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399.c3" text="EVs are small non-enveloped viruses containing a single positive-strand RNA genome of approximately 7.5 kb in length. This genome encodes a large open reading frame (ORF) that is translated into a polyprotein processed by viral proteases (2A, 3C, and 3CD) to yield four capsid proteins (VP1-4) and non-structural proteins, such as proteases and the RNA-dependent RNA polymerase (RdRp) 3D, which are involved in the viral multiplication and the control of the cellular environment ( Figure 1 ). Viral replication cycles entirely occur in the cytoplasm of infected cells [12] . It was recently demonstrated that the majority of EV-A and EV-B genomes and around half the EV-C genomes contain a second ORF located upstream and overlapping the polyprotein ORF (ppORF) [13] . This second upstream ORF (uORF) encodes a single protein that may play a role in virus growth in gut epithelial cells, which are the entry site of these viruses into a susceptible host. Two untranslated regions flank the coding region of EV genome (5 and 3 UTR). The EV 5 UTR is about 740 nucleotides in length and it contains seven highly conserved stem-loop domains (I to VII) forming two functional units (Figure 1) . Domain I forms a cloverleaf (CL) structure that is required for initiating both negative-and positive-strand RNA synthesis [14] [15] [16] [17] . Domains II to VI (dII to dVI) contain the internal ribosome entry site (IRES) that initiates cap-independent translation by interacting with canonical and noncanonical cellular translation factors to recruit ribosomes [18, 19] . The CL and IRES elements are separated by a short pyrimidine-rich sequence, named spacer 1, and the IRES is linked to the initiation AUG codon of the ppORF by dVII and a poorly structured sequence of about 100 nucleotides, named spacer 2 [20]. This dVII-spacer 2 region contains the main part of the uORF that is present in many EV genomes [13] .">
    <entity charOffset="379-383" id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399.c3.e0" ontology_id="GO_0003968" text="RdRp" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="541-550" id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399.c3.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005737" text="cytoplasm" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="857-863" id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399.c3.e2" ontology_id="GO_0040007" text="growth" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1300-1313" id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399.c3.e3" ontology_id="GO_0032774" text="RNA synthesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1304-1313" id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399.c3.e4" ontology_id="GO_0009058" text="synthesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1387-1395" id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399.c3.e5" ontology_id="GO_0005840" text="ribosome" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1445-1456" id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399.c3.e6" ontology_id="GO_0006412" text="translation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1513-1524" id="22a7db49b1d6a2856d8737d3739af18b715cd399.c3.e7" ontology_id="GO_0006412" text="translation" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
