<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="232dc9f3baa927facbe91722ae717e0738a73981">
  <chunk id="232dc9f3baa927facbe91722ae717e0738a73981.c0" text="Genome-wide expression profiling shows transcriptional reprogramming in Fusarium graminearum by Fusarium graminearum virus 1-DK21 infection"/>
  <chunk id="232dc9f3baa927facbe91722ae717e0738a73981.c1" text="Background: Fusarium graminearum virus 1 strain-DK21 (FgV1-DK21) is a mycovirus that confers hypovirulence to F. graminearum, which is the primary phytopathogenic fungus that causes Fusarium head blight (FHB) disease in many cereals. Understanding the interaction between mycoviruses and plant pathogenic fungi is necessary for preventing damage caused by F. graminearum. Therefore, we investigated important cellular regulatory processes in a host containing FgV1-DK21 as compared to an uninfected parent using a transcriptional approach. Results: Using a 3′-tiling microarray covering all known F. graminearum genes, we carried out genome-wide expression analyses of F. graminearum at two different time points. At the early point of growth of an infected strain as compared to an uninfected strain, genes associated with protein synthesis, including ribosome assembly, nucleolus, and ribosomal RNA processing, were significantly up-regulated. In addition, genes required for transcription and signal transduction, including fungal-specific transcription factors and cAMP signaling, respectively, were actively up-regulated. In contrast, genes involved in various metabolic pathways, particularly in producing carboxylic acids, aromatic amino acids, nitrogen compounds, and polyamines, showed dramatic down-regulation at the early time point. Moreover, genes associated with transport systems localizing to transmembranes were down-regulated at both time points.">
    <entity charOffset="736-742" id="232dc9f3baa927facbe91722ae717e0738a73981.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0040007" text="growth" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="853-861" id="232dc9f3baa927facbe91722ae717e0738a73981.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005840" text="ribosome" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="887-900" id="232dc9f3baa927facbe91722ae717e0738a73981.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0005840" text="ribosomal RNA" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1377-1386" id="232dc9f3baa927facbe91722ae717e0738a73981.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0006810" text="transport" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="232dc9f3baa927facbe91722ae717e0738a73981.c2" text="Conclusion: This is the first report of global change in the prominent cellular pathways in the Fusarium host containing FgV1-DK21. The significant increase in transcripts for transcription and translation machinery in fungal host cells seems to be related to virus replication. In addition, significant down-regulation of genes required for metabolism and transporting systems in a fungal host containing the virus appears to be related to the host defense mechanism and fungal virulence. Taken together, our data aid in the understanding of how FgV1-DK21 regulates the transcriptional reprogramming of F. graminearum.">
    <entity charOffset="194-205" id="232dc9f3baa927facbe91722ae717e0738a73981.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0006412" text="translation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="342-352" id="232dc9f3baa927facbe91722ae717e0738a73981.c2.e1" ontology_id="GO_0008152" text="metabolism" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
