<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="2448743a5de075f6a1816e46fe72b69cc791da18">
  <chunk id="2448743a5de075f6a1816e46fe72b69cc791da18.c0" text="Expression of 9-O-and 7,9-O-Acetyl Modified Sialic Acid in Cells and Their Effects on Influenza Viruses"/>
  <chunk id="2448743a5de075f6a1816e46fe72b69cc791da18.c1" text="Sialic acids (Sia) are widely displayed on the surfaces of cells and tissues. Sia come in a variety of chemically modified forms, including those with acetyl modifications at the C-7, C-8, and C-9 positions. Here, we analyzed the distribution and amounts of these acetyl modifications in different human and canine cells. Since Sia or their variant forms are receptors for influenza A, B, C, and D viruses, we examined the effects of these modifications on virus infections. We confirmed that 9-O-acetyl and 7,9-O-acetyl modified Sia are widely but variably expressed across cell lines from both humans and canines. Although they were expressed on the cell surfaces of canine MDCK cell lines, they were located primarily within the Golgi compartment of human HEK-293 and A549 cells. The O-acetyl modified Sia were expressed at low levels of 1 to 2% of total Sia in these cell lines. We knocked out and overexpressed the sialate O-acetyltransferase gene (CasD1) and knocked out the sialate O-acetylesterase gene (SIAE) using CRISPR/Cas9 editing. Knocking out CasD1 removed 7,9-O-and 9-O-acetyl Sia expression, confirming previous reports. However, overexpression of CasD1 and knockout of SIAE gave only modest increases in 9-Oacetyl levels in cells and no change in 7,9-O-acetyl levels, indicating that there are complex regulations of these modifications. These modifications were essential for influenza C and D infection but had no obvious effect on influenza A and B infection. IMPORTANCE Sialic acids are key glycans that are involved in many different normal cellular functions, as well as being receptors for many pathogens. However, Sia come in diverse chemically modified forms. Here, we examined and manipulated the expression of 7,9-O-and 9-O-acetyl modified Sia on cells commonly used in influenza virus and other research by engineering the enzymes that produce or remove the acetyl groups."/>
</document>
