<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="24de2f3f8107492057953a49ec7182514e9ff95a">
  <chunk id="24de2f3f8107492057953a49ec7182514e9ff95a.c0" text="Epidemiology and Infection Prevalence of comorbidities in cases of Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus: a retrospective study"/>
  <chunk id="24de2f3f8107492057953a49ec7182514e9ff95a.c1" text="The Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus (MERS-CoV) is a life-threatening respiratory disease with a high case fatality rate; however, its risk factors remain unclear. We aimed to explore the influence of demographic factors, clinical manifestations and underlying comorbidities on mortality in MERS-CoV patients. Retrospective chart reviews were performed to identify all laboratory-confirmed cases of MERS-COV infection in Saudi Arabia that were reported to the Ministry of Health of Saudi Arabia between 23 April 2014 and 7 June 2016. Statistical analyses were conducted to assess the effect of sex, age, clinical presentation and comorbidities on mortality from MERS-CoV. A total of 281 confirmed MERS-CoV cases were identified: 167 (59.4%) patients were male and 55 (20%) died. Mortality predominantly occurred among Saudi nationals and older patients and was significantly associated with respiratory failure and shortness of breath. Of the 281 confirmed cases, 160 (56.9%) involved comorbidities, wherein diabetes mellitus, hypertension, ischemic heart disease, congestive heart failure, end-stage renal disease and chronic kidney disease were significantly associated with mortality from MERS-CoV and two or three comorbidities significantly affected the fatality rates from MERS-CoV. The findings of this study show that old age and the existence of underlying comorbidities significantly increase mortality from MERS-CoV.">
    <entity charOffset="903-922" id="24de2f3f8107492057953a49ec7182514e9ff95a.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002878" text="respiratory failure" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1077-1101" id="24de2f3f8107492057953a49ec7182514e9ff95a.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0001635" text="congestive heart failure" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1103-1126" id="24de2f3f8107492057953a49ec7182514e9ff95a.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0003774" text="end-stage renal disease" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1131-1138" id="24de2f3f8107492057953a49ec7182514e9ff95a.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0011010" text="chronic" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1131-1153" id="24de2f3f8107492057953a49ec7182514e9ff95a.c1.e4" ontology_id="HP_0012622" text="chronic kidney disease" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1258-1266" id="24de2f3f8107492057953a49ec7182514e9ff95a.c1.e5" ontology_id="HP_0032320" text="affected" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
