<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="27bafe2069fadba9638ec9eb5ae1afaf3c78cfb8">
  <chunk id="27bafe2069fadba9638ec9eb5ae1afaf3c78cfb8.c0" text="Mechanisms of HIV non-progression; robust and sustained CD4+ T-cell proliferative responses to p24 antigen correlate with control of viraemia and lack of disease progression after long-term transfusion-acquired HIV-1 infection"/>
  <chunk id="27bafe2069fadba9638ec9eb5ae1afaf3c78cfb8.c1" text="Background: Elite non-progressors (plasma viral load &lt;50 copies/ml while antiretroviral naive) constitute a tiny fraction of HIV-infected individuals. After 12 years follow-up of a cohort of 13 long-term non-progressors (LTNP) identified from 135 individuals with transfusion-acquired HIV infection, 5 remained LTNP after 23 to 26 years infection, but only 3 retained elite LTNP status. We examined the mechanisms that differentiated delayed progressors from LTNP in this cohort."/>
  <chunk id="27bafe2069fadba9638ec9eb5ae1afaf3c78cfb8.c2" text="Results: A survival advantage was conferred on 12 of 13 subjects, who had at least one host genetic factor (HLA, chemokine receptor or TLR polymorphisms) or viral attenuating factor (defective nef) associated with slow progression. However, antiviral immune responses differentiated the course of disease into and beyond the second decade of infection. A stable p24specific proliferative response was associated with control of viraemia and retention of nonprogressor status, but this p24 response was absent or declined in viraemic subjects. Strong Gagdominant cytotoxic T lymphocyte (CTL) responses were identified in most LTNP, or Pol dominant-CTL in those with nef-defective HIV infection. CTL were associated with control of viraemia when combined with p24 proliferative responses. However, CTL did not prevent late disease progression. Individuals with sustained viral suppression had CTL recognising numerous Gag epitopes, while strong but restricted responses to one or two immunodominant epitopes was effective for some time, but failed to contain viraemia over the course of this study. Viral escape mutants at a HLA B27-restricted Gag-p24 epitope were detected in only">
    <entity charOffset="355-361" id="27bafe2069fadba9638ec9eb5ae1afaf3c78cfb8.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0031915" text="stable" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
