<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="28040123483f1f80ef9b612102f0b2083eac4ec4">
  <chunk id="28040123483f1f80ef9b612102f0b2083eac4ec4.c0" text="Epstein-Barr Virus Stimulates Torque Teno Virus Replication: A Possible Relationship to Multiple Sclerosis"/>
  <chunk id="28040123483f1f80ef9b612102f0b2083eac4ec4.c1" text="Viral infections have been implicated in the pathogenesis of multiple sclerosis. Epstein-Barr virus (EBV) has frequently been investigated as a possible candidate and torque teno virus (TTV) has also been discussed in this context. Nevertheless, mechanistic aspects remain unresolved. We report viral replication, as measured by genome amplification, as well as quantitative PCR of two TTV-HD14 isolates isolated from multiple sclerosis brain in a series of EBV-positive and -negative lymphoblastoid and Burkitt's lymphoma cell lines. Our results demonstrate the replication of both transfected TTV genomes up to day 21 post transfection in all the evaluated cell lines. Quantitative amplification indicates statistically significant enhanced TTV replication in the EBV-positive cell lines, including the EBV-converted BJAB line, in comparison to the EBVnegative Burkitt's lymphoma cell line BJAB. This suggests a helper effect of EBV infections in the replication of TTV. The present study provides information on a possible interaction of EBV and TTV in the etiology and progression of multiple sclerosis.">
    <entity charOffset="45-57" id="28040123483f1f80ef9b612102f0b2083eac4ec4.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0009405" text="pathogenesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="514-522" id="28040123483f1f80ef9b612102f0b2083eac4ec4.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0002665" text="lymphoma" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="873-881" id="28040123483f1f80ef9b612102f0b2083eac4ec4.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0002665" text="lymphoma" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="28040123483f1f80ef9b612102f0b2083eac4ec4.c1.e0" e2="28040123483f1f80ef9b612102f0b2083eac4ec4.c1.e1" id="28040123483f1f80ef9b612102f0b2083eac4ec4.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="28040123483f1f80ef9b612102f0b2083eac4ec4.c1.e0" e2="28040123483f1f80ef9b612102f0b2083eac4ec4.c1.e2" id="28040123483f1f80ef9b612102f0b2083eac4ec4.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
