<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="28a0bf1e235fe876fff1127346bb3bac0b6e5072">
  <chunk id="28a0bf1e235fe876fff1127346bb3bac0b6e5072.c0" text="Elucidating the Interacting Domains of Chandipura Virus Nucleocapsid Protein">
    <entity charOffset="56-68" id="28a0bf1e235fe876fff1127346bb3bac0b6e5072.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0019013" text="Nucleocapsid" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="28a0bf1e235fe876fff1127346bb3bac0b6e5072.c1" text="The nucleocapsid (N) protein of Chandipura virus (CHPV) plays a crucial role in viral life cycle, besides being an important structural component of the virion through proper organization of its interactions with other viral proteins. In a recent study, the authors had mapped the associations among CHPV proteins and shown that N protein interacts with four of the viral proteins: N, phosphoprotein (P), matrix protein (M), and glycoprotein (G). The present study aimed to distinguish the regions of CHPV N protein responsible for its interactions with other viral proteins. In this direction, we have generated the structure of CHPV N protein by homology modeling using SWISS-MODEL workspace and Accelrys Discovery Studio client 2.55 and mapped the domains of N protein using PiSQRD. The interactions of N protein fragments with other proteins were determined by ZDOCK rigid-body docking method and validated by yeast two-hybrid and ELISA. The study revealed a unique binding site, comprising of amino acids 1-30 at the N terminus of the nucleocapsid protein (N1) that is instrumental in its interactions with N, P, M, and G proteins. It was also observed that N2 associates with N and G proteins while N3 interacts with N, P, and M proteins.">
    <entity charOffset="4-16" id="28a0bf1e235fe876fff1127346bb3bac0b6e5072.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0019013" text="nucleocapsid" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="80-96" id="28a0bf1e235fe876fff1127346bb3bac0b6e5072.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0019058" text="viral life cycle" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="153-159" id="28a0bf1e235fe876fff1127346bb3bac0b6e5072.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0019012" text="virion" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="401-404" id="28a0bf1e235fe876fff1127346bb3bac0b6e5072.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_1990295" text="Paa" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="970-977" id="28a0bf1e235fe876fff1127346bb3bac0b6e5072.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1040-1052" id="28a0bf1e235fe876fff1127346bb3bac0b6e5072.c1.e5" ontology_id="GO_0019013" text="nucleocapsid" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
