<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="2bf72671f78524129acb86ceef6c598e10c7daa7">
  <chunk id="2bf72671f78524129acb86ceef6c598e10c7daa7.c0" text="Structure of a Highly Active Cephalopod S-crystallin Mutant: New Molecular Evidence for Evolution from an Active Enzyme into Lens-Refractive Protein OPEN"/>
  <chunk id="2bf72671f78524129acb86ceef6c598e10c7daa7.c1" text="(GST) with various homologs differentially expressed in the lens. However, there is no direct structural information that helps to delineate the mechanisms by which S-crystallin could have evolved. Here we report the structural and biochemical characterization of novel S-crystallin-glutathione complex. The 2.35-Å crystal structure of a S-crystallin mutant from Octopus vulgaris reveals an active-site architecture that is different from that of GST. S-crystallin has a preference for glutathione binding, although almost lost its GST enzymatic activity. We've also identified four historical mutations that are able to produce a &quot;GST-like&quot; S-crystallin that has regained activity. This protein recapitulates the evolution of S-crystallin from GST. Protein stability studies suggest that S-crystallin is stabilized by glutathione binding to prevent its aggregation; this contrasts with GST-σ, which do not possess this protection. We suggest that a tradeoff between enzyme activity and the stability of the lens protein might have been one of the major driving force behind lens evolution.">
    <entity charOffset="486-505" id="2bf72671f78524129acb86ceef6c598e10c7daa7.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0043295" text="glutathione binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="498-505" id="2bf72671f78524129acb86ceef6c598e10c7daa7.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="819-838" id="2bf72671f78524129acb86ceef6c598e10c7daa7.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0043295" text="glutathione binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="831-838" id="2bf72671f78524129acb86ceef6c598e10c7daa7.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="967-982" id="2bf72671f78524129acb86ceef6c598e10c7daa7.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0003824" text="enzyme activity" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="2bf72671f78524129acb86ceef6c598e10c7daa7.c2" text="Crystallins are soluble proteins in eye lenses that play an important role in the maintenance of lens transparency and optical clarity 1 . Their aggregation can result in the formation of cataracts, which are the most common cause of blindness worldwide 2 . Up to the present, the only treatment for this is the surgical removal of cataractous lens, albeit it has been reported very recently that lanosterol may reverse aggregation of crystallin 3 . Interestingly, some taxon-specific crystallins have been found to have structures that are related to cytosolic housekeeping enzymes 4,5 . How lens crystallins evolved from such housekeeping enzymes is a most important question and answers to this question will greatly help our understanding of protein function, folding, and stability 6 .">
    <entity charOffset="234-243" id="2bf72671f78524129acb86ceef6c598e10c7daa7.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0000618" text="blindness" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="2bf72671f78524129acb86ceef6c598e10c7daa7.c3" text="Among the crystallins, S-crystallin in the cephalopod lens has been shown to have an amino acid sequence similar to that of glutathione S-transferase (GST) 6-8 , which catalyzes the conjugation of glutathione (GSH) to various endogenous and xenobiotic electrophilic compounds and is a major detoxification mechanism of biological systems 9-12 (Extended data Fig. 1 ). Previous studies have led to a model that involves multiple gene duplications and exon shuffling to allow the evolution from GST to S-crystallin 4,7,8 and this process then creates a diverse and large family of S-crystallins. There are about ten, twenty four and four different S-crystallins in the lens of the squids, Nototodarus sloanii and Loligo opalescens, and Octopus vulgaris (the West Pacific octopus), respectively 7,13,14 . The cDNAs encoding these S-crystallins have nucleotide sequence identities ranging from 58% to 98%, while their proteins have identities ranging from 46% to 99% at the amino acid sequence level 7 . Among these proteins, &quot;short-loop&quot; S-crystallins (SL11, S4 and Cry9) are expressed less in the lens and are more GST-like, while &quot;long-loop&quot; S-crystallins">
    <entity charOffset="182-193" id="2bf72671f78524129acb86ceef6c598e10c7daa7.c3.e0" ontology_id="GO_0000746" text="conjugation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="291-305" id="2bf72671f78524129acb86ceef6c598e10c7daa7.c3.e1" ontology_id="GO_0098754" text="detoxification" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
