<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="2f446f5b176d426f14b28a4898d83c43291ae82d">
  <chunk id="2f446f5b176d426f14b28a4898d83c43291ae82d.c0" text="Vaccination with recombinant adenovirus expressing multi-stage antigens of Toxoplasma gondii by the mucosal route induces higher systemic cellular and local mucosal immune responses than with other vaccination routes"/>
  <chunk id="2f446f5b176d426f14b28a4898d83c43291ae82d.c1" text="Toxoplasmosis caused by Toxoplasma gondii, an obligate intracellular protozoan, is a cause of congenital disease and abortion in humans and animals. Various vaccination strategies against toxoplasmosis in rodent models have been used in the past few decades; however, effective vaccines remain a challenge. A recombinant adenovirus vaccine expressing ubiquitin-conjugated multi-stage antigen segments (Ad-UMAS) derived from different life-cycle stages of T. gondii was constructed previously. Here, we compared the immune responses and protection effects in vaccination of mice with Ad-UMAS by five vaccination routes including intramuscular (i.m.), intravenous (i.v.), subcutaneous (s.c.), intraoral (i.o.), and intranasal (i.n.). Much higher levels of T. gondii-specific IgG and IgA antibodies were detected in the sera of the intraoral and intranasal vaccination groups on day 49 compared with controls (p &lt; 0.05). The percentages of CD8 + T-cells in mice immunized intranasally and intraorally were larger than in mice immunized intramuscularly (p &lt; 0.05). The highest level of IL-2 and IFN-c was detected in the group with nasal immunization, and splenocyte proliferation activity was significantly enhanced in mice immunized via the oral and nasal routes. Furthermore, the higher survival rate (50%) and lower cyst numbers observed in the intraoral and intranasal groups all indicate that Ad-UMAS is far more effective in protecting mice against T. gondii infection via the mucosal route. Ad-UMAS could be an effective and safe mucosal candidate vaccine to protect animals and humans against T. gondii infection.">
    <entity charOffset="46-54" id="2f446f5b176d426f14b28a4898d83c43291ae82d.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0040280" text="obligate" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="55-68" id="2f446f5b176d426f14b28a4898d83c43291ae82d.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005622" text="intracellular" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="817-821" id="2f446f5b176d426f14b28a4898d83c43291ae82d.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0004617" text="sera" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="2f446f5b176d426f14b28a4898d83c43291ae82d.c1.e0" e2="2f446f5b176d426f14b28a4898d83c43291ae82d.c1.e1" id="2f446f5b176d426f14b28a4898d83c43291ae82d.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="2f446f5b176d426f14b28a4898d83c43291ae82d.c1.e0" e2="2f446f5b176d426f14b28a4898d83c43291ae82d.c1.e2" id="2f446f5b176d426f14b28a4898d83c43291ae82d.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="2f446f5b176d426f14b28a4898d83c43291ae82d.c2" text="Résumé -La vaccination par adénovirus recombinant exprimant des antigènes multi-stades de Toxoplasma gondii par voie muqueuse induit des réponses immunitaires systémiques cellulaires et locales muqueuses meilleures que d'autres voies de vaccination. La toxoplasmose, causée par Toxoplasma gondii, un protozoaire intracellulaire obligatoire, est une cause de maladie congénitale et d'avortement chez l'homme et chez l'animal. Différentes stratégies de vaccination contre la toxoplasmose, chez les rongeurs, ont été employées au cours des dernières décennies, mais obtenir un vaccin efficace demeure un défi. Un vaccin d'adénovirus recombinant exprimant des segments d'antigènes multi-stades conjugués à l'ubiquitine (Ad-UMAS), dérivés de différents stades du cycle de vie de T. gondii, a été construit précédemment. Dans cette étude, nous avons comparé les réponses immunitaires et les effets de protection de la vaccination des souris avec Ad-UMAS par cinq voies de vaccination, y compris intramusculaire, intraveineuse, sous-cutanée, intra-orale et intranasale. Des taux beaucoup plus élevés d'anticorps IgG et IgA spécifiques de T. gondii ont été détectés dans le sérum des groupes de souris des vaccinations intra-orales et intranasale au jour 49, par rapport aux témoins (p &lt; 0.05). Les pourcentages de lymphocytes CD8 + sont plus importants chez les souris immunisées par voie intranasale et intraorale que chez les souris immunisées par voie intramusculaire (p &lt; 0.05). Le niveau le plus élevé d'IL-2 et d'IFN-y a été détecté dans le groupe d'immunisation nasale et l'activité de prolifération des splénocytes a été significativement augmentée chez les souris immunisées par voie orale et nasale. En outre, un taux de survie plus élevé (50 %) et a These authors contributed equally to this work. This is an Open Access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0), which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original work is properly cited.">
    <entity charOffset="2001-2013" id="2f446f5b176d426f14b28a4898d83c43291ae82d.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0000003" text="reproduction" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="2f446f5b176d426f14b28a4898d83c43291ae82d.c3" text="plus petit nombre de kystes observés dans les groupes intra-oraux et intranasaux indiquent qu'Ad-UMAS est beaucoup plus efficace pour protéger les souris contre l'infection par T. gondii par voie muqueuse. Ad-UMAS pourrait être un candidat vaccin par voie muqueuse efficace et sûr pour protéger les animaux et les humains contre l'infection par T. gondii."/>
</document>
