<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="2fc84e709c4978a92c3f4168a6c145080d1b046b">
  <chunk id="2fc84e709c4978a92c3f4168a6c145080d1b046b.c0" text="Presence of Infectious Bronchitis Virus Strain CK/CH/LDL/97I in the Middle East">
    <entity charOffset="23-33" id="2fc84e709c4978a92c3f4168a6c145080d1b046b.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012387" text="Bronchitis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="2fc84e709c4978a92c3f4168a6c145080d1b046b.c1" text="Infectious bronchitis virus (IBV) is a very dynamic and evolving virus, causing major economic losses to the global poultry industry. In early 2011, respiratory disease outbreaks were investigated in Iraq, Jordan, and Saudi Arabia. Five IBV isolates (JOA2, JOA4, Saudi-1, Saudi-2, and Iraqi IBV) were detected by diagnostic-nested nucleocapsid RT-PCR. Strain identification was characterised by sequencing and phylogenetic analysis of the amplified hypervariable region of the spike 1 (S1) gene. These five IBV isolates were found to be of the IBV strain CK/CH/LDL/97I. Nucleotide identity between these five IBV isolates ranged from 96.9% to 99.7%, and between these isolates and the CK/CH/LDL/97I strain in the range of 96.6-99.1%. The sequenced fragment of the S1 gene of the CK/CH/LDL/97I strain had less than 80% nucleotide identity to the IBV vaccine strains commonly used in the Middle East (M41 and H120). The presence of these CK/CH/LDL/97I-like strains may account for vaccination failure against IBV, since all IBV isolates were from vaccinated chickens. In this paper, we documented for the first time the presence of IBV strain CK/CH/LDL/97I in the Middle East. This strain is known to have originated in China and Taiwan.">
    <entity charOffset="11-21" id="2fc84e709c4978a92c3f4168a6c145080d1b046b.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012387" text="bronchitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="331-343" id="2fc84e709c4978a92c3f4168a6c145080d1b046b.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0019013" text="nucleocapsid" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="2fc84e709c4978a92c3f4168a6c145080d1b046b.c1.e0" e2="2fc84e709c4978a92c3f4168a6c145080d1b046b.c1.e1" id="2fc84e709c4978a92c3f4168a6c145080d1b046b.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
