<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="32501343a772539b8477e17940f7333e8678fe5f">
  <chunk id="32501343a772539b8477e17940f7333e8678fe5f.c0" text="Kinetic Modelling of Infection Tracers [ 18 F]FDG, [ 68 Ga]Ga-Citrate, [ 11 C]Methionine, and [ 11 C]Donepezil in a Porcine Osteomyelitis Model">
    <entity charOffset="124-137" id="32501343a772539b8477e17940f7333e8678fe5f.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002754" text="Osteomyelitis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="32501343a772539b8477e17940f7333e8678fe5f.c1" text="imaging using [ 18 F]FDG as tracer, but uptake is unspecific. The present study compares the kinetics of [ 18 F]FDG and three other PET tracers with relevance for infection imaging. Methods. A juvenile porcine osteomyelitis model was used. Eleven pigs underwent PET/CT with 60-minute dynamic PET imaging of [ 18 F]FDG, [ 68 Ga]Ga-citrate, [ 11 C]methionine, and/or [ 11 C]donepezil, along with blood sampling. For infectious lesions, kinetic modelling with one-and two-tissue-compartment models was conducted for each tracer. Results. Irreversible uptake was found for [ 18 F]FDG and [ 68 Ga]Ga-citrate; reversible uptake was found for [ 11 C]methionine (two-tissue model) and [ 11 C]donepezil (one-tissue model). The uptake rate for [ 68 Ga]Ga-citrate was slow and diffusion-limited. For the other tracers, the uptake rate was primarily determined by perfusion (flow-limited uptake). Net uptake rate for [ 18 F]FDG and distribution volume for [ 11 C]methionine were significantly higher for infectious lesions than for correspondingly noninfected tissue. For [ 11 C]donepezil in pigs, labelled metabolite products appeared to be important for the analysis. Conclusions. The kinetics of the four studied tracers in infection was characterized. For clinical applications, [ 18 F]FDG remains the first-choice PET tracer. [ 11 C]methionine may have a potential for detecting soft tissue infections. [ 68 Ga]Ga-citrate and [ 11 C]donepezil were not found useful for imaging of osteomyelitis.">
    <entity charOffset="210-223" id="32501343a772539b8477e17940f7333e8678fe5f.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002754" text="osteomyelitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1473-1486" id="32501343a772539b8477e17940f7333e8678fe5f.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0002754" text="osteomyelitis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
