<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="3345fa1a77d9ad2f4bce48138490e60a462fe18b">
  <chunk id="3345fa1a77d9ad2f4bce48138490e60a462fe18b.c0" text="Sugar-Binding Profiles of Chitin-Binding Lectins from the Hevein Family: A Comprehensive Study"/>
  <chunk id="3345fa1a77d9ad2f4bce48138490e60a462fe18b.c1" text="Chitin-binding lectins form the hevein family in plants, which are defined by the presence of single or multiple structurally conserved GlcNAc (N-acetylglucosamine)-binding domains. Although they have been used as probes for chito-oligosaccharides, their detailed specificities remain to be investigated. In this study, we analyzed six chitin-binding lectins, DSA, LEL, PWM, STL, UDA, and WGA, by quantitative frontal affinity chromatography. Some novel features were evident: WGA showed almost comparable affinity for pyridylaminated chitotriose and chitotetraose, while LEL and UDA showed much weaker affinity, and DSA, PWM, and STL had no substantial affinity for the former. WGA showed selective affinity for hybrid-type N-glycans harboring a bisecting GlcNAc residue. UDA showed extensive binding to high-mannose type N-glycans, with affinity increasing with the number of Man residues. DSA showed the highest affinity for highly branched N-glycans consisting of type II LacNAc (N-acetyllactosamine). Further, multivalent features of these lectins were investigated by using glycoconjugate and lectin microarrays. The lectins showed substantial binding to immobilized LacNAc as well as chito-oligosaccharides, although the extents to which they bound varied among them. WGA showed strong binding to heavily sialylated glycoproteins. The above observations will help interpret lectin-glycoprotein interactions in histochemical studies and glyco-biomarker investigations.">
    <entity charOffset="794-801" id="3345fa1a77d9ad2f4bce48138490e60a462fe18b.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1150-1157" id="3345fa1a77d9ad2f4bce48138490e60a462fe18b.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1293-1300" id="3345fa1a77d9ad2f4bce48138490e60a462fe18b.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="3345fa1a77d9ad2f4bce48138490e60a462fe18b.c2" text="well as disulfide bridges (Figure 1) . Hevein was originally found in latex from rubber as a component of chitinase in 1970. Although hevein is known to show relatively weak (i.e., 1 mM or lower K d ) affinity for chito-oligosaccharides [12] [13] [14] , other chitin-binding lectins have multiple carbohydrate-binding domains and their amino acid sequences are significantly different, including the conserved aromatic residues involved in GlcNAc recognition (Figure 1) . Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2017, 18, x 2 of 26 consisting of 43 amino acids (hevein domain), including evolutionarily conserved serine and aromatic residues as well as disulfide bridges (Figure 1) . Hevein was originally found in latex from rubber as a component of chitinase in 1970. Although hevein is known to show relatively weak (i.e., 1 mM or lower Kd) affinity for chito-oligosaccharides [12] [13] [14] , other chitin-binding lectins have multiple carbohydrate-binding domains and their amino acid sequences are significantly different, including the conserved aromatic residues involved in GlcNAc recognition (Figure 1 )."/>
</document>
