<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="341fd3d94baafcde2e5e7c0b1d166028d69523e4">
  <chunk id="341fd3d94baafcde2e5e7c0b1d166028d69523e4.c0" text="F1000Research Open Peer Review v2"/>
  <chunk id="341fd3d94baafcde2e5e7c0b1d166028d69523e4.c1" text="(0) Comments 2 1 OPINION ARTICLE FDA approved drugs as potential Ebola treatments [v2; ref status: indexed, http://f1000r.es/554] Abstract"/>
  <chunk id="341fd3d94baafcde2e5e7c0b1d166028d69523e4.c2" text="In the search for treatments for the Ebola Virus, multiple screens of FDA drugs have led to the identification of several with promising activity. These in vitro compounds were not originally developed as antivirals and some have been further tested in mouse models. We put forward the opinion that some of in vivo these drugs could be evaluated further and move into the clinic as they are already FDA approved and in many cases readily available. This may be important if there is a further outbreak in future and no other therapeutic is available."/>
  <chunk id="341fd3d94baafcde2e5e7c0b1d166028d69523e4.c3" text="Drugs mobile app http://molmatinf.com/approveddrugs.html. Supplemental Figure 2. Amodiaquine similarity in Approved drugs mobile app http://molmatinf.com/approveddrugs.html. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 2. Trad MA, Fisher DA, Tambyah PA, et al.: Ebola in west Africa. Lancet Infect Dis. 2014; 14(11): 1045. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 3. Madrid PB, Chopra S, Manger ID, et al.: A systematic screen of FDA-approved drugs for inhibitors of biological threat agents. PLoS One. 2013; 8(4): e60579. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 4. de Wilde AH, Jochmans D, Posthuma CC, et al.: Screening of an FDA-approved compound library identifies four small-molecule inhibitors of Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus replication in cell culture. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2014; 58(8): 4875-84. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 5. Keyaerts E, Li S, Vijgen L, et al.: Antiviral activity of chloroquine against human coronavirus OC43 infection in newborn mice. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2009; 53(8): 3416-21. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 6. Vincent MJ, Bergeron E, Benjannet S, et al.: Chloroquine is a potent inhibitor of SARS coronavirus infection and spread. Virol J. 2005; 2: 69. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 7. Boonyasuppayakorn S, Reichert ED, Manzano M, et al.: Amodiaquine, an antimalarial drug, inhibits dengue virus type 2 replication and infectivity. Antiviral Res. 2014; 106: 125-34. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 8. Johansen LM, Brannan JM, Delos SE, et al.: FDA-approved selective estrogen receptor modulators inhibit Ebola virus infection. Sci Transl Med. 2013; 5(190): 190ra79. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 9. Gehring G, Rohrmann K, Atenchong N, et al.: The clinically approved drugs amiodarone, dronedarone and verapamil inhibit filovirus cell entry. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2014; 69(8): 2123-31. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 10. Ekins S, Freundlich JS, Coffee M, et al.: A common feature pharmacophore for FDA-approved drugs inhibiting the Ebola virus [v2; ref status: indexed, http:// f1000r.es/4wt]. F1000Res. 2014; 3: 277. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 11. Veljkovic V, Loiseau PM, Figadere B, et al.: Virtual screen for repurposing approved and experimental drugs for candidate inhibitors of EBOLA virus infection [v2; ref status: indexed, http://f1000r.es/53d]. F1000Res. 2015; 4: 34. Publisher Full Text 12. Kouznetsova J, Sun W, Martínez-Romero C, et al.: Identification of 53 compounds that block Ebola virus-like particle entry via a repurposing screen of approved drugs. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2014; 3: e84. Publisher Full Text 13. Long J, Wright E, Molesti E, et al.: Antiviral therapies against Ebola and other emerging viral diseases using existing medicines that block virus entry [v2; ref status: awaiting peer review, http://f1000r.es/52g]. F1000Res. 2015; 4: 30. Publisher Full Text 14. Litterman N, Lipinski C, Ekins S, et al.: Small molecules with antiviral activity against the Ebola virus [v1; ref status: indexed, http://f1000r.es/523]. F1000Res. 2015; 4: 38. Publisher Full Text 15. Picazo E, Giordanetto F: Small molecule inhibitors of ebola virus infection. Drug Discov Today. 2015; 20(2): 277-286. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 16. Yan H, Zhong G, Xu G, et al.: Sodium taurocholate cotransporting polypeptide is a functional receptor for human hepatitis B and D virus. Elife. 2012; 1: Page 5 of 9 F1000Research 2015, 4:48 Last updated: 11 MAR 2015 e00049. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 17. Dong Z, Ekins S, Polli JE, et al.: Quantitative NTCP pharmacophore and lack of association between DILI and NTCP Inhibition. Eur J Pharm Sci. 2014; 66C: 1-9. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 18. Fu LL, Liu J, Chen Y, et al.: In silico analysis and experimental validation of azelastine hydrochloride (N4) targeting sodium taurocholate co-transporting polypeptide (NTCP) in HBV therapy. Cell Prolif. 2014; 47(4): 326-35. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 19. Blatt J, Farag S, Corey SJ, et al.: Expanding the scope of drug repurposing in pediatrics: the Children's Pharmacy Collaborative. Drug Discov Today. 2014; 19(11): 1696-1698. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 20. Dyall J, Coleman CM, Hart BJ, et al.: Repurposing of clinically developed drugs for treatment of Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus infection. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2014; 58(8): 4885-93. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 21. Huang R, Southall N, Wang Y, et al.: The NCGC pharmaceutical collection: a comprehensive resource of clinically approved drugs enabling repurposing and chemical genomics. Sci Transl Med. 2011; 3(80): 80ps16. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 22. Oprea TI, Mestres J: Drug repurposing: far beyond new targets for old drugs. AAPS J. 2012; 14(4): 759-63. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 23. Walsh CT, Fischbach MA: Repurposing libraries of eukaryotic protein kinase inhibitors for antibiotic discovery. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2009; 106(6): 1689-90. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 24. Dudley JT, Deshpande T, Butte AJ: Exploiting drug-disease relationships for computational drug repositioning. Brief Bioinform. 2011; 12(4): 303-11. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 25. Dudley JT, Sirota M, Shenoy M, et al.: Computational repositioning of the anticonvulsant topiramate for inflammatory bowel disease. Sci Transl Med. 2011; 3(96): 96ra76. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 26. Ekins S, Williams AJ, Krasowski MD, et al.: In silico repositioning of approved drugs for rare and neglected diseases. Drug Discov Today. 2011; 16(7-8): 298-310. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 27. Ekins S, Southan C, Coffee M: Finding small molecules for the 'next Ebola' [v1; ref status: awaiting peer review, http://f1000r.es/542].">
    <entity charOffset="2610-2629" id="341fd3d94baafcde2e5e7c0b1d166028d69523e4.c3.e0" ontology_id="GO_0000943" text="virus-like particle" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="3477-3486" id="341fd3d94baafcde2e5e7c0b1d166028d69523e4.c3.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012115" text="hepatitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="5557-5583" id="341fd3d94baafcde2e5e7c0b1d166028d69523e4.c3.e2" ontology_id="HP_0002037" text="inflammatory bowel disease" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="341fd3d94baafcde2e5e7c0b1d166028d69523e4.c3.e0" e2="341fd3d94baafcde2e5e7c0b1d166028d69523e4.c3.e1" id="341fd3d94baafcde2e5e7c0b1d166028d69523e4.c3.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="341fd3d94baafcde2e5e7c0b1d166028d69523e4.c3.e0" e2="341fd3d94baafcde2e5e7c0b1d166028d69523e4.c3.e2" id="341fd3d94baafcde2e5e7c0b1d166028d69523e4.c3.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
