<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="34277d7f5f84c871e13853e830eb07b2186f8fec">
  <chunk id="34277d7f5f84c871e13853e830eb07b2186f8fec.c0" text="Delta inulin-based adjuvants promote the generation of polyfunctional CD4 + T cell responses and protection against Mycobacterium tuberculosis infection"/>
  <chunk id="34277d7f5f84c871e13853e830eb07b2186f8fec.c1" text="There is an urgent need for the rational design of safe and effective vaccines to protect against chronic bacterial pathogens such as Mycobacterium tuberculosis. Advax ™ is a novel adjuvant based on delta inulin microparticles that enhances immunity with a minimal inflammatory profile and has entered human trials to protect against viral pathogens. In this report we determined if Advax displays broad applicability against important human pathogens by assessing protective immunity against infection with M. tuberculosis. The fusion protein CysVac2, comprising the M. tuberculosis antigens Ag85B (Rv1886c) and CysD (Rv1285) formulated with Advax provided significant protection in the lungs of M. tuberculosis-infected mice. Protection was associated with the generation of CysVac2specific multifunctional CD4 + T cells (IFN-γ + TNF + IL-2 + ). Addition to Advax of the TLR9 agonist, CpG oligonucleotide (Advax CpG ), improved both the immunogenicity and protective efficacy of CysVac2. Immunisation with CysVac2/Advax CpG resulted in heightened release of the chemoattractants, CXCL1, CCL3, and TNF, and rapid influx of monocytes and neutrophils to the site of vaccination, with pronounced early priming of CysVac2-specific CD4 + T cells. As delta inulin adjuvants have shown an excellent safety and tolerability profile in humans, CysVac2/Advax CpG is a strong candidate for further preclinical evaluation for progression to human trials.">
    <entity charOffset="98-105" id="34277d7f5f84c871e13853e830eb07b2186f8fec.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011010" text="chronic" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="34277d7f5f84c871e13853e830eb07b2186f8fec.c2" text="Vaccines are the most efficient tool for preventing diseases caused by infectious pathogens. Tuberculosis (TB) remains a major world health problem, with over 10 million new cases and 1.4 million deaths per year worldwide 1 . The current vaccine, M. bovis BCG displays variable protection in humans and new TB vaccines are urgently required 2 . Although genetic engineering has allowed the development of recombinant proteins in large scale, vaccination with such antigens alone is generally insufficient to elicit a protective immune response and adjuvants are required to enhance antigen-specific immune responses, although in many cases the mechanism of adjuvant action is still not well defined 3 . A major challenge is how to achieve a potent adjuvant effect while avoiding reactogenicity and toxicity. Unfortunately, the most potent adjuvants are typically associated with the greatest local and systemic toxicity (e.g. complete Freund's adjuvant 4 ), thereby largely precluding their use particularly in a prophylactic vaccine setting. Ideally, in addition to being safe and well tolerated, adjuvants should promote an appropriate (humoral and/or cellular) immune response, have a long shelf-life, and be stable, biodegradable and cheap to produce.">
    <entity charOffset="528-543" id="34277d7f5f84c871e13853e830eb07b2186f8fec.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0006955" text="immune response" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1164-1179" id="34277d7f5f84c871e13853e830eb07b2186f8fec.c2.e1" ontology_id="GO_0006955" text="immune response" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
