<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054">
  <chunk id="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c0" text="Different residues in the SARS-CoV spike protein determine cleavage and activation by the host cell protease TMPRSS2">
    <entity charOffset="90-99" id="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0043657" text="host cell" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1" text="The spike (S) protein of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus (SARS-CoV) mediates viral entry into target cells. Cleavage and activation of SARS S by a host cell protease is essential for infectious viral entry and the responsible enzymes are potential targets for antiviral intervention. The type II transmembrane serine protease TMPRSS2 cleaves and activates SARS S in cell culture and potentially also in the infected host. Here, we investigated which determinants in SARS S control cleavage and activation by TMPRSS2. We found that SARS S residue R667, a previously identified trypsin cleavage site, is also required for S protein cleavage by TMPRSS2. The cleavage fragments produced by trypsin and TMPRSS2 differed in their decoration with N-glycans, suggesting that these proteases cleave different SARS S glycoforms. Although R667 was required for SARS S cleavage by TMPRSS2, this residue was dispensable for TMPRSS2-mediated S protein activation. Conversely, residue R797, previously reported to be required for SARS S activation by trypsin, was dispensable for S protein cleavage but required for S protein activation by TMPRSS2. Collectively, these results show that different residues in SARS S control cleavage and activation by TMPRSS2, suggesting that these processes are more complex than initially appreciated. OPEN ACCESS Citation: Reinke LM, Spiegel M, Plegge T, Hartleib A, Nehlmeier I, Gierer S, et al. (2017) Different residues in the SARS-CoV spike protein determine cleavage and activation by the host cell protease TMPRSS2. PLoS ONE 12(6): e0179177. https://">
    <entity charOffset="25-31" id="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="32-37" id="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="161-170" id="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0043657" text="host cell" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="310-323" id="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0016021" text="transmembrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1529-1538" id="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0043657" text="host cell" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1.e0" e2="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1.e2" id="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1.e0" e2="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1.e3" id="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1.e0" e2="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1.e4" id="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1.e1" e2="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1.e2" id="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1.e1" e2="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1.e3" id="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1.e1" e2="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1.e4" id="388bf10627c470191554ffe46e7fcddbf00aa054.c1.p5" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
