<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="389053111a32e148f8b7c07c883818f70525aa73">
  <chunk id="389053111a32e148f8b7c07c883818f70525aa73.c0" text="Integrated micro-optofluidic platform for real-time detection of airborne microorganisms OPEN"/>
  <chunk id="389053111a32e148f8b7c07c883818f70525aa73.c1" text="We demonstrate an integrated micro-optofluidic platform for real-time, continuous detection and quantification of airborne microorganisms. Measurements of the fluorescence and light scattering from single particles in a microfluidic channel are used to determine the total particle number concentration and the microorganism number concentration in real-time. The system performance is examined by evaluating standard particle measurements with various sample flow rates and the ratios of fluorescent to non-fluorescent particles. To apply this method to real-time detection of airborne microorganisms, airborne Escherichia coli, Bacillus subtilis, and Staphylococcus epidermidis cells were introduced into the micro-optofluidic platform via bioaerosol generation, and a liquid-type particle collection setup was used. We demonstrate successful discrimination of SYTO82-dyed fluorescent bacterial cells from other residue particles in a continuous and real-time manner. In comparison with traditional microscopy cell counting and colony culture methods, this micro-optofluidic platform is not only more accurate in terms of the detection efficiency for airborne microorganisms but it also provides additional information on the total particle number concentration."/>
  <chunk id="389053111a32e148f8b7c07c883818f70525aa73.c2" text="Airborne microorganisms (or bioaerosols), including viruses, bacteria, and fungal spores, are associated with a wide range of health effects and environmental issues 1 . Because of the low settling velocities due to the small size of particles (~20 nm to 100 μ m), such bioaerosols may be suspended in the atmosphere for a prolonged period, and can be carried over large distances 2 . Therefore, there is significant potential for inhalation into the human respiratory system, which has health consequences 3 . There have been many studies on the health effects of exposure to harmful bioaerosols, such as infectious diseases, pneumonia, asthma, and allergies 4,5 . The increased use of buildings that are isolated from external ventilation brings about increased risk of exposure to bioaerosols 6,7 . Outdoor workers in the recycling industry are often exposed to high concentrations of bioaerosols 8, 9 . The recent pandemic outbreaks of H1N1 influenza A and severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS) demonstrate the importance of bioaerosol monitoring and control 10-12 .">
    <entity charOffset="323-332" id="389053111a32e148f8b7c07c883818f70525aa73.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0025297" text="prolonged" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="961-967" id="389053111a32e148f8b7c07c883818f70525aa73.c2.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="968-973" id="389053111a32e148f8b7c07c883818f70525aa73.c2.e2" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="389053111a32e148f8b7c07c883818f70525aa73.c3" text="Growing concerns over airborne microorganisms have led to demand for accurate and reliable monitoring systems to protect humans from exposure to harmful microorganisms. Several epidemiological studies have demonstrated links between airborne microorganisms and health problems. The airborne concentration of culturable microorganisms (i.e., colony-forming units (CFUs) per cubic meter of air) is a particularly widely used indicator, and is a simple parameter that can be used in the quantification of air quality 4,7,13,14 . For example, the World Health Organization (WHO) has suggested guidelines regarding the maximum allowable airborne fungal count (i.e., &lt; 500 CFU/m 3 ) 15 ."/>
  <chunk id="389053111a32e148f8b7c07c883818f70525aa73.c4" text="Microscopy and culture techniques are conventionally used to analyze bioaerosols. Microscopy methods can determine the total bioaerosol concentrations based on the use of hemocytometers; however, this is time-consuming and operator-dependent. Culturing methods require a growth medium, which">
    <entity charOffset="271-277" id="389053111a32e148f8b7c07c883818f70525aa73.c4.e0" ontology_id="GO_0040007" text="growth" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
