<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="3adfcb05fa2004182d3c232a69429d2b1adfe12f">
  <chunk id="3adfcb05fa2004182d3c232a69429d2b1adfe12f.c0" text="Molecular Sciences Synthesis and Application of Silver Nanoparticles (Ag NPs) for the Prevention of Infection in Healthcare Workers">
    <entity charOffset="19-28" id="3adfcb05fa2004182d3c232a69429d2b1adfe12f.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0009058" text="Synthesis" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="3adfcb05fa2004182d3c232a69429d2b1adfe12f.c1" text="Silver is easily available and is known to have microbicidal effect; moreover, it does not impose any adverse effects on the human body. The microbicidal effect is mainly due to silver ions, which have a wide antibacterial spectrum. Furthermore, the development of multidrug-resistant bacteria, as in the case of antibiotics, is less likely. Silver ions bind to halide ions, such as chloride, and precipitate; therefore, when used directly, their microbicidal activity is shortened. To overcome this issue, silver nanoparticles (Ag NPs) have been recently synthesized and frequently used as microbicidal agents that release silver ions from particle surface. Depending on the specific surface area of the nanoparticles, silver ions are released with high efficiency. In addition to their bactericidal activity, small Ag NPs (&lt;10 nm in diameter) affect viruses although the microbicidal effect of silver mass is weak. Because of their characteristics, Ag NPs are useful countermeasures against infectious diseases, which constitute a major issue in the medical field. Thus, medical tools coated with Ag NPs are being developed. This review outlines the synthesis and utilization of Ag NPs in the medical field, focusing on environment-friendly synthesis and the suppression of infections in healthcare workers (HCWs).">
    <entity charOffset="1152-1161" id="3adfcb05fa2004182d3c232a69429d2b1adfe12f.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0009058" text="synthesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1243-1252" id="3adfcb05fa2004182d3c232a69429d2b1adfe12f.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0009058" text="synthesis" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="3adfcb05fa2004182d3c232a69429d2b1adfe12f.c2" text="synthesized by the method (Figure 2 ) [14, 48] . Moreover, no harmful material was generated by the synthesis method.">
    <entity charOffset="100-109" id="3adfcb05fa2004182d3c232a69429d2b1adfe12f.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0009058" text="synthesis" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="3adfcb05fa2004182d3c232a69429d2b1adfe12f.c3" text="Environment-friendly method for Ag NP synthesis with the diameters control by glucose concentration. We have reported that environment-friendly processes were used to produce small Ag NPs (&lt;10 nm) within a narrow size distribution. The diameters of generated Ag NPs were easily controlled by glucose concentrations [14] .">
    <entity charOffset="38-47" id="3adfcb05fa2004182d3c232a69429d2b1adfe12f.c3.e0" ontology_id="GO_0009058" text="synthesis" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="3adfcb05fa2004182d3c232a69429d2b1adfe12f.c4" text="Some chemical methods for the synthesis of Ag NPs include chemical reduction [12, [49] [50] [51] [52] [53] [54] , electrochemical synthesis [55-57], the irradiation-assisted method [58] [59] [60] [61] , and the pyrolysis method [62, 63] , as summarized in Table 2 .">
    <entity charOffset="30-39" id="3adfcb05fa2004182d3c232a69429d2b1adfe12f.c4.e0" ontology_id="GO_0009058" text="synthesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="130-139" id="3adfcb05fa2004182d3c232a69429d2b1adfe12f.c4.e1" ontology_id="GO_0009058" text="synthesis" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="3adfcb05fa2004182d3c232a69429d2b1adfe12f.c5" text="Among them, chemical reduction is well known and requires two main components: a reducing agent and a silver source for the reaction. Various reagents are used for reducing agents [12, 50, 51] . Of these, borohydride is the most widely used because of its extremely strong and rapid reducing action [12, [64] [65] [66] [67] . In addition, Ag NPs synthesized using a co-reduction approach (e.g., sodium borohydride/trisodium citrate [52], hydrazine hydrate/sodium citrate [53] , and borohydride/citrate [54]) were reported. Agnihotri et al. reported that Ag NPs were synthesized employing sodium borohydride as a primary reductant and trisodium citrate both as secondary reductant as well as protective agent [52] . In this method, nucleation and growth kinetics during the synthesis process were precisely controlled and Ag NPs of average size 5, 7, 10, 15, 20, 30, 50, 63, 85 , and 100 nm were synthesized with good yield and monodispersity. As described, a protective agent is often added to stabilize the produced nanoparticles in a dispersed state. The crystal structure can also be controlled using this protective agent: Rhomboid structures and nanosheets can be produced in addition to the general spherical shape. Silver nitrate, which is chemically stable, easily available, and inexpensive compared to other silver salts [68], can supply silver ions to synthesis systems and is frequently used as the silver source.">
    <entity charOffset="746-752" id="3adfcb05fa2004182d3c232a69429d2b1adfe12f.c5.e0" ontology_id="GO_0040007" text="growth" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="773-782" id="3adfcb05fa2004182d3c232a69429d2b1adfe12f.c5.e1" ontology_id="GO_0009058" text="synthesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1363-1372" id="3adfcb05fa2004182d3c232a69429d2b1adfe12f.c5.e2" ontology_id="GO_0009058" text="synthesis" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="3adfcb05fa2004182d3c232a69429d2b1adfe12f.c6" text="Instead of reducing agents, a silver source is also reduced by electrochemical reaction, irradiation-assisted reaction, and pyrolysis reaction. For example, an electrochemical method, which can be used to produce certain transition metal colloids in the nanometer region, was demonstrated for the first time [55] . Ag NPs of ≤ 20 nm can be synthesized using an electrochemical method [55, 56] . Using this method, Zhang et al. reported new modification method of ultrathin zeolite film of about 400 nm in thickness; the films are promising candidates for use in membrane applications [56] . Recently, Ag NPs were prepared by an electrochemical method using only polyethylene glycol as a stabilizer and without any other reactant [57] . Interestingly, using irradiation-assisted method, Ag NPs can be extended easily to synthesize relatively monodisperse triangular silver nanocrystals with desired edge lengths in the 30-120 nm range [58] and cubic crystal with 2-8 nm lengths [59] . In addition, irradiation-assisted method contributive to shortening of the synthesis time. According to Manikprabhu and Lingappa, Ag NPs were synthesized rapidly in just 90 s from 20 min by a">
    <entity charOffset="562-570" id="3adfcb05fa2004182d3c232a69429d2b1adfe12f.c6.e0" ontology_id="GO_0016020" text="membrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1059-1068" id="3adfcb05fa2004182d3c232a69429d2b1adfe12f.c6.e1" ontology_id="GO_0009058" text="synthesis" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
