<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="3e168aef44683549563640db5ca32da62be4e27b">
  <chunk id="3e168aef44683549563640db5ca32da62be4e27b.c0" text="Aminopeptidase n-null neonatal piglets are protected from transmissible gastroenteritis virus but not porcine epidemic diarrhea virus">
    <entity charOffset="119-127" id="3e168aef44683549563640db5ca32da62be4e27b.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002014" text="diarrhea" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="3e168aef44683549563640db5ca32da62be4e27b.c1" text="Recently, Whitworth et al. have reported that APN knockout pigs are resistant to TGEV but not PEDV after weaning. However, it remains unclear if APN-null neonatal pigs are protected from TGEV. Here we report the generation of APN-null pigs by using CRISPR/Cas9 technology followed by somatic cell nuclear transfer. APN-null pigs are produced with normal pregnancy rate and viability, indicating lack of APN is not embryonic lethal. After viral challenge, APN-null neonatal piglets are resistant to highly virulent transmissible gastroenteritis virus. Histopathological analyses indicate APN-null pigs exhibit normal small intestine villi, while wildtype pigs show typical lesions in small intestines. Immunochemistry analyses confirm that no transmissible gastroenteritis virus antigen is detected in target tissues in APN-null piglets. However, upon porcine epidemic diarrhea virus challenge, APNnull pigs are still susceptible with 100% mortality. Collectively, this report provides a viable tool for producing animals with enhanced resistance to TGEV and clarifies that APN is dispensable for the PEDV infection in pigs.">
    <entity charOffset="868-876" id="3e168aef44683549563640db5ca32da62be4e27b.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002014" text="diarrhea" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="3e168aef44683549563640db5ca32da62be4e27b.c2" text="Swine enteric coronavirus disease is a devastating disease that has caused significant economic losses to the global swine industry 1 . Transmissible gastroenteritis virus (TGEV) and porcine epidemic diarrhea virus (PEDV) have traditionally been the major etiological agents of swine enteric diseases, in particular, in Asia. Since 2010, greater economic losses have been made due to the outbreak of emerging and reemerging CoVs, including variant strains of PEDV 2 , porcine deltacoronavirus (PDCoV) and swine acute diarrhea syndrome coronavirus (SADS-CoV) 3-5 .">
    <entity charOffset="200-208" id="3e168aef44683549563640db5ca32da62be4e27b.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002014" text="diarrhea" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="511-516" id="3e168aef44683549563640db5ca32da62be4e27b.c2.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="517-525" id="3e168aef44683549563640db5ca32da62be4e27b.c2.e2" ontology_id="HP_0002014" text="diarrhea" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="3e168aef44683549563640db5ca32da62be4e27b.c3" text="Only in year 2013, PEDV outbreak has wiped out more than 10% of America's pig population 5 . These CoVs primarily affect suckling piglets and result in high morbidity and up to 100% mortality. They infects the small intestine and can induce watery diarrhea and vomiting, eventually leading to dehydration, body weight loss, and other devastating outcomes. To date, no effective means are available to control these diseases.">
    <entity charOffset="248-256" id="3e168aef44683549563640db5ca32da62be4e27b.c3.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002014" text="diarrhea" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="3e168aef44683549563640db5ca32da62be4e27b.c4" text="Receptor binding and cellular entry are crucial for understanding of the infection processes, host range and tropism of a virus as well as identifying targets for antiviral interventions 6 . For example, CD163 has been identified as an entry receptor for porcine reproductive and respiratory syndrome (PRRS) virus and subsequent studies demonstrated that CD163-null pigs are immune to PRRS, which presents a valuable resource for breeding PRRS-resistant pigs 7 . Aminopeptidase-N (APN) is widely present in the membrane of the epithelial cells of the small intestine in a variety of species, including pigs. In addition, it has been shown to be involved in multiple functions, including peptide metabolism, cell adhesion and cholesterol uptake 8 . Curiously, APN has also been suggested as a receptor for multiple alphacoronaviruses, including TGEV 9 , PDCoV 10,11 , and human coronavirus 229E (HCoV-229E) 12,13 . However, these reports relied on the use of cell line or other in vitro models, raising the concern regarding the biological significance of APN's role in vivo. Meanwhile, whether APN is also required for PEDV infection is unresolved. Previous studies regarding of the role of APN in PEDV susceptibility have yielded conflicting results [14] [15] [16] [17] [18] [19] . To resolve unambiguously the functional requirement for porcine APN in TGEV and PEDV infection in vivo, APN-null pigs have to be produced and viral challenge assay performed. Recently, Whitworth et al. have reported APN-null post-weaning pigs are resistant to TGEV but not PEDV 20 . However, TGEV and PEDV primarily affect suckling piglets with up to 100% mortality and post-weaning pigs have been shown to be less susceptible to these viruses 21 . We believe it is more biological relevant to determine if APN-null neonatal piglets (&lt;10 days) are resistant to TGEV and PEDV. Meanwhile, only 1 APN-null piglet was used for PEDV challenge experiment in Whitworth et al. study, further consolidating the necessity to clarify the role of APN in PEDV infection again.">
    <entity charOffset="9-16" id="3e168aef44683549563640db5ca32da62be4e27b.c4.e0" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="109-116" id="3e168aef44683549563640db5ca32da62be4e27b.c4.e1" ontology_id="GO_0009606" text="tropism" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="511-519" id="3e168aef44683549563640db5ca32da62be4e27b.c4.e2" ontology_id="GO_0016020" text="membrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="707-720" id="3e168aef44683549563640db5ca32da62be4e27b.c4.e3" ontology_id="GO_0007155" text="cell adhesion" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="725-743" id="3e168aef44683549563640db5ca32da62be4e27b.c4.e4" ontology_id="GO_0070508" text="cholesterol uptake" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="3e168aef44683549563640db5ca32da62be4e27b.c5" text="Here, we generated APN-null pigs using CRISPR/Cas9 and somatic cell nuclear transfer (SCNT) technology. After viral challenge, the neonatal pigs exhibited significant resistance to TGEV infection. However, APN-null neonatal pigs are still susceptible to PEDV infection. Together with Whitworth et al. 's work, the present study highlights the potential for APN editing in swine breeding to improve TGEV resistance. The report also clarify that APN is dispensable for PEDV infection in pigs."/>
</document>
