<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="417754f2c930dac6e586d36eb8bfb07355f6e0ff">
  <chunk id="417754f2c930dac6e586d36eb8bfb07355f6e0ff.c0" text="Feasibility of a birth cohort study dedicated to assessing acute infections using symptom diaries and parental collection of biomaterials">
    <entity charOffset="59-64" id="417754f2c930dac6e586d36eb8bfb07355f6e0ff.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="417754f2c930dac6e586d36eb8bfb07355f6e0ff.c1" text="Background: A birth cohort dedicated to studying infections in early childhood may be assisted by parental recording of symptoms on a daily basis and a collection of biomaterials. We aimed at testing the feasibility of this approach for use in a long-term study focusing on infections in children in Germany. Methods: Parents of 1-to 3-year-old children (n = 75) were recruited in nursery schools. They were asked to complete a symptom diary on a daily basis and to take monthly and symptom-triggered nasal swabs and stool samples from their child over the study period of three months. Feasibility was measured by means of the return proportions of symptom diaries and bio samples; acceptance was assessed by a questionnaire delivered to participants at the end of the study. Results: The majority of the participants filled in the symptom diary during the three months study for 75 or more days (77.3 %), and provided the monthly nasal swabs (62.7 %) and stool samples (65.3 %). The time needed for the tasks was acceptable for most participants (symptom diary: 92.3 %, nasal swabs: 98.5 %, stool samples: 100.0 %). In 64.3 % of the symptom-triggered nasal swabs, respiratory viruses were found compared to 55.5 % in throat swabs taken by health-care professionals within the &quot;ARE surveillance Lower Saxony&quot;, a special project by the Governmental Institute of Public Health of Lower Saxony to investigate causal pathogens for acute respiratory infections in children.">
    <entity charOffset="1428-1433" id="417754f2c930dac6e586d36eb8bfb07355f6e0ff.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1434-1456" id="417754f2c930dac6e586d36eb8bfb07355f6e0ff.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011947" text="respiratory infections" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="417754f2c930dac6e586d36eb8bfb07355f6e0ff.c2" text="The parental assessment of symptoms and collection of biomaterials in a birth cohort dedicated to studying infections appears feasible in a middle class German population. The success of the study will depend on the ability to maintain these activities over a long time period."/>
</document>
