<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="424cd6cb670119aed604833cf1f107598f217574">
  <chunk id="424cd6cb670119aed604833cf1f107598f217574.c0" text="Astragalin inhibits autophagy-associated airway epithelial fibrosis"/>
  <chunk id="424cd6cb670119aed604833cf1f107598f217574.c1" text="Background: Fibrotic remodeling of airway and lung parenchymal compartments is attributed to pulmonary dysfunction with an involvement of reactive oxygen species (ROS) in chronic lung diseases such as idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis and asthma.">
    <entity charOffset="171-178" id="424cd6cb670119aed604833cf1f107598f217574.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011010" text="chronic" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="212-230" id="424cd6cb670119aed604833cf1f107598f217574.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0002206" text="pulmonary fibrosis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="424cd6cb670119aed604833cf1f107598f217574.c2" text="Methods: The in vitro study elucidated inhibitory effects of astragalin, kaempferol-3-O-glucoside from leaves of persimmon and green tea seeds, on oxidative stress-induced airway fibrosis. The in vivo study explored the demoting effects of astragalin on epithelial to mesenchymal transition in BALB/c mice sensitized with ovalbumin (OVA). Results: The exposure of 20 μM H 2 O 2 for 72 h accelerated E-cadherin loss and vimentin induction in airway epithelial BEAS-2B cells, which was reversed by non-toxic astragalin at 1-20 μM. Astragalin allayed the airway tissue levels of ROS and vimentin enhanced by OVA challenge. Collagen type 1 production increased in H 2 O 2 -exposed epithelial cells and collagen fiber deposition was observed in OVA-challenged mouse airways. This study further investigated that the oxidative stress-triggered autophagic regulation was responsible for inducing airway fibrosis. H 2 O 2 highly enhanced the expression induction of the autophagy-related beclin-1 and light chains 3A/B (LC3A/B) within 4 h and astragalin blocked such induction by H 2 O 2 . This compound deterred the ROS-promoted autophagosome formation in BEAS-2B cells. Consistently, in OVA-sensitized mice the expression of beclin-1 and LC3A/B was highly induced, and oral administration of astragalin suppressed the autophagosome formation with inhibiting the induction of these proteins in OVA-challenged airway subepithelium. Induction of autophagy by spermidine influenced the epithelial induction of E-cadherin and vimentin that was blocked by treating astragalin.">
    <entity charOffset="1122-1135" id="424cd6cb670119aed604833cf1f107598f217574.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0005776" text="autophagosome" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1122-1145" id="424cd6cb670119aed604833cf1f107598f217574.c2.e1" ontology_id="GO_0000045" text="autophagosome formation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1312-1325" id="424cd6cb670119aed604833cf1f107598f217574.c2.e2" ontology_id="GO_0005776" text="autophagosome" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1312-1335" id="424cd6cb670119aed604833cf1f107598f217574.c2.e3" ontology_id="GO_0000045" text="autophagosome formation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1437-1446" id="424cd6cb670119aed604833cf1f107598f217574.c2.e4" ontology_id="GO_0006914" text="autophagy" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="424cd6cb670119aed604833cf1f107598f217574.c3" text="Conclusion: These results demonstrate that astragalin can be effective in allaying ROS-promoted bronchial fibrosis through inhibiting autophagosome formation in airways.">
    <entity charOffset="134-147" id="424cd6cb670119aed604833cf1f107598f217574.c3.e0" ontology_id="GO_0005776" text="autophagosome" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="134-157" id="424cd6cb670119aed604833cf1f107598f217574.c3.e1" ontology_id="GO_0000045" text="autophagosome formation" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
