<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="42c1d88111ece7fdf4a80dc8ddb30be44b211d80">
  <chunk id="42c1d88111ece7fdf4a80dc8ddb30be44b211d80.c0" text="Rhesus Macaque Theta Defensins Suppress Inflammatory Cytokines and Enhance Survival in Mouse Models of Bacteremic Sepsis">
    <entity charOffset="114-120" id="42c1d88111ece7fdf4a80dc8ddb30be44b211d80.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0100806" text="Sepsis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="42c1d88111ece7fdf4a80dc8ddb30be44b211d80.c1" text="Theta-defensins (h-defensins) are macrocyclic antimicrobial peptides expressed in leukocytes of Old World monkeys. The peptides are broad spectrum microbicides in vitro and numerous h-defensin isoforms have been identified in granulocytes of rhesus macaques and Olive baboons. Several mammalian aand b-defensins, genetically related to h-defensins, have proinflammatory and immune-activating properties that bridge innate and acquired immunity. In the current study we analyzed the immunoregulatory properties of rhesus h-defensins 1-5 (RTDs 1-5). RTD-1, the most abundant h-defensin in macaques, reduced the levels of TNF, IL-1a, IL-1b, IL-6, and IL-8 secreted by blood leukocytes stimulated by several TLR agonists. RTDs 1-5 suppressed levels of soluble TNF released by bacteria-or LPS-stimulated blood leukocytes and THP-1 monocytes. Despite their highly conserved conformation and amino acid sequences, the anti-TNF activities of RTDs 1-5 varied by as much as 10-fold. Systemically administered RTD-1 was non-toxic for BALB/c mice, and escalating intravenous doses were well tolerated and non-immunogenic in adult chimpanzees. The peptide was highly stable in serum and plasma. Single dose administration of RTD-1 at 5 mg/kg significantly improved survival of BALB/c mice with E. coli peritonitis and cecal ligation-and-puncture induced polymicrobial sepsis. Peptide treatment reduced serum levels of several inflammatory cytokines/chemokines in bacteremic animals. Collectively, these results indicate that the anti-inflammatory properties of hdefensins in vitro and in vivo are mediated by the suppression of numerous proinflammatory cytokines and blockade of TNF release may be a primary effect.">
    <entity charOffset="1154-1160" id="42c1d88111ece7fdf4a80dc8ddb30be44b211d80.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0031915" text="stable" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1289-1300" id="42c1d88111ece7fdf4a80dc8ddb30be44b211d80.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0002586" text="peritonitis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
