<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="44f82307e441f32a4ddd4ea51a8f823c593e2151">
  <chunk id="44f82307e441f32a4ddd4ea51a8f823c593e2151.c0" text="Glycyrrhizic Acid Promotes M1 Macrophage Polarization in Murine Bone Marrow-Derived Macrophages Associated with the Activation of JNK and NF-B">
    <entity charOffset="30-53" id="44f82307e441f32a4ddd4ea51a8f823c593e2151.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0042116" text="Macrophage Polarization" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="130-133" id="44f82307e441f32a4ddd4ea51a8f823c593e2151.c0.e1" ontology_id="GO_0004705" text="JNK" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="44f82307e441f32a4ddd4ea51a8f823c593e2151.c1" text="The roots and rhizomes of Glycyrrhiza species (licorice) have been widely used as natural sweeteners and herbal medicines. The aim of this study is to investigate the effect of glycyrrhizic acid (GA) from licorice on macrophage polarization. Both phenotypic and functional activities of murine bone marrow-derived macrophages (BMDMs) treated by GA were assessed. Our results showed that GA obviously increased the cell surface expression of CD80, CD86, and MHCII molecules. Meanwhile, GA upregulated the expression of CCR7 and the production of TNF-, IL-12, IL-6, and NO (the markers of classically activated (M1) macrophages), whereas it downregulated the expression of MR, Ym1, and Arg1 (the markers of alternatively activated (M2) macrophage). The functional tests showed that GA dramatically enhanced the uptake of FITC-dextran and E. coli K88 by BMDMs and decreased the intracellular survival of E. coli K88 and S. typhimurium. Moreover, we demonstrated that JNK and NF-B activation are required for GA-induced NO and M1-related cytokines production, while ERK1/2 pathway exhibits a regulatory effect via induction of IL-10. Together, these findings indicated that GA promoted polarization of M1 macrophages and enhanced its phagocytosis and bactericidal capacity. The results expanded our knowledge about the role of GA in macrophage polarization.">
    <entity charOffset="414-426" id="44f82307e441f32a4ddd4ea51a8f823c593e2151.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0009986" text="cell surface" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="875-888" id="44f82307e441f32a4ddd4ea51a8f823c593e2151.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005622" text="intracellular" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="964-967" id="44f82307e441f32a4ddd4ea51a8f823c593e2151.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0004705" text="JNK" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1230-1242" id="44f82307e441f32a4ddd4ea51a8f823c593e2151.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0006909" text="phagocytosis" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
