<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="468cd07dc546d39f95529846f303e76f02ae51b3">
  <chunk id="468cd07dc546d39f95529846f303e76f02ae51b3.c0" text="Nucleolin stabilizes G-quadruplex structures folded by the LTR promoter and silences HIV-1 viral transcription">
    <entity charOffset="91-110" id="468cd07dc546d39f95529846f303e76f02ae51b3.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0019083" text="viral transcription" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="468cd07dc546d39f95529846f303e76f02ae51b3.c1" text="Folding of the LTR promoter into dynamic Gquadruplex conformations has been shown to suppress its transcriptional activity in HIV-1. Here we sought to identify the proteins that control the folding of this region of proviral genome by inducing/stabilizing G-quadruplex structures. The implementation of electrophorethic mobility shift assay and pull-down experiments coupled with mass spectrometric analysis revealed that the cellular protein nucleolin is able to specifically recognize G-quadruplex structures present in the LTR promoter. Nucleolin recognized with high affinity and specificity the majority, but not all the possible Gquadruplexes folded by this sequence. In addition, it displayed greater binding preference towards DNA than RNA G-quadruplexes, thus indicating two levels of selectivity based on the sequence and nature of the target. The interaction translated into stabilization of the LTR G-quadruplexes and increased promoter silencing activity; in contrast, disruption of nucleolin binding in cells by both siRNAs and a nucleolin binding aptamer greatly increased LTR promoter activity. These data indicate that nucleolin possesses a specific and regulated activity toward the HIV-1 LTR promoter, which is mediated by G-quadruplexes. These observations provide new essential insights into viral transcription and a possible low mutagenic target for antiretroviral therapy.">
    <entity charOffset="708-715" id="468cd07dc546d39f95529846f303e76f02ae51b3.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1006-1013" id="468cd07dc546d39f95529846f303e76f02ae51b3.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1054-1061" id="468cd07dc546d39f95529846f303e76f02ae51b3.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1313-1332" id="468cd07dc546d39f95529846f303e76f02ae51b3.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0019083" text="viral transcription" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
