<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="47d9a4720ad71e2f3fa79c9b54ff23ababcec330">
  <chunk id="47d9a4720ad71e2f3fa79c9b54ff23ababcec330.c0" text="Find the right sample: A study on the versatility of saliva and urine samples for the diagnosis of emerging viruses">
    <entity charOffset="9-14" id="47d9a4720ad71e2f3fa79c9b54ff23ababcec330.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012834" text="right" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="47d9a4720ad71e2f3fa79c9b54ff23ababcec330.c1" text="The emergence of different viral infections during the last decades like dengue, West Nile, SARS, chikungunya, MERS-CoV, Ebola, Zika and Yellow Fever raised some questions on quickness and reliability of laboratory diagnostic tests for verification of suspected cases. Since sampling of blood requires medically trained personal and comprises some risks for the patient as well as for the health care personal, the sampling by noninvasive methods (e.g. saliva and/ or urine) might be a very valuable alternative for investigating a diseased patient. Main body: To analyse the usefulness of alternative noninvasive samples for the diagnosis of emerging infectious viral diseases, a literature search was performed on PubMed for alternative sampling for these viral infections. In total, 711 papers of potential relevance were found, of which we have included 128 in this review. Conclusions: Considering the experience using non-invasive sampling for the diagnostic of emerging viral diseases, it seems important to perform an investigation using alternative samples for routine diagnostics. Moreover, during an outbreak situation, evaluation of appropriate sampling and further processing for laboratory analysis on various diagnostic platforms are very crucial. This will help to achieve optimal diagnostic results for a good and reliable case identification.">
    <entity charOffset="144-149" id="47d9a4720ad71e2f3fa79c9b54ff23ababcec330.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0001945" text="Fever" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
