<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="48d2cdd1975a60aa6d7ab15b51b523b10529b038">
  <chunk id="48d2cdd1975a60aa6d7ab15b51b523b10529b038.c0" text="Virology Journal The role of single N-glycans in proteolytic processing and cell surface transport of the Lassa virus glycoprotein GP-C">
    <entity charOffset="76-88" id="48d2cdd1975a60aa6d7ab15b51b523b10529b038.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0009986" text="cell surface" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="89-98" id="48d2cdd1975a60aa6d7ab15b51b523b10529b038.c0.e1" ontology_id="GO_0006810" text="transport" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="48d2cdd1975a60aa6d7ab15b51b523b10529b038.c1" text="Lassa virus glycoprotein is synthesised as a precursor (preGP-C) into the lumen of the endoplasmic reticulum. After cotranslational cleavage of the signal peptide, the immature GP-C is posttranslationally processed into the N-terminal subunit GP-1 and the C-terminal subunit GP-2 by the host cell subtilase SKI-1/S1P. The glycoprotein precursor contains eleven potential Nglycosylation sites. In this report, we investigated the effect of each N-glycan on proteolytic cleavage and cell surface transport by disrupting the consensus sequences of eleven potential Nglycan attachment sites individually. Five glycoprotein mutants with disrupted N-glycosylation sites were still proteolytically processed, whereas the remaining N-glycosylation sites are necessary for GP-C cleavage. Despite the lack of proteolytic processing, all cleavage-defective mutants were transported to the cell surface and remained completely endo H-sensitive. The findings indicate that N-glycans are needed for correct conformation of GP-C in order to be cleaved by SKI-1/S1P.">
    <entity charOffset="287-296" id="48d2cdd1975a60aa6d7ab15b51b523b10529b038.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0043657" text="host cell" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="481-493" id="48d2cdd1975a60aa6d7ab15b51b523b10529b038.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0009986" text="cell surface" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="494-503" id="48d2cdd1975a60aa6d7ab15b51b523b10529b038.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0006810" text="transport" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="878-890" id="48d2cdd1975a60aa6d7ab15b51b523b10529b038.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0009986" text="cell surface" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
