<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="49f01042ee1df642748c8b65f2abde687b2750ed">
  <chunk id="49f01042ee1df642748c8b65f2abde687b2750ed.c0" text="Antioxidant Status and Immune Activity of Glycyrrhizin in Allergic Rhinitis Mice">
    <entity charOffset="58-75" id="49f01042ee1df642748c8b65f2abde687b2750ed.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0003193" text="Allergic Rhinitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="67-75" id="49f01042ee1df642748c8b65f2abde687b2750ed.c0.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012384" text="Rhinitis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="49f01042ee1df642748c8b65f2abde687b2750ed.c1" text="Oxidative stress is considered as a major risk factor that contributes to increased lipid peroxidation and declined antioxidants in some degenerative diseases. Glycyrrhizin is widely used to cure allergic diseases due to its medicinal properties. In the present study, we evaluated the role of glycyrrhizin on lipid peroxidation and antioxidant status in the blood and nasal mucosa of allergic rhinitis (AR) mice. Mice were divided into six groups: normal control mice, model control (MC) mice, three glycyrrhizin-treated mice groups and lycopene-treated mice. Sensitization-associated increase in lipid peroxidation was observed in the blood and nasal mucosa of MC mice. Activities of antioxidant enzymes like superoxide dismutase (SOD), catalase (CAT), glutathione peroxidase (GSH-Px), total antioxidant capacity (TAOC) and levels of glutathione (GSH) were found to be significantly decreased in the blood and nasal mucosa in MC mice when compared to normal control mice. However, normalized lipid peroxidation and antioxidant defenses were reported in the glycyrrhizin-treated and lycopene-treated mice. Moreover, glycyrrhizin treatment still enhanced IFN-γ and reduced IL-4 levels in glycyrrhizin-treated mice. These findings demonstrated that glycyrrhizin treatment enhanced the antioxidant status and">
    <entity charOffset="0-16" id="49f01042ee1df642748c8b65f2abde687b2750ed.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0025464" text="Oxidative stress" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="385-402" id="49f01042ee1df642748c8b65f2abde687b2750ed.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0003193" text="allergic rhinitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="394-402" id="49f01042ee1df642748c8b65f2abde687b2750ed.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0012384" text="rhinitis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="49f01042ee1df642748c8b65f2abde687b2750ed.c2" text="Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2011, 12 906 decreased the incidence of free radical-induced lipid peroxidation and improved immunity activities in the blood and nasal mucosa of AR mice."/>
</document>
