<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="4abc50cfc81265083d4cb2aed0a493bb704d0b5b">
  <chunk id="4abc50cfc81265083d4cb2aed0a493bb704d0b5b.c0" text="viruses Rabies Control and Treatment: From Prophylaxis to Strategies with Curative Potential"/>
  <chunk id="4abc50cfc81265083d4cb2aed0a493bb704d0b5b.c1" text="Rabies is an acute, fatal, neurological disease that affects almost all kinds of mammals. Vaccination (using an inactivated rabies vaccine), combined with administration of rabies immune globulin, is the only approved, effective method for post-exposure prophylaxis against rabies in humans. In the search for novel rabies control and treatment strategies, live-attenuated viruses have recently emerged as a practical and promising approach for immunizing and controlling rabies. Unlike the conventional, inactivated rabies vaccine, live-attenuated viruses are genetically modified viruses that are able to replicate in an inoculated recipient without causing adverse effects, while still eliciting robust and effective immune responses against rabies virus infection. A number of viruses with an intrinsic capacity that could be used as putative candidates for live-attenuated rabies vaccine have been intensively evaluated for therapeutic purposes. Additional novel strategies, such as a monoclonal antibody-based approach, nucleic acid-based vaccines, or small interfering RNAs (siRNAs) interfering with virus replication, could further add to the arena of strategies to combat rabies. In this review, we highlight current advances in rabies therapy and discuss the role that they might have in the future of rabies treatment. Given the pronounced and complex impact of rabies on a patient, a combination of these novel modalities has the potential to achieve maximal anti-rabies efficacy, or may even have promising curative effects in the future. However, several hurdles regarding clinical safety considerations and public awareness should be overcome before these approaches can ultimately become clinically relevant therapies. exposed on the surface of the virus and is not only the major determinant of viral pathogenicity, but also the major protective antigen responsible for inducing protective immunity against rabies [2] [3] [4] [5] ."/>
  <chunk id="4abc50cfc81265083d4cb2aed0a493bb704d0b5b.c2" text="Fortunately, rabies can be a vaccine-preventable disease, provided that post-exposure prophylaxis (PEP) is given promptly and correctly. Protection against rabies correlates with the presence of rabies-specific virus-neutralizing antibodies (VNAs). According to the WHO, VNA titers greater than 0.5 international units per mL serum can reliably provide protection to humans and animals. Currently, rabies-infected dogs are the major reason for the high incidence of human rabies, and therefore vaccinating dogs has been shown to be the most cost-effective strategy for preventing rabies in humans. As reported by the WHO, vaccination coverage of 70% of the canine population can efficiently reduce virus transmission and prevent human rabies. However, despite the fact that efficacious vaccines are readily available, rabies still has a high death rate, mainly due to the cost and accessibility of proper PEP treatment. The current PEP schedule not only requires multiple injections but is also time-consuming, a problem that is even more pronounced due to the fact that RABV-specific immunoglobulin (RIG), which is both expensive and often in short supply, is required to treat severe exposure. This creates a particular burden for rural regions of developing countries that suffer from the highest incidence rates of rabies. Therefore, the development of alternative, cost-effective vaccines that would induce sustained immunity after a single dose inoculation and could ideally clear virus infection from the CNS is warranted.">
    <entity charOffset="1085-1099" id="4abc50cfc81265083d4cb2aed0a493bb704d0b5b.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="immunoglobulin" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1179-1185" id="4abc50cfc81265083d4cb2aed0a493bb704d0b5b.c2.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="4abc50cfc81265083d4cb2aed0a493bb704d0b5b.c2.e0" e2="4abc50cfc81265083d4cb2aed0a493bb704d0b5b.c2.e1" id="4abc50cfc81265083d4cb2aed0a493bb704d0b5b.c2.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="4abc50cfc81265083d4cb2aed0a493bb704d0b5b.c3" text="The advent of the reverse genetics technique has revolutionized the study of RABV, as well as other negative-strand RNA viruses, which has greatly advanced our understanding of the biology of these viruses and profoundly accelerated the development of novel vaccines against various pathogens [6] . While a number of excellent reviews have been written focusing on reverse genetics of negative-strand RNA viruses, the biology of RABV, rabies vaccines, and the pathology and prophylaxis of rabies [6-10], this review rectifies the lack of focus on current strategies that have been evaluated for prevention or as PEP of rabies. This review places particular emphasis on the most promising approaches using live-attenuated and/or recombinant vaccine platforms for preventive vaccinations. Other innovative modalities, such as monoclonal antibody-based platforms and small interfering RNAs (siRNAs) interfering with virus replication, which may deserve future research for rabies treatment, will also be briefly introduced."/>
</document>
