<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="4c6a45d1e56660fa713b637825b96e287a0acef5">
  <chunk id="4c6a45d1e56660fa713b637825b96e287a0acef5.c0" text="Experimental infection of dogs with a feline endogenous retrovirus RD-114"/>
  <chunk id="4c6a45d1e56660fa713b637825b96e287a0acef5.c1" text="Background: The feline endogenous retrovirus RD114 is contained in the genome of cats. The virus may contaminate live canine vaccines based on cultured feline cells. The in vivo infectivity, acute and subacute pathogenicity, and viral proliferation of the RD114 virus were evaluated by experimental infection of dogs. Methods: Nine specific pathogen free dogs were divided into three groups, with each group consisting of one female and two male dogs. Dogs were subcutaneously inoculated in the neck with either 1 ml RD114 stock virus (group A), inactivated RD114 virus suspension (group B), or cell culture medium (group C) as a negative control. To assess blood cell counts and biochemical properties, blood samples from each group were collected 5 days before inoculation, just prior to inoculation, and 1, 3, 7 and 10 days post-inoculation. Result: During the experimental period of 51 days, none of the dogs inoculated with RD114 virus showed any clinical signs, significant increases in rectal temperature or abnormal blood biochemical characteristics including C-reactive protein when compared with the negative controls. We were not able to re-isolate the RD114 virus from buffy coat cells of group A dogs. Additionally, we could not detect RD114 provirus in the genomic DNA isolated from peripheral blood leukocytes, lymph node, spleen and sternal bone marrow cells. Conclusions: Signs of RD114 virus proliferation were not found after subcutaneous infection of dogs. Although the potential risk caused by infection with RD114 virus in dogs could not be assessed in this study, we suspect that RD114 virus has little or no virulence in dogs.">
    <entity charOffset="191-196" id="4c6a45d1e56660fa713b637825b96e287a0acef5.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="201-209" id="4c6a45d1e56660fa713b637825b96e287a0acef5.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011011" text="subacute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1297-1307" id="4c6a45d1e56660fa713b637825b96e287a0acef5.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0030646" text="peripheral" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
