<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="4d94a96a67f554bab5caafc4501fb7fda538609f">
  <chunk id="4d94a96a67f554bab5caafc4501fb7fda538609f.c0" text="molecules Anti-Herpetic, Anti-Dengue and Antineoplastic Activities of Simple and Heterocycle-Fused Derivatives of Terpenyl-1,4-Naphthoquinone and 1,4-Anthraquinone †"/>
  <chunk id="4d94a96a67f554bab5caafc4501fb7fda538609f.c1" text="Quinones are secondary metabolites of higher plants associated with many biological activities, including antiviral effects and cytotoxicity. In this study, the anti-herpetic and anti-dengue evaluation of 27 terpenyl-1,4-naphthoquinone (NQ), 1,4-anthraquinone (AQ) and heterocycle-fused quinone (HetQ) derivatives was done in vitro against Human Herpesvirus (HHV) type 1 and 2, and Dengue virus serotype 2 (DENV-2). The cytotoxicity on HeLa and Jurkat tumor cell lines was also tested. Using plaque forming unit assays, cell viability assays and molecular docking, we found that NQ 4 was the best antiviral compound, while AQ 11 was the most active and selective molecule on the tested tumor cells. NQ 4 showed a fair antiviral activity against Herpesviruses (EC 50 : &lt;0.4 µg/mL, &lt;1.28 µM) and DENV-2 (1.6 µg/mL, 5.1 µM) on pre-infective stages. Additionally, NQ 4 disrupted the viral attachment of HHV-1 to Vero cells (EC 50 : 0.12 µg/mL, 0.38 µM) with a very high selectivity index (SI = 1728). The in silico analysis predicted that this quinone could bind to the prefusion form of the E glycoprotein of DENV-2. These findings demonstrate that NQ 4 is a potent and highly selective antiviral compound, while suggesting its ability to prevent Herpes and Dengue infections. Additionally, AQ 11 can be considered of interest as a leader for the design of new anticancer agents.">
    <entity charOffset="452-457" id="4d94a96a67f554bab5caafc4501fb7fda538609f.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002664" text="tumor" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="686-691" id="4d94a96a67f554bab5caafc4501fb7fda538609f.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0002664" text="tumor" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
