<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="4dd0f09aa22d567e9f5f9a0bebd8686be35da853">
  <chunk id="4dd0f09aa22d567e9f5f9a0bebd8686be35da853.c0" text="Molecular Sciences Review Advances in Zika Virus-Host Cell Interaction: Current Knowledge and Future Perspectives"/>
  <chunk id="4dd0f09aa22d567e9f5f9a0bebd8686be35da853.c1" text="Emerging mosquito-transmitted RNA viruses, such as Zika virus (ZIKV) and Chikungunya represent human pathogens of an immense global health problem. In particular, ZIKV has emerged explosively since 2007 to cause a series of epidemics in the South Pacific and most recently in the Americas. Although typical ZIKV infections are asymptomatic, ZIKV infection during pregnancy is increasingly associated with microcephaly and other fetal developmental abnormalities. In the last few years, genomic and molecular investigations have established a remarkable progress on the pathogenic mechanisms of ZIKV infection using in vitro and in vivo models. Here, we highlight recent advances in ZIKV-host cell interaction studies, including cellular targets of ZIKV, ZIKV-mediated cell death mechanisms, host cell restriction factors that limit ZIKV replication, and immune evasion mechanisms utilized by ZIKV. Understanding of the mechanisms of ZIKV-host interaction at the cellular level will contribute crucial insights into the development of ZIKV therapeutics and vaccines.">
    <entity charOffset="405-417" id="4dd0f09aa22d567e9f5f9a0bebd8686be35da853.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0000252" text="microcephaly" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="768-778" id="4dd0f09aa22d567e9f5f9a0bebd8686be35da853.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0008219" text="cell death" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="791-800" id="4dd0f09aa22d567e9f5f9a0bebd8686be35da853.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0043657" text="host cell" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="854-868" id="4dd0f09aa22d567e9f5f9a0bebd8686be35da853.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0042783" text="immune evasion" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="4dd0f09aa22d567e9f5f9a0bebd8686be35da853.c1.e0" e2="4dd0f09aa22d567e9f5f9a0bebd8686be35da853.c1.e1" id="4dd0f09aa22d567e9f5f9a0bebd8686be35da853.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="4dd0f09aa22d567e9f5f9a0bebd8686be35da853.c1.e0" e2="4dd0f09aa22d567e9f5f9a0bebd8686be35da853.c1.e2" id="4dd0f09aa22d567e9f5f9a0bebd8686be35da853.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="4dd0f09aa22d567e9f5f9a0bebd8686be35da853.c1.e0" e2="4dd0f09aa22d567e9f5f9a0bebd8686be35da853.c1.e3" id="4dd0f09aa22d567e9f5f9a0bebd8686be35da853.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
