<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="4ec19e6a2799bf2bebe635732de198d04ddedf64">
  <chunk id="4ec19e6a2799bf2bebe635732de198d04ddedf64.c0" text="Biochemical and Structural Insights into the Mechanisms of SARS Coronavirus RNA Ribose 29-O-Methylation by nsp16/nsp10 Protein Complex"/>
  <chunk id="4ec19e6a2799bf2bebe635732de198d04ddedf64.c1" text="The 59-cap structure is a distinct feature of eukaryotic mRNAs, and eukaryotic viruses generally modify the 59-end of viral RNAs to mimic cellular mRNA structure, which is important for RNA stability, protein translation and viral immune escape. SARS coronavirus (SARS-CoV) encodes two S-adenosyl-L-methionine (SAM)-dependent methyltransferases (MTase) which sequentially methylate the RNA cap at guanosine-N7 and ribose 29-O positions, catalyzed by nsp14 N7-MTase and nsp16 29-O-MTase, respectively. A unique feature for SARS-CoV is that nsp16 requires non-structural protein nsp10 as a stimulatory factor to execute its MTase activity. Here we report the biochemical characterization of SARS-CoV 29-O-MTase and the crystal structure of nsp16/nsp10 complex bound with methyl donor SAM. We found that SARS-CoV nsp16 MTase methylated m7GpppA-RNA but not m7GpppG-RNA, which is in contrast with nsp14 MTase that functions in a sequence-independent manner. We demonstrated that nsp10 is required for nsp16 to bind both m7GpppA-RNA substrate and SAM cofactor. Structural analysis revealed that nsp16 possesses the canonical scaffold of MTase and associates with nsp10 at 1:1 ratio. The structure of the nsp16/nsp10 interaction interface shows that nsp10 may stabilize the SAM-binding pocket and extend the substrate RNA-binding groove of nsp16, consistent with the findings in biochemical assays. These results suggest that nsp16/nsp10 interface may represent a better drug target than the viral MTase active site for developing highly specific anticoronavirus drugs. Citation: Chen Y, Su C, Ke M, Jin X, Xu L, et al. (2011) Biochemical and Structural Insights into the Mechanisms of SARS Coronavirus RNA Ribose 29-O-Methylation by nsp16/nsp10 Protein Complex. PLoS Pathog 7(10): e1002294.">
    <entity charOffset="201-220" id="4ec19e6a2799bf2bebe635732de198d04ddedf64.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0006412" text="protein translation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="209-220" id="4ec19e6a2799bf2bebe635732de198d04ddedf64.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0006412" text="translation" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
