<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="4f5a550869a4ff5f8c754a9aa89453486cab2985">
  <chunk id="4f5a550869a4ff5f8c754a9aa89453486cab2985.c0" text="Limited Promiscuity of HLA-DRB1 Presented Peptides Derived of Blood Coagulation Factor VIII">
    <entity charOffset="62-79" id="4f5a550869a4ff5f8c754a9aa89453486cab2985.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0007596" text="Blood Coagulation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="68-79" id="4f5a550869a4ff5f8c754a9aa89453486cab2985.c0.e1" ontology_id="GO_0050817" text="Coagulation" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="4f5a550869a4ff5f8c754a9aa89453486cab2985.c1" text="The formation of inhibitory antibodies directed against coagulation factor VIII (FVIII) is a severe complication in the treatment of hemophilia A patients. The induction of anti-FVIII antibodies is a CD4 + T cell-dependent process. Activation of FVIII-specific CD4 + T cells is dependent on the presentation of FVIII-derived peptides on MHC class II by antigen-presenting cells. Previously, we have shown that FVIII-pulsed human monocyte-derived dendritic cells can present peptides from several FVIII domains. In this study we show that FVIII peptides are presented on immature as well as mature dendritic cells. In immature dendritic cells half of the FVIII-loaded MHC class II molecules are retained within the cell, whereas in LPS-matured dendritic cells the majority of MHC class II/peptide complexes is present on the plasma membrane. Time-course studies revealed that presentation of FVIII-derived peptides was optimal between 12 and 24 hours after maturation but persisted for at least 96 hours. We also show that macrophages are able to internalize FVIII as efficiently as dendritic cells, however FVIII was presented on MHC class II with a lower efficiency and with different epitopes compared to dendritic cells. In total, 48 FVIII core-peptides were identified using a DCs derived of 8 different donors. Five HLA-promiscuous FVIII peptide regions were found -these were presented by at least 4 out of 8 donors. The remaining 42 peptide core regions in FVIII were presented by DCs derived from a single (30 peptides) or two to three donors (12 peptides). Overall, our findings show that a broad repertoire of FVIII peptides can be presented on HLA-DR. Citation: van Haren SD, Wroblewska A, Herczenik E, Kaijen PH, Ruminska A, et al. (2013) Limited Promiscuity of HLA-DRB1 Presented Peptides Derived of Blood Coagulation Factor VIII . PLoS ONE 8(11): e80239.">
    <entity charOffset="56-67" id="4f5a550869a4ff5f8c754a9aa89453486cab2985.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0050817" text="coagulation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="93-99" id="4f5a550869a4ff5f8c754a9aa89453486cab2985.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1813-1830" id="4f5a550869a4ff5f8c754a9aa89453486cab2985.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0007596" text="Blood Coagulation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1819-1830" id="4f5a550869a4ff5f8c754a9aa89453486cab2985.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0050817" text="Coagulation" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="4f5a550869a4ff5f8c754a9aa89453486cab2985.c1.e0" e2="4f5a550869a4ff5f8c754a9aa89453486cab2985.c1.e1" id="4f5a550869a4ff5f8c754a9aa89453486cab2985.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="4f5a550869a4ff5f8c754a9aa89453486cab2985.c1.e1" e2="4f5a550869a4ff5f8c754a9aa89453486cab2985.c1.e2" id="4f5a550869a4ff5f8c754a9aa89453486cab2985.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="4f5a550869a4ff5f8c754a9aa89453486cab2985.c1.e1" e2="4f5a550869a4ff5f8c754a9aa89453486cab2985.c1.e3" id="4f5a550869a4ff5f8c754a9aa89453486cab2985.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
