<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="4f7c1aeb6e5b1e35d6be98d478259a83a8dd6993">
  <chunk id="4f7c1aeb6e5b1e35d6be98d478259a83a8dd6993.c0" text="Epidemiology of Respiratory Pathogens among Elderly Nursing Home Residents with Acute Respiratory Infections in Corsica, France, 2013-2017">
    <entity charOffset="80-85" id="4f7c1aeb6e5b1e35d6be98d478259a83a8dd6993.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="Acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="86-108" id="4f7c1aeb6e5b1e35d6be98d478259a83a8dd6993.c0.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011947" text="Respiratory Infections" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="4f7c1aeb6e5b1e35d6be98d478259a83a8dd6993.c1" text="Background. The current study aims to describe the demographical and clinical characteristics of elderly nursing home (NH) residents with acute respiratory infections (ARIs) during four winter seasons (2013/2014-2016/2017), as well as the microbiological etiology of these infections. Methods. Seventeen NHs with at least one ARI resident in Corsica, France, were included. An ARI resident was defined as a resident developing a sudden onset of any constitutional symptoms in addition to any respiratory signs. Nasopharyngeal swabs from ARI residents were screened for the presence of 21 respiratory agents, including seasonal influenza viruses. Results. Of the 107 ARI residents enrolled from NHs, 61 (57%) were positive for at least one of the 21 respiratory pathogens. Forty-one (38.3%) of the 107 ARI residents had influenza: 38 (92%) were positive for influenza A (100% A(H3N2)) and three (8%) for influenza B/Victoria. Axillary fever (≥38 ∘ C) was significantly more common among patients infected with influenza A(H3N2). Conclusion. The circulation of seasonal respiratory viruses other than influenza A(H3N2) seems to be sporadic among elderly NH residents. Investigating the circulation of respiratory viruses in nonwinter seasons seems to be important in order to understand better the dynamic of their year-round circulation in NHs.">
    <entity charOffset="138-143" id="4f7c1aeb6e5b1e35d6be98d478259a83a8dd6993.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="144-166" id="4f7c1aeb6e5b1e35d6be98d478259a83a8dd6993.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011947" text="respiratory infections" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="436-441" id="4f7c1aeb6e5b1e35d6be98d478259a83a8dd6993.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0003674" text="onset" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="934-939" id="4f7c1aeb6e5b1e35d6be98d478259a83a8dd6993.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0001945" text="fever" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1129-1137" id="4f7c1aeb6e5b1e35d6be98d478259a83a8dd6993.c1.e4" ontology_id="HP_0003745" text="sporadic" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
