<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="4fc79293e3efdfd44b408d923b2448ac6a5ddd0d">
  <chunk id="4fc79293e3efdfd44b408d923b2448ac6a5ddd0d.c0" text="A self-adjuvanted nanoparticle based vaccine against infectious bronchitis virus">
    <entity charOffset="64-74" id="4fc79293e3efdfd44b408d923b2448ac6a5ddd0d.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012387" text="bronchitis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="4fc79293e3efdfd44b408d923b2448ac6a5ddd0d.c1" text="Infectious bronchitis virus (IBV) affects poultry respiratory, renal and reproductive systems. Currently the efficacy of available live attenuated or killed vaccines against IBV has been challenged. We designed a novel IBV vaccine alternative using a highly innovative platform called Self-Assembling Protein Nanoparticle (SAPN). In this vaccine, B cell epitopes derived from the second heptad repeat (HR2) region of IBV spike proteins were repetitively presented in its native trimeric conformation. In addition, flagellin was co-displayed in the SAPN to achieve a self-adjuvanted effect. Three groups of chickens were immunized at four weeks of age with the vaccine prototype, IBV-Flagellin-SAPN, a negative-control construct Flagellin-SAPN or a buffer control. The immunized chickens were challenged with 5x10 4.7 EID50 IBV M41 strain. High antibody responses were detected in chickens immunized with IBV-Flagellin-SAPN. In ex vivo proliferation tests, peripheral mononuclear cells (PBMCs) derived from IBV-Flagellin-SAPN immunized chickens had a significantly higher stimulation index than that of PBMCs from chickens receiving Flagellin-SAPN. Chickens immunized with IBV-Flagellin-SAPN had a significant reduction of tracheal virus shedding and lesser tracheal lesion scores than did negative control chickens. The data demonstrated that the IBV-Flagellin-SAPN holds promise as a vaccine for IBV.">
    <entity charOffset="11-21" id="4fc79293e3efdfd44b408d923b2448ac6a5ddd0d.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012387" text="bronchitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="844-852" id="4fc79293e3efdfd44b408d923b2448ac6a5ddd0d.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="844-852" id="4fc79293e3efdfd44b408d923b2448ac6a5ddd0d.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="956-966" id="4fc79293e3efdfd44b408d923b2448ac6a5ddd0d.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0030646" text="peripheral" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="4fc79293e3efdfd44b408d923b2448ac6a5ddd0d.c1.e0" e2="4fc79293e3efdfd44b408d923b2448ac6a5ddd0d.c1.e1" id="4fc79293e3efdfd44b408d923b2448ac6a5ddd0d.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="4fc79293e3efdfd44b408d923b2448ac6a5ddd0d.c1.e0" e2="4fc79293e3efdfd44b408d923b2448ac6a5ddd0d.c1.e2" id="4fc79293e3efdfd44b408d923b2448ac6a5ddd0d.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="4fc79293e3efdfd44b408d923b2448ac6a5ddd0d.c1.e1" e2="4fc79293e3efdfd44b408d923b2448ac6a5ddd0d.c1.e3" id="4fc79293e3efdfd44b408d923b2448ac6a5ddd0d.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="4fc79293e3efdfd44b408d923b2448ac6a5ddd0d.c1.e2" e2="4fc79293e3efdfd44b408d923b2448ac6a5ddd0d.c1.e3" id="4fc79293e3efdfd44b408d923b2448ac6a5ddd0d.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
