<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="509e9bda6a2f6b5525ba06641f8af156653a2aab">
  <chunk id="509e9bda6a2f6b5525ba06641f8af156653a2aab.c0" text="Intracranial Injection of Dengue Virus Induces Interferon Stimulated Genes and CD8 + T Cell Infiltration by Sphingosine Kinase 1 Independent Pathways"/>
  <chunk id="509e9bda6a2f6b5525ba06641f8af156653a2aab.c1" text="We have previously reported that the absence of sphingosine kinase 1 (SK1) affects both dengue virus (DENV) infection and innate immune responses in vitro. Here we aimed to define SK1-dependancy of DENV-induced disease and the associated innate responses in vivo. The lack of a reliable mouse model with a fully competent interferon response for DENV infection is a challenge, and here we use an experimental model of DENV infection in the brain of immunocompetent mice. Intracranial injection of DENV-2 into C57BL/6 mice induced body weight loss and neurological symptoms which was associated with a high level of DENV RNA in the brain. Body weight loss and DENV RNA level tended to be greater in SK1 -/compared with wildtype (WT) mice. Brain infection with DENV-2 is associated with the induction of interferon-β (IFN-β) and IFN-stimulated gene (ISG) expression including viperin, Ifi27l2a, IRF7, and CXCL10 without any significant differences between WT and SK1 -/mice. The SK2 and sphingosine-1-phosphate (S1P) levels in the brain were unchanged by DENV infection or the lack of SK1. Histological analysis demonstrated the presence of a cellular infiltrate in DENV-infected brain with a significant increase in mRNA for CD8 but not CD4 suggesting this infiltrate is likely CD8 + but not CD4 + T-lymphocytes. This increase in T-cell infiltration was not affected by the lack of SK1. Overall, DENV-infection in the brain induces IFN and T-cell responses but does not influence the SK/S1P axis. In contrast to our observations in vitro, SK1 has no major influence on these responses following DENV-infection in the mouse brain.">
    <entity charOffset="535-546" id="509e9bda6a2f6b5525ba06641f8af156653a2aab.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0001824" text="weight loss" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="643-654" id="509e9bda6a2f6b5525ba06641f8af156653a2aab.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0001824" text="weight loss" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1357-1365" id="509e9bda6a2f6b5525ba06641f8af156653a2aab.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0032320" text="affected" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="509e9bda6a2f6b5525ba06641f8af156653a2aab.c2" text="Total RNA was extracted from brain tissues using TRIzol (Ambion Life Technologies), according to the manufacturer's instructions. The extracted RNA was DNase I treated (Zymo Research) and quantitated by spectrophotometry (NanoDrop elite, Thermo Scientific). Total RNA (0.5 μg) was reverse transcribed using M-MuLV reverse transcriptase (NEB) and random hexamers (NEB) in a 20 μl final volume, and subjected to a real-time qRT-PCR. qRT-PCR was carried out using 2 μl of cDNA template in a 10 μl reaction using iTaq SYBER green (BioRad) with 20 μM of each forward and reverse primer. All PCR primers were synthesised by Gene-Works with sequences as listed in Table 1 . Real-time qRT-PCR was performed using Rotor-Gene 3000 real-time PCR system (Corbett research, Australia) under the following conditions: one cycle of 95˚C for 5 minutes; 45 cycles of 95˚C for 15 seconds, 59˚C for 30 seconds, and 72˚C for 30 seconds; and one cycle of 72˚C for 60 seconds followed by melt curve analysis. Quantitative DENV copy number was calculated from a standard curve generated from Dengue Virus Induces ISGs in the Mouse Brain PLOS ONE |"/>
</document>
