<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="51340894a896316b58653a60c48da9c16b3ad0e3">
  <chunk id="51340894a896316b58653a60c48da9c16b3ad0e3.c0" text="Repositioning salicylanilide anthelmintic drugs to treat adenovirus infections"/>
  <chunk id="51340894a896316b58653a60c48da9c16b3ad0e3.c1" text="The repositioning of drugs already approved by regulatory agencies for other indications is an emerging alternative for the development of new antimicrobial therapies. The repositioning process involves lower risks and costs than the de novo development of novel antimicrobial drugs. Currently, infections by adenovirus show a steady increment with a high clinical impact in immunosuppressed and immunocompetent patients. The lack of a safe and efficacious drug to treat these infections supports the search for new antiviral drugs. Here we evaluated the anti-adenovirus activity of niclosanide, oxyclozanide, and rafoxanide, three salicylanilide anthelmintic drugs. Also, we carried out the cytotoxicity evaluation and partial characterization of the mechanism of action of these drugs. The salicylanilide anthelmintic drugs showed significant anti-adenovirus activity at low micromolar concentrations with little cytotoxicity. Moreover, our mechanistic assays suggest differences in the way the drugs exert anti-adenovirus activity. Niclosamide and rafoxanide target transport of the HAdV particle from the endosome to the nuclear envelope, whilst oxyclozanide specifically targets adenovirus immediately early gene E1A transcription. Data suggests that the studied salicylanilide anthelmintic drugs could be suitable for further clinical evaluation for the development of new antiviral drugs to treat infections by adenovirus in immunosuppressed patients and in immunocompetent individuals with community-acquired pneumonia.">
    <entity charOffset="1069-1078" id="51340894a896316b58653a60c48da9c16b3ad0e3.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0006810" text="transport" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1109-1117" id="51340894a896316b58653a60c48da9c16b3ad0e3.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005768" text="endosome" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
