<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="534a301ea6a76eb47c8d42e30981088ac5603418">
  <chunk id="534a301ea6a76eb47c8d42e30981088ac5603418.c0" text="Coxsackievirus B3 Responds to Polyamine Depletion via Enhancement of 2A and 3C Protease Activity">
    <entity charOffset="79-96" id="534a301ea6a76eb47c8d42e30981088ac5603418.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0008233" text="Protease Activity" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="534a301ea6a76eb47c8d42e30981088ac5603418.c1" text="Polyamines are small positively-charged molecules abundant in eukaryotic cells that are crucial to RNA virus replication. In eukaryotic cells, polyamines facilitate processes such as transcription, translation, and DNA replication, and viruses similarly rely on polyamines to facilitate transcription and translation. Whether polyamines function at additional stages in viral replication remains poorly understood. Picornaviruses, including Coxsackievirus B3 (CVB3), are sensitive to polyamine depletion both in vitro and in vivo; however, precisely how polyamine function in picornavirus infection has not been described. Here, we describe CVB3 mutants that arise with passage in polyamine-depleted conditions. We observe mutations in the 2A and 3C proteases, and we find that these mutant proteases confer resistance to polyamine depletion. Using a split luciferase reporter system to measure protease activity, we determined that polyamines facilitate viral protease activity. We further observe that the 2A and 3C protease mutations enhance reporter protease activity in polyamine-depleted conditions. Finally, we find that these mutations promote cleavage of cellular eIF4G during infection of polyamine-depleted cells. In sum, our results suggest that polyamines are crucial to protease function during picornavirus infection. Further, these data highlight viral proteases as potential antiviral targets and highlight how CVB3 may overcome polyamine-depleting antiviral therapies. Viral proteases play many roles during infection, and picornaviruses encode two distinct proteases: 2A (2A pro ) and 3C (3C pro ). The 2A and 3C picornaviral proteases function to cleave both host and viral proteins. 3C is responsible for the majority of viral polyprotein cleavage. Importantly, 3C also functions as part of 3CD (a polyprotein consisting of the 3C protease and 3D polymerase) and acts as a protease in this context as well [11] . To date, reports demonstrated that 2A facilitates the cleavage between the P1 and P2 protein segments [12] . The precise regulation of these proteases, their activities, and their overlapping and unique functions remains to be fully understood. However, due to their copious functions during infection, they represent potential drug targets [13] [14] [15] .">
    <entity charOffset="895-912" id="534a301ea6a76eb47c8d42e30981088ac5603418.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0008233" text="protease activity" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="961-978" id="534a301ea6a76eb47c8d42e30981088ac5603418.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0008233" text="protease activity" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1054-1071" id="534a301ea6a76eb47c8d42e30981088ac5603418.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0008233" text="protease activity" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="534a301ea6a76eb47c8d42e30981088ac5603418.c2" text="Polyamines are small, positively-charged molecules that are abundant in eukaryotic cells. Polyamines function in nucleotide metabolism, cell cycling, and cell signaling, among several other functions [16] [17] [18] . Several compounds have been developed that specifically target polyamine metabolism, either by reducing their synthesis or enhancing their breakdown, and these compounds have been tested clinically for the treatment of cancers and parasites [19] [20] [21] . Difluoromethylornithine (DFMO), which inhibits polyamine biosynthesis, has received attention as an anti-trypanosomal molecule and is well-tolerated in patients [22, 23] . Polyamines are also crucial for RNA virus infection, including CVB3 [24]. Polyamine depletion via DFMO restricts CVB3 infection, in vitro and in vivo [25]. We previously described how Chikungunya and Zika viruses rely on polyamines for viral translation and genome replication [26] ; however, whether similar processes are affected for other viruses and precisely how polyamines function during CVB3 replication remain to be completely understood.">
    <entity charOffset="327-336" id="534a301ea6a76eb47c8d42e30981088ac5603418.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0009058" text="synthesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="883-900" id="534a301ea6a76eb47c8d42e30981088ac5603418.c2.e1" ontology_id="GO_0019081" text="viral translation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="889-900" id="534a301ea6a76eb47c8d42e30981088ac5603418.c2.e2" ontology_id="GO_0006412" text="translation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="970-978" id="534a301ea6a76eb47c8d42e30981088ac5603418.c2.e3" ontology_id="HP_0032320" text="affected" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="534a301ea6a76eb47c8d42e30981088ac5603418.c2.e0" e2="534a301ea6a76eb47c8d42e30981088ac5603418.c2.e3" id="534a301ea6a76eb47c8d42e30981088ac5603418.c2.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="534a301ea6a76eb47c8d42e30981088ac5603418.c2.e1" e2="534a301ea6a76eb47c8d42e30981088ac5603418.c2.e3" id="534a301ea6a76eb47c8d42e30981088ac5603418.c2.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="534a301ea6a76eb47c8d42e30981088ac5603418.c2.e2" e2="534a301ea6a76eb47c8d42e30981088ac5603418.c2.e3" id="534a301ea6a76eb47c8d42e30981088ac5603418.c2.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="534a301ea6a76eb47c8d42e30981088ac5603418.c3" text="To investigate how polyamines facilitate CVB3 infection, we performed a screen for virus escape mutants that were resistant to DFMO treatment. We isolated two distinct viral mutants in the 2A and 3C proteases. We determined that these mutant viruses were resistant to polyamine depletion and that these mutations conferred no fitness advantage in the absence of polyamine depletion. To investigate the proteolytic activity of these enzymes, we developed a protease-dependent split-luciferase reporter system to measure 2A and 3C activity. Using this assay, we observed that 2A and 3C activity was diminished with polyamine depletion, to which mutant 2A and 3C proteases were resistant. Additionally, we observed that viruses containing these mutants were able to cleave cellular targets efficiently in polyamine-depleted cells. Together, these data suggest that polyamines are crucial for viral protease activity and that we may target CVB3 proteolytic activity through polyamine-depleting pharmaceuticals like DFMO.">
    <entity charOffset="895-912" id="534a301ea6a76eb47c8d42e30981088ac5603418.c3.e0" ontology_id="GO_0008233" text="protease activity" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
