<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="534bc15ce844653ae863844b86d4ace2b98d42a3">
  <chunk id="534bc15ce844653ae863844b86d4ace2b98d42a3.c0" text="Diversity of Cryptosporidium species occurring in sheep and goat breeds reared in Poland"/>
  <chunk id="534bc15ce844653ae863844b86d4ace2b98d42a3.c1" text="The aim of this study was molecular identification of Cryptosporidium species and assessment of their prevalence in different breeds of sheep and goat reared in Poland. In addition, the relationship between animal age, breed type, and the frequency of Cryptosporidium infections was determined. Fecal samples from 234 lambs and 105 goat kids aged up to 9 weeks, representing 24 breeds and their cross-breeds were collected from 71 small ruminant farms across Poland. The identification of Cryptosporidium species was performed at the 18 SSU ribosomal RNA (rRNA) and COWP loci followed by subtyping of C. parvum and C. hominis strains at GP60 gene locus. The presence of Cryptosporidium DNA at the 18 SSU rRNA locus was detected in 45/234 (19.2%) lamb feces samples and in 39/105 (37.1%) taken from goats. The following Cryptosporidium species: C. xiaoi, C. bovis, C. ubiquitum, C. parvum, and C. hominis were detected in small ruminants. Infections caused by C. xiaoi were predominant without favoring any tested animal species. Subsequent GP60 subtyping revealed the presence of C. parvum IIaA17G1R1 subtype in sheep and IIdA23G1 subtype in goats. IIdA23G1 subtype was detected in a goat host for the first time. There were no significant differences found in frequency of infections between the age groups (&lt;3 and 3-9 weeks) of lambs (P = 0.14, α &gt; 0.05) or goat kids (P = 0.06, α &gt; 0.05). In addition, there was no correlation observed between the frequency in occurrence of particular parasite species and breed type in relation to native sheep breeds (F = 0.11; P = 0.990 &gt; 0.05). In the case of goats, more breed-related differences in parasite occurrence were found. The results of this study improve our knowledge on the breedrelated occurrence of Cryptosporidium infections in the population of small ruminants reared in Poland.">
    <entity charOffset="239-248" id="534bc15ce844653ae863844b86d4ace2b98d42a3.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0040279" text="frequency" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="541-554" id="534bc15ce844653ae863844b86d4ace2b98d42a3.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005840" text="ribosomal RNA" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1261-1270" id="534bc15ce844653ae863844b86d4ace2b98d42a3.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0040279" text="frequency" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1451-1460" id="534bc15ce844653ae863844b86d4ace2b98d42a3.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0040279" text="frequency" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="534bc15ce844653ae863844b86d4ace2b98d42a3.c1.e0" e2="534bc15ce844653ae863844b86d4ace2b98d42a3.c1.e1" id="534bc15ce844653ae863844b86d4ace2b98d42a3.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="534bc15ce844653ae863844b86d4ace2b98d42a3.c1.e1" e2="534bc15ce844653ae863844b86d4ace2b98d42a3.c1.e2" id="534bc15ce844653ae863844b86d4ace2b98d42a3.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="534bc15ce844653ae863844b86d4ace2b98d42a3.c1.e1" e2="534bc15ce844653ae863844b86d4ace2b98d42a3.c1.e3" id="534bc15ce844653ae863844b86d4ace2b98d42a3.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
