<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="577c6a13f9ef70e9756890fc66e98f537c01ac0a">
  <chunk id="577c6a13f9ef70e9756890fc66e98f537c01ac0a.c0" text="Replication and shedding of MERS- CoV in Jamaican fruit bats (Artibeus jamaicensis) OPEN"/>
  <chunk id="577c6a13f9ef70e9756890fc66e98f537c01ac0a.c1" text="The emergence of Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus (MERS-CoV) highlights the zoonotic potential of Betacoronaviruses. Investigations into the origin of MERS-CoV have focused on two potential reservoirs: bats and camels. Here, we investigated the role of bats as a potential reservoir for MERS-CoV. In vitro, the MERS-CoV spike glycoprotein interacted with Jamaican fruit bat (Artibeus jamaicensis) dipeptidyl peptidase 4 (DPP4) receptor and MERS-CoV replicated efficiently in Jamaican fruit bat cells, suggesting there is no restriction at the receptor or cellular level for MERS-CoV. To shed light on the intrinsic host-virus relationship, we inoculated 10 Jamaican fruit bats with MERS-CoV. Although all bats showed evidence of infection, none of the bats showed clinical signs of disease. Virus shedding was detected in the respiratory and intestinal tract for up to 9 days. MERS-CoV replicated transiently in the respiratory and, to a lesser extent, the intestinal tracts and internal organs; with limited histopathological changes observed only in the lungs. Analysis of the innate gene expression in the lungs showed a moderate, transient induction of expression. Our results indicate that MERS-CoV maintains the ability to replicate in bats without clinical signs of disease, supporting the general hypothesis of bats as ancestral reservoirs for MERS-CoV.">
    <entity charOffset="1098-1113" id="577c6a13f9ef70e9756890fc66e98f537c01ac0a.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0010467" text="gene expression" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1146-1155" id="577c6a13f9ef70e9756890fc66e98f537c01ac0a.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0025153" text="transient" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="577c6a13f9ef70e9756890fc66e98f537c01ac0a.c1.e0" e2="577c6a13f9ef70e9756890fc66e98f537c01ac0a.c1.e1" id="577c6a13f9ef70e9756890fc66e98f537c01ac0a.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="577c6a13f9ef70e9756890fc66e98f537c01ac0a.c2" text="In 2012 a novel coronavirus, Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus (MERS-CoV), was isolated from a patient with a fatal case of pneumonia and renal failure in the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia 1 . Since then, more than 1600 human cases of MERS-CoV have been reported with a case-fatality rate of ~30% 2 . MERS-CoV cases were initially largely confined to six countries on the Arabian Peninsula: Jordan, Qatar, United Arab Emirates, Oman, Kuwait, and the majority of cases have been detected in the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia 2 . Travel-related cases have been identified in Europe, Asia, Africa and North America 3 . The recent outbreak caused by a single imported case in South Korea highlights the potential of MERS-CoV to cause large outbreaks when appropriate infection control measures are lacking in health care settings 3,4 .">
    <entity charOffset="135-144" id="577c6a13f9ef70e9756890fc66e98f537c01ac0a.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="149-162" id="577c6a13f9ef70e9756890fc66e98f537c01ac0a.c2.e1" ontology_id="HP_0000083" text="renal failure" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="577c6a13f9ef70e9756890fc66e98f537c01ac0a.c3" text="MERS-CoV is classified within the group C Betacoronaviruses 4,5 . Since the emergence of MERS-CoV, considerable effort has been expended to identify potential natural and intermediate reservoir hosts. A variety of closely related coronavirus sequences have been obtained from numerous bat species in Africa, Asia, the Americas and Eurasia 6-19 , suggesting widespread distribution of MERS-CoV related viruses among bat species belonging to the order Chiroptera. A 190 nucleotide RNA fragment with 100% match to the RNA dependent RNA polymerase (RdRp) of MERS-CoV was detected in a fecal sample of an Egyptian tomb bat (Taphozous perforates) roosting in the vicinity of a MERS-CoV index case in Bisha, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia 20 . In addition, the detection of MERS-CoV-specific antibodies in dromedary camels in the Middle East and northern and eastern Africa suggest the widespread circulation of MERS-CoV-like viruses in dromedary camels 21-27 . MERS-CoV infection of dromedary camels was detected by qRT-PCR and virus isolation in the Kingdom">
    <entity charOffset="545-549" id="577c6a13f9ef70e9756890fc66e98f537c01ac0a.c3.e0" ontology_id="GO_0003968" text="RdRp" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
