<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="59cee2c2d1c8e2b5c732523f10682153c278395c">
  <chunk id="59cee2c2d1c8e2b5c732523f10682153c278395c.c0" text="mRNA-Mediated Duplexes Play Dual Roles in the Regulation of Bidirectional Ribosomal Frameshifting">
    <entity charOffset="74-97" id="59cee2c2d1c8e2b5c732523f10682153c278395c.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0075523" text="Ribosomal Frameshifting" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="59cee2c2d1c8e2b5c732523f10682153c278395c.c1" text="In contrast to −1 programmed ribosomal frameshifting (PRF) stimulation by an RNA pseudoknot downstream of frameshifting sites, a refolding upstream RNA hairpin juxtaposing the frameshifting sites attenuates −1 PRF in human cells and stimulates +1 frameshifting in yeast. This eukaryotic functional mimicry of the internal Shine-Dalgarno (SD) sequence-mediated duplex was confirmed directly in the 70S translation system, indicating that both frameshifting regulation activities of upstream hairpin are conserved between 70S and 80S ribosomes. Unexpectedly, a downstream pseudoknot also possessed two opposing hungry codon-mediated frameshifting regulation activities: attenuation of +1 frameshifting and stimulation of a non-canonical −1 frameshifting within the +1 frameshift-prone CUUUGA frameshifting site in the absence of release factor 2 (RF2) in vitro. However, the −1 frameshifting activity of the downstream pseudoknot is not coupled with its +1 frameshifting attenuation ability. Similarly, the +1 frameshifting activity of the upstream hairpin is not required for its −1 frameshifting attenuation function Thus, each of the mRNA duplexes flanking the two ends of a ribosomal mRNA-binding channel possesses two functions in bi-directional ribosomal frameshifting regulation: frameshifting stimulation and counteracting the frameshifting activity of each other.">
    <entity charOffset="29-52" id="59cee2c2d1c8e2b5c732523f10682153c278395c.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0075523" text="ribosomal frameshifting" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="401-412" id="59cee2c2d1c8e2b5c732523f10682153c278395c.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0006412" text="translation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1249-1272" id="59cee2c2d1c8e2b5c732523f10682153c278395c.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0075523" text="ribosomal frameshifting" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
