<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="59f96c4166966aa929450a859c3d3fb2b6058c50">
  <chunk id="59f96c4166966aa929450a859c3d3fb2b6058c50.c0" text="Genotyping of human rhinovirus in adult patients with acute respiratory infections identified predominant infections of genotype A21 OPEN">
    <entity charOffset="54-59" id="59f96c4166966aa929450a859c3d3fb2b6058c50.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="60-82" id="59f96c4166966aa929450a859c3d3fb2b6058c50.c0.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011947" text="respiratory infections" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="59f96c4166966aa929450a859c3d3fb2b6058c50.c1" text="The roles of specific HRV genotypes in patients suffering from ARTIs have not been well established. We recruited 147 adult inpatients with community-acquired pneumonia (CAP) and 291 adult outpatients with upper ARTIs (URTIs). Respiratory pathogens were screened via PCR assays. HRV was detected in 42 patients, with 35 species A, five B and two C. Seventeen genotypes were identified, and HRV-A21 ranked the highest (9/42, 21.4%). The HRV-A21-positive infections were detected in four patients with CAP and in five with URTIs, all without co-infections. The HRV-A21 genome sequenced in this study contained 12 novel coding polymorphisms in viral protein (VP) 1, VP2 EF loop, VP3 knob and 3D regions. The infections of HRV-A21 virus obtained in this study could not be neutralized by antiserum of HRV-A21 prototype strain (VR-1131), indicating remarkable antigenic variation. Metagenomic analysis showed the HRV-A21 reads were dominant in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid of the three HRV-A21positive patients with severe CAP, in which two dead. Our results highlight an unexpected infection of genotype HRV-A21 in the clinic, indicating the necessity of precise genotyping and surveillance of HRVs to improve the clinical management of ARTIs.">
    <entity charOffset="159-168" id="59f96c4166966aa929450a859c3d3fb2b6058c50.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1011-1017" id="59f96c4166966aa929450a859c3d3fb2b6058c50.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
