<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="5a6330a739f18fd6bc502bd9b59de55e8c081d4e">
  <chunk id="5a6330a739f18fd6bc502bd9b59de55e8c081d4e.c0" text="ESICM LIVES 2016: part one Oral Sessions. ARDS: CLINICAL STUDIES A1 Identification of distinct endophenotypes in patients with acute respiratory distress syndrome by unbiased cluster analysis, and their association with mortality">
    <entity charOffset="127-132" id="5a6330a739f18fd6bc502bd9b59de55e8c081d4e.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="133-153" id="5a6330a739f18fd6bc502bd9b59de55e8c081d4e.c0.e1" ontology_id="HP_0002098" text="respiratory distress" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="5a6330a739f18fd6bc502bd9b59de55e8c081d4e.c1" text="Intensive Care Medicine Experimental 2016, 4(Suppl 1):A1"/>
  <chunk id="5a6330a739f18fd6bc502bd9b59de55e8c081d4e.c2" text="Introduction: Pharmacological immunomodulatory interventions in 'acute respiratory distress syndrome' (ARDS) have been unsuccessful in clinical trials [1-3] despite promising results in preclinical studies using animals [4][5]. Poor phenotyping of patients could be responsible for these disappointing results. Objectives: We hypothesized that ARDS patients can be clustered based on concentrations of plasma biomarkers and that such biological endophenotypes are association with clinical outcomes. Methods: Patients were screened for presence of ARDS. Unbiased cluster analysis of plasma concentrations of 20 biomarkers of inflammation, coagulation and endothelial activation at diagnosis of ARDS provided the endophenotypes. A decision tree was then used to predict cluster membership based on a more restricted set of biomarkers. The independent association of endophenotypes with ICU mortality was studied by multivariate logistic regression. Results: Three endophenotypes of ARDS were identified in 771 patients, which we named 'impassive' (N = 383), 'intermediate' (N = 224) and 'reactive' (N = 164), had mortality rates of 16 %, 26 % and 47 %, respectively (P &lt; 0.01). Patients with a 'reactive' endophenotype were younger, had higher disease severity scores, more failing organs and more frequently had an indirect cause for ARDS than patients with an 'impassive' or 'intermediate' endophenotype. A 'reactive endophenotype' was independent from confounders associated with ICU mortality (OR 1.18 [95 % confidence interval: 1.09-1.28]). The concentration of interleukin 10, interleukin 8 and matrix metalloproteinase 8 were sufficient to predict the three endophenotypes. Conclusions: ARDS patients can be clustered into three biological endophenotypes, with different mortality rates. Three easy to measure biomarkers can be used to predict the endophenotype.">
    <entity charOffset="71-91" id="5a6330a739f18fd6bc502bd9b59de55e8c081d4e.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002098" text="respiratory distress" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="639-650" id="5a6330a739f18fd6bc502bd9b59de55e8c081d4e.c2.e1" ontology_id="GO_0050817" text="coagulation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1251-1259" id="5a6330a739f18fd6bc502bd9b59de55e8c081d4e.c2.e2" ontology_id="HP_0012824" text="severity" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="5a6330a739f18fd6bc502bd9b59de55e8c081d4e.c2.e0" e2="5a6330a739f18fd6bc502bd9b59de55e8c081d4e.c2.e1" id="5a6330a739f18fd6bc502bd9b59de55e8c081d4e.c2.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5a6330a739f18fd6bc502bd9b59de55e8c081d4e.c2.e1" e2="5a6330a739f18fd6bc502bd9b59de55e8c081d4e.c2.e2" id="5a6330a739f18fd6bc502bd9b59de55e8c081d4e.c2.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
