<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="5ae438eff01ac41a451ff26064c3346805d1c1dc">
  <chunk id="5ae438eff01ac41a451ff26064c3346805d1c1dc.c0" text="Respiratory DNA viruses are undetectable in nasopharyngeal secretions from adenotonsillectomized children"/>
  <chunk id="5ae438eff01ac41a451ff26064c3346805d1c1dc.c1" text="Respiratory viruses are frequently detected in association with chronic tonsillar hypertrophy in the absence of symptoms of acute respiratory infection (ARI). The present analysis was done in follow-up to a previous clinical study done by this same group. Nasopharyngeal washes (NPWs) were obtained from 83 of 120 individuals at variable times post adenotonsillectomy, in the absence of ARI symptoms. A look back at virus detection results in NPWs from the same 83 individuals at the time of tonsillectomy revealed that 73.5% (61/83) were positive for one or more viruses. The overall frequency of respiratory virus detection in posttonsillectomy NPWs was 58.8%. Rhinovirus (RV) was the agent most frequently detected, in 38 of 83 subjects (45.8%), followed by enterovirus in 7 (8.4%), human metapneumovirus in 6 (7.2%), human respiratory syncytial virus in 3 (3.6%) and human coronavirus in 1 (1.2%). Remarkably, there was no detection of adenovirus (HAdV) or human bocavirus (HBoV) in asymptomatic individuals in follow-up of adenotonsillectomy. In keeping with persistence of respiratory DNA viruses in human tonsils, tonsillectomy significantly reduces asymptomatic shedding of HAdV and HBoV in NPWs.">
    <entity charOffset="64-71" id="5ae438eff01ac41a451ff26064c3346805d1c1dc.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011010" text="chronic" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="72-93" id="5ae438eff01ac41a451ff26064c3346805d1c1dc.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0030812" text="tonsillar hypertrophy" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="124-129" id="5ae438eff01ac41a451ff26064c3346805d1c1dc.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="130-151" id="5ae438eff01ac41a451ff26064c3346805d1c1dc.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0011947" text="respiratory infection" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="585-594" id="5ae438eff01ac41a451ff26064c3346805d1c1dc.c1.e4" ontology_id="HP_0040279" text="frequency" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
