<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1">
  <chunk id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c0" text="Open Peer Review Targeting viral entry as a strategy for broad-spectrum antivirals [version 1; peer review: 3 approved] v1"/>
  <chunk id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c1" text="F1000 Faculty Reviews are written by members of the prestigious . They are F1000 Faculty commissioned and are peer reviewed before publication to ensure that the final, published version is comprehensive and accessible. The reviewers who approved the final version are listed with their names and affiliations."/>
  <chunk id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c2" text="The process of entry into a host cell is a key step in the life cycle of most viruses. In recent years, there has been a significant increase in our understanding of the routes and mechanisms of entry for a number of these viruses. This has led to the development of novel broad-spectrum antiviral approaches that target host cell proteins and pathways, in addition to strategies focused on individual viruses or virus families. Here we consider a number of these approaches and their broad-spectrum potential. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 2. Mercer J, Schelhaas M, Helenius A: Virus entry by endocytosis. Annu Rev Biochem. 2010; 79: 803-33. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 3. Sánchez-San Martín C, Liu CY, Kielian M: Dealing with low pH: entry and exit of alphaviruses and flaviviruses. Trends Microbiol. 2009; 17(11): 514-21. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 4. Mercer J, Helenius A: Vaccinia virus uses macropinocytosis and apoptotic mimicry to enter host cells. Science. 2008; 320(5875): 531-5. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | F1000 Recommendation 5. Moller-Tank S, Maury W: Ebola virus entry: a curious and complex series of events. PLoS Pathog. 2015; 11(4): e100473. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 6. Saeed MF, Kolokoltsov AA, Albrecht T, et al.: Cellular entry of ebola virus involves uptake by a macropinocytosis-like mechanism and subsequent trafficking through early and late endosomes. PLoS Pathog. 2010; 6(9): e1001110. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 7. WuDunn D, Spear PG: Initial interaction of herpes simplex virus with cells is binding to heparan sulfate. J Virol. 1989; 63(1): 52-8. PubMed Abstract | Free Full Text 8. Giroglou T, Florin L, Schäfer F, et al.: Human papillomavirus infection requires cell surface heparan sulfate. J Virol. 2001; 75(3): 1565-70. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 9. Feldman SA, Hendry RM, Beeler JA: Identification of a linear heparin binding domain for human respiratory syncytial virus attachment glycoprotein G. J Virol. 1999; 73(8): 6610-7. PubMed Abstract | Free Full Text 10. Klimyte EM, Smith SE, Oreste P, et al.: Inhibition of Human Metapneumovirus Binding to Heparan Sulfate Blocks Infection in Human Lung Cells and Airway Tissues. J Virol. 2016; 90(20): 9237-50. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 11. Collett MS, Hincks JR, Benschop K, et al.: Antiviral Activity of Pocapavir in a Randomized, Blinded, Placebo-Controlled Human Oral Poliovirus Vaccine Challenge Model. J Infect Dis. 2017; 215(3): 335-343.">
    <entity charOffset="28-37" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0043657" text="host cell" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="321-330" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c2.e1" ontology_id="GO_0043657" text="host cell" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="943-959" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c2.e2" ontology_id="GO_0044351" text="macropinocytosis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1637-1644" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c2.e3" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1810-1822" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c2.e4" ontology_id="GO_0009986" text="cell surface" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1990-2005" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c2.e5" ontology_id="GO_0008201" text="heparin binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1998-2005" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c2.e6" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="2221-2228" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c2.e7" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="Binding" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3" text="PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 12. Ghosh T, Chattopadhyay K, Marschall M, et al.: Focus on antivirally active sulfated polysaccharides: from structure-activity analysis to clinical evaluation. Glycobiology. 2009; 19(1): 2-15. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 13. Lee E, Pavy M, Young N, et al.: Antiviral effect of the heparan sulfate mimetic, PI-88, against dengue and encephalitic flaviviruses. Antiviral Res. 2006; 69(1): 31-8. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 14. Cagno V, Andreozzi P, D'Alicarnasso M, et al.: Broad-spectrum non-toxic antiviral nanoparticles with a virucidal inhibition mechanism. Nat Mater. 2018; 17(2): 195-203. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | F1000 Recommendation 15. Botos I, Wlodawer A: Cyanovirin-N: a sugar-binding antiviral protein with a new twist. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2003; 60(2): 277-87. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 16. Barrientos LG, O'Keefe BR, Bray M, et al.: Cyanovirin-N binds to the viral surface glycoprotein, GP 1,2 and inhibits infectivity of Ebola virus. Antiviral Res. 2003; 58(1): 47-56. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 17. Zhou Y, Simmons G: Development of novel entry inhibitors targeting emerging viruses. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2012; 10(10): 1129-38. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 18. Carette JE, Raaben M, Wong AC, et al.: Ebola virus entry requires the cholesterol transporter Niemann-Pick C1. Nature. 2011; 477(7364): 340-3. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text | F1000 Recommendation 19. Malakhov MP, Aschenbrenner LM, Smee DF, et al.: Sialidase fusion protein as a novel broad-spectrum inhibitor of influenza virus infection. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2006; 50(4): 1470-9. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 20. Moss RB, Hansen C, Sanders RL, et al.: A phase II study of DAS181, a novel host directed antiviral for the treatment of influenza infection. J Infect Dis. 2012; 206(12): 1844-51. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text | F1000 Recommendation 21. Li F, Ma C, Wang J: Inhibitors targeting the influenza virus hemagglutinin. Curr Med Chem. 2015; 22(11): 1361-82. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 22. MacArthur RD, Novak RM: Reviews of anti-infective agents: maraviroc: the first of a new class of antiretroviral agents. Clin Infect Dis. 2008; 47(2): 236-41. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 23. Dorr P, Westby M, Dobbs S, et al.: Maraviroc (UK-427,857), a potent, orally bioavailable, and selective small-molecule inhibitor of chemokine receptor CCR5 with broad-spectrum anti-human immunodeficiency virus type 1 activity. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2005; 49(11): 4721-32. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 24. Pastore C, Ramos A, Mosier DE: Intrinsic obstacles to human immunodeficiency virus type 1 coreceptor switching. J Virol. 2004; 78(14): 7565-74. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 25. Vermeire K, Bell TW, van Puyenbroeck V, et al.: Signal peptide-binding drug as a selective inhibitor of co-translational protein translocation. PLoS Biol. 2014; 12(12): e1002011. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 26. van Dongen MJP, Kadam RU, Juraszek J, et al.: A small-molecule fusion inhibitor of influenza virus is orally active in mice. Science. 2019; 363(641): pii: eaar6221. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text | F1000 Recommendation 27. Jae LT, Raaben M, Herbert AS, et al.: Virus entry. Lassa virus entry requires a trigger-induced receptor switch. Science. 2014; 344(6191): 1506-10. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 28. Wec AZ, Nyakatura EK, Herbert AS, et al.: A &quot;Trojan horse&quot; bispecificantibody strategy for broad protection against ebolaviruses. Science. 2016; 354(6310): 350-4. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text | F1000 Recommendation 29. Fabozzi G, Pegu A, Koup RA, et al.: Bispecific antibodies: Potential immunotherapies for HIV treatment. Methods. 2019; 154: 118-24. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 30. Côté M, Misasi J, Ren T, et al.: Small molecule inhibitors reveal Niemann-Pick C1 is essential for Ebola virus infection. Nature. 2011; 477(7364): 344-8. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text | F1000 Recommendation 31. Buontempo PJ, Cox S, Wright-Minogue J, et al.: SCH 48973: a potent, broadspectrum, antienterovirus compound. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 1997; 41(6): 1220-5. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 32. Torres-Torres S, Myers AL, Klatte JM, et al.: First use of investigational antiviral drug pocapavir (v-073) for treating neonatal enteroviral sepsis. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2015; 34(1): 52-4. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 33. Smith TJ, Kremer MJ, Luo M, et al.: The site of attachment in human rhinovirus 14 for antiviral agents that inhibit uncoating. Science. 1986; 233(4770): 1286-93. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 34. Abdelnabi R, Geraets JA, Ma Y, et al.: A novel druggable interprotomer pocket in the capsid of rhino-and enteroviruses. PLoS Biol. 2019; 17(6): e3000281. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text | F1000 Recommendation 35. Sun L, Lee H, Thibaut HJ, et al.: Viral engagement with host receptors blocked by a novel class of tryptophan dendrimers that targets the 5-fold-axis of the enterovirus-A71 capsid. PLoS Pathog. 2019; 15(5): e1007760. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text | F1000 Recommendation 36. Diehl N, Schaal H: Make yourself at home: viral hijacking of the PI3K/Akt signaling pathway. Viruses. 2013; 5(12): 3192-212. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 37. Mazzon M, Castro C, Thaa B, et al.: Alphavirus-induced hyperactivation of PI3K/ AKT directs pro-viral metabolic changes. PLoS Pathog. 2018; 14(1): e1006835. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 38. Mercer J, Knébel S, Schmidt FI, et al.: Vaccinia virus strains use distinct forms of macropinocytosis for host-cell entry. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2010; 107(20): 9346-51. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 39. Dutta D, Williamson CD, Cole NB, et al.: Pitstop 2 is a potent inhibitor of clathrinindependent endocytosis. PLoS One. 2012; 7(9): e45799. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 40. Macia E, Ehrlich M, Massol R, et al.: Dynasore, a cell-permeable inhibitor of dynamin. Dev Cell. 2006; 10(6): 839-50. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | F1000 Recommendation 41. McCluskey A, Daniel JA, Hadzic G, et al.: Building a better dynasore: the dyngo compounds potently inhibit dynamin and endocytosis. Traffic. 2013; 14(12): 1272-89. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 42. Harper CB, Martin S, Nguyen TH, et al.: Dynamin inhibition blocks botulinum neurotoxin type A endocytosis in neurons and delays botulism. J Biol Chem. 2011; 286(41): 35966-76. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text | F1000 Recommendation 43. de Wilde AH, Jochmans D, Posthuma CC, et al.: Screening of an FDA-approved compound library identifies four small-molecule inhibitors of Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus replication in cell culture. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2014; 58(8): 4875-84. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 44. Blaising J, Lévy PL, Polyak SJ, et al.: Arbidol inhibits viral entry by interfering PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 45. Mazzon M, Ortega-Prieto AM, Imrie D, et al.: Identification of Broad-Spectrum Antiviral Compounds by Targeting Viral Entry. Viruses. 2019; 11(2): pii: E176. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 46. Banbury DN, Oakley JD, Sessions RB, et al.: Tyrphostin A23 inhibits internalization of the transferrin receptor by perturbing the interaction between tyrosine motifs and the medium chain subunit of the AP-2 adaptor complex. J Biol Chem. 2003; 278(14): 12022-8. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 47. Dejonghe W, Kuenen S, Mylle E, et al.: Mitochondrial uncouplers inhibit clathrinmediated endocytosis largely through cytoplasmic acidification. Nat Commun. 2016; 7: 11710. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 48. Jurgeit A, McDowell R, Moese S, et al.: Niclosamide is a proton carrier and targets acidic endosomes with broad antiviral effects. PLoS Pathog. 2012; 8(10): e1002976. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 49. HAYES WJ, LAWS JR: Classes of pesticides. In: LAWS H. (ed.) Handbook of Pesticide Toxicology. New york, NY: Academic press. 1991. Publisher Full Text 50. Doms RW, Moore JP: HIV-1 membrane fusion: targets of opportunity. J Cell Biol. 2000; 151(2): F9-14. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 51. Kaufmann SHE, Dorhoi A, Hotchkiss RS, et al.: Host-directed therapies for bacterial and viral infections. Nat Rev Drug Discov. 2018; 17(1): 35-56. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 52. Savarino A, Boelaert JR, Cassone A, et al.: Effects of chloroquine on viral infections: an old drug against today's diseases? Lancet Infect Dis. 2003; 3(11): 722-7.">
    <entity charOffset="2599-2615" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002721" text="immunodeficiency" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="2810-2826" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e1" ontology_id="HP_0002721" text="immunodeficiency" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="5581-5590" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e2" ontology_id="GO_0023052" text="signaling" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="5992-6008" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e3" ontology_id="GO_0044351" text="macropinocytosis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="6235-6246" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e4" ontology_id="GO_0006897" text="endocytosis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="6639-6650" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e5" ontology_id="GO_0006897" text="endocytosis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="6837-6848" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e6" ontology_id="GO_0006897" text="endocytosis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="7866-7886" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e7" ontology_id="GO_0030122" text="AP-2 adaptor complex" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="8006-8019" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e8" ontology_id="HP_0001427" text="Mitochondrial" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="8056-8067" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e9" ontology_id="GO_0006897" text="endocytosis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="8262-8269" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e10" ontology_id="GO_0005215" text="carrier" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="8603-8611" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e11" ontology_id="GO_0016020" text="membrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e0" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e2" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e0" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e3" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e0" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e4" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e0" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e5" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e0" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e6" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e0" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e7" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p5" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e0" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e9" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p6" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e0" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e10" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p7" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e0" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e11" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p8" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e1" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e2" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p9" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e1" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e3" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p10" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e1" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e4" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p11" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e1" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e5" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p12" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e1" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e6" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p13" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e1" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e7" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p14" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e1" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e9" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p15" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e1" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e10" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p16" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e1" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e11" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p17" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e2" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e8" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p18" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e3" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e8" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p19" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e4" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e8" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p20" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e5" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e8" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p21" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e6" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e8" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p22" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e7" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e8" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p23" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e8" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e9" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p24" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e8" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e10" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p25" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e8" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.e11" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c3.p26" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4" text="PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 53. Long J, Wright E, Molesti E, et al.: Antiviral therapies against Ebola and other emerging viral diseases using existing medicines that block virus entry [version 2; peer review: 2 approved]. F1000Res. 2015; 4: 30. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 54. Nicholson KG, Wiselka MJ: Amantadine for influenza A. BMJ. 1991; 302(6774): 425-6. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 55. Monto AS, Arden NH: Implications of Viral Resistance to Amantadine in Control of Influenza A. Clin Infect Dis. 1992; 15(2): 362-7. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 56. Schornberg K, Matsuyama S, Kabsch K, et al.: Role of endosomal cathepsins in entry mediated by the Ebola virus glycoprotein. J Virol. 2006; 80(8): 4174-8. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 57. Sakurai Y, Kolokoltsov AA, Chen CC, et al.: Ebola virus. Two-pore channels control Ebola virus host cell entry and are drug targets for disease treatment. Science. 2015; 347(6225): 995-8. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text | F1000 Recommendation 58. Xiao JH, Rijal P, Schimanski L, et al.: Characterization of Influenza Virus Pseudotyped with Ebolavirus Glycoprotein. J Virol. 2018; 92(4): pii: e00941-17. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 59. Penny CJ, Vassileva K, Jha A, et al.: Mining of Ebola virus entry inhibitors identifies approved drugs as two-pore channel pore blockers. Biochim Biophys Acta Mol Cell Res. 2019; 1866(7): 1151-1161. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 78. Han Y, Mesplède T, Xu H, et al.: The antimalarial drug amodiaquine possesses anti-ZIKA virus activities J Med Virol. 2018; 90(5): 796-802. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 79. Vigant F, Lee J, Hollmann A, et al.: A Mechanistic Paradigm for Broad-Spectrum Antivirals that Target Virus-Cell Fusion. PLoS Pathog. 2013; 9(4): e1003297. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text | F1000 Recommendation 80. Wolf MC, Freiberg AN, Zhang T, et al.: A broad-spectrum antiviral targeting entry of enveloped viruses. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2010; 107(7): 3157-62. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text | F1000 Recommendation 81. Zhu JD, Meng W, Wang XJ, et al.: Broad-spectrum antiviral agents. Front Microbiol. 2015; 6: 517. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 82. Lu DY, Wu HY, Yarla NS, et al.: HAART in HIV/AIDS Treatments: Future Trends. Infect Disord Drug Targets. 2018; 18(1): 15-22. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | F1000 Recommendation 83. Ford N, Shubber Z, Calmy A, et al.: Choice of Antiretroviral Drugs for Postexposure Prophylaxis for Adults and Adolescents: A Systematic Review. Clin Infect Dis. 2015; 60 Suppl 3: S170-S176. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 84. Kirby BJ, Symonds WT, Kearney BP, et al.: Pharmacokinetic, Pharmacodynamic, and Drug-Interaction Profile of the Hepatitis C Virus NS5B Polymerase Inhibitor Sofosbuvir. Clin Pharmacokinet. 2015; 54(7): 677-90. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 85. Bekerman E, Einav S: Infectious disease. Combating emerging viral threats. Science. 2015; 348(6232): 282-3. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 86. Cross RW, Mire CE, Feldmann H, et al.: Post-exposure treatments for Ebola and Marburg virus infections. Nat Rev Drug Discov. 2018; 17: 413-34. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 87. de La Vega MA, Caleo G, Audet J, et al.: Ebola viral load at diagnosis associates with patient outcome and outbreak evolution. J Clin Invest. 2015; 125(12): 4421-8. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 88. Thi EP, Lee ACH, Geisbert JB, et al.: Rescue of non-human primates from advanced Sudan ebolavirus infection with lipid encapsulated siRNA. Nat Microbiol. 2016; 1(10): 16142. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text | F1000 Recommendation 89. Vaughn DW, Green S, Kalayanarooj S, et al.: Dengue Viremia Titer, Antibody Response Pattern, and Virus Serotype Correlate with Disease Severity. J Infect Dis. 2000; 181(1): 2-9. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 90. Dwek RA, Butters TD, Platt FM, et al.: Targeting glycosylation as a therapeutic approach. Nat Rev Drug Discov. 2002; 1(1): 65-75. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text">
    <entity charOffset="939-948" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e0" ontology_id="GO_0043657" text="host cell" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1452-1456" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e1" ontology_id="GO_0046930" text="pore" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="2915-2924" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e2" ontology_id="HP_0012115" text="Hepatitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="3937-3944" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e3" ontology_id="HP_0020071" text="Viremia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="3952-3960" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e4" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="Antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="3952-3960" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e5" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="Antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="4155-4168" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e6" ontology_id="GO_0070085" text="glycosylation" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e0" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e2" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e0" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e3" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e1" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e2" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e1" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e3" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e2" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e4" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e2" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e5" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.p5" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e2" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e6" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.p6" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e3" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e4" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.p7" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e3" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e5" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.p8" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e3" e2="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.e6" id="5aebac2302d94acc406291d65cc7c538ab71dae1.c4.p9" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
