<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="5e77269850b7b4bf57514e226ea66cd48ac31db5">
  <chunk id="5e77269850b7b4bf57514e226ea66cd48ac31db5.c0" text="Profiling of Glycan Receptors for Minute Virus of Mice in Permissive Cell Lines Towards Understanding the Mechanism of Cell Recognition">
    <entity charOffset="119-135" id="5e77269850b7b4bf57514e226ea66cd48ac31db5.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0008037" text="Cell Recognition" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="5e77269850b7b4bf57514e226ea66cd48ac31db5.c1" text="The recognition of sialic acids by two strains of minute virus of mice (MVM), MVMp (prototype) and MVMi (immunosuppressive), is an essential requirement for successful infection. To understand the potential for recognition of different modifications of sialic acid by MVM, three types of capsids, virus-like particles, wild type empty (no DNA) capsids, and DNA packaged virions, were screened on a sialylated glycan microarray (SGM). Both viruses demonstrated a preference for binding to 9-O-methylated sialic acid derivatives, while MVMp showed additional binding to 9-O-acetylated and 9-Olactoylated sialic acid derivatives, indicating recognition differences. The glycans recognized contained a type-2 Galb1-4GlcNAc motif (Neu5Aca2-3Galb1-4GlcNAc or 39SIA-LN) and were biantennary complex-type N-glycans with the exception of one. To correlate the recognition of the 39SIA-LN glycan motif as well as the biantennary structures to their natural expression in cell lines permissive for MVMp, MVMi, or both strains, the N-and O-glycans, and polar glycolipids present in three cell lines used for in vitro studies, A9 fibroblasts, EL4 T lymphocytes, and the SV40 transformed NB324K cells, were analyzed by MALDI-TOF/TOF mass spectrometry. The cells showed an abundance of the sialylated glycan motifs recognized by the viruses in the SGM and previous glycan microarrays supporting their role in cellular recognition by MVM. Significantly, the NB324K showed fucosylation at the non-reducing end of their biantennary glycans, suggesting that recognition of these cells is possibly mediated by the Lewis X motif as in 39SIA-Le X identified in a previous glycan microarray screen.">
    <entity charOffset="477-484" id="5e77269850b7b4bf57514e226ea66cd48ac31db5.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="557-564" id="5e77269850b7b4bf57514e226ea66cd48ac31db5.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1456-1468" id="5e77269850b7b4bf57514e226ea66cd48ac31db5.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0036065" text="fucosylation" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
