<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="5eb1e53fb44c8a997713bd4fc55d65b904df3ce8">
  <chunk id="5eb1e53fb44c8a997713bd4fc55d65b904df3ce8.c0" text="Silver Sucrose Octasulfate (IASOS TM ) as a Valid Active Ingredient into a Novel Vaginal Gel against Human Vaginal Pathogens: In Vitro Antimicrobial Activity Assessment"/>
  <chunk id="5eb1e53fb44c8a997713bd4fc55d65b904df3ce8.c1" text="This in vitro study assessed the antimicrobial properties of a novel octasilver salt of Sucrose Octasulfate (IASOS) as well as of an innovative vaginal gel containing IASOS (SilSOS Femme), against bacterial and yeast pathogens isolated from human clinical cases of symptomatic vaginal infections. In BHI and LAPT culture media, different ionic silver concentrations and different pHs were tested. IASOS exerted a strong antimicrobial activity towards all the pathogens tested in both culture media. The results demonstrated that salts and organic compounds present in the culture media influenced IASOS efficacy only to a moderate extent. Whereas comparable MBCs (Minimal Bactericidal Concentrations) were observed for G. vaginalis (10 mg/L Ag + ), E. coli and E. aerogenes (25 mg/L Ag + ) in both media, higher MBCs were found for S. aureus and S. agalactiae in LAPT cultures (50 mg/L Ag + versus 25 mg/L Ag + ). No minimal concentration totally inhibiting the growth of C. albicans was found. Nevertheless, in both media at the highest ionic silver concentrations (50-200 mg/L Ag + ), a significant 34-52% drop in Candida growth was observed. pH differently affected the antimicrobial properties of IASOS against bacteria or yeasts; however, a stronger antimicrobial activity at pH higher than the physiological pH was generally observed. It can be therefore concluded that IASOS exerts a bactericidal action against all the tested bacteria and a clear fungistatic action against C. albicans. The antimicrobial activity of the whole vaginal gel SilSOS Femme further confirmed the antimicrobial activity of IASOS. Overall, our findings support IASOS as a valid active ingredient into a vaginal gel.">
    <entity charOffset="622-630" id="5eb1e53fb44c8a997713bd4fc55d65b904df3ce8.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012826" text="moderate" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="962-968" id="5eb1e53fb44c8a997713bd4fc55d65b904df3ce8.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0040007" text="growth" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1124-1130" id="5eb1e53fb44c8a997713bd4fc55d65b904df3ce8.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0040007" text="growth" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1160-1168" id="5eb1e53fb44c8a997713bd4fc55d65b904df3ce8.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0032320" text="affected" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="5eb1e53fb44c8a997713bd4fc55d65b904df3ce8.c1.e0" e2="5eb1e53fb44c8a997713bd4fc55d65b904df3ce8.c1.e1" id="5eb1e53fb44c8a997713bd4fc55d65b904df3ce8.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5eb1e53fb44c8a997713bd4fc55d65b904df3ce8.c1.e0" e2="5eb1e53fb44c8a997713bd4fc55d65b904df3ce8.c1.e2" id="5eb1e53fb44c8a997713bd4fc55d65b904df3ce8.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5eb1e53fb44c8a997713bd4fc55d65b904df3ce8.c1.e1" e2="5eb1e53fb44c8a997713bd4fc55d65b904df3ce8.c1.e3" id="5eb1e53fb44c8a997713bd4fc55d65b904df3ce8.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5eb1e53fb44c8a997713bd4fc55d65b904df3ce8.c1.e2" e2="5eb1e53fb44c8a997713bd4fc55d65b904df3ce8.c1.e3" id="5eb1e53fb44c8a997713bd4fc55d65b904df3ce8.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
