<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841">
  <chunk id="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c0" text="Test Paper for Colorimetric Inspection of Fatty Acids and Edible Oils"/>
  <chunk id="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c1" text="Fatty acids (FAs) are of interest to the areas of food science and medicine because they are important dietary sources of fuel for animals and play important roles in many biological processes. The health effects of FAs are different due to the diversity of olefinic bonds in the alkyl chains including number, position and configuration. However, the discrimination of FAs is difficult from a chemical sensing perspective due to the lack of diversity in terms of functional groups. Until now, only a few chemosensors have been developed for selective sensing of FAs based on their overall shape, however they are still limited in discrimination of FAs with subtle structural differences, moreover, they cannot be used for rapid and in situ inspections. Herein, for the first time, we designed a test paper for in situ colorimetric inspection for FAs based on the combination of the highly selective binding of Ag + to olefinic bonds and Ag + mediated color variation of 3,3 ,5,5 ,-tetramethylbenzidine. As a result, the sensor exhibited high sensitivity and good selectivity for five FAs with subtle structural differences. Furthermore, our method described herein was successfully applied to monitor the structural variations of FAs and quality changes in mixture edible hot pot oils with heat treatment in time course. Hence, the test paper presented herein holds great potential in the inspection of fats and edible oils in food industries. Therefore, the approaches to determine FAs profile in food industries are important in order to correct nutrition labeling and control of labeling authenticity, which is of great significance to the implementation of the plan of REPLACE.">
    <entity charOffset="311-319" id="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012830" text="position" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="900-907" id="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c1.e0" e2="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c1.e1" id="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c2" text="The structures of FAs are diversity, because the length (carbon number) and unsaturation degree (olefinic bond number) of alkyl chains, position and configuration (cis/trans) of the olefinic bond in FAs are different. The chemical discrimination of FAs is difficult, because they lack special functional groups other than the hydrophobic alkyl chain and carboxyl group. Currently, the most used methods for the determination of FAs are based on gas chromatography (GC) or liquid chromatography (LC) coupling with mass spectrometry (MS) analysis [9] [10] [11] . However, the GC/LC-MS techniques suffer from some drawbacks, such as being time-consuming, expensive, operationally complex and relying on sophisticated instrumentation that cannot be used for rapid and in situ analysis. Moreover, a variety of regio-and stereoisomers can exist for FAs, posing a challenge for MS based analyses. Chemosensors have been widely used in various fields because of their rapid, facile and convenient features, and these features just make up for the inadequacies of the GC/LC-MS related techniques. Until now, only a few colorimetric and fluorimetric chemosensors have been developed for selective sensing of FAs based on their overall shape [12, 13] . The main capability of these chemosensors is discrimination of mono-CUFAs (with bent alkyl chain) from mono-TUFAs and SFAs (with linear alkyl chains), but they do not show promise in differentiating poly-UFAs and SFAs. Therefore, a portable sensing method for in situ inspection of FAs with different degree of unsaturation, position of olefins, and the configuration of the olefins is urgent but difficult.">
    <entity charOffset="136-144" id="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012830" text="position" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="445-448" id="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c2.e1" ontology_id="GO_0034005" text="gas" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1567-1575" id="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c2.e2" ontology_id="HP_0012830" text="position" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c2.e0" e2="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c2.e1" id="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c2.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c2.e1" e2="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c2.e2" id="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c2.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c3" text="It is well known that silver ion (Ag + ) can complex with olefinic bonds reversibly [14] . The stabilities of Ag + -olefin complexes are highly dependent on the properties of olefins that can usually be divided into two groups, namely steric (chain length, cis/trans isomers and number of olefinic bonds) and electronic (conjugation and electron cloud density) properties [15] . Thus, Ag + chromatography has been widely used for the separation of unsaturated compounds with subtle structural differences such as FAs and sterols [16] [17] [18] [19] . However, a FAs sensor based on the selective complexation between Ag + and olefinic bonds has never been explored. Interestingly, the colorless 3,3 ,5,5 ,-tetramethylbenzidine (TMB) can be oxidized by Ag + and turn blue, and the color intensity is positively correlated with the concentration of Ag + [20] [21] [22] . When combining the highly selective binding ability of Ag + to olefinic bonds and Ag + mediated color variation of TMB, a colorimetric sensing method to inspection of FAs is possibly designed.">
    <entity charOffset="321-332" id="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c3.e0" ontology_id="GO_0000746" text="conjugation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="786-795" id="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c3.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012824" text="intensity" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="905-912" id="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c3.e2" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c3.e0" e2="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c3.e1" id="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c3.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c3.e1" e2="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c3.e2" id="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c3.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c4" text="Recently, test paper-based colorimetric sensors have been widely applicated in various fields such as disease diagnosis [23-26], environmental monitoring [27,28] and food safety inspection [29, 30] due to their simplicity, disposability, economical efficiency and minimal samples requirement [31] . More importantly, they are easier to use in in situ inspections. According to the principle of paper-based colorimetric sensing, some specific reagents are necessary to develop color intensity and/or hue correlates with types and concentration of analytes [32] . Herein, considering the Ag + mediated color variation of TMB and selective binding of Ag + with olefinic bonds, we propose a test paper for FAs inspection (Scheme 1). By mixing Ag + with FAs in a solution, a part of Ag + could form Ag + -FAs complexes and the remnant part is free Ag + ions. The free Ag + could further oxidize TMB and develop blue colors. The proportion of free Ag + is dependent on the concentration and type of FAs. Therefore, by taking advantage of the complexation difference of Ag + to olefinic bonds of FAs, we successfully identified five types of model FAs with subtle structural differences. Using the approach described herein, the structural variation of FAs with heat treatment can be successfully monitored. Furthermore, the quality changes of mixture FAs in edible hot pot oils with heat treatment were successfully monitored by the test paper presented herein.">
    <entity charOffset="482-491" id="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c4.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012824" text="intensity" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="637-644" id="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c4.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c4.e0" e2="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c4.e1" id="5ec99e67f23c0c2795fad1ad551ab1abe4406841.c4.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
