<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="5eeeb39d1eda252e3ba5fff3596679b8e3376f8d">
  <chunk id="5eeeb39d1eda252e3ba5fff3596679b8e3376f8d.c0" text="Access to"/>
  <chunk id="5eeeb39d1eda252e3ba5fff3596679b8e3376f8d.c1" text="Alzheimer's disease susceptibility genes, APP and gamma-secretase, are involved in the herpes simplex life cycle, and that of other suspect pathogens (C. pneumoniae, H. pylori, C. neoformans, B. burgdorferri, P. gingivalis) or immune defence. Such pathogens promote beta-amyloid deposition and tau phosphorylation and may thus be causative agents, whose effects are conditioned by genes. The antimicrobial effects of beta-amyloid, the localisation of APP/gamma-secretase in immunocompetent dendritic cells, and gamma secretase cleavage of numerous pathogen receptors suggest that this network is concerned with pathogen disposal, effects which may be abrogated by the presence of beta-amyloid autoantibodies in the elderly. These autoantibodies, as well as those to nerve growth factor and tau, also observed in Alzheimer's disease, may well be antibodies to pathogens, due to homology between human autoantigens and pathogen proteins. NGF or tau antibodies promote beta-amyloid deposition, neurofibrillary tangles, or cholinergic neuronal loss, and, with other autoantibodies, such as anti-ATPase, are potential agents of destruction, whose formation is dictated by sequence homology between pathogen and human proteins, and thus by pathogen strain and human genes. Pathogen elimination in the ageing population and removal of culpable autoantibodies might reduce the incidence and offer hope for a cure in this affliction. (NP 002497.2), or the microtubule protein, tau (NP 001116538.2) were identified using the BepiPred server http://www.cbs.dtu.dk/services/BepiPred/ [35] and their sequences compared with pathogen proteomes (Borrelia burgdorferi, C. neoformans, Helicobacter pylori, herpes viruses HSV-1, HSV-2, HHV-6, and the cytomegalovirus (HHV-5)) using the NCBI BLAST server (Protein versus protein: BlastP) [36] .">
    <entity charOffset="298-313" id="5eeeb39d1eda252e3ba5fff3596679b8e3376f8d.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0016310" text="phosphorylation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="435-447" id="5eeeb39d1eda252e3ba5fff3596679b8e3376f8d.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0051179" text="localisation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="772-778" id="5eeeb39d1eda252e3ba5fff3596679b8e3376f8d.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0040007" text="growth" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1295-1301" id="5eeeb39d1eda252e3ba5fff3596679b8e3376f8d.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0007568" text="ageing" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1447-1458" id="5eeeb39d1eda252e3ba5fff3596679b8e3376f8d.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0005874" text="microtubule" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
