<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="604491e627b3cb8661ee7f8747623eb4c61f0315">
  <chunk id="604491e627b3cb8661ee7f8747623eb4c61f0315.c0" text="Tropical Medicine and Infectious Disease A Case History in Cooperative Biological Research: Compendium of Studies and Program Analyses in Kazakhstan"/>
  <chunk id="604491e627b3cb8661ee7f8747623eb4c61f0315.c1" text="Kazakhstan and the United States have partnered since 2003 to counter the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction. The US Department of Defense (US DoD) has funded threat reduction programs to eliminate biological weapons, secure material in repositories that could be targeted for theft, and enhance surveillance systems to monitor infectious disease outbreaks that would affect national security. The cooperative biological research (CBR) program of the US DoD's Biological Threat Reduction Program has provided financing, mentorship, infrastructure, and biologic research support to Kazakhstani scientists and research institutes since 2005. The objective of this paper is to provide a historical perspective for the CBR involvement in Kazakhstan, including project chronology, successes and challenges to allow lessons learned to be applied to future CBR endeavors. A project compendium from open source data and interviews with partner country Kazakhstani participants, project collaborators, and stakeholders was developed utilizing studies from 2004 to the present. An earlier project map was used as a basis to determine project linkages and continuations during the evolution of the CBR program. It was determined that consistent and effective networking increases the chances to collaborate especially for competitive funding opportunities. Overall, the CBR program has increased scientific capabilities in Kazakhstan while reducing their risk of biological threats. However, there is still need for increased scientific transparency and an overall strategy to develop a capability-based model to better enhance and sustain future research. Finally, we offer a living perspective that can be applied to further link related studies especially those related to One Health and zoonoses and the assessment of similar capability-building programs. ME, Aikimbayev A. Analysing the spatial patterns of livestock anthrax in Kazakhstan in relation to environmental factors: a comparison of local (Gi*) and morphology cluster statistics. Geospatial Health. 2012;7(1):111-26. Mullins J, Lukhnova L, Aikimbayev A, Pazilov Y, Van Ert M, Blackburn JK. Ecological Niche Modelling of the Bacillus anthracis A1.a sub-lineage in Kazakhstan. BMC ecology. 2011 Dec;11(1):32. Joyner TA, Lukhnova L, Pazilov Y, Temiralyeva G, Hugh-Jones ME, Aikimbayev A, Blackburn JK. Modeling the potential distribution of Bacillus anthracis under multiple climate change scenarios for Kazakhstan. PloS one. 2010 Mar 9;5(3):e9596. Aikembayev AM, Lukhnova L, Temiraliyeva G, Meka-Mechenko T, Pazylov Y, Zakaryan S, Denissov G, Easterday WR, Van Ert MN, Keim P, Francesconi SC. Historical distribution and molecular diversity of Bacillus anthracis, Kazakhstan. Emerging Infectious Diseases. 2010 May;16(5):789. KZ-2 Brucellosis Mizanbayeva S, Smits HL, Zhalilova K, Abdoel TH, Kozakov S, Ospanov KS, Elzer PH, Douglas JT. The evaluation of a user-friendly lateral flow assay for the serodiagnosis of human brucellosis in Kazakhstan. Diagnostic microbiology and infectious disease. Nikolich, I. Sytnik. Exploring spatio-temporal shifts of human and livestock brucellosis using serological surveillance in Kazakhstan 2007-2008. Brucellosis Research Conference, Chicago, Illinois 4-6 December 2010. KZ-28 Multi-pathogen, zoonotic diseases: anthrax, plague, and tularemia Abstract: Sadovskaya, V.P., Atshabar, B.B., Kazakov, S.V., Burdelov, L.A., Zhumadilova, Z.B., Syzdykov, M.S., Blackburn, J.K. Employing GIS and spatial analysis to inform plague surveillance in Kazakhstan.">
    <entity charOffset="2933-2940" id="604491e627b3cb8661ee7f8747623eb4c61f0315.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0025275" text="lateral" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
