<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="6276adaeca8fcd42c9565718ac6bbdc4f97aa10f">
  <chunk id="6276adaeca8fcd42c9565718ac6bbdc4f97aa10f.c0" text="A single-dose ChAdOx1-vectored vaccine provides complete protection against Nipah Bangladesh and Malaysia in Syrian golden hamsters"/>
  <chunk id="6276adaeca8fcd42c9565718ac6bbdc4f97aa10f.c1" text="Nipah virus (NiV) is a highly pathogenic re-emerging virus that causes outbreaks in South East Asia. Currently, no approved and licensed vaccine or antivirals exist. Here, we investigated the efficacy of ChAdOx1 NiV B , a simian adenovirus-based vaccine encoding NiV glycoprotein (G) Bangladesh, in Syrian hamsters. Prime-only as well as prime-boost vaccination resulted in uniform protection against a lethal challenge with NiV Bangladesh: all animals survived challenge and we were unable to find infectious virus either in oral swabs, lung or brain tissue. Furthermore, no pathological lung damage was observed. A singledose of ChAdOx1 NiV B also prevented disease and lethality from heterologous challenge with NiV Malaysia. While we were unable to detect infectious virus in swabs or tissue of animals challenged with the heterologous strain, a very limited amount of viral RNA could be found in lung tissue by in situ hybridization. A single dose of ChAdOx1 NiV B also provided partial protection against Hendra virus and passive transfer of antibodies elicited by ChAd-Ox1 NiV B vaccination partially protected Syrian hamsters against NiV Bangladesh. From these data, we conclude that ChAdOx1 NiV B is a suitable candidate for further NiV vaccine pre-clinical development."/>
  <chunk id="6276adaeca8fcd42c9565718ac6bbdc4f97aa10f.c2" text="Nipah virus was discovered in 1998 after an outbreak in Malaysia. Since then, several outbreaks have been reported in Bangladesh and India. Although most outbreaks are relatively small, a very high case-fatality rate is reported (75%). Furthermore, human-to-PLOS Neglected Tropical Diseases | https://doi."/>
</document>
