<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="634b8c282afdd06201cb2531fb70985d92270271">
  <chunk id="634b8c282afdd06201cb2531fb70985d92270271.c0" text="In Situ Tagged nsp15 Reveals Interactions with Coronavirus Replication/Transcription Complex- Associated Proteins"/>
  <chunk id="634b8c282afdd06201cb2531fb70985d92270271.c1" text="Coronavirus (CoV) replication and transcription are carried out in close proximity to restructured endoplasmic reticulum (ER) membranes in replication/transcription complexes (RTC). Many of the CoV nonstructural proteins (nsps) are required for RTC function; however, not all of their functions are known. nsp15 contains an endoribonuclease domain that is conserved in the CoV family. While the enzymatic activity and crystal structure of nsp15 are well defined, its role in replication remains elusive. nsp15 localizes to sites of RNA replication, but whether it acts independently or requires additional interactions for its function remains unknown. To begin to address these questions, we created an in situ tagged form of nsp15 using the prototypic CoV, mouse hepatitis virus (MHV). In MHV, nsp15 contains the genomic RNA packaging signal (P/S), a 95-bp RNA stem-loop structure that is not required for viral replication or nsp15 function. Utilizing this knowledge, we constructed an internal hemagglutinin (HA) tag that replaced the P/S. We found that nsp15-HA was localized to discrete perinuclear puncta and strongly colocalized with nsp8 and nsp12, both welldefined members of the RTC, but not the membrane (M) protein, involved in virus assembly. Finally, we found that nsp15 interacted with RTC-associated proteins nsp8 and nsp12 during infection, and this interaction was RNA independent. From this, we conclude that nsp15 localizes and interacts with CoV proteins in the RTC, suggesting it plays a direct or indirect role in virus replication. Furthermore, the use of in situ epitope tags could be used to determine novel nsp-nsp interactions in coronaviruses.">
    <entity charOffset="99-120" id="634b8c282afdd06201cb2531fb70985d92270271.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0005783" text="endoplasmic reticulum" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="765-774" id="634b8c282afdd06201cb2531fb70985d92270271.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012115" text="hepatitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1071-1080" id="634b8c282afdd06201cb2531fb70985d92270271.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0012838" text="localized" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1207-1215" id="634b8c282afdd06201cb2531fb70985d92270271.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0016020" text="membrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="634b8c282afdd06201cb2531fb70985d92270271.c1.e0" e2="634b8c282afdd06201cb2531fb70985d92270271.c1.e1" id="634b8c282afdd06201cb2531fb70985d92270271.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="634b8c282afdd06201cb2531fb70985d92270271.c1.e0" e2="634b8c282afdd06201cb2531fb70985d92270271.c1.e2" id="634b8c282afdd06201cb2531fb70985d92270271.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="634b8c282afdd06201cb2531fb70985d92270271.c1.e1" e2="634b8c282afdd06201cb2531fb70985d92270271.c1.e3" id="634b8c282afdd06201cb2531fb70985d92270271.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="634b8c282afdd06201cb2531fb70985d92270271.c1.e2" e2="634b8c282afdd06201cb2531fb70985d92270271.c1.e3" id="634b8c282afdd06201cb2531fb70985d92270271.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="634b8c282afdd06201cb2531fb70985d92270271.c2" text="Citation Athmer J, Fehr AR, Grunewald M, Smith EC, Denison MR, Perlman S. 2017. In situ tagged nsp15 reveals interactions with coronavirus replication/transcription complexassociated proteins. mBio 8:e02320-16. https://"/>
</document>
