<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="68011fab7fc7a4d29797a161cb32d21ffd2a2ea7">
  <chunk id="68011fab7fc7a4d29797a161cb32d21ffd2a2ea7.c0" text="Prediction and Identification of T Cell Epitopes in the H5N1 Influenza Virus Nucleoprotein in Chicken"/>
  <chunk id="68011fab7fc7a4d29797a161cb32d21ffd2a2ea7.c1" text="T cell epitopes can be used for the accurate monitoring of avian influenza virus (AIV) immune responses and the rational design of vaccines. No T cell epitopes have been previously identified in the H5N1 AIV virus nucleoprotein (NP) in chickens. For the first time, this study used homology modelling techniques to construct three-dimensional structures of the peptidebinding domains of chicken MHC class I molecules for four commonly encountered unique haplotypes, i.e., B4, B12, B15, and B19. H5N1 AIV NP was computationally parsed into octapeptides or nonapeptides according to the peptide-binding motifs of MHC class I molecules of the B4, B12, B15 and B19 haplotypes. Seventy-five peptide sequences were modelled and their MHC class I molecule-binding abilities were analysed by molecular docking. Twenty-five peptides (Ten for B4, six for B12, two for B15, and seven for B19) were predicted to be potential T cell epitopes in chicken. Nine of these peptides and one unrelated peptide were manually synthesized and their T cell responses were tested in vitro. Spleen lymphocytes were collected from SPF chickens that had been immunised with a NP-expression plasmid, pCAGGS-NP, and they were stimulated using the synthesized peptides. The secretion of chicken IFN-c and the proliferation of CD8 + T cells were tested using an ELISA kit and flow cytometry, respectively. The significant secretion of chicken IFN-c and proliferation of CD8 + T lymphocytes increased by 13.7% and 11.9% were monitored in cells stimulated with peptides NP [89][90][91][92][93][94][95][96][97] , respectively. The results indicate that peptides NP 89-97 (PKKTGGPIY) and NP 198-206 (KRGINDRNF) are NP T cell epitopes in chicken of certain haplotypes. The method used in this investigation is applicable to predicting T cell epitopes for other antigens in chicken, while this study also extends our understanding of the mechanisms of the immune response to AIV in chicken.">
    <entity charOffset="1243-1252" id="68011fab7fc7a4d29797a161cb32d21ffd2a2ea7.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0046903" text="secretion" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1390-1399" id="68011fab7fc7a4d29797a161cb32d21ffd2a2ea7.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0046903" text="secretion" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1918-1933" id="68011fab7fc7a4d29797a161cb32d21ffd2a2ea7.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0006955" text="immune response" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
