<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="682a9c91d32a70c08413f3c3f0daba54239c0af0">
  <chunk id="682a9c91d32a70c08413f3c3f0daba54239c0af0.c0" text="Historical Epidemiology of the Second Cholera Pandemic: Relevance to Present Day Disease Dynamics"/>
  <chunk id="682a9c91d32a70c08413f3c3f0daba54239c0af0.c1" text="Despite nearly two centuries of study, the fundamental transmission dynamic properties of cholera remain incompletely characterized. We used historical time-series data on the spread of cholera in twelve European and North American cities during the second cholera pandemic, as reported in Amariah Brigham's 1832 A Treatise on Epidemic Cholera, to parameterize simple mathematical models of cholera transmission. Richards growth models were used to derive estimates of the basic reproductive number (R 0 ) (median: 16.0, range: 1.9 to 550.9) and the proportion of unrecognized cases (mean: 96.3%, SD: 0.04%). Heterogeneity in model-generated R 0 estimates was consistent with variability in cholera dynamics described by contemporary investigators and may represent differences in the nature of cholera spread. While subject to limitations associated with measurement and the absence of microbiological diagnosis, historical epidemic data are a potentially rich source for understanding pathogen dynamics in the absence of control measures, particularly when used in conjunction with simple and readily interpretable mathematical models. Citation: Chan CH, Tuite AR, Fisman DN (2013) Historical Epidemiology of the Second Cholera Pandemic: Relevance to Present Day Disease Dynamics. PLoS ONE 8(8): e72498.">
    <entity charOffset="422-428" id="682a9c91d32a70c08413f3c3f0daba54239c0af0.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0040007" text="growth" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="609-622" id="682a9c91d32a70c08413f3c3f0daba54239c0af0.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0001425" text="Heterogeneity" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="682a9c91d32a70c08413f3c3f0daba54239c0af0.c1.e0" e2="682a9c91d32a70c08413f3c3f0daba54239c0af0.c1.e1" id="682a9c91d32a70c08413f3c3f0daba54239c0af0.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
