<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="69718b1722e6fb921fa5c56b5135454ddbdf7457">
  <chunk id="69718b1722e6fb921fa5c56b5135454ddbdf7457.c0" text="KDELR2 Competes with Measles Virus Envelope Proteins for Cellular Chaperones Reducing Their Chaperone-Mediated Cell Surface Transport">
    <entity charOffset="35-43" id="69718b1722e6fb921fa5c56b5135454ddbdf7457.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0031975" text="Envelope" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="111-123" id="69718b1722e6fb921fa5c56b5135454ddbdf7457.c0.e1" ontology_id="GO_0009986" text="Cell Surface" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="124-133" id="69718b1722e6fb921fa5c56b5135454ddbdf7457.c0.e2" ontology_id="GO_0006810" text="Transport" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="69718b1722e6fb921fa5c56b5135454ddbdf7457.c1" text="Recently, we found that the cytidine deaminase APOBEC3G (A3G) inhibits measles (MV) replication. Using a microarray, we identified differential regulation of several host genes upon ectopic expression of A3G. One of the up-regulated genes, the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) protein retention receptor KDELR2, reduced MV replication~5 fold when it was over-expressed individually in Vero and CEM-SS T cells. Silencing of KDELR2 in A3G-expressing Vero cells abrogated the antiviral activity induced by A3G, confirming its role as an A3G-regulated antiviral host factor. Recognition of the KDEL (Lys-Asp-Glu-Leu) motif by KDEL receptors initiates the retrograde transport of soluble proteins that have escaped the ER and play an important role in ER quality control. Although KDELR2 over-expression reduced MV titers in cell cultures, we observed no interaction between KDELR2 and the MV hemagglutinin (H) protein. Instead, KDELR2 retained chaperones in the ER, which are required for the correct folding and transport of the MV envelope glycoproteins H and fusion protein (F) to the cell surface. Our data indicate that KDELR2 competes with MV envelope proteins for binding to calnexin and GRP78/Bip, and that this interaction limits the availability of the chaperones for MV proteins, causing the reduction of virus spread and titers.">
    <entity charOffset="244-265" id="69718b1722e6fb921fa5c56b5135454ddbdf7457.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0005783" text="endoplasmic reticulum" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="656-665" id="69718b1722e6fb921fa5c56b5135454ddbdf7457.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0006810" text="transport" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1003-1012" id="69718b1722e6fb921fa5c56b5135454ddbdf7457.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0006810" text="transport" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1023-1031" id="69718b1722e6fb921fa5c56b5135454ddbdf7457.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0031975" text="envelope" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1139-1147" id="69718b1722e6fb921fa5c56b5135454ddbdf7457.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0031975" text="envelope" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1161-1168" id="69718b1722e6fb921fa5c56b5135454ddbdf7457.c1.e5" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
