<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="6a2d0c94c7467bc93eab84eb348c458e85738aa3">
  <chunk id="6a2d0c94c7467bc93eab84eb348c458e85738aa3.c0" text="Anti-inflammatory effect of torilidis fructus ethanol extract through inhibition of Src"/>
  <chunk id="6a2d0c94c7467bc93eab84eb348c458e85738aa3.c1" text="Context: Torilidis fructus, fruits of Torilis japonica Decadolle (Umbelliferae), is a medicinal herb traditionally used as a pesticide, an astrictive, or a medicine for various inflammatory diseases. Objectives: Due to the lack of pharmacological studies on this herbal medicine, we explored the inhibitory activity of torilidis fructus on the macrophage-mediated inflammatory response using its ethanol extract (Tf-EE). Material and methods: The Griess assay and prostaglandin (PGE 2 ) ELISA assay were conducted with Tf-EE (0-75 mg/mL) and LPS (1 mg/mL) treated RAW264.7 cells in cultured media. Tf-EE pretreated RAW264.7 cells were incubated with LPS for 6 h and semi-quantitative PCR was performed. Reporter gene assays, overexpression of target enzymes and immunoblotting were performed on macrophages to determine the molecular targets of Tf-EE. Results: Tf-EE markedly suppressed the inflammatory response of macrophages, such as lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced nitric oxide (NO) and PGE 2 production with IC 50 values of 35.66 and 62.47 mg/mL, respectively. It was also found that Tf-EE reduced the expression of inducible NO synthase (iNOS) and cyclooxygenase (COX)-2 by 80%. Nuclear translocation and activation of nuclear factor (NF)-jB (p65 and p50) were declined by 60% and 30% respectively, and their regulatory events including the phosphorylation of AKT, IjBa, Src, and the formation of complexes between Src and p-p85 were also recognized to be diminished. Conclusions: The signalling events managed by Src and p85 complex seemed to be critically involved in Tf-EE-mediated anti-inflammatory response. This might suggest that Tf-EE exhibited anti-inflammatory effects through Src-targeted inhibition of NF-jB.">
    <entity charOffset="364-385" id="6a2d0c94c7467bc93eab84eb348c458e85738aa3.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0006954" text="inflammatory response" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="891-912" id="6a2d0c94c7467bc93eab84eb348c458e85738aa3.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0006954" text="inflammatory response" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1348-1363" id="6a2d0c94c7467bc93eab84eb348c458e85738aa3.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0016310" text="phosphorylation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1492-1502" id="6a2d0c94c7467bc93eab84eb348c458e85738aa3.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0023052" text="signalling" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="6a2d0c94c7467bc93eab84eb348c458e85738aa3.c2" text="ARTICLE HISTORY"/>
</document>
