<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="6c9c09c364d2fbd8d8f319029e60693060b6c756">
  <chunk id="6c9c09c364d2fbd8d8f319029e60693060b6c756.c0" text="A Caprine Herpesvirus 1 Vaccine Adjuvanted with MF59 TM Protects against Vaginal Infection and Interferes with the Establishment of Latency in Goats"/>
  <chunk id="6c9c09c364d2fbd8d8f319029e60693060b6c756.c1" text="The immunogenicity and the efficacy of a beta-propiolactone-inactivated caprine herpesvirus 1 (CpHV-1) vaccine adjuvanted with MF59 TM were tested in goats. Following two subcutaneous immunizations, goats developed high titers of CpHV-1-specific serum and vaginal IgG and high serum virus neutralization (VN) titers. Peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMC) stimulated in vitro with inactivated CpHV-1 produced high levels of soluble IFN-gamma and exhibited high frequencies of IFN-gamma producing cells while soluble IL-4 was undetectable. On the other hand, control goats receiving the inactivated CpHV-1 vaccine without adjuvant produced only low serum antibody responses. A vaginal challenge with virulent CpHV-1 was performed in all vaccinated goats and in na誰ve goats to assess the efficacy of the two vaccines. Vaginal disease was not detected in goats vaccinated with inactivated CpHV-1 plus MF59 TM and these animals had undetectable levels of infectious challenge virus in their vaginal washes. Goats vaccinated with inactivated CpHV-1 in the absence of adjuvant exhibited a less severe disease when compared to na誰ve goats but shed titers of challenge virus that were similar to those of na誰ve goats. Detection and quantitation of latent CpHV-1 DNA in sacral ganglia in challenged goats revealed that the inactivated CpHV-1 plus MF59 TM vaccine was able to significantly reduce the latent viral load when compared either to the na誰ve goats or to the goats vaccinated with inactivated CpHV-1 in the absence of adjuvant. Thus, a vaccine composed of inactivated CpHV-1 plus MF59 TM as adjuvant was strongly immunogenic and induced effective immunity against vaginal CpHV-1 infection in goats.">
    <entity charOffset="317-327" id="6c9c09c364d2fbd8d8f319029e60693060b6c756.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0030646" text="Peripheral" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="657-665" id="6c9c09c364d2fbd8d8f319029e60693060b6c756.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="657-665" id="6c9c09c364d2fbd8d8f319029e60693060b6c756.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1091-1097" id="6c9c09c364d2fbd8d8f319029e60693060b6c756.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="6c9c09c364d2fbd8d8f319029e60693060b6c756.c1.e0" e2="6c9c09c364d2fbd8d8f319029e60693060b6c756.c1.e1" id="6c9c09c364d2fbd8d8f319029e60693060b6c756.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="6c9c09c364d2fbd8d8f319029e60693060b6c756.c1.e0" e2="6c9c09c364d2fbd8d8f319029e60693060b6c756.c1.e2" id="6c9c09c364d2fbd8d8f319029e60693060b6c756.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="6c9c09c364d2fbd8d8f319029e60693060b6c756.c1.e1" e2="6c9c09c364d2fbd8d8f319029e60693060b6c756.c1.e3" id="6c9c09c364d2fbd8d8f319029e60693060b6c756.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="6c9c09c364d2fbd8d8f319029e60693060b6c756.c1.e2" e2="6c9c09c364d2fbd8d8f319029e60693060b6c756.c1.e3" id="6c9c09c364d2fbd8d8f319029e60693060b6c756.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
