<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="6cbe44ed557bcc33f3373f4901da645d23e37901">
  <chunk id="6cbe44ed557bcc33f3373f4901da645d23e37901.c0" text="Evaluation of Public Health Emergency Management in China: A Systematic Review"/>
  <chunk id="6cbe44ed557bcc33f3373f4901da645d23e37901.c1" text="To summarize the present status of health emergency management assessment in China, a comprehensive search of Chinese databases for research that explicitly mention health emergency assessment indicators and indicator systems was performed. Studies were evaluated using the Ekman quality assessment tool, and data were extracted with an original extraction form. Sixty-one studies were included. There are many types and methods of health emergency management assessment in China, and the dimensions and the indicators involved are complex. Legal, regulatory, and policy bases for such assessment need to be further strengthened. The relevance of the entire assessment process and its practical application should be enhanced. In the occupational practice, appropriate evaluation methods should be selected according to respective evaluation purposes, evaluation objects, and contents. Laws, regulations, and policies in the evaluation of health emergency management should be improved. Finally, further correlational research on health emergency management evaluation system processes should be explored and improved."/>
  <chunk id="6cbe44ed557bcc33f3373f4901da645d23e37901.c2" text="index for public health emergency response capacity of township hospitals&quot; has two dimensions, the system named the &quot;National Health and Family Planning Commission, Health Assessment Capacity Assessment Standard&quot; only has one dimension, the system called &quot;A comprehensive assessment tool of the ability of all provinces, autonomous regions (municipalities)/prefectures (states) to respond to public health emergencies&quot; has 214 indicators, and the evaluation system named the &quot;Competency model of health emergency personnel in county-level disease control institutions&quot; only has four indicators. In general, the dimensions of health emergency assessment are mostly second-level dimensions. The assessment indicators mainly include management capabilities, improvement capabilities, drill capabilities, and reporting capabilities. For purposes of this research, a &quot;dimension&quot; refers to the content of public health emergency management features of the institution, such as health emergency response dimension, and &quot;indicator&quot; is used to refer to evaluation features, including emergency command coordination mechanism. After the establishment of the National Emergency Management Department, it was necessary to pay attention to the differences and the connections between the health emergency and the national emergency laws and policies. It is necessary to improve the relevance of the entire process of the health emergency management assessment system. The practical application of the health emergency management assessment system also should focus on the application of health supervision agencies, schools, and other institutions. China includes a vast territory, a substantial population, and diverse regional cultures. In May 2005, the 58 th World Health Assembly (WHA) adopted International Health Regulations [2005] (hereinafter &quot;IHR&quot; or &quot;the Regulations&quot;), which were subsequently implemented on 15 June 2007. All state parties are required by the IHR to develop certain minimum core public health capacities. The development of China's health emergency research has played an important role in promoting the development of global health emergency systems. Systematic evaluation as a method produces high-quality evidence, and its application in the collection and the production of scientific evidence in health emergency management assessment research serves to effectively guarantee the quality of research results, providing a scientific reference for researchers and policymakers. This study analyzes the characteristics of health emergency management assessment indicators using a qualitative system evaluation to appraise the current status of assessment in China as well as to provide evidence-based research for global health emergency policy development."/>
</document>
