<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="6ccce7b6fb9a213959f56ae465bb75ad130d6c9a">
  <chunk id="6ccce7b6fb9a213959f56ae465bb75ad130d6c9a.c0" text="Accuracy of MRI diagnosis of early osteonecrosis of the femoral head: a meta-analysis and systematic review">
    <entity charOffset="35-48" id="6ccce7b6fb9a213959f56ae465bb75ad130d6c9a.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0010885" text="osteonecrosis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="6ccce7b6fb9a213959f56ae465bb75ad130d6c9a.c1" text="Objective: To evaluate the overall diagnostic value related to magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) in patients with early osteonecrosis of the femoral head. Methods: By searching multiple databases and sources, including PubMed, Cochrane, and Embase database, by the index words updated in December 2017, qualified studies were identified and relevant literature sources were also searched. The qualified studies included prospective cohort studies and cross-sectional studies. Heterogeneity of the included studies were reviewed to select proper effect model for pooled weighted sensitivity, specificity, and diagnostic odds ratio (DOR). Summary receiver operating characteristic (SROC) analyses were performed for meniscal tears. Results: Forty-three studies related to diagnostic accuracy of MRI to detect early osteonecrosis of the femoral head were involved in the meta-analysis. The global sensitivity and specificity of MRI in early osteonecrosis of the femoral head were 93.0% (95% CI 92.0-94.0%) and 91.0% (95% CI 89.0%-93.0%), respectively. The global positive likelihood ratio and global negative likelihood ratio of MRI in early osteonecrosis of the femoral head were 2.74 (95% CI 1.98-3.79) and 0.18 (95% CI 0.14-0.23), respectively. The global DOR was 27.27 (95% CI 17.02-43.67), and the area under the SROC was 93.38% (95% CI 90.87%-95.89%). Conclusions: This review provides a systematic review and meta-analysis to evaluate the diagnostic accuracy of MRI in early osteonecrosis of the femoral head. Moderate to strong evidence indicated that MRI appears to be significantly associated with higher diagnostic accuracy for early osteonecrosis of the femoral head.">
    <entity charOffset="119-132" id="6ccce7b6fb9a213959f56ae465bb75ad130d6c9a.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0010885" text="osteonecrosis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="475-488" id="6ccce7b6fb9a213959f56ae465bb75ad130d6c9a.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0001425" text="Heterogeneity" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="812-825" id="6ccce7b6fb9a213959f56ae465bb75ad130d6c9a.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0010885" text="osteonecrosis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="937-950" id="6ccce7b6fb9a213959f56ae465bb75ad130d6c9a.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0010885" text="osteonecrosis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1138-1151" id="6ccce7b6fb9a213959f56ae465bb75ad130d6c9a.c1.e4" ontology_id="HP_0010885" text="osteonecrosis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1478-1491" id="6ccce7b6fb9a213959f56ae465bb75ad130d6c9a.c1.e5" ontology_id="HP_0010885" text="osteonecrosis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1513-1521" id="6ccce7b6fb9a213959f56ae465bb75ad130d6c9a.c1.e6" ontology_id="HP_0012826" text="Moderate" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1641-1654" id="6ccce7b6fb9a213959f56ae465bb75ad130d6c9a.c1.e7" ontology_id="HP_0010885" text="osteonecrosis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
