<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="6d2f0e8c7dd69338395c49a3e3aab7c4239766c2">
  <chunk id="6d2f0e8c7dd69338395c49a3e3aab7c4239766c2.c0" text="A Novel Supplementation Approach to Enhance Host Response to Sublingual Vaccination OPEN"/>
  <chunk id="6d2f0e8c7dd69338395c49a3e3aab7c4239766c2.c1" text="IgA responses. Using Bacillus anthracis edema toxin (EdTx) as an adjuvant, we previously showed that innate responses triggered after sublingual immunization could limit generation of IgA responses. We tested whether co-administration of a neutrophil elastase inhibitor (NEI) could rescue the ability of EdTx to induce broad antibody responses, including mucosal IgA. NEI supplementation of sublingual vaccines containing EdTx promoted antigen-specific serum IgA responses but also enhanced serum IgG1, and IgG2b responses. This enhancing effect of NEI did not extend to all antibody isotypes and IgG sublclasses, since NEI reduced serum IgE responses and did not affect IgG2a/c and IgG3 responses. NEI supplementation also promoted anti-Bacillus anthracis protective antigen (PA) neutralizing antibodies and enhanced high affinity IgG1 and IgA antibodies. In addition to serum IgA, NEI supplementation stimulated antigen-specific mucosal IgA responses in the GI tract, and enhanced antigen-specific IgG responses in vaginal washes. Analysis of CD4 + T helper cell responses revealed that co-administration of NEI broadened the profile of cytokine responses, by stimulating Th1, Th2, Th17, and Tfh cytokines. We also noted that NEI had a higher stimulatory effect on IL-5, IL-10, IL-17 responses.">
    <entity charOffset="40-45" id="6d2f0e8c7dd69338395c49a3e3aab7c4239766c2.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0000969" text="edema" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="325-333" id="6d2f0e8c7dd69338395c49a3e3aab7c4239766c2.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="325-333" id="6d2f0e8c7dd69338395c49a3e3aab7c4239766c2.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="575-583" id="6d2f0e8c7dd69338395c49a3e3aab7c4239766c2.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="575-583" id="6d2f0e8c7dd69338395c49a3e3aab7c4239766c2.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="6d2f0e8c7dd69338395c49a3e3aab7c4239766c2.c1.e0" e2="6d2f0e8c7dd69338395c49a3e3aab7c4239766c2.c1.e1" id="6d2f0e8c7dd69338395c49a3e3aab7c4239766c2.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="6d2f0e8c7dd69338395c49a3e3aab7c4239766c2.c1.e0" e2="6d2f0e8c7dd69338395c49a3e3aab7c4239766c2.c1.e2" id="6d2f0e8c7dd69338395c49a3e3aab7c4239766c2.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="6d2f0e8c7dd69338395c49a3e3aab7c4239766c2.c1.e0" e2="6d2f0e8c7dd69338395c49a3e3aab7c4239766c2.c1.e3" id="6d2f0e8c7dd69338395c49a3e3aab7c4239766c2.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="6d2f0e8c7dd69338395c49a3e3aab7c4239766c2.c1.e0" e2="6d2f0e8c7dd69338395c49a3e3aab7c4239766c2.c1.e4" id="6d2f0e8c7dd69338395c49a3e3aab7c4239766c2.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="6d2f0e8c7dd69338395c49a3e3aab7c4239766c2.c2" text="Published: xx xx xxxx OPEN www.nature.com/scientificreports/"/>
</document>
