<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="6da3f66c681b4b60ce1f6f246340517b79b67137">
  <chunk id="6da3f66c681b4b60ce1f6f246340517b79b67137.c0" text="Chicken Interferon-Inducible Transmembrane Protein 3 Restricts Influenza Viruses and Lyssaviruses In Vitro">
    <entity charOffset="29-42" id="6da3f66c681b4b60ce1f6f246340517b79b67137.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0016021" text="Transmembrane" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="6da3f66c681b4b60ce1f6f246340517b79b67137.c1" text="Interferon-inducible transmembrane protein 3 (IFITM3) is an effector protein of the innate immune system. It confers potent, cell-intrinsic resistance to infection by diverse enveloped viruses both in vitro and in vivo, including influenza viruses, West Nile virus, and dengue virus. IFITM3 prevents cytosolic entry of these viruses by blocking complete virus envelope fusion with cell endosome membranes. Although the IFITM locus, which includes IFITM1, -2, -3, and -5, is present in mammalian species, this locus has not been unambiguously identified or functionally characterized in avian species. Here, we show that the IFITM locus exists in chickens and is syntenic with the IFITM locus in mammals. IFITM2 and -3 are constitutively expressed in all tissues examined, whereas IFITM1 is only expressed in the bursa of Fabricius, gastrointestinal tract, cecal tonsil, and trachea. Despite being highly divergent at the amino acid level, IFITM3 proteins of birds and mammals can restrict replication of viruses that are able to infect different host species, suggesting IFITM proteins may provide a crucial barrier for zoonotic infections.">
    <entity charOffset="21-34" id="6da3f66c681b4b60ce1f6f246340517b79b67137.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0016021" text="transmembrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="360-368" id="6da3f66c681b4b60ce1f6f246340517b79b67137.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0031975" text="envelope" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="386-394" id="6da3f66c681b4b60ce1f6f246340517b79b67137.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0005768" text="endosome" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="6da3f66c681b4b60ce1f6f246340517b79b67137.c2" text="The chicken IFITM3 protein restricts cell infection by influenza A viruses and lyssaviruses to a similar level as its human orthologue. Furthermore, we show that chicken IFITM3 is functional in chicken cells and that knockdown of constitutive expression in chicken fibroblasts results in enhanced infection by influenza A virus. Chicken"/>
</document>
