<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="7110b46076a08c546102c3501ab5220f96e78708">
  <chunk id="7110b46076a08c546102c3501ab5220f96e78708.c0" text="Dipeptidyl peptidase-4 regulation of SDF-1/CXCR4 axis: implications for cardiovascular disease">
    <entity charOffset="72-94" id="7110b46076a08c546102c3501ab5220f96e78708.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0001626" text="cardiovascular disease" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="7110b46076a08c546102c3501ab5220f96e78708.c1" text="Dipeptidyl peptidase-4 (DPP4) is a ubiquitously expressed protease that regulates diverse number of physiological functions. As a dipeptidase, it exerts its catalytic effects on proteins/peptides with proline, alanine, or serine in the penultimate (P1) amino acid residue from the amino terminus. The evidence to date supports an important effect of DPP4 in catalytic cleavage of incretin peptides and this perhaps represents the main mechanism by which DPP4 inhibition improves glycemic control. DPP4 also plays an important role in the degradation of multiple chemokines of which stromal cell-derived factor-1 (SDF-1, also known as CXCL12) is perhaps an increasingly recognized target, given its importance in processes, such as hematopoiesis, angiogenesis, and stem cell homing. In the current review, we will summarize the importance of DPP4-mediated enzymatic processing of cytokines/chemokines with an emphasis on SDF-1 and resultant implications for cardiovascular physiology and disease.">
    <entity charOffset="538-549" id="7110b46076a08c546102c3501ab5220f96e78708.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0009056" text="degradation" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="7110b46076a08c546102c3501ab5220f96e78708.c2" text="Dipeptidyl peptidase-4 (DPP4) is a type-II integral transmembrane glycoprotein that has recently gained attention owing to its role in the catalytic degradation of incretins and as a receptor for entry for the Middle Eastern respiratory syndrome (MERS) virus. DPP4 is best known for its catalytic function, whereby it proteolytically cleaves a number of peptide and protein substrates. It exhibits a strong preference for peptides with proline, serine, or alanine as the penultimate amino acid from the amino terminus. The N-terminus of glucagon insulotropic peptide (GIP) and glucagon-like peptide-1 (GLP-1) consist of Tyr-Ala and His-Ala, respectively, rendering them excellent substrates for DPP4. In addition to its role in modulation of incretin peptides, such as GLP-1 and GIP, DPP4 regulates immune responses via cleavage of many cytokines and chemokines, including stromal cellderived factor-1 (SDF-1, also known as CXCL12), involved in immune function and physiological functions, such as angiogenesis. In this review, we will focus on the regulatory aspects of DPP4 on chemokines, such as SDF-1, and its potential implications in the pathogenesis and management of cardiovascular disease.">
    <entity charOffset="52-65" id="7110b46076a08c546102c3501ab5220f96e78708.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0016021" text="transmembrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="149-160" id="7110b46076a08c546102c3501ab5220f96e78708.c2.e1" ontology_id="GO_0009056" text="degradation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1144-1156" id="7110b46076a08c546102c3501ab5220f96e78708.c2.e2" ontology_id="GO_0009405" text="pathogenesis" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="7110b46076a08c546102c3501ab5220f96e78708.c3" text="Dipeptidyl peptidase-4 also called cluster of differentiation-26 (CD26) or adenosine deaminasebinding protein (ADA-binding protein), is a member of S9b peptidases. The S9b family consists of structurally homologous proteolytic enzymes, including DPP2 (also called quiescent cell proline dipeptidase, QPP), DPP4, DPP8, DPP9, and fibroblast activation protein (FAP). DPP4 was first">
    <entity charOffset="328-349" id="7110b46076a08c546102c3501ab5220f96e78708.c3.e0" ontology_id="GO_0072537" text="fibroblast activation" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
