<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1">
  <chunk id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c0" text="Effects of Adjuvants on the Immunogenicity and Efficacy of a Zika Virus Envelope Domain III Subunit Vaccine">
    <entity charOffset="72-80" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0031975" text="Envelope" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c1" text="Zika virus (ZIKV), a mosquito-borne flavivirus, has attracted global attention due to its close association with congenital Zika syndrome and neurological diseases, and transmission through additional routes, such as sexual contact. Currently there are no vaccines approved for ZIKV, and thus, there is an urgent need to develop an effective and safe ZIKV vaccine. Domain III (DIII) of the ZIKV envelope (E) protein is an important vaccine target, and a vaccine developed using a mutant DIII of E (EDIII) protein protects adult and pregnant mice, and unborn offspring, against ZIKV infection. Here, we have used immunocompetent BALB/c mice treated with anti-interferon-α/β receptor 1 (Ifnar1) antibodies to investigate whether three adjuvants (aluminum (Alum), monophosphoryl lipid A (MPL), and MF59), either alone or in combination, could improve the efficacy of this EDIII subunit vaccine. Our data show that, although vaccine formulated with a single adjuvant induced a specific antibody and cellular immune response, and reduced viral load in mice challenged with ZIKV, the combination of Alum and MPL adjuvants led to a more robust and balanced immune response, stronger neutralizing activity against three recent ZIKV human strains, and greater protection against a high-dose ZIKV challenge. Particularly, the combination of Alum with MPL significantly reduced viral titers and viral RNA copy numbers in sera and tissues, including the male reproductive organs. Overall, this study has identified the combination of Alum and MPL as the most effective adjuvant for ZIKV EDIII subunit vaccines, and it has important implications for subunit vaccines against other enveloped viruses, including non-ZIKV flaviviruses.">
    <entity charOffset="395-403" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0031975" text="envelope" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="982-990" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="982-990" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="995-1019" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0002443" text="cellular immune response" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1410-1414" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0004617" text="sera" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c2" text="Vaccines 2019, 7, 161 2 of 16 with microcephaly, fetal demise, and other congenital disorders [4] [5] [6] . Thus, ZIKV has emerged as a global health threat and there is an urgent requirement for an effective vaccine to combat ZIKV-associated diseases."/>
  <chunk id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c3" text="The ZIKV genome encodes a single polyprotein, which is processed into three structural proteins (capsid (C), precursor of membrane/membrane (prM/M), and envelope (E)) and seven non-structural proteins (NS1, NS2A, NS2B, NS3, NS4A, NS4B, and NS5) [7] [8] [9] . The E protein has important roles in infection and pathogenesis, is involved in virus binding to target cells and membrane fusion, and also serves as an important vaccine target [7, 8] . The E protein is a transmembrane protein and consists of three domains termed I, II, and III (DI-DIII), a fusion loop (FL), and a stalk region (S) [8] . The DI-DII region of ZIKV E protein is a target for cross-reactive antibodies with other flaviviruses, such as dengue virus (DENV) and West Nile virus (WNV), whereas the DIII domain induces ZIKV-specific antibodies [10] [11] [12] , and therefore, is a key target for ZIKV vaccine development. ZIKV vaccine candidates under development include inactivated virus, live attenuated virus, DNA, mRNA, viral vectors, virus-like particles (VLPs), and viral proteins (or subunit vaccines) [13] [14] [15] [16] . Although many have advanced clinical trials and been tested for immunogenicity and/or levels of protection [17] [18] [19] , none are approved for use in humans. Thus, continuous efforts are required to develop safe and efficacious ZIKV vaccines.">
    <entity charOffset="122-130" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c3.e0" ontology_id="GO_0016020" text="membrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="131-139" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c3.e1" ontology_id="GO_0016020" text="membrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="153-161" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c3.e2" ontology_id="GO_0031975" text="envelope" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="345-352" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c3.e3" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="373-381" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c3.e4" ontology_id="GO_0016020" text="membrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="465-478" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c3.e5" ontology_id="GO_0016021" text="transmembrane" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c4" text="Subunit vaccines do not contain live virus or normally elicit adverse side effects and are safe for use in humans including pregnant women and unborn offspring [20, 21] . However, subunit vaccines often suffer from low immunogenicity, although this may be improved by adjuvants. Adjuvants are important components of vaccines as they enhance the immunogenicity of vaccine antigens by boosting the quality and duration of the humoral and/or cellular immune response. Aluminum salts (Alum) are approved for use as adjuvants for human vaccines in the U.S. They are also key components of vaccines for a number of viruses including Hepatitis A virus (HAV), Hepatitis B virus (HBV), and human Papilloma virus (HPV) [22, 23] . The Alum adjuvants most commonly used in licensed vaccines are Alum hydroxide and Alum phosphate [24] . Monophosphoryl lipid A (MPL), a non-toxic derivative of lipopolysaccharide (LPS) and a toll-like receptor (TLR) agonist, can also be used as an adjuvant for human vaccines [25] . In addition, AS04 (a combination of Alum and MPL) is used in vaccines for HBV and HPV [23], while MF59 (an oil-in-water emulsion) has been approved for use with conjugated vaccines for a number of viruses, including influenza virus, herpes simplex virus (HSV), and human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) [22, 23] .">
    <entity charOffset="440-464" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c4.e0" ontology_id="GO_0002443" text="cellular immune response" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="628-637" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c4.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012115" text="Hepatitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="653-662" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c4.e2" ontology_id="HP_0012115" text="Hepatitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="688-697" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c4.e3" ontology_id="HP_0012740" text="Papilloma" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1275-1291" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c4.e4" ontology_id="HP_0002721" text="immunodeficiency" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c4.e0" e2="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c4.e1" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c4.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c4.e0" e2="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c4.e2" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c4.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c4.e0" e2="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c4.e3" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c4.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c4.e0" e2="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c4.e4" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c4.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c5" text="Previously, we have shown that a ZIKV E protein DIII-based subunit vaccine, fused with the Fc region of human IgG, induced specific neutralizing antibodies against divergent ZIKV strains [26] . Furthermore, masking a non-neutralizing epitope (centered on residue 375) of this protein by a glycan probe (DIII of E (EDIII)) enhanced the neutralizing antibody response, and increased protection of adult and pregnant mice against ZIKV challenge without any impact on fetal development [27] . Here, using this EDIII-based subunit vaccine, we compared the adjuvanticity of MF59, Alum, MPL, or Alum + MPL combination (refer to AS04), in a hope to identify an adjuvant or adjuvant combination that is able to promote the EDIII-based ZIKV vaccine to induce a balanced immune response and potent protection against ZIKV infection. Our results show that a more balanced (Th1/Th2) immune response is generated and that the immunogenicity and the ability to protect against ZIKV infection are significantly enhanced when both Alum and MPL are used in the same vaccine formulation. This study has identified the combination of Alum with MPL as an effective adjuvant formulation for ZIKV EDIII-based subunit vaccines.">
    <entity charOffset="348-356" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c5.e0" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="348-356" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c5.e1" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="760-775" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c5.e2" ontology_id="GO_0006955" text="immune response" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="870-885" id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c5.e3" ontology_id="GO_0006955" text="immune response" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c6" text="Materials and Methods"/>
  <chunk id="71e571db52c00a9c67fffc6f075580fe0732cde1.c7" text="Four-to-five-week-old male BALB/c mice were used in the study. The animal studies were carried out in strict accordance with the recommendations in the Guide for the Care and Use of"/>
</document>
