<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="73aec7f72de1b225ab650b78a7633aab4ebd97bc">
  <chunk id="73aec7f72de1b225ab650b78a7633aab4ebd97bc.c0" text="The Inhibition of HIV-1 Entry Imposed by Interferon Inducible Transmembrane Proteins Is Independent of Co-Receptor Usage">
    <entity charOffset="62-75" id="73aec7f72de1b225ab650b78a7633aab4ebd97bc.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0016021" text="Transmembrane" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="73aec7f72de1b225ab650b78a7633aab4ebd97bc.c1" text="Interferon inducible transmembrane proteins (IFITMs) are one of several IFN-stimulated genes (ISGs) that restrict entry of enveloped viruses, including flaviviruses, filoviruses and retroviruses. It has been recently reported that in U87 glioblastoma cells IFITM proteins inhibit HIV-1 entry in a co-receptor-dependent manner, that is, IFITM1 is more inhibitory on CCR5 tropic HIV-1 whereas IFITM2/3 confers a greater suppression of CXCR4 counterparts. However, how entry of HIV-1 with distinct co-receptor usage is modulated by different IFITM orthologs in physiologically relevant CD4 + T cells and monocytes/macrophages has not been investigated in detail. Here, we report that overexpression of IFITM1, 2 and 3 in human CD4 + HuT78 cells, SupT1 cells, monocytic THP-1 cells and U87 cells expressing CD4 and co-receptor CCR5 or CXCR4, suppressed entry of CXCR4 tropic viruses NL4.3 and HXB2, CCR5 tropic viruses AD8 and JRFL, dual tropic 89.6 virus, as well as a panel of 32 transmitted founder (T/F) viruses, with a consistent order of potency, that is, IFITM3 &gt; IFITM2 &gt; IFITM1. Consistent with previous reports, we found that some CCR5-using HIV-1 isolates, such as AD8 and JRFL, were relatively resistant to inhibition by IFITM2 and IFITM3, although the effect can be cell-type dependent. However, in no case have we observed that IFITM1 had a stronger inhibition on entry of any HIV-1 strains tested, including those of CCR5-using T/Fs. We knocked down the endogenous IFITMs in peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs) and purified CD4 + T cells and observed that, while this treatment did greatly enhance the multiple-round of HIV-1 replication but had modest effect to rescue the single-round HIV-1 infection, reinforcing our previous conclusion that the predominant effect of IFITMs on HIV-1 infection is in viral producer cells, rather than in target cells to block viral entry. Overall, our results argue against the idea that IFITM proteins distinguish co-receptors CCR5 and CXCR4 to inhibit entry but emphasize that the predominant role of IFITMs on HIV-1 is in producer cells that intrinsically impair the viral infectivity.">
    <entity charOffset="21-34" id="73aec7f72de1b225ab650b78a7633aab4ebd97bc.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0016021" text="transmembrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="238-250" id="73aec7f72de1b225ab650b78a7633aab4ebd97bc.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012174" text="glioblastoma" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1486-1496" id="73aec7f72de1b225ab650b78a7633aab4ebd97bc.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0030646" text="peripheral" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="73aec7f72de1b225ab650b78a7633aab4ebd97bc.c1.e0" e2="73aec7f72de1b225ab650b78a7633aab4ebd97bc.c1.e1" id="73aec7f72de1b225ab650b78a7633aab4ebd97bc.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="73aec7f72de1b225ab650b78a7633aab4ebd97bc.c1.e0" e2="73aec7f72de1b225ab650b78a7633aab4ebd97bc.c1.e2" id="73aec7f72de1b225ab650b78a7633aab4ebd97bc.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
