<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="76418514384003ef87ee3e6922525db0b8bf0bd3">
  <chunk id="76418514384003ef87ee3e6922525db0b8bf0bd3.c0" text="Immunogenicity of Candidate MERS-CoV DNA Vaccines Based on the Spike Protein OPEN"/>
  <chunk id="76418514384003ef87ee3e6922525db0b8bf0bd3.c1" text="Its apparent endemicity and the wide spread of its reservoir host (dromedary camels) in the Arabian Peninsula highlight the ongoing public health threat of this virus. Therefore, development of effective prophylactic vaccine needs to be urgently explored given that there are no approved prophylactics or therapeutics for humans or animals to date. Different vaccine candidates have been investigated but serious safety concerns remain over protein or full-length spike (S) protein-based vaccines. Here, we investigated the immunogenicity of naked DNA vaccines expressing different fragments of MERS-CoV S protein in mice. We found that plasmids expressing full-length (pS) or S1-subunit (pS1) could induce significant levels of S1-specific antibodies (Abs) but with distinct IgG isotype patterns. Specifically, pS1 immunization elicited a balanced Th1/Th2 response and generally higher levels of all IgG isotypes compared to pS vaccination. Interestingly, only mice immunized with pS1 demonstrated significant S1specific cellular immune response. Importantly, both constructs induced cross-neutralizing Abs against multiple strains of human and camel origins. These results indicate that vaccines expressing S1-subunit of the MERS-CoV S protein could represent a potential vaccine candidate without the possible safety concerns associated with full-length protein-based vaccines.">
    <entity charOffset="1022-1046" id="76418514384003ef87ee3e6922525db0b8bf0bd3.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0002443" text="cellular immune response" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="76418514384003ef87ee3e6922525db0b8bf0bd3.c2" text="Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus (MERS-CoV) is an emerging zoonotic pathogen recovered first from a fatal human case in Saudi Arabia in 2012 1 and continued to infect almost 1800 people in over 25 countries. Saudi Arabia has reported the largest number of cases so far with cases continuing to increase. The virus causes severe respiratory infection associated with fever, cough, acute pneumonia, shortness of breath, systemic infection and occasional multi-organ failure in infected individuals leading to death in 35-40% of the cases 2-4 . Such a severe disease usually occurs in immunocompromised patients, individuals with comorbidities and the elderly 1,4-6 . Most of the reported MERS cases are linked to hospital outbreaks and family clusters due to close contact with infected patients 4,7-10 . However, accumulating epidemiological data show high prevalence of MERS-CoV in dromedary camels from several Arabian and African countries, suggesting that dromedaries might be the reservoir hosts of this virus 4,11-15 . The continued endemicity of MERS-CoV in the Arabian Peninsula and the associated high death rate clearly represent a public health concern with potential global spread as observed in the recent outbreak in South Korea 10 . This is further complicated by the lack of prophylactic or therapeutic measures, underscoring the importance of preparedness research against this potential pandemic virus.">
    <entity charOffset="333-339" id="76418514384003ef87ee3e6922525db0b8bf0bd3.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="340-361" id="76418514384003ef87ee3e6922525db0b8bf0bd3.c2.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011947" text="respiratory infection" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="392-397" id="76418514384003ef87ee3e6922525db0b8bf0bd3.c2.e2" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="453-463" id="76418514384003ef87ee3e6922525db0b8bf0bd3.c2.e3" ontology_id="HP_0040283" text="occasional" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="561-567" id="76418514384003ef87ee3e6922525db0b8bf0bd3.c2.e4" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="76418514384003ef87ee3e6922525db0b8bf0bd3.c3" text="Several supportive therapies and antivirals were proposed and examined for the treatment of MERS-CoV infections [16] [17] [18] [19] [20] . However, most of these strategies were based on the experience gained during the severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS) outbreak or from MERS-CoV in vitro studies and require further preclinical and">
    <entity charOffset="220-226" id="76418514384003ef87ee3e6922525db0b8bf0bd3.c3.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="227-232" id="76418514384003ef87ee3e6922525db0b8bf0bd3.c3.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
