<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="790506537d41f8336265c309548c3f95759c7370">
  <chunk id="790506537d41f8336265c309548c3f95759c7370.c0" text="Enhanced Nasal Mucosal Delivery and Immunogenicity of Anti-Caries DNA Vaccine through Incorporation of Anionic Liposomes in Chitosan/DNA Complexes"/>
  <chunk id="790506537d41f8336265c309548c3f95759c7370.c1" text="The design of optimized nanoparticles offers a promising strategy to enable DNA vaccines to cross various physiological barriers for eliciting a specific and protective mucosal immunity via intranasal administration. Here, we reported a new designed nanoparticle system through incorporating anionic liposomes (AL) into chitosan/DNA (CS/DNA) complexes. With enhanced cellular uptake, the constructed AL/CS/DNA nanoparticles can deliver the anti-caries DNA vaccine pGJA-P/VAX into nasal mucosa. TEM results showed the AL/CS/DNA had a spherical structure. High DNA loading ability and effective DNA protection against nuclease were proved by gel electrophoresis. The surface charge of the AL/CS/DNA depended strongly on pH environment, enabling the intracellular release of loaded DNA via a pH-mediated manner. In comparison to the traditional CS/DNA system, our new design rendered a higher transfection efficiency and longer residence time of the AL/CS/DNA at nasal mucosal surface. These outstanding features enable the AL/CS/DNA to induce a significantly (p,0.01) higher level of secretory IgA (SIgA) than the CS/DNA in animal study, and a longer-term mucosal immunity. On the other hand, the AL/CS/DNA exhibited minimal cytotoxicity. These results suggest that the developed nanoparticles offer a potential platform for DNA vaccine packaging and delivery for more efficient elicitation of mucosal immunity.">
    <entity charOffset="494-497" id="790506537d41f8336265c309548c3f95759c7370.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0097197" text="TEM" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="593-607" id="790506537d41f8336265c309548c3f95759c7370.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0042262" text="DNA protection" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="747-760" id="790506537d41f8336265c309548c3f95759c7370.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0005622" text="intracellular" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
