<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="7927b8f05155e6933aaf8d9509dbd379d017dfe7">
  <chunk id="7927b8f05155e6933aaf8d9509dbd379d017dfe7.c0" text="Transferrin receptor 1 is a supplementary receptor that assists transmissible gastroenteritis virus entry into porcine intestinal epithelium"/>
  <chunk id="7927b8f05155e6933aaf8d9509dbd379d017dfe7.c1" text="Background: Transmissible gastroenteritis virus (TGEV), the etiologic agent of transmissible gastroenteritis, infects swine of all ages causing vomiting and diarrhea, in newborn piglets the mortality rate is near 100%. Intestinal epithelial cells are the primary target cells of TGEV. Transferrin receptor 1 (TfR1), which is highly expressed in piglets with anemia, may play a role in TGEV infection. However, the underlying mechanism of TGEV invasion remains largely unknown. Results: Our study investigated the possibility that TfR1 can serve as a receptor for TGEV infection and enables the invasion and replication of TGEV. We observed that TGEV infection promoted TfR1 internalization, clustering, and co-localization with TfR1 early in infection, while TfR1 expression was significantly down-regulated as TGEV infection proceeded. TGEV infection and replication were inhibited by occluding TfR1 with antibodies or by decreasing TfR1 expression. TGEV infection increased in TGEV-susceptible ST or IPEC-J2 cell lines and TGEV-resistant Caco-2 cells when porcine TfR1 was over-expressed. Finally, we found that the TGEV S1 protein interacts with the extracellular region of TfR1, and that pre-incubating TGEV with a protein fragment containing the extracellular region of TfR1 blocked viral infection. Conclusions: Our results support the hypothesis that TfR1 is an additional receptor for TGEV and assists TGEV invasion and replication.">
    <entity charOffset="144-152" id="7927b8f05155e6933aaf8d9509dbd379d017dfe7.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002013" text="vomiting" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1153-1166" id="7927b8f05155e6933aaf8d9509dbd379d017dfe7.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005576" text="extracellular" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1153-1173" id="7927b8f05155e6933aaf8d9509dbd379d017dfe7.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0005576" text="extracellular region" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1251-1264" id="7927b8f05155e6933aaf8d9509dbd379d017dfe7.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0005576" text="extracellular" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1251-1271" id="7927b8f05155e6933aaf8d9509dbd379d017dfe7.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0005576" text="extracellular region" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="7927b8f05155e6933aaf8d9509dbd379d017dfe7.c1.e0" e2="7927b8f05155e6933aaf8d9509dbd379d017dfe7.c1.e1" id="7927b8f05155e6933aaf8d9509dbd379d017dfe7.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="7927b8f05155e6933aaf8d9509dbd379d017dfe7.c1.e0" e2="7927b8f05155e6933aaf8d9509dbd379d017dfe7.c1.e2" id="7927b8f05155e6933aaf8d9509dbd379d017dfe7.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="7927b8f05155e6933aaf8d9509dbd379d017dfe7.c1.e0" e2="7927b8f05155e6933aaf8d9509dbd379d017dfe7.c1.e3" id="7927b8f05155e6933aaf8d9509dbd379d017dfe7.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="7927b8f05155e6933aaf8d9509dbd379d017dfe7.c1.e0" e2="7927b8f05155e6933aaf8d9509dbd379d017dfe7.c1.e4" id="7927b8f05155e6933aaf8d9509dbd379d017dfe7.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
