<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="7a6e0d1d7e1a31f6107a62a0030818b766a00dd8">
  <chunk id="7a6e0d1d7e1a31f6107a62a0030818b766a00dd8.c0" text="Comparison of Influenza Epidemiological and Virological Characteristics between Outpatients and Inpatients in Zhejiang Province"/>
  <chunk id="7a6e0d1d7e1a31f6107a62a0030818b766a00dd8.c1" text="Given the rapid rate of global spread and consequently healthcare costs related to influenza, surveillance plays an important role in monitoring the emerging pandemics in China. However, the characteristics of influenza in Southeast of China haven't been fully studied. Our study use the surveillance data collected from 16 sentinel hospitals across Zhejiang Province during March 2011 through June 2015, including the demographic information and respiratory specimens from influenza-like illness (ILI) patients and severe acute respiratory illness (SARI) patients. As analysis results, most SARI and ILI patients were in the age group of 0-4 years old (62.38% of ILI and 71.54% of SARI). The respiratory specimens have statistically significantly higher positive rate for influenza among ILI patients than that among SARI patients (p &lt; 0.001). The comparison between ILI patients and SARI patients shows no statistically significantly difference in detecting influenza virus type and influenza A virus subtype. The SARI and ILI patients were found to be positively correlated for overall positive rate (r = 0.63, p &lt; 0.001), the weekly percentage of A(H1N1)pdm09 (r = 0.51, p &lt; 0.001), influenza B virus (r = 0.17, p = 0.013), and A/H3N2 (r = 0.43, p &lt; 0.001) among all the positive numbers. Our study demonstrated that the activities of influenza virus, including its subtypes, had a similar temporal pattern between ILI and SARI cases.">
    <entity charOffset="516-522" id="7a6e0d1d7e1a31f6107a62a0030818b766a00dd8.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="523-528" id="7a6e0d1d7e1a31f6107a62a0030818b766a00dd8.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1394-1410" id="7a6e0d1d7e1a31f6107a62a0030818b766a00dd8.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0011008" text="temporal pattern" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
