<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="7b22c0d8cb7675bcc5aa283fe3bfef6c72052519">
  <chunk id="7b22c0d8cb7675bcc5aa283fe3bfef6c72052519.c0" text="Real-Time Sequence-Validated Loop- Mediated Isothermal Amplification Assays for Detection of Middle East Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus (MERS-CoV)"/>
  <chunk id="7b22c0d8cb7675bcc5aa283fe3bfef6c72052519.c1" text="The Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus (MERS-CoV), an emerging human coronavirus, causes severe acute respiratory illness with a 35% mortality rate. In light of the recent surge in reported infections we have developed asymmetric five-primer reverse transcription loop-mediated isothermal amplification (RT-LAMP) assays for detection of MERS-CoV. Isothermal amplification assays will facilitate the development of portable point-of-care diagnostics that are crucial for management of emerging infections. The RT-LAMP assays are designed to amplify MERS-CoV genomic loci located within the open reading frame (ORF)1a and ORF1b genes and upstream of the E gene. Additionally we applied one-step strand displacement probes (OSD) for real-time sequence-specific verification of LAMP amplicons. Asymmetric amplification effected by incorporating a single loop primer in each assay accelerated the time-to-result of the OSD-RT-LAMP assays. The resulting assays could detect 0.02 to 0.2 plaque forming units (PFU) (5 to 50 PFU/ml) of MERS-CoV in infected cell culture supernatants within 30 to 50 min and did not cross-react with common human respiratory pathogens.">
    <entity charOffset="99-105" id="7b22c0d8cb7675bcc5aa283fe3bfef6c72052519.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="106-111" id="7b22c0d8cb7675bcc5aa283fe3bfef6c72052519.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="252-273" id="7b22c0d8cb7675bcc5aa283fe3bfef6c72052519.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0001171" text="reverse transcription" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="703-722" id="7b22c0d8cb7675bcc5aa283fe3bfef6c72052519.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0000732" text="strand displacement" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="7b22c0d8cb7675bcc5aa283fe3bfef6c72052519.c1.e0" e2="7b22c0d8cb7675bcc5aa283fe3bfef6c72052519.c1.e2" id="7b22c0d8cb7675bcc5aa283fe3bfef6c72052519.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="7b22c0d8cb7675bcc5aa283fe3bfef6c72052519.c1.e0" e2="7b22c0d8cb7675bcc5aa283fe3bfef6c72052519.c1.e3" id="7b22c0d8cb7675bcc5aa283fe3bfef6c72052519.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="7b22c0d8cb7675bcc5aa283fe3bfef6c72052519.c1.e1" e2="7b22c0d8cb7675bcc5aa283fe3bfef6c72052519.c1.e2" id="7b22c0d8cb7675bcc5aa283fe3bfef6c72052519.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="7b22c0d8cb7675bcc5aa283fe3bfef6c72052519.c1.e1" e2="7b22c0d8cb7675bcc5aa283fe3bfef6c72052519.c1.e3" id="7b22c0d8cb7675bcc5aa283fe3bfef6c72052519.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
