<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="7b5d559562d07c48dfbba720712d27a53ee81504">
  <chunk id="7b5d559562d07c48dfbba720712d27a53ee81504.c0" text="In-plate recapturing of a dual-tagged recombinant Fasciola antigen (FhLAP) by a monoclonal antibody (US9) prevents non- specific binding in ELISA">
    <entity charOffset="91-99" id="7b5d559562d07c48dfbba720712d27a53ee81504.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="91-99" id="7b5d559562d07c48dfbba720712d27a53ee81504.c0.e1" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="129-136" id="7b5d559562d07c48dfbba720712d27a53ee81504.c0.e2" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="7b5d559562d07c48dfbba720712d27a53ee81504.c1" text="Recombinant proteins expressed in E. coli are frequently purified by immobilized metal affinity chromatography (IMAC). By means of this technique, tagged proteins containing a polyhistidine sequence can be obtained up to 95% pure in a single step, but some host proteins also bind with great affinity to metal ions and contaminate the sample. A way to overcome this problem is to include a second tag that is recognized by a preexistent monoclonal antibody (mAb) in the gene encoding the target protein, allowing further purification. With this strategy, the recombinant protein can be directly used as target in capture ELISA using plates sensitized with the corresponding mAb. As a proof of concept, in this study we engineered a Trichinella-derived tag (MTFSVPIS, recognized by mAb US9) into a His-tagged recombinant Fasciola antigen (rFhLAP) to make a new chimeric recombinant protein (rUS9-FhLAP), and tested its specificity in capture and indirect ELISAs with sera from sheep and cattle. FhLAP was selected since it was previously reported to be immunogenic in ruminants and is expressed in soluble form in E. coli, which anticipates a higher contamination by host proteins than proteins expressed in inclusion bodies. Our results showed that a large number of sera from non-infected ruminants (mainly cattle) reacted in indirect ELISA with rUS9-FhLAP after single-step purification by IMAC, but that this reactivity disappeared testing the same antigen in capture ELISA with mAb US9. These results demonstrate that the 6XHis and US9 tags can be combined when double purification of recombinant proteins is required. OPEN ACCESS Citation: Orbegozo-Medina RA, Martínez-Sernández V, Perteguer MJ, Hernández-González A, Mezo M, González-Warleta M, et al. (2019) Inplate recapturing of a dual-tagged recombinant Fasciola antigen (FhLAP) by a monoclonal antibody (US9) prevents non-specific binding in ELISA. PLoS ONE 14(2): e0211035. https://doi.org/ 10.] and the Consellería de Cultura, Educación">
    <entity charOffset="225-229" id="7b5d559562d07c48dfbba720712d27a53ee81504.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0034023" text="pure" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="448-456" id="7b5d559562d07c48dfbba720712d27a53ee81504.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="448-456" id="7b5d559562d07c48dfbba720712d27a53ee81504.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="966-970" id="7b5d559562d07c48dfbba720712d27a53ee81504.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0004617" text="sera" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1267-1271" id="7b5d559562d07c48dfbba720712d27a53ee81504.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0004617" text="sera" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1855-1863" id="7b5d559562d07c48dfbba720712d27a53ee81504.c1.e5" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1855-1863" id="7b5d559562d07c48dfbba720712d27a53ee81504.c1.e6" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1892-1899" id="7b5d559562d07c48dfbba720712d27a53ee81504.c1.e7" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="7b5d559562d07c48dfbba720712d27a53ee81504.c2" text="antigens were more specific than natural ones, but several studies have shown just the contrary [1] [2] [3] [4] . Although this phenomenon has not yet been investigated in detail, some reports pointed out that the presence of contaminants derived from the expression of His-tagged proteins in E. coli may explain the poor specificity of such antigens [5] . Optimized E. coli expression [6], acidic washes [7, 8] , and washing with low amounts of imidazole [9] are methods commonly used to prevent the co-purification of proteins on immobilized metal affinity chromatography (IMAC), thus improving the purity of His-tagged recombinant proteins. Also, disulfide bond formation between the protein of interest and other proteins, as well as nonspecific hydrophobic interactions, can be minimized by inclusion of 2-mercaptoethanol and non-ionic detergents, respectively, in the loading buffer [8] . However, since a relevant fraction of contaminant E. coli proteins exhibit moderate to strong affinity for metal-chelating resins [9], these methods do not guarantee complete purity of recombinant proteins and may decrease the yield of the purified protein.">
    <entity charOffset="970-978" id="7b5d559562d07c48dfbba720712d27a53ee81504.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012826" text="moderate" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="7b5d559562d07c48dfbba720712d27a53ee81504.c3" text="Another way to overcome the above problems is grafting a second linear epitope tag recognized by a monoclonal antibody (mAb) into the target sequence of interest, thus allowing repurification of the protein by affinity chromatography. Currently there are some proprietary tag-mAb pairs that can be used for affinity-purification and for detection of tagged recombinant proteins [10, 11] . However, to the best of our knowledge, none of them were used to develop sandwich ELISA methods for serodiagnosis of infectious diseases, a strategy that, if successful, would allow recapturing of the refolded antigen of interest in a single step. To explore this methodology, in the present study we grafted the linear sequence MTFSVPIS, located at the amino terminal region of the gp53 antigen from encapsulated species of Trichinella and recognized by the IgG1/κ mAb US9 [12] [13] [14] , into a His-tagged Fasciola hepatica recombinant protein (leucine aminopeptidase; FhLAP). FhLAP is a cytoplasmic metalloproteinase isolated from adult flukes [15] , which was reported to be able to induce specific antibodies during infection as well as partial protection against reinfection in immunized sheep [16] [17] [18] . Although native [19] [20] [21] and recombinant [4, 22, 23] Fasciola cathepsins (clades L1, L2 and/or L5) are more adequate as target antigens in ELISA for immunodiagnosis of human and animal infections, for the proof of concept of the present study, we preferred FhLAP since it can be expressed soluble in transformed E. coli and, consequently, undesirable host proteins are more prone to be present. Moreover, since native FhLAP was previously tested as target antigen for immunodiagnosis of human fascioliasis, this study provides us with the opportunity to evaluate its usefulness to diagnose F. hepatica infections in domestic ruminants (sheep and cattle).">
    <entity charOffset="110-118" id="7b5d559562d07c48dfbba720712d27a53ee81504.c3.e0" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="110-118" id="7b5d559562d07c48dfbba720712d27a53ee81504.c3.e1" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
