<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="7d4b0efca3cb904640b8fd489fdfc413a8fae264">
  <chunk id="7d4b0efca3cb904640b8fd489fdfc413a8fae264.c0" text="TMPRSS2 and MSPL Facilitate Trypsin-Independent Porcine Epidemic Diarrhea Virus Replication in Vero Cells">
    <entity charOffset="65-73" id="7d4b0efca3cb904640b8fd489fdfc413a8fae264.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002014" text="Diarrhea" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="7d4b0efca3cb904640b8fd489fdfc413a8fae264.c1" text="Type II transmembrane serine proteases (TTSPs) facilitate the spread and replication of viruses such as influenza and human coronaviruses, although it remains unclear whether TTSPs play a role in the progression of animal coronavirus infections, such as that by porcine epidemic diarrhea virus (PEDV). In this study, TTSPs including TMPRSS2, HAT, DESC1, and MSPL were tested for their ability to facilitate PEDV replication in Vero cells. Our results showed that TMPRSS2 and MSPL played significant roles in the stages of cell-cell fusion and virus-cell fusion, whereas HAT and DESC1 exhibited weaker effects. This activation may be involved in the interaction between TTSPs and the PEDV S protein, as the S protein extensively co-localized with TMPRSS2 and MSPL and could be cleaved by co-expression with TMPRSS2 or MSPL. Moreover, the use of Vero cells expressing TMPRSS2 and MSPL facilitated PEDV replication in the absence of exogenous trypsin. In sum, we identified two host proteases, TMPRSS2 and MSPL, which may provide insights and a novel method for enhancing viral titers, expanding virus production, and improving the adaptability of PEDV isolates in vitro.">
    <entity charOffset="8-21" id="7d4b0efca3cb904640b8fd489fdfc413a8fae264.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0016021" text="transmembrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="279-287" id="7d4b0efca3cb904640b8fd489fdfc413a8fae264.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0002014" text="diarrhea" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="522-538" id="7d4b0efca3cb904640b8fd489fdfc413a8fae264.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0140253" text="cell-cell fusion" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="7d4b0efca3cb904640b8fd489fdfc413a8fae264.c1.e0" e2="7d4b0efca3cb904640b8fd489fdfc413a8fae264.c1.e1" id="7d4b0efca3cb904640b8fd489fdfc413a8fae264.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="7d4b0efca3cb904640b8fd489fdfc413a8fae264.c1.e1" e2="7d4b0efca3cb904640b8fd489fdfc413a8fae264.c1.e2" id="7d4b0efca3cb904640b8fd489fdfc413a8fae264.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
