<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4">
  <chunk id="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c0" text="X-Ray Structure and Inhibition of 3C-like Protease from Porcine Epidemic Diarrhea Virus OPEN">
    <entity charOffset="73-81" id="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002014" text="Diarrhea" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c1" text="approaching 100% in piglets, causing serious economic impact. The 3C-like protease (3CL pro ) is essential for the coronaviral life cycle and is an appealing target for the development of therapeutics. We report the expression, purification, crystallization and 2.10 Å X-ray structure of 3CL pro from PEDV. Analysis of the PEDV 3CL pro structure and comparison to other coronaviral 3CL pro 's from the same alphacoronavirus phylogeny shows that the overall structures and active site architectures across 3CL pro 's are conserved, with the exception of a loop that comprises the protease S 2 pocket. We found a known inhibitor of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus (SARS-CoV) 3CL pro , (R)-16, to have inhibitor activity against PEDV 3CL pro , despite that SARS-3CL pro and PEDV 3CL pro share only 45.4% sequence identity. Structural comparison reveals that the majority of residues involved in (R)-16 binding to SARS-3CL pro are conserved in PEDV-3CL pro ; however, the sequence variation and positional difference in the loop forming the S 2 pocket may account for large observed difference in IC 50 values. This work advances our understanding of the subtle, but important, differences in coronaviral 3CL pro architecture and contributes to the broader structural knowledge of coronaviral 3CL pro 's.">
    <entity charOffset="630-636" id="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="637-642" id="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="913-920" id="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c1.e0" e2="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c1.e2" id="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c1.e1" e2="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c1.e2" id="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c2" text="The causative virus of porcine epidemic diarrhea in pigs was first described in England in 1978 1 , though the disease was first observed in 1971 among English feed pigs 2 . Subsequently termed porcine epidemic diarrhea virus (PEDV), it was classified as a coronavirus as a result of its appearance in electron microscopes and its polypeptide structure 3-5 . Before its occurrence in the United States, there were numerous reports of PEDV in various European countries, as well as in Korea, China, Japan, the Philippines and Thailand 6 . The first four reports of PEDV in the United States occurred within 10 days of each other on four farms in Iowa in late April of 2013 7 . The disease is characterized by porcine epidemic diarrhea with concomitant vomiting and dehydration, resulting in high fatality rates especially in piglets where mortality rates approach 100% 8 . The origin of transmission of PEDV to the United States is still unknown; however, in the past two years, it has resulted in a sizeable and negative impact on the US economy. The estimated net annual loss for the US economy as a result of PEDV, summed across all effects, is reported to range from $900 million to $1.8 billon as of June, 2014 9 .">
    <entity charOffset="40-48" id="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002014" text="diarrhea" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="211-219" id="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c2.e1" ontology_id="HP_0002014" text="diarrhea" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="725-733" id="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c2.e2" ontology_id="HP_0002014" text="diarrhea" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="751-759" id="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c2.e3" ontology_id="HP_0002013" text="vomiting" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c3" text="Coronaviruses are enveloped, single-stranded, positive-sense zoonotic RNA viruses with genomes ranging from 27 to 32 kilobases in length, where the genes encoding for the structural proteins are located at the 3′ end and the replicase genes are located at the 5′ end of the genome. Two long ORFs encode for the replicase proteins, ORF1a and ORF1b, which are connected by a ribosomal frame-shift and produce the coronaviral polyproteins pp1a and pp1ab upon translation 10 . These viral polyproteins are processed at 14 cleavage sites by two or three cysteine proteases producing 16 non-structural proteins (nsps). The papain-like protease (PLP1 and PLP2 or PL pro ) cleaves the polyprotein at 3 sites, whereas the 3C-like protease (3CL pro ), also known as the main-protease (M pro ) or nsp5, cleaves the polyprotein at 11 sites. The function of both proteases is essential for viral replication and therefore they are attractive targets for the development of anti-coronaviral therapeutics. In this study, we report the expression, purification, crystallization, and X-ray structure of PEDV-3CL pro in its unbound state to 2.10 Å. We tested PEDV-3CL pro for inhibition by (R)-16, a compound known to inhibit severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus (SARS-CoV) 3CL pro , and found (R)-16 to inhibit PEDV-3CL pro with an IC 50 of 25.4 ± 1.4 μM. The structural information provided by the PEDV-3CL pro X-ray crystal structure adds new details to our general">
    <entity charOffset="456-467" id="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c3.e0" ontology_id="GO_0006412" text="translation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1208-1214" id="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c3.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1215-1220" id="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c3.e2" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c3.e0" e2="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c3.e1" id="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c3.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c3.e0" e2="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c3.e2" id="7d5cd4faf19ae8838653aa65ea172c97f8bfe9f4.c3.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
