<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="7e2cac5308e11493311bc4a3e8d15c9b9e7885ad">
  <chunk id="7e2cac5308e11493311bc4a3e8d15c9b9e7885ad.c0" text="The coronavirus macrodomain is required to prevent PARP-mediated inhibition of virus replication and enhancement of IFN expression"/>
  <chunk id="7e2cac5308e11493311bc4a3e8d15c9b9e7885ad.c1" text="ADP-ribosylation is a ubiquitous post-translational addition of either monomers or polymers of ADP-ribose to target proteins by ADP-ribosyltransferases, usually by interferon-inducible diphtheria toxin-like enzymes known as PARPs. While several PARPs have known antiviral activities, these activities are mostly independent of ADP-ribosylation. Consequently, less is known about the antiviral effects of ADP-ribosylation. Several viral families, including Coronaviridae, Togaviridae, and Hepeviridae, encode for macrodomain proteins that bind to and hydrolyze ADP-ribose from proteins and are critical for optimal replication and virulence. These results suggest that macrodomains counter cellular ADP-ribosylation, but whether PARPs or, alternatively, other ADP-ribosyltransferases cause this modification is not clear. Here we show that pan-PARP inhibition enhanced replication and inhibited interferon production in primary macrophages infected with macrodomain-mutant but not wild-type coronavirus. Specifically, knockdown of two abundantly expressed PARPs, PARP12 and PARP14, led to increased replication of mutant but did not significantly affect wild-type virus. PARP14 was also important for the induction of interferon in mouse and human cells, indicating a critical role for this PARP in the regulation of innate immunity. In summary, these data demonstrate that the macrodomain is required to prevent PARP-mediated inhibition of coronavirus replication and enhancement of interferon production."/>
  <chunk id="7e2cac5308e11493311bc4a3e8d15c9b9e7885ad.c2" text="Author summary ADP-ribosylation, an understudied post-translational modification, facilitates the host response to virus infection. Several viruses, including all members of the coronavirus PLOS Pathogens | https://doi."/>
</document>
