<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="8171299fc5073dfe98c4c56d5760ccb5f802f8f0">
  <chunk id="8171299fc5073dfe98c4c56d5760ccb5f802f8f0.c0" text="Adenine Enrichment at the Fourth CDS Residue in Bacterial Genes Is Consistent with Error Proofing for 11 Frameshifts"/>
  <chunk id="8171299fc5073dfe98c4c56d5760ccb5f802f8f0.c1" text="Beyond selection for optimal protein functioning, coding sequences (CDSs) are under selection at the RNA and DNA levels. Here, we identify a possible signature of &quot;dual-coding,&quot; namely extensive adenine (A) enrichment at bacterial CDS fourth sites. In 99.07% of studied bacterial genomes, fourth site A use is greater than expected given genomic A-starting codon use. Arguing for nucleotide level selection, A-starting serine and arginine second codons are heavily utilized when compared with their non-A starting synonyms. Several models have the ability to explain some of this trend. In part, A-enrichment likely reduces 5 0 mRNA stability, promoting translation initiation. However T/U, which may also reduce stability, is avoided. Further, þ1 frameshifts on the initiating ATG encode a stop codon (TGA) provided A is the fourth residue, acting either as a frameshift &quot;catch and destroy&quot; or a frameshift stop and adjust mechanism and hence implicated in translation initiation. Consistent with both, genomes lacking TGA stop codons exhibit weaker fourth site Aenrichment. Sequences lacking a Shine-Dalgarno sequence and those without upstream leader genes, that may be more error prone during initiation, have greater utilization of A, again suggesting a role in initiation. The frameshift correction model is consistent with the notion that many genomic features are error-mitigation factors and provides the first evidence for site-specific out of frame stop codon selection. We conjecture that the NTG universal start codon may have evolved as a consequence of TGA being a stop codon and the ability of NTGA to rapidly terminate or adjust a ribosome.">
    <entity charOffset="654-665" id="8171299fc5073dfe98c4c56d5760ccb5f802f8f0.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0006412" text="translation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="958-969" id="8171299fc5073dfe98c4c56d5760ccb5f802f8f0.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0006412" text="translation" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
