<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="83e137405afc87914e9128afa5aec46cc2b152cd">
  <chunk id="83e137405afc87914e9128afa5aec46cc2b152cd.c0" text="Seroepidemiologic Survey of Potential Pathogens in Obligate and Facultative Scavenging Avian Species in California">
    <entity charOffset="51-59" id="83e137405afc87914e9128afa5aec46cc2b152cd.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0040280" text="Obligate" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="83e137405afc87914e9128afa5aec46cc2b152cd.c1" text="Throughout the world, populations of scavenger birds are declining rapidly with some populations already on the brink of extinction. Much of the current research into the factors contributing to these declines has focused on exposure to drug residues, lead, and other toxins. Despite increased monitoring of these declining populations, little is known about infectious diseases affecting scavenger bird species. To assess potential infectious disease risks to both obligate and facultative scavenger bird species, we performed a serosurvey for eleven potential pathogens in three species of scavenging birds in California: the California condor (Gymnogyps californianus), turkey vulture (Cathartes aura) and golden eagle (Aquila chrysaetos). California condors were seropositive for avian adenovirus, infectious bronchitis virus, Mycoplasma gallisepticum, avian paramyxovirus-2, West Nile virus (WNV) and Toxoplasma gondii. Golden eagles were seropositive for avian adenovirus, Chlamydophila psittaci and Toxoplasma gondii, and turkey vultures were seropositive for avian adenovirus, Chlamydophila psittaci, avian paramyxovirus-1, Toxoplasma gondii and WNV. Risk factor analyses indicated that rearing site and original release location were significantly associated with a positive serologic titer to WNV among free-flying condors. This study provides preliminary baseline data on infectious disease exposure in these populations for aiding in early disease detection and provides potentially critical information for conservation of the endangered California condor as it continues to expand its range and encounter new infectious disease threats. AIC 101.2 € Wild = hatched and raised in the wild, LAZ = raised at the Los Angeles Zoo, SDZSP = raised at San Diego Zoo Safari Park, OUT = raised outside of California, SE = standard error, CI = confidence interval, ref = reference category">
    <entity charOffset="466-474" id="83e137405afc87914e9128afa5aec46cc2b152cd.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0040280" text="obligate" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="813-823" id="83e137405afc87914e9128afa5aec46cc2b152cd.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012387" text="bronchitis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
