<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="8437870dfb10809764da7204fd758ff3e9ee85db">
  <chunk id="8437870dfb10809764da7204fd758ff3e9ee85db.c0" text="HYPOTHESIS AND THEORY ARTICLE Dangerous liaisons: molecular basis for a syndemic relationship between Kaposi's sarcoma and P. falciparum malaria">
    <entity charOffset="111-118" id="8437870dfb10809764da7204fd758ff3e9ee85db.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0100242" text="sarcoma" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="8437870dfb10809764da7204fd758ff3e9ee85db.c1" text="The most severe manifestations of malaria (caused by Plasmodium falciparum) occur as a direct result of parasitemia following invasion of erythrocytes by post-liver blood-stage merozoites, and during subsequent cyto-adherence of infected erythrocytes to the vascular endothelium. However, the disproportionate epidemiologic clustering of severe malaria with aggressive forms of endemic diseases such as Kaposi's sarcoma (KS), a neoplasm that is etiologically linked to infection with KS-associated herpesvirus (KSHV), underscores the significance of previously unexplored co-pathogenetic interactions that have the potential to modify the overall disease burden in co-infected individuals. Based on recent studies of the mechanisms that P. falciparum and KSHV have evolved to interact with their mutual human host, several new perspectives are emerging that highlight a surprising convergence of biological themes potentially underlying their associated co-morbidities. Against this background, ongoing studies are rapidly constructing a fascinating new paradigm in which the major host receptors that control parasite invasion (Basigin/CD147) and cyto-adherence (CD36) are, surprisingly, also important targets for exploitation by KSHV. In this article, we consider the major pathobiological implications of the co-option of Basigin/CD147 and CD36 signaling pathways by both P. falciparum and KSHV, not only as essential host factors for parasite persistence but also as important mediators of the pro-angiogenic phenotype within the virus-infected endothelial microenvironment. Consequently, the triangulation of interactions between P. falciparum, KSHV, and their mutual human host articulates a syndemic relationship that points to a conceptual framework for prevalence of aggressive forms of KS in malaria-endemic areas, with implications for the possibility of dual-use therapies against these debilitating infections in resource-limited parts of the world.">
    <entity charOffset="9-15" id="8437870dfb10809764da7204fd758ff3e9ee85db.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="338-344" id="8437870dfb10809764da7204fd758ff3e9ee85db.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="412-419" id="8437870dfb10809764da7204fd758ff3e9ee85db.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0100242" text="sarcoma" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="428-436" id="8437870dfb10809764da7204fd758ff3e9ee85db.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0002664" text="neoplasm" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1349-1358" id="8437870dfb10809764da7204fd758ff3e9ee85db.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0023052" text="signaling" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="8437870dfb10809764da7204fd758ff3e9ee85db.c1.e0" e2="8437870dfb10809764da7204fd758ff3e9ee85db.c1.e4" id="8437870dfb10809764da7204fd758ff3e9ee85db.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8437870dfb10809764da7204fd758ff3e9ee85db.c1.e1" e2="8437870dfb10809764da7204fd758ff3e9ee85db.c1.e4" id="8437870dfb10809764da7204fd758ff3e9ee85db.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8437870dfb10809764da7204fd758ff3e9ee85db.c1.e2" e2="8437870dfb10809764da7204fd758ff3e9ee85db.c1.e4" id="8437870dfb10809764da7204fd758ff3e9ee85db.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8437870dfb10809764da7204fd758ff3e9ee85db.c1.e3" e2="8437870dfb10809764da7204fd758ff3e9ee85db.c1.e4" id="8437870dfb10809764da7204fd758ff3e9ee85db.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
