<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="85d7376aca04b7df9b23618734948c2814ccfe19">
  <chunk id="85d7376aca04b7df9b23618734948c2814ccfe19.c0" text="Immunostimulatory activity of water- extractable polysaccharides from Cistanche deserticola as a plant adjuvant in vitro and in vivo"/>
  <chunk id="85d7376aca04b7df9b23618734948c2814ccfe19.c1" text="A safe and effective vaccine adjuvant is important in modern vaccines. Various Chinese herbal polysaccharides can activate the immune system. Cistanche deserticola (CD) is a traditional Chinese herb and an adjuvant candidate. Here, we confirmed that water-extractable polysaccharides of CD (WPCD) could modulate immune responses in vitro and in vivo. In a dose-dependent manner, WPCD significantly promoted the maturation and function of murine marrow-derived dendritic cells (BM-DCs) through up-regulating the expression levels of MHC-II, CD86, CD80, and CD40, allogenic T cell proliferation, and the yields of IL-12 and TNF-α via toll-like receptor4 (TLR4), as indicated by in vitro experiments. In addition, its immunomodulatory activity was also observed in mice. WPCD effectively improved the titers of IgG, IgG 1 and IgG 2a and markedly enhanced the proliferation of T and B cells, the production of IFN-γ and IL-4 in CD4 + T cells and the expression level of IFN-γ in CD8 + T cells better than Alum. Furthermore, WPCD could markedly up-regulate the expression levels of CD40 and CD80 on DCs in spleen and down-regulate the Treg frequency. The study suggests that polysaccharides of Cistanche deserticola are a safe and effective vaccine adjuvant for eliciting both humoral immunity and cellular immunity by activating DCs via TLR4 signaling pathway. , et al. (2018) Immunostimulatory activity of water-extractable polysaccharides from Cistanche deserticola as a plant adjuvant in vitro and in vivo. PLoS ONE 13(1): e0191356. https://">
    <entity charOffset="572-592" id="85d7376aca04b7df9b23618734948c2814ccfe19.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0042098" text="T cell proliferation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1333-1355" id="85d7376aca04b7df9b23618734948c2814ccfe19.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0034142" text="TLR4 signaling pathway" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1338-1347" id="85d7376aca04b7df9b23618734948c2814ccfe19.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0023052" text="signaling" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
