<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="8c4450ec40a0642f9c28bb561ae210baacc032fa">
  <chunk id="8c4450ec40a0642f9c28bb561ae210baacc032fa.c0" text="Middle east respiratory syndrome corona virus spike glycoprotein suppresses macrophage responses via DPP4- mediated induction of IRAK-M and PPARγ"/>
  <chunk id="8c4450ec40a0642f9c28bb561ae210baacc032fa.c1" text="via the respiratory tract and causes severe Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome by infecting lung epithelial cells and macrophages. Macrophages can readily recognize the virus and eliminate it. MERS-CoV infects cells via its Spike (S) glycoprotein that binds on Dipeptidyl-Peptidase 4 (DPP4) receptor present on macrophages. Whether this Spike/DPP4 association affects macrophage responses remains unknown. Herein we demonstrated that infection of macrophages with lentiviral particles pseudotyped with MERS-CoV S glycoprotein results in suppression of macrophage responses since it reduced the capacity of macrophages to produce TNFα and IL-6 in naive and LPS-activated THP-1 macrophages and augmented LPS-induced production of the immunosuppressive cytokine IL-10. MERS-CoV S glycoprotein induced the expression of the negative regulator of TLR signaling IRAK-M as well as of the transcriptional repressor PPARγ. Inhibition of DPP4 by its inhibitor sitagliptin or siRNA abrogated the effects of MERS-CoV S glycoprotein on IRAK-M, PPARγ and IL-10, confirming that its immunosuppressive effects were mediated by DPP4 receptor. The effect was observed both in THP-1 macrophages and human primary peripheral blood monocytes. These findings support a DPP4-mediated suppressive action of MERS-CoV in macrophages and suggest a potential target for effective elimination of its pathogenicity.">
    <entity charOffset="37-43" id="8c4450ec40a0642f9c28bb561ae210baacc032fa.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="44-49" id="8c4450ec40a0642f9c28bb561ae210baacc032fa.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="Acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="50-70" id="8c4450ec40a0642f9c28bb561ae210baacc032fa.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0002098" text="Respiratory Distress" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="847-856" id="8c4450ec40a0642f9c28bb561ae210baacc032fa.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0023052" text="signaling" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1195-1205" id="8c4450ec40a0642f9c28bb561ae210baacc032fa.c1.e4" ontology_id="HP_0030646" text="peripheral" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="8c4450ec40a0642f9c28bb561ae210baacc032fa.c1.e0" e2="8c4450ec40a0642f9c28bb561ae210baacc032fa.c1.e3" id="8c4450ec40a0642f9c28bb561ae210baacc032fa.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8c4450ec40a0642f9c28bb561ae210baacc032fa.c1.e1" e2="8c4450ec40a0642f9c28bb561ae210baacc032fa.c1.e3" id="8c4450ec40a0642f9c28bb561ae210baacc032fa.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8c4450ec40a0642f9c28bb561ae210baacc032fa.c1.e2" e2="8c4450ec40a0642f9c28bb561ae210baacc032fa.c1.e3" id="8c4450ec40a0642f9c28bb561ae210baacc032fa.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8c4450ec40a0642f9c28bb561ae210baacc032fa.c1.e3" e2="8c4450ec40a0642f9c28bb561ae210baacc032fa.c1.e4" id="8c4450ec40a0642f9c28bb561ae210baacc032fa.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
