<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="8c9382eed553c5cbe1de32cd4dc4c9975250e274">
  <chunk id="8c9382eed553c5cbe1de32cd4dc4c9975250e274.c0" text="A mechanistic spatio-temporal framework for modelling individual-to-individual transmission-With an application to the 2014-2015 West Africa Ebola outbreak"/>
  <chunk id="8c9382eed553c5cbe1de32cd4dc4c9975250e274.c1" text="In recent years there has been growing availability of individual-level spatio-temporal disease data, particularly due to the use of modern communicating devices with GPS tracking functionality. These detailed data have been proven useful for inferring disease transmission to a more refined level than previously. However, there remains a lack of statistically sound frameworks to model the underlying transmission dynamic in a mechanistic manner. Such a development is particularly crucial for enabling a general epidemic predictive framework at the individual level. In this paper we propose a new statistical framework for mechanistically modelling individual-to-individual disease transmission in a landscape with heterogeneous population density. Our methodology is first tested using simulated datasets, validating our inferential machinery. The methodology is subsequently applied to data that describes a regional Ebola outbreak in Western Africa (2014)(2015). Our results show that the methods are able to obtain estimates of key epidemiological parameters that are broadly consistent with the literature, while revealing a significantly shorter distance of transmission. More importantly, in contrast to existing approaches, we are able to perform a more general model prediction that takes into account the susceptible population. Finally, our results show that, given reasonable scenarios, the framework can be an effective surrogate for susceptible-explicit individual models which are often computationally challenging.">
    <entity charOffset="719-732" id="8c9382eed553c5cbe1de32cd4dc4c9975250e274.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0001425" text="heterogeneous" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="8c9382eed553c5cbe1de32cd4dc4c9975250e274.c2" text="PLOS Computational Biology | https://doi.Availability of individual-level, spatio-temporal disease data (e.g. GPS locations of infected individuals) has been increasing in recent years, primarily due to the increased use of modern communication devices such as mobile phones. Such data create invaluable opportunities for researchers to study disease transmission on a more refined individualto-individual level, facilitating the designs of potentially more effective control measures. However, the growing availability of such precise data has not been accompanied by development of statistically sound mechanistic frameworks. Developing such frameworks is an essential step for systematically extracting maximal information from data, in particular, evaluating the efficacy of individually-targeted control strategies and enabling forward epidemic prediction at the individual level. In this paper we develop a novel statistical framework that overcomes a few key limitations of existing approaches, enabling a machinery that can be used to infer the history of partially observed outbreaks and, more importantly, to produce a more comprehensive epidemic prediction. Our framework may also be a good surrogate for more computationally challenging individual-based models."/>
  <chunk id="8c9382eed553c5cbe1de32cd4dc4c9975250e274.c3" text="Modelling individual-level spatio-temporal disease data PLOS Computational Biology | https://doi."/>
  <chunk id="8c9382eed553c5cbe1de32cd4dc4c9975250e274.c4" text="The authors have declared that no competing interests exist. an individual-based SEIR model (see also S1 Text). Subsequently, our proposed framework is fitted to the simulated epidemics. The fitted model is then used in predictive mode to simulate epidemics (95% C.I. in grey). We first compare the incidence with 5-day intervals between the 'real' epidemics (from SEIR) and the forward-simulated epidemics (from our fitted model). We also compare the (normalized) 'real' distance-dependent spatial infectivity (solid line), with that inferred from our Modelling individual-level spatio-temporal disease data PLOS Computational Biology | https://doi."/>
</document>
