<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac">
  <chunk id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c0" text="Methanolic Extract of Rhizoma Coptidis Inhibits the Early Viral Entry Steps of Hepatitis C Virus Infection">
    <entity charOffset="79-88" id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012115" text="Hepatitis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c1" text="Hepatitis C Virus (HCV) remains an important public health threat with approximately 170 million carriers worldwide who are at risk of developing hepatitis C-associated end-stage liver diseases. Despite improvement of HCV treatment using the novel direct-acting antivirals (DAAs) targeting viral replication, there is a lack of prophylactic measures for protection against HCV infection. Identifying novel antivirals such as those that target viral entry could help broaden the therapeutic arsenal against HCV. Herein, we investigated the anti-HCV activity of the methanolic extract from Rhizoma coptidis (RC), a widely used traditional Chinese medicine documented by the WHO and experimentally reported to possess several pharmacological functions including antiviral effects. Using the cell culture-derived HCV system, we demonstrated that RC dose-dependently inhibited HCV infection of Huh-7.5 cells at non-cytotoxic concentrations. In particular, RC blocked HCV attachment and entry/fusion into the host cells without exerting any significant effect on the cell-free viral particles or modulating key host cell entry factors to HCV. Moreover, RC robustly suppressed HCV pseudoparticles infection of Huh-7.5 cells and impeded infection by several HCV genotypes. Collectively, our results identified RC as a potent antagonist to HCV entry with potential pan-genotypic properties, which deserves further evaluation for use as an anti-HCV agent.">
    <entity charOffset="0-9" id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012115" text="Hepatitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="146-155" id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012115" text="hepatitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1105-1114" id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0043657" text="host cell" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c1.e0" e2="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c1.e2" id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c1.e1" e2="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c1.e2" id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c2" text="Viruses 2018, 10, 669 2 of 12 with several notable cell surface and tight junction receptors/co-receptors including heparin sulfate proteoglycans (HSPG), cluster of differentiation 81 (CD81), low density lipoprotein receptor (LDLR), scavenger receptor class B type I (SR-BI), claudin-1 (CLDN1), and occludin (OCLN) [2, 3] . Additional factors that can influence viral entry include apolipoprotein E (ApoE), which is incorporated on infectious HCV virions [4] , and can function as an exchangeable apolipoprotein between secreted ApoE-associated lipoproteins and the HCV lipoviroparticle (LVP) to enhanced HCV infection [5] .">
    <entity charOffset="51-63" id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0009986" text="cell surface" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="68-82" id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c2.e1" ontology_id="GO_0070160" text="tight junction" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c3" text="There are over 170 million HCV carriers worldwide. HCV infection can lead to chronic hepatitis, cirrhosis, and liver cancer, and there is still no effective vaccine against the virus. While the previous standard of care consisting of PEGylated-interferon (IFN)-α in combination with ribavirin is associated with several important drawbacks including severe side effects and low efficacy against HCV genotype 1, the recent introduction of the direct-acting antivirals (DAAs) targeting the viral non-structural proteins has substantially improved the sustained virological response (SVR) in the most difficult to treat genotype 1 patients [6] . However, the DAAs also have challenges including potential toxicity, especially from drug-drug interactions (DDIs). For instance, HCV protease inhibitors are at high risk for DDIs as they are known substrates and inhibitors of cytochrome P450 (CYP) 3A4 system and can interfere with the metabolism of other drugs including immunosuppressants (e.g. cyclosporine and tacrolimus) when co-administered in liver transplant setting [7] . Other drug-drug interactions from HCV DAAs include those with acid-suppression therapies (e.g. famotidine and omeprazole) or the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) antiretroviral agents (e.g. Rilpivirine and Efavirenz), which have been shown to decrease the effectiveness of the HCV NS5A inhibitor Ledipasvir [8] and produce adverse drug reactions with the protease inhibitor Paritaprevir [7], respectively. In addition, due to the great genetic variability of HCV, selection of resistant mutants is becoming a challenge as a greater number of people are being treated in real-world settings, which can potentially lead to DAA failures [6, 9] . Therefore, continuous identification of novel candidate drugs particularly with a different mode of action to improve the current therapeutic strategies is highly envisaged.">
    <entity charOffset="77-84" id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c3.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011010" text="chronic" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="350-356" id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c3.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="930-940" id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c3.e2" ontology_id="GO_0008152" text="metabolism" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1210-1226" id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c3.e3" ontology_id="HP_0002721" text="immunodeficiency" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c3.e0" e2="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c3.e2" id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c3.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c3.e1" e2="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c3.e2" id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c3.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c3.e2" e2="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c3.e3" id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c3.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c4" text="Rhizoma Coptidis (RC) is the dried rhizome typically obtained from Coptis chinensis Franch ('Chinese goldthread'), which is a medicinal plant of the Ranunculaceae family [10]. RC is one of the most commonly used Chinese medicinal herbs (also known as 'Huang Lian') documented by the WHO [10] and is known to contain various bioactive alkaloids [11] . It is traditionally used for its &quot;heat clearing&quot; and &quot;detoxification&quot; effects such as treatment against arthritis, burns, eczema, microbial infections, and gastrointestinal diseases [10, 12, 13 ]. In addition, RC's traditional usage against infections has been correlated through several recent studies that validated its antimicrobial functions, including against several bacteria and viruses [13] . Specifically, RC and its major constituents have been shown to exert inhibitory effects against herpesvirus, respiratory syncytial virus, and mouse hepatitis A virus infections [14] [15] [16] . These precedents suggest that RC may be a potent source for the discovery of novel antiviral treatments. Since the effect of RC on HCV infection remains largely unexplored, and in an attempt to identify novel anti-HCV agents, in this study we examined the impact of the methanolic extract of RC on HCV infection. Our results demonstrated that RC could robustly inhibit HCV infection by targeting the early steps in viral entry. Specifically, the targeted steps included viral attachment and entry/fusion into the host cells. In addition, the RC-mediated inhibition of HCV is not genotype-specific as the drug equally inhibits other HCV genotypes, thereby identifying RC as a potential pan-genotypic anti-HCV agent.">
    <entity charOffset="900-909" id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c4.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012115" text="hepatitis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c5" text="Materials and Methods"/>
  <chunk id="8cd645b337ac36abbd467302eb73b4ae086e60ac.c6" text="Culture of Huh-7.5 cells (human hepatoma, Huh-7 cell derivative) and production of cell-culture derived HCV particles (HCVcc) from the Gaussia luciferase reporter-tagged Jc1FLAG2(p7-nsGluc2A) construct (genotype 2a; kindly provided by Dr. Charles M. Rice) were carried out as previously described [17] . Virus concentration was expressed as multiplicity of infection (MOI) and the"/>
</document>
