<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="8d6ac4365bc4ab3f85ea3a5c287cddfaef482707">
  <chunk id="8d6ac4365bc4ab3f85ea3a5c287cddfaef482707.c0" text="Comparison of Infectious Agents Susceptibility to Photocatalytic Effects of Nanosized Titanium and Zinc Oxides: A Practical Approach"/>
  <chunk id="8d6ac4365bc4ab3f85ea3a5c287cddfaef482707.c1" text="Nanotechnology contributes towards a more effective eradication of pathogens that have emerged in hospitals, veterinary clinics, and food processing plants and that are resistant to traditional drugs or disinfectants. Since new methods of pathogens eradication must be invented and implemented, nanotechnology seems to have become the response to that acute need. A remarkable achievement in this field of science was the creation of selfdisinfecting surfaces that base on advanced oxidation processes (AOPs). Thus, the phenomenon of photocatalysis was practically applied. Among the AOPs that have been most studied in respect of their ability to eradicate viruses, prions, bacteria, yeasts, and molds, there are the processes of TiO 2 /UV and ZnO/UV. Titanium dioxide (TiO 2 ) and zinc oxide (ZnO) act as photocatalysts, after they have been powdered to nanoparticles. Ultraviolet (UV) radiation is an agent that determines their excitation. Methods using photocatalytic properties of nanosized TiO 2 and ZnO prove to be highly efficient in inactivation of infectious agents. Therefore, they are being applied on a growing scale. AOP-based disinfection is regarded as a very promising tool that might help overcome problems in food hygiene and public health protection. The susceptibility of infectious agents to photocatalylic processes can be generally arranged in the following order: viruses &gt; prions &gt; Gram-negative bacteria &gt; Gram-positive bacteria &gt; yeasts &gt; molds.">
    <entity charOffset="352-357" id="8d6ac4365bc4ab3f85ea3a5c287cddfaef482707.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
