<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="8f44e4d806117b957383a7ee870d2dd38213f094">
  <chunk id="8f44e4d806117b957383a7ee870d2dd38213f094.c0" text="Perspective of Use of Antiviral Peptides against Influenza Virus"/>
  <chunk id="8f44e4d806117b957383a7ee870d2dd38213f094.c1" text="The threat of a worldwide influenza pandemic has greatly increased over the past decade with the emergence of highly virulent avian influenza strains. The increased frequency of drug-resistant influenza strains against currently available antiviral drugs requires urgent development of new strategies for antiviral therapy, too. The research in the field of therapeutic peptides began to develop extensively in the second half of the 20 th century. Since then, the mechanisms of action for several peptides and their antiviral prospect received large attention due to the global threat posed by viruses. Here, we discussed the therapeutic properties of peptides used in influenza treatment. Peptides with antiviral activity against influenza can be divided into three main groups. First, entry blocker peptides such as a Flupep that interact with influenza hemagglutinin, block its binding to host cells and prevent viral fusion. Second, several peptides display virucidal activity, disrupting viral envelopes, e.g., Melittin. Finally, a third set of peptides interacts with the viral polymerase complex and act as viral replication inhibitors such as PB1 derived peptides. Here, we present a review of the current literature describing the antiviral activity, mechanism and future therapeutic potential of these influenza antiviral peptides.">
    <entity charOffset="165-174" id="8f44e4d806117b957383a7ee870d2dd38213f094.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0040279" text="frequency" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="882-889" id="8f44e4d806117b957383a7ee870d2dd38213f094.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="8f44e4d806117b957383a7ee870d2dd38213f094.c1.e0" e2="8f44e4d806117b957383a7ee870d2dd38213f094.c1.e1" id="8f44e4d806117b957383a7ee870d2dd38213f094.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
