<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="8f9eda12b9470bd15725025244000aeb69b9ebb7">
  <chunk id="8f9eda12b9470bd15725025244000aeb69b9ebb7.c0" text="The glycoprotein of vesicular stomatitis virus promotes release of virus-like particles from tetherin-positive cells">
    <entity charOffset="30-40" id="8f9eda12b9470bd15725025244000aeb69b9ebb7.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0010280" text="stomatitis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="8f9eda12b9470bd15725025244000aeb69b9ebb7.c1" text="(IFN)-inducible antiviral host cell factor tetherin (BST-2, CD317). However, several viruses encode tetherin antagonists and it is at present unknown whether residual VSV spread in tetherin-positive cells is also promoted by a virus-encoded tetherin antagonist. Here, we show that the viral glycoprotein (VSV-G) antagonizes tetherin in transfected cells, although with reduced efficiency as compared to the HIV-1 Vpu protein. Tetherin antagonism did not involve alteration of tetherin expression and was partially dependent on a GXXXG motif in the transmembrane domain of VSV-G. However, mutation of the GXXXG motif did not modulate tetherin sensitivity of infectious VSV. These results identify VSV-G as a tetherin antagonist in transfected cells but fail to provide evidence for a contribution of tetherin antagonism to viral spread. OPEN ACCESS Citation: Brinkmann C, Hoffmann M, Lübke A, Nehlmeier I, Krämer-Kühl A, Winkler M, et al. (2017) The glycoprotein of vesicular stomatitis virus promotes release of virus-like particles from tetherin-positive cells. PLoS ONE 12(12): e0189073. https://doi.org/10.">
    <entity charOffset="26-35" id="8f9eda12b9470bd15725025244000aeb69b9ebb7.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0043657" text="host cell" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="548-561" id="8f9eda12b9470bd15725025244000aeb69b9ebb7.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0016021" text="transmembrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="975-985" id="8f9eda12b9470bd15725025244000aeb69b9ebb7.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0010280" text="stomatitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="8f9eda12b9470bd15725025244000aeb69b9ebb7.c1.e0" e2="8f9eda12b9470bd15725025244000aeb69b9ebb7.c1.e2" id="8f9eda12b9470bd15725025244000aeb69b9ebb7.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8f9eda12b9470bd15725025244000aeb69b9ebb7.c1.e1" e2="8f9eda12b9470bd15725025244000aeb69b9ebb7.c1.e2" id="8f9eda12b9470bd15725025244000aeb69b9ebb7.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
