<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070">
  <chunk id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c0" text="Modulation of the Host Lipid Landscape to Promote RNA Virus Replication: The Picornavirus Encephalomyocarditis Virus Converges on the Pathway Used by Hepatitis C Virus">
    <entity charOffset="150-159" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012115" text="Hepatitis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c1" text="Cardioviruses, including encephalomyocarditis virus (EMCV) and the human Saffold virus, are small non-enveloped viruses belonging to the Picornaviridae, a large family of positivesense RNA [(+)RNA] viruses. All (+)RNA viruses remodel intracellular membranes into unique structures for viral genome replication. Accumulating evidence suggests that picornaviruses from different genera use different strategies to generate viral replication organelles (ROs). For instance, enteroviruses (e.g. poliovirus, coxsackievirus, rhinovirus) rely on the Golgi-localized phosphatidylinositol 4-kinase III beta (PI4KB), while cardioviruses replicate independently of the kinase. By which mechanisms cardioviruses develop their ROs is currently unknown. Here we show that cardioviruses manipulate another PI4K, namely the ER-localized phosphatidylinositol 4-kinase III alpha (PI4KA), to generate PI4P-enriched ROs. By siRNA-mediated knockdown and pharmacological inhibition, we demonstrate that PI4KA is an essential host factor for EMCV genome replication. We reveal that the EMCV nonstructural protein 3A interacts with and is responsible for PI4KA recruitment to viral ROs. The ensuing phosphatidylinositol 4-phosphate (PI4P) proved important for the recruitment of oxysterol-binding protein (OSBP), which delivers cholesterol to EMCV ROs in a PI4P-dependent manner. PI4P lipids and cholesterol are shown to be required for the global organization of the ROs and for viral genome replication. Consistently, inhibition of OSBP expression or function efficiently blocked EMCV RNA replication. In conclusion, we describe for the first time a cellular pathway involved in the biogenesis of cardiovirus ROs. Remarkably, the same pathway was reported to promote formation of the replication sites of PLOS Pathogens | Organization for Scientific Research (NWO): ALW-820.02.018 and VICI-91812628 (FJMvK), VENI-722.012.006 (JRPMS), and VENI-863.12.005 (HMvdS), the Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (LO 1556/1-2 and TRR77, TPA1) to VL, and the hepatitis C virus, a member of the Flaviviridae family, but not other picornaviruses or flaviviruses. Thus, our results highlight the convergent recruitment by distantly related (+)RNA viruses of a host lipid-modifying pathway underlying formation of viral replication sites.">
    <entity charOffset="234-247" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0005622" text="intracellular" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="285-309" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0019079" text="viral genome replication" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1456-1480" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0019079" text="viral genome replication" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="2022-2031" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0012115" text="hepatitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c1.e0" e2="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c1.e3" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c1.e1" e2="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c1.e3" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c1.e2" e2="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c1.e3" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c2" text="All positive-sense RNA viruses [(+)RNA viruses] replicate their viral genomes in tight association with reorganized membranous structures. Viruses generate these unique structures, often termed &quot;replication organelles&quot; (ROs), by efficiently manipulating the host lipid metabolism. While the molecular mechanisms underlying RO formation by enteroviruses (e.g. poliovirus) of the family Picornaviridae have been extensively investigated, little is known about other members belonging to this large family. This study provides the first detailed insight into the RO biogenesis of encephalomyocarditis virus (EMCV), a picornavirus from the genus Cardiovirus. We reveal that EMCV hijacks the lipid kinase phosphatidylinositol-4 kinase IIIα (PI4KA) to generate viral ROs enriched in phosphatidylinositol 4-phosphate (PI4P). In EMCV-infected cells, PI4P lipids play an essential role in virus replication by recruiting another cellular protein, oxysterol-binding protein (OSBP), to the ROs. OSBP further impacts the lipid composition of the RO membranes, by mediating the exchange of PI4P with cholesterol. This membrane-modification mechanism of EMCV is remarkably similar to that of the distantly related flavivirus hepatitis C virus (HCV), while distinct from that of the closely related enteroviruses, which recruit OSBP via another PI4K, namely PI4K IIIβ (PI4KB). Thus, EMCV and HCV represent a striking case of functional convergence in (+)RNA virus evolution. University (MoBiLe) and the Leiden University Fund to AEG. The funders had no role in study design, data collection and analysis, decision to publish, or preparation of the manuscript.">
    <entity charOffset="1211-1220" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012115" text="hepatitis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c3" text="Competing Interests: The authors have declared that no competing interests exist."/>
  <chunk id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c4" text="proteins and co-opted host factors. Enteroviruses, for instance, hijack members of the secretory pathway for replication and formation of ROs [7, 8] . Among the viral nonstructural proteins, 2B, 2C, 3A as well as their precursors 2BC and 3AB contain hydrophobic domains which confer them membrane-modifying properties [9] [10] [11] . Considerable interest has been given to the study of the small viral protein 3A, which is the key viral player involved in membrane rearrangements. 3A interacts with and recruits secretory pathway components GBF1 (Golgi-specific brefeldin A-resistance guanine nucleotide exchange factor 1) and PI4KB (phosphatidylinositol-4 kinase type III isoform β) to ROs [12] [13] [14] [15] [16] . Despite intensive investigation, the role of GBF1 in enterovirus replication is not yet elucidated (reviewed in [8]). Recruitment of PI4KB to ROs leads to a significant local increase of membranes in its enzymatic product PI4P [15] . This PI4P-rich environment serves to further recruit other essential viral and host factors to replication sites, such as the viral polymerase 3D pol , which is able to specifically bind PI4P in vitro. Recently, we and others revealed that PI4P plays a central role in enterovirus replication by recruiting the oxysterol-binding protein (OSBP) to ROs [17] [18] [19] . In uninfected cells, OSBP bridges the ER and Golgi membranes by binding to the ER integral membrane protein VAP-A and to PI4P and Arf1-GTP at the trans-Golgi [20] . Through its sterol-binding domain, OSBP shuttles cholesterol from ER to the Golgi and PI4P from the Golgi to the ER, thereby generating a lipid counterflow at ER-Golgi membrane contact sites (MCSs). In enterovirus infection, OSBP exchanges PI4P for cholesterol most likely at ER-RO MCSs [18] . The unique lipid and protein composition of enterovirus ROs determines their particular 3D architecture, which consists of a complex tubulo-vesicular network, as shown in cells infected with PV and coxsackievirus B3 (CVB3) [21, 22] .">
    <entity charOffset="457-465" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c4.e0" ontology_id="GO_0016020" text="membrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1206-1213" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c4.e1" ontology_id="HP_0030645" text="central" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1385-1392" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c4.e2" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1400-1428" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c4.e3" ontology_id="GO_0030176" text="ER integral membrane protein" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1412-1420" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c4.e4" ontology_id="GO_0016020" text="membrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1654-1662" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c4.e5" ontology_id="GO_0016020" text="membrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c4.e0" e2="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c4.e1" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c4.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c4.e1" e2="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c4.e2" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c4.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c4.e1" e2="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c4.e3" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c4.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c4.e1" e2="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c4.e4" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c4.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c4.e1" e2="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c4.e5" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c4.p4" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c5" text="The lipid transfer function of OSBP at membrane contact sites is not only vital for enteroviruses, but also for HCV [23] . HCV genome replication occurs in association with an ER-derived network of specialized membrane vesicles called the membranous web (MW). Like enterovirus ROs, the HCV MW is enriched in PI4P lipids and cholesterol [23] [24] [25] . In the case of HCV, PI4P are generated through recruitment and activation of the ER-localized enzyme PI4KA (phosphatidylinositol-4-phopshate kinase type III isoform α) by the viral protein NS5A [24, 26] .">
    <entity charOffset="39-47" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c5.e0" ontology_id="GO_0016020" text="membrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="210-218" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c5.e1" ontology_id="GO_0016020" text="membrane" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c6" text="Thus far, information regarding virus-host interactions that govern the formation of cardiovirus ROs remains scarce. In a report by Zhang et al, it was suggested that autophagy supports EMCV replication [27] . The study showed that EMCV infection triggered an accumulation of autophagosome-like vesicles in the cytoplasm and that EMCV 3A colocalized with the autophagy marker LC3. However, inhibition of autophagy exerted only minor effects on virus replication [27] , which argues against a strong implication of the autophagy pathway in cardiovirus genome replication and/or formation of ROs. Evidence for a role of autophagy in virus replication also exists for enteroviruses and flaviviruses, but rather related to non-lytic virus release or modulation of host innate immune responses than viral genome replication [28] [29] [30] [31] .">
    <entity charOffset="167-176" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c6.e0" ontology_id="GO_0006914" text="autophagy" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="311-320" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c6.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005737" text="cytoplasm" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="359-368" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c6.e2" ontology_id="GO_0006914" text="autophagy" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="404-413" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c6.e3" ontology_id="GO_0006914" text="autophagy" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="518-527" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c6.e4" ontology_id="GO_0006914" text="autophagy" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="618-627" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c6.e5" ontology_id="GO_0006914" text="autophagy" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="794-818" id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c6.e6" ontology_id="GO_0019079" text="viral genome replication" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="8feaa6f0bac0c30c9b3cf6634082e8923d99b070.c7" text="Based on observations that cardioviruses do not require GBF1 or PI4KB for replication [32] [33] [34] , it is generally believed that cardiovirus replication strategies are distinct from those of enteroviruses. Here, we set out to elucidate whether cardiovirus replication depends on another PI4K isoform. By siRNA-mediated knockdown, we identified PI4KA as a key player in the replication of EMCV. EMCV 3A interacts with and recruits PI4KA to ROs, which increases local PI4P synthesis, eventually leading to downstream recruitment of OSBP. We show that the cholesterol-PI4P shuttling activity of OSBP is important for the global distribution of the ROs and for virus genome replication. Our data reveal that, by exploiting the same cellular pathway, the cardiovirus replication strategy profoundly resembles that of the distantly related HCV and is dissimilar to those of other characterized picornaviruses and flaviviruses in this critical aspect. Thus, the similarity between EMCV and HCV is a striking case of functional convergence in The Picornavirus EMCV Converges on the Host Lipid Pathway Used by HCV PLOS Pathogens |"/>
</document>
