<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d">
  <chunk id="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d.c0" text="Comparison of DNA-Hydrolyzing Antibodies from the Cerebrospinal Fluid and Serum of Patients with Multiple Sclerosis"/>
  <chunk id="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d.c1" text="It was found that high-affinity anti-DNA antibodies were one of the major components of the intrathecal IgG response in multiple sclerosis (MS) patients [Williamson et al., PNAS, 2001]. Recently we have shown that IgGs from the sera of MS patients are active in the hydrolysis of DNA. Here we have shown, for the first time, that average concentration of total proteins (132-fold), total IgGs (194-fold) and anti-DNA antibodies (200-fold) in the sera is significantly higher than that in the cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) of fifteen MS patients. The relative activities of total protein from sera and CSFs varied remarkably from patient to patient. It was surprising that the specific DNase activity of the total protein of CSF reparations were 198fold higher than the serum ones. Electrophoretically and immunologically homogeneous IgGs were obtained by sequential affinity chromatography of the CSF proteins on protein G-Sepharose and FPLC gel filtration. We present first evidence showing that IgGs from CSF not only bind but efficiently hydrolyze DNA and that average specific DNase activity of homogeneous antibodies from CSF is unpredictably ,49-fold higher than that from the sera of the same MS patients. Some possible reasons of these findings are discussed. We suggest that DNase IgGs of CSF may promote important neuropathologic mechanisms in this chronic inflammatory disorder and MS pathogenesis development. Citation: Parkhomenko TA, Doronin VB, Castellazzi M, Padroni M, Pastore M, et al. (2014) Comparison of DNA-Hydrolyzing Antibodies from the Cerebrospinal Fluid and Serum of Patients with Multiple Sclerosis. PLoS ONE 9(4): e93001.">
    <entity charOffset="228-232" id="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0004617" text="sera" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="446-450" id="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0004617" text="sera" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="588-592" id="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0004617" text="sera" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1179-1183" id="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0004617" text="sera" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1355-1362" id="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d.c1.e4" ontology_id="HP_0011010" text="chronic" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1392-1404" id="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d.c1.e5" ontology_id="GO_0009405" text="pathogenesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d.c1.e0" e2="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d.c1.e4" id="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d.c1.e1" e2="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d.c1.e4" id="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d.c1.e2" e2="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d.c1.e4" id="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d.c1.e3" e2="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d.c1.e4" id="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d.c1.e4" e2="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d.c1.e5" id="900f9612d2b06b3e32f4d460305a282d259f370d.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
