<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="90967c73d3f3e10ba8ab863b3deba3a40ca22fd1">
  <chunk id="90967c73d3f3e10ba8ab863b3deba3a40ca22fd1.c0" text="Enterovirus 71 protease 2A pro and 3C pro differentially inhibit the cellular endoplasmic reticulum-associated degradation (ERAD) pathway via distinct mechanisms, and enterovirus 71 hijacks ERAD component p97 to promote its replication">
    <entity charOffset="78-122" id="90967c73d3f3e10ba8ab863b3deba3a40ca22fd1.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0036503" text="endoplasmic reticulum-associated degradation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="111-122" id="90967c73d3f3e10ba8ab863b3deba3a40ca22fd1.c0.e1" ontology_id="GO_0009056" text="degradation" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="90967c73d3f3e10ba8ab863b3deba3a40ca22fd1.c1" text="Endoplasmic reticulum-associated degradation (ERAD) is an important function for cellular homeostasis. The mechanism of how picornavirus infection interferes with ERAD remains unclear. In this study, we demonstrated that enterovirus 71 (EV71) infection significantly inhibits cellular ERAD by targeting multiple key ERAD molecules with its proteases 2A pro and 3C pro using different mechanisms. Ubc6e was identified as the key E2 ubiquitin-conjugating enzyme in EV71 disturbed ERAD. EV71 3C pro cleaves Ubc6e at Q219G, Q260S, and Q273G. EV71 2A pro mainly inhibits the de novo synthesis of key ERAD molecules Herp and VIMP at the protein translational level. Herp differentially participates in the degradation of different glycosylated ERAD substrates α-1 antitrypsin Null Hong Kong (NHK) and the Cterminus of sonic hedgehog (SHH-C) via unknown mechanisms. p97 was identified as a host factor in EV71 replication; it redistributed and co-exists with the viral protein and other known replication-related molecules in EV71-induced replication organelles. Electron microscopy and multiple-color confocal assays also showed that EV71-induced membranous vesicles were closely associated with the endoplasmic reticulum (ER), and the ER membrane molecule RTN3 was redistributed to the viral replication complex during EV71 infection. Therefore, we propose that EV71 rearranges ER membranes and hijacks p97 from cellular ERAD to benefit its replication. These findings add to our understanding of how viruses disturb ERAD and provide potential anti-viral targets for EV71 infection. , et al. (2017) Enterovirus 71 protease 2A pro and 3C pro differentially inhibit the cellular endoplasmic reticulum-associated degradation (ERAD) pathway via distinct mechanisms, and enterovirus 71 hijacks ERAD component p97 to promote its replication. PLoS Pathog 13(10): e1006674. https://doi.org/10.">
    <entity charOffset="0-44" id="90967c73d3f3e10ba8ab863b3deba3a40ca22fd1.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0036503" text="Endoplasmic reticulum-associated degradation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="33-44" id="90967c73d3f3e10ba8ab863b3deba3a40ca22fd1.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0009056" text="degradation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="578-587" id="90967c73d3f3e10ba8ab863b3deba3a40ca22fd1.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0009058" text="synthesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="700-711" id="90967c73d3f3e10ba8ab863b3deba3a40ca22fd1.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0009056" text="degradation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1194-1215" id="90967c73d3f3e10ba8ab863b3deba3a40ca22fd1.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0005783" text="endoplasmic reticulum" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1230-1241" id="90967c73d3f3e10ba8ab863b3deba3a40ca22fd1.c1.e5" ontology_id="GO_0005789" text="ER membrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1233-1241" id="90967c73d3f3e10ba8ab863b3deba3a40ca22fd1.c1.e6" ontology_id="GO_0016020" text="membrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1281-1306" id="90967c73d3f3e10ba8ab863b3deba3a40ca22fd1.c1.e7" ontology_id="GO_0019034" text="viral replication complex" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1672-1716" id="90967c73d3f3e10ba8ab863b3deba3a40ca22fd1.c1.e8" ontology_id="GO_0036503" text="endoplasmic reticulum-associated degradation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1705-1716" id="90967c73d3f3e10ba8ab863b3deba3a40ca22fd1.c1.e9" ontology_id="GO_0009056" text="degradation" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="90967c73d3f3e10ba8ab863b3deba3a40ca22fd1.c2" text="Understanding of viral-host interactions is important for learning about viral pathogenesis and providing potential anti-viral targets. The protein quality control system, which consists of ERAD and autophagic degradation, is necessary for cellular homeostasis. Our previous studies and others have demonstrated that autophagy is involved in the EV71 lifecycle, but the role of ERAD remains unclear. In this study, we found that EV71 infection also significantly inhibits physiological ERAD at multiple points, causing ERAD substrates to remain tethered in the ER lumen. When exploring the mechanism of EV71induced ERAD inhibition, data revealed that EV71-encoded viral proteases 2A pro and 3C pro are involved, and they target different molecules with different mechanisms. We also found that ERAD component p97 was essential for the EV71 lifecycle, and it redistributed and co-exists with viral protein and other known replication-related molecules in EV71-induced replication organelles. Thus, we found a novel viral-host interaction that provides new potential anti-viral targets for EV71 infection.">
    <entity charOffset="58-66" id="90967c73d3f3e10ba8ab863b3deba3a40ca22fd1.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0007612" text="learning" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="79-91" id="90967c73d3f3e10ba8ab863b3deba3a40ca22fd1.c2.e1" ontology_id="GO_0009405" text="pathogenesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="317-326" id="90967c73d3f3e10ba8ab863b3deba3a40ca22fd1.c2.e2" ontology_id="GO_0006914" text="autophagy" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
