<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="9148852f390403699eb166e03dc4147520b7ed5e">
  <chunk id="9148852f390403699eb166e03dc4147520b7ed5e.c0" text="3. Supporting Information S3 -Cohort characteristics 3.1. Summary of the patient cohorts used in this study"/>
  <chunk id="9148852f390403699eb166e03dc4147520b7ed5e.c1" text="A total of 1002 patients were recruited and 892 were enrolled (110 were excluded based on pre-determined exclusion criteria). Based on the reference standard process described in the 'Methods' section, patients were assigned to four different diagnosis groups: (i) bacterial; (ii) viral; (iii) no apparent infectious disease or healthy (controls); and (iv) indeterminate. Patients diagnosed by the panel as having mixed infections (bacteria plus virus) were labeled as bacterial because they are managed similarly (e.g. treated with antibiotics) (see 'Methods', Fig. 1A ). In total, 89% of all enrolled patients were assigned a diagnosis, a rate which approaches the literature-documented limit [1-3]. The following sections provide a detailed description of patient characteristics, which includes all the patients with a final diagnosis (n=794): 765 patients included in the study cohort and 29 patients for which the serum samples were depleted during the screening phase (Fig. 1). ">
    <entity charOffset="72-80" id="9148852f390403699eb166e03dc4147520b7ed5e.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0040285" text="excluded" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="328-335" id="9148852f390403699eb166e03dc4147520b7ed5e.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0032322" text="healthy" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="9148852f390403699eb166e03dc4147520b7ed5e.c2" text="Patients of all ages were recruited to the study. The patients with agreed diagnosis (diagnosed patients; n=794) included more pediatric (≤18 years) than adult (&gt;18 years) patients (445 patients [56%] vs 349 [44%]). The age distribution was relatively uniform for patients aged 20-80 years and peaked at &lt;4 years of age for pediatric patients (Fig.  S2) . The observed age distribution for pediatric patients is consistent with that expected and represents the background distribution in the inpatient setting [4] (e.g., the emergency department [ED], pediatrics departments, and internal departments). Patients of both genders were recruited to the study. The patient population was balanced in respect to gender distribution (47% females, 53% males)."/>
</document>
