<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="9405b40aa26445cd02d7382bf256641ca774de46">
  <chunk id="9405b40aa26445cd02d7382bf256641ca774de46.c0" text="Cholesteryl Pullulan Encapsulated TNF-Nanoparticles Are an Effective Mucosal Vaccine Adjuvant against Influenza Virus"/>
  <chunk id="9405b40aa26445cd02d7382bf256641ca774de46.c1" text="We encapsulated tumor necrosis factor-(TNF-), a major proinflammatory cytokine, into cholesteryl pullulan (CHP) to prepare TNF/CHP nanoparticles. In this report, we describe the immune-enhancing capability of the nanoparticles to act as a vaccine adjuvant. TNF/CHP nanoparticles showed excellent storage stability and enhanced host immune responses to external immunogens. The nanoparticles were effective via the nasal route of administration for inducing systemic IgG 1 as well as mucosal IgA. We applied the nanoparticles in a model experimental influenza virus infection to investigate their adjuvant ability. TNF/CHP nanoparticles combined with a conventional split vaccine protected mice via nasal administration against a lethal challenge of A/PR/8/34 (H1N1) influenza virus. Mechanistic studies showed that the nanoparticles enhanced antigen uptake by dendritic cells (DCs) and moderately induced the expression of inflammation-related genes in nasopharynx lymphoid tissue (NALT), leading to the activation of both B and T cells. Preliminary safety study revealed no severe toxicity to TNF/CHP nanoparticles. Slight-tomoderate influences in nasal mucosa were observed only in the repeated administration and they seemed to be reversible. Our data show that TNF/CHP nanoparticles effectively enhance both humoral and cellular immunity and could be a potential adjuvant for vaccines against infectious diseases, especially in the mucosa.">
    <entity charOffset="16-21" id="9405b40aa26445cd02d7382bf256641ca774de46.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002664" text="tumor" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="22-30" id="9405b40aa26445cd02d7382bf256641ca774de46.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0001906" text="necrosis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1075-1081" id="9405b40aa26445cd02d7382bf256641ca774de46.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="9405b40aa26445cd02d7382bf256641ca774de46.c1.e0" e2="9405b40aa26445cd02d7382bf256641ca774de46.c1.e1" id="9405b40aa26445cd02d7382bf256641ca774de46.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="9405b40aa26445cd02d7382bf256641ca774de46.c1.e1" e2="9405b40aa26445cd02d7382bf256641ca774de46.c1.e2" id="9405b40aa26445cd02d7382bf256641ca774de46.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
