<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="94156e6941fe78191b5997cdeb10cb3fd06e1221">
  <chunk id="94156e6941fe78191b5997cdeb10cb3fd06e1221.c0" text="Complete genome sequence of acute viral necrosis virus associated with massive mortality outbreaks in the Chinese scallop, Chlamys farreri">
    <entity charOffset="28-33" id="94156e6941fe78191b5997cdeb10cb3fd06e1221.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="40-48" id="94156e6941fe78191b5997cdeb10cb3fd06e1221.c0.e1" ontology_id="GO_0001906" text="necrosis" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="94156e6941fe78191b5997cdeb10cb3fd06e1221.c0.e0" e2="94156e6941fe78191b5997cdeb10cb3fd06e1221.c0.e1" id="94156e6941fe78191b5997cdeb10cb3fd06e1221.c0.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="94156e6941fe78191b5997cdeb10cb3fd06e1221.c1" text="Background: Acute viral necrosis virus (AVNV) is the causative agent of a serious disease resulting in high mortality in cultured Chinese scallops, Chlamys farreri. We have sequenced and analyzed the complete genome of AVNV. Results: The AVNV genome is a linear, double-stranded DNA molecule of 210,993 bp with a nucleotide composition of 38.5% G + C. A total of 123 open reading frames were predicted to encode functional proteins, ranging from 41 to 1,878 amino acid residues. The DNA sequence of AVNV is 97% identical to that of ostreid herpesvirus 1 (OsHV-1), and the amino acid sequences of the encoded proteins of these two viruses are 94-100% identical. The genomic organization of AVNV is similar to that of OsHV-1, and consists of two unique regions (170.4 kb and 3.4 kb, respectively), each flanked by two inverted repeats (7.6 kb and 10.2 kb, respectively), with a third unique region (1.5 kb) situated between the two internal repeats. Conclusions: Our results indicate that AVNV is a variant of OsHV-1. The AVNV genome sequence provides information useful for understanding the evolution and divergence of OsHV-1 in marine molluscs.">
    <entity charOffset="12-17" id="94156e6941fe78191b5997cdeb10cb3fd06e1221.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="Acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="24-32" id="94156e6941fe78191b5997cdeb10cb3fd06e1221.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0001906" text="necrosis" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="94156e6941fe78191b5997cdeb10cb3fd06e1221.c1.e0" e2="94156e6941fe78191b5997cdeb10cb3fd06e1221.c1.e1" id="94156e6941fe78191b5997cdeb10cb3fd06e1221.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
