<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="963285bb042097a1c7b9053b74db098d24818b25">
  <chunk id="963285bb042097a1c7b9053b74db098d24818b25.c0" text="Virology Journal Reverse genetic characterization of the natural genomic deletion in SARS-Coronavirus strain Frankfurt-1 open reading frame 7b reveals an attenuating function of the 7b protein in-vitro and in-vivo"/>
  <chunk id="963285bb042097a1c7b9053b74db098d24818b25.c1" text="During the outbreak of SARS in 2002/3, a prototype virus was isolated from a patient in Frankfurt/ Germany (strain Frankfurt-1). As opposed to all other SARS-Coronavirus strains, Frankfurt-1 has a 45-nucleotide deletion in the transmembrane domain of its ORF 7b protein. When overexpressed in HEK 293 cells, the full-length protein but not the variant with the deletion caused interferon beta induction and cleavage of procaspase 3. To study the role of ORF 7b in the context of virus replication, we cloned a full genome cDNA copy of Frankfurt-1 in a bacterial artificial chromosome downstream of a T7 RNA polymerase promoter. Transfection of capped RNA transcribed from this construct yielded infectious virus that was indistinguishable from the original virus isolate. The presumed Frankfurt-1 ancestor with an intact ORF 7b was reconstructed. In CaCo-2 and HUH7 cells, but not in Vero cells, the variant carrying the ORF 7b deletion had a replicative advantage against the parental virus (4-and 6-fold increase of virus RNA in supernatant, respectively). This effect was neither associated with changes in the induction or secretion of type I interferon, nor with altered induction of apoptosis in cell culture. However, pretreatment of cells with interferon beta caused the deleted virus to replicate to higher titers than the parental strain (3.4-fold in Vero cells, 7.9-fold in CaCo-2 cells).">
    <entity charOffset="227-240" id="963285bb042097a1c7b9053b74db098d24818b25.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0016021" text="transmembrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="573-583" id="963285bb042097a1c7b9053b74db098d24818b25.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005694" text="chromosome" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1127-1136" id="963285bb042097a1c7b9053b74db098d24818b25.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0046903" text="secretion" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
