<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="9683ced158e728a9be859ddbeaf2930584e4dea8">
  <chunk id="9683ced158e728a9be859ddbeaf2930584e4dea8.c0" text="Comparative analysis of serologic cross-reactivity using convalescent sera from filovirus-experimentally infected fruit bats">
    <entity charOffset="70-74" id="9683ced158e728a9be859ddbeaf2930584e4dea8.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0004617" text="sera" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="9683ced158e728a9be859ddbeaf2930584e4dea8.c1" text="Filoviridae) cause outbreaks of viral hemorrhagic fever in sub-saharan Africa. the egyptian rousette bat (ERB) is a natural reservoir host for the marburgviruses and evidence suggests that bats are also natural reservoirs for the ebolaviruses. Although the search for the natural reservoirs of the ebolaviruses has largely involved serosurveillance of the bat population, there are no validated serological assays to screen bat sera for ebolavirus-specific IgG antibodies. Here, we generate filovirus-specific antisera by prime-boost immunization of groups of captive ERBs with all seven known culturable filoviruses. After validating a system of filovirus-specific indirect ELISAs utilizing infectious-based virus antigens for detection of virus-specific IgG antibodies from bat sera, we assess the level of serological crossreactivity between the virus-specific antisera and heterologous filovirus antigens. This data is then used to generate a filovirus antibody fingerprint that can predict which of the filovirus species in the system is most antigenically similar to the species responsible for past infection. Our filovirus IgG indirect ELISA system will be a critical tool for identifying bat species with high ebolavirus seroprevalence rates to target for longitudinal studies aimed at establishing natural reservoir host-ebolavirus relationships.">
    <entity charOffset="50-55" id="9683ced158e728a9be859ddbeaf2930584e4dea8.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0001945" text="fever" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="428-432" id="9683ced158e728a9be859ddbeaf2930584e4dea8.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0004617" text="sera" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="780-784" id="9683ced158e728a9be859ddbeaf2930584e4dea8.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0004617" text="sera" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="957-965" id="9683ced158e728a9be859ddbeaf2930584e4dea8.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="957-965" id="9683ced158e728a9be859ddbeaf2930584e4dea8.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="9683ced158e728a9be859ddbeaf2930584e4dea8.c1.e0" e2="9683ced158e728a9be859ddbeaf2930584e4dea8.c1.e1" id="9683ced158e728a9be859ddbeaf2930584e4dea8.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="9683ced158e728a9be859ddbeaf2930584e4dea8.c1.e0" e2="9683ced158e728a9be859ddbeaf2930584e4dea8.c1.e2" id="9683ced158e728a9be859ddbeaf2930584e4dea8.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="9683ced158e728a9be859ddbeaf2930584e4dea8.c1.e0" e2="9683ced158e728a9be859ddbeaf2930584e4dea8.c1.e3" id="9683ced158e728a9be859ddbeaf2930584e4dea8.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="9683ced158e728a9be859ddbeaf2930584e4dea8.c1.e0" e2="9683ced158e728a9be859ddbeaf2930584e4dea8.c1.e4" id="9683ced158e728a9be859ddbeaf2930584e4dea8.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
