<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="9903fc2ee43aca54acf2469fdc2ae8de2e62a09c">
  <chunk id="9903fc2ee43aca54acf2469fdc2ae8de2e62a09c.c0" text="Foxp3 + Regulatory T Cells Control Persistence of Viral CNS Infection"/>
  <chunk id="9903fc2ee43aca54acf2469fdc2ae8de2e62a09c.c1" text="We earlier established a model of a persistent viral CNS infection using two week old immunologically normal (genetically unmodified) mice and recombinant measles virus (MV). Using this model infection we investigated the role of regulatory T cells (Tregs) as regulators of the immune response in the brain, and assessed whether the persistent CNS infection can be modulated by manipulation of Tregs in the periphery. CD4 + CD25 + Foxp3 + Tregs were expanded or depleted during the persistent phase of the CNS infection, and the consequences for the virus-specific immune response and the extent of persistent infection were analyzed. Virus-specific CD8 + T cells predominantly recognising the H-2D b -presented viral hemagglutinin epitope MV-H 22-30 (RIVINREHL) were quantified in the brain by pentamer staining. Expansion of Tregs after intraperitoneal (i.p.) application of the superagonistic anti-CD28 antibody D665 inducing transient immunosuppression caused increased virus replication and spread in the CNS. In contrast, depletion of Tregs using diphtheria toxin (DT) in DEREG (depletion of regulatory T cells)-mice induced an increase of virus-specific CD8 + effector T cells in the brain and caused a reduction of the persistent infection. These data indicate that manipulation of Tregs in the periphery can be utilized to regulate virus persistence in the CNS.">
    <entity charOffset="278-293" id="9903fc2ee43aca54acf2469fdc2ae8de2e62a09c.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0006955" text="immune response" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="565-580" id="9903fc2ee43aca54acf2469fdc2ae8de2e62a09c.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0006955" text="immune response" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="906-914" id="9903fc2ee43aca54acf2469fdc2ae8de2e62a09c.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="906-914" id="9903fc2ee43aca54acf2469fdc2ae8de2e62a09c.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="929-938" id="9903fc2ee43aca54acf2469fdc2ae8de2e62a09c.c1.e4" ontology_id="HP_0025153" text="transient" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="9903fc2ee43aca54acf2469fdc2ae8de2e62a09c.c1.e0" e2="9903fc2ee43aca54acf2469fdc2ae8de2e62a09c.c1.e4" id="9903fc2ee43aca54acf2469fdc2ae8de2e62a09c.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="9903fc2ee43aca54acf2469fdc2ae8de2e62a09c.c1.e1" e2="9903fc2ee43aca54acf2469fdc2ae8de2e62a09c.c1.e4" id="9903fc2ee43aca54acf2469fdc2ae8de2e62a09c.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="9903fc2ee43aca54acf2469fdc2ae8de2e62a09c.c1.e2" e2="9903fc2ee43aca54acf2469fdc2ae8de2e62a09c.c1.e4" id="9903fc2ee43aca54acf2469fdc2ae8de2e62a09c.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="9903fc2ee43aca54acf2469fdc2ae8de2e62a09c.c1.e3" e2="9903fc2ee43aca54acf2469fdc2ae8de2e62a09c.c1.e4" id="9903fc2ee43aca54acf2469fdc2ae8de2e62a09c.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
