<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="99f61ec3a18d65b10e7df69531368c3afae01e45">
  <chunk id="99f61ec3a18d65b10e7df69531368c3afae01e45.c0" text="marine drugs Characterizing Eckol as a Therapeutic Aid: A Systematic Review"/>
  <chunk id="99f61ec3a18d65b10e7df69531368c3afae01e45.c1" text="The marine biosphere is a treasure trove of natural bioactive secondary metabolites and the richest source of structurally diverse and unique compounds, such as phlorotannins and halo-compounds, with high therapeutic potential. Eckol is a precursor compound representing the dibenzo-1,4-dioxin class of phlorotannins abundant in the Ecklonia species, which are marine brown algae having a ubiquitous distribution. In search of compounds having biological activity from macro algae during the past three decades, this particular compound has attracted massive attention for its multiple therapeutic properties and health benefits. Although several varieties of marine algae, seaweed, and phlorotannins have already been well scrutinized, eckol deserves a place of its own because of the therapeutic properties it possesses. The relevant information about this particular compound has not yet been collected in one place; therefore, this review focuses on its biological applications, including its potential health benefits and possible applications to restrain diseases leading to good health. The facts compiled in this review could contribute to novel insights into the functions of eckol and potentially enable its use in different uninvestigated fields. Among the marine seaweeds, brown algae, including Ecklonia species and Ishige okamurae, have been considerably evaluated as these species contains phlorotannins [9] . Phlorotannins with both phenyl and phenoxy units having different molecular weights are present in the marine brown algae [10] . According to their linkages, phlorotannins can be characterized into fuhalols and phlorethols having an ether linkage, fucols having a phenyl linkage, fucophloroethols with an ether and phenyl linkage, and eckols having a dibenzodioxin linkage. Ecklonia is the most abundant genus of kelp (brown algae) associated with the Lessoniaceae family having an affluence of eckol-type phlorotannins."/>
</document>
