<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="9aa51dd5b5755afa670398027272f2e6b4f3d83b">
  <chunk id="9aa51dd5b5755afa670398027272f2e6b4f3d83b.c0" text="BMC Microbiology Adaptive evolution of the spike gene of SARS coronavirus: changes in positively selected sites in different epidemic groups"/>
  <chunk id="9aa51dd5b5755afa670398027272f2e6b4f3d83b.c1" text="Background: It is believed that animal-to-human transmission of severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS) coronavirus (CoV) is the cause of the SARS outbreak worldwide. The spike (S) protein is one of the best characterized proteins of SARS-CoV, which plays a key role in SARS-CoV overcoming species barrier and accomplishing interspecies transmission from animals to humans, suggesting that it may be the major target of selective pressure. However, the process of adaptive evolution of S protein and the exact positively selected sites associated with this process remain unknown.">
    <entity charOffset="64-70" id="9aa51dd5b5755afa670398027272f2e6b4f3d83b.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="71-76" id="9aa51dd5b5755afa670398027272f2e6b4f3d83b.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="9aa51dd5b5755afa670398027272f2e6b4f3d83b.c2" text="Results: By investigating the adaptive evolution of S protein, we identified twelve amino acid sites (75, 239, 244, 311, 479, 609, 613, 743, 765, 778, 1148, and 1163) in the S protein under positive selective pressure. Based on phylogenetic tree and epidemiological investigation, SARS outbreak was divided into three epidemic groups: 02-04 interspecies, 03-early-mid, and 03-late epidemic groups in the present study. Positive selection was detected in the first two groups, which represent the course of SARS-CoV interspecies transmission and of viral adaptation to human host, respectively. In contrast, purifying selection was detected in 03-late group. These indicate that S protein experiences variable positive selective pressures before reaching stabilization. A total of 25 sites in 02-04 interspecies epidemic group and 16 sites in 03-early-mid epidemic group were identified under positive selection. The identified sites were different between these two groups except for site 239, which suggests that positively selected sites are changeable between groups. Moreover, it was showed that a larger proportion (24%) of positively selected sites was located in receptor-binding domain (RBD) than in heptad repeat (HR)1-HR2 region in 02-04 interspecies epidemic group (p = 0.0208), and a greater percentage (25%) of these sites occurred in HR1-HR2 region than in RBD in 03-early-mid epidemic group (p = 0.0721). These suggest that functionally different domains of S protein may not experience same positive selection in each epidemic group. In addition, three specific replacements (F360S, T487S and L665S) were only found between 03human SARS-CoVs and strains from 02-04 interspecies epidemic group, which reveals that selective sweep may also force the evolution of S genes before the jump of SARS-CoVs into human hosts. Since certain residues at these positively selected sites are associated with receptor recognition and/or membrane fusion, they are likely to be the crucial residues for animal-to-human transmission of SARS-CoVs, and subsequent adaptation to human hosts.">
    <entity charOffset="1938-1946" id="9aa51dd5b5755afa670398027272f2e6b4f3d83b.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0016020" text="membrane" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="9aa51dd5b5755afa670398027272f2e6b4f3d83b.c3" text="The variation of positive selective pressures and positively selected sites are likely to contribute to the adaptive evolution of S protein from animals to humans."/>
</document>
