<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="9bd22fc1297bd20710ca26f6e79b6339d576bb74">
  <chunk id="9bd22fc1297bd20710ca26f6e79b6339d576bb74.c0" text="Accelerated disease progression and robust innate host response in aged SIVmac239-infected Chinese rhesus macaques is associated with enhanced immunosenescence"/>
  <chunk id="9bd22fc1297bd20710ca26f6e79b6339d576bb74.c1" text="The elderly population infected with HIV-1 is often characterized by the rapid AIDS progression and poor treatment outcome, possibly because of immunosenescence resulting from both HIV infection and aging. However, this hypothesis remains to be fully tested. Here, we studied 6 young and 12 old Chinese rhesus macaques (ChRM) over the course of three months after simian immunodeficiency virus (SIV) SIVmac239 infection. Old ChRM showed a higher risk of accelerated AIDS development than did young macaques, owing to rapidly elevated plasma viral loads and decreased levels of CD4 + T cells. The low frequency of na誰ve CD4 + T cells before infection was strongly predictive of an increased disease progression, whereas the severe depletion of CD4 + T cells and the rapid proliferation of na誰ve lymphocytes accelerated the exhaustion of na誰ve lymphocytes in old ChRM. Moreover, in old ChRM, a robust innate host response with defective regulation was associated with a compensation for na誰ve T cell depletion and a high level of immune activation. Therefore, we suggest that immunosenescence plays an important role in the accelerated AIDS progression in elderly individuals and that SIV-infected old ChRM may be a favorable model for studying AIDS pathogenesis and researching therapies for elderly AIDS patients.">
    <entity charOffset="371-387" id="9bd22fc1297bd20710ca26f6e79b6339d576bb74.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002721" text="immunodeficiency" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="600-609" id="9bd22fc1297bd20710ca26f6e79b6339d576bb74.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0040279" text="frequency" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="723-729" id="9bd22fc1297bd20710ca26f6e79b6339d576bb74.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1248-1260" id="9bd22fc1297bd20710ca26f6e79b6339d576bb74.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0009405" text="pathogenesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="9bd22fc1297bd20710ca26f6e79b6339d576bb74.c1.e0" e2="9bd22fc1297bd20710ca26f6e79b6339d576bb74.c1.e3" id="9bd22fc1297bd20710ca26f6e79b6339d576bb74.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="9bd22fc1297bd20710ca26f6e79b6339d576bb74.c1.e1" e2="9bd22fc1297bd20710ca26f6e79b6339d576bb74.c1.e3" id="9bd22fc1297bd20710ca26f6e79b6339d576bb74.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="9bd22fc1297bd20710ca26f6e79b6339d576bb74.c1.e2" e2="9bd22fc1297bd20710ca26f6e79b6339d576bb74.c1.e3" id="9bd22fc1297bd20710ca26f6e79b6339d576bb74.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="9bd22fc1297bd20710ca26f6e79b6339d576bb74.c2" text="Published: xx xx xxxx OPEN www.nature.com/scientificreports/ 2 Scientific RepoRts | 7: 37 |"/>
</document>
