<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="9d941db9f06f446ae113c5f76f7597553a2f365b">
  <chunk id="9d941db9f06f446ae113c5f76f7597553a2f365b.c0" text="Overexpression of the nucleocapsid protein of Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus up-regulates CXCL10">
    <entity charOffset="22-34" id="9d941db9f06f446ae113c5f76f7597553a2f365b.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0019013" text="nucleocapsid" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="9d941db9f06f446ae113c5f76f7597553a2f365b.c1" text="Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus (MERS-CoV) causes respiratory diseases in humans and has a high mortality rate. During infection, MERS-CoV regulates several host cellular processes including antiviral response genes. In order to determine if the nucleocapsid protein of MERS-CoV (MERS-N) plays a role in viral-host interactions, a murine monoclonal antibody was generated so as to allow detection of the protein in infected cells as well as in overexpression system. Then, MERS-N was stably overexpressed in A549 cells, and a PCR array containing 84 genes was used to screen for genes transcriptionally regulated by it. Several up-regulated antiviral genes, namely TNF, IL6, IL8, and CXCL10, were selected for independent validation in transiently transfected 293FT cells. Out of these, the overexpression of MERS-N was found to up-regulate CXCL10 at both transcriptional and translational levels. Interestingly, CXCL10 has been reported to be up-regulated in MERS-CoV infected airway epithelial cells and lung fibroblast cells, as well as monocyte-derived macrophages and dendritic cells. High secretions and persistent increase of CXCL10 in MERS-CoV patients have been also associated with severity of disease. To our knowledge, this is the first report showing that the MERS-N protein is one of the contributing factors for CXCL10 up-regulation during infection. In addition, our results showed that a fragment consisting of residues 196-413 in MERS-N is sufficient to up-regulate CXCL10, while the N-terminal domain and serine-arginine (SR)-rich motif of MERS-N do not play a role in this up-regulation.">
    <entity charOffset="204-222" id="9d941db9f06f446ae113c5f76f7597553a2f365b.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0051607" text="antiviral response" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="259-271" id="9d941db9f06f446ae113c5f76f7597553a2f365b.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0019013" text="nucleocapsid" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="362-370" id="9d941db9f06f446ae113c5f76f7597553a2f365b.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="362-370" id="9d941db9f06f446ae113c5f76f7597553a2f365b.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1205-1213" id="9d941db9f06f446ae113c5f76f7597553a2f365b.c1.e4" ontology_id="HP_0012824" text="severity" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="9d941db9f06f446ae113c5f76f7597553a2f365b.c1.e0" e2="9d941db9f06f446ae113c5f76f7597553a2f365b.c1.e4" id="9d941db9f06f446ae113c5f76f7597553a2f365b.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="9d941db9f06f446ae113c5f76f7597553a2f365b.c1.e1" e2="9d941db9f06f446ae113c5f76f7597553a2f365b.c1.e4" id="9d941db9f06f446ae113c5f76f7597553a2f365b.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="9d941db9f06f446ae113c5f76f7597553a2f365b.c1.e2" e2="9d941db9f06f446ae113c5f76f7597553a2f365b.c1.e4" id="9d941db9f06f446ae113c5f76f7597553a2f365b.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="9d941db9f06f446ae113c5f76f7597553a2f365b.c1.e3" e2="9d941db9f06f446ae113c5f76f7597553a2f365b.c1.e4" id="9d941db9f06f446ae113c5f76f7597553a2f365b.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
