<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="a4995af42a012dd1b7f8da3936d79d78d0e24405">
  <chunk id="a4995af42a012dd1b7f8da3936d79d78d0e24405.c0" text="Key project of National Natural Science Funds from National Natural Science Foundation of China"/>
  <chunk id="a4995af42a012dd1b7f8da3936d79d78d0e24405.c1" text="The nonstructural protein 2 (NSP2) is considered to be one of crucial viral proteins in the replication and pathogenesis of porcine reproductive and respiratory syndrome virus (PRRSV). In the present study, the host cellular proteins that interact with the NSP2 of PRRSV were immunoprecipitated with anti-Myc antibody from the MARC-145 cells infected by a recombinant PRRSV with 3xMyc tag insertion in its NSP2-coding region, and then 285 cellular proteins interacting with NSP2 were identified by LC-MS/MS. The Gene Ontology and enriched KEGG Pathway bioinformatics analyses indicated that the identified proteins could be assigned to different subcellular locations and functional classes. Functional analysis of the interactome profile highlighted cellular pathways associated with infectious disease, translation, immune system, nervous system and signal transduction. Two interested cellular proteins-BCL2-associated athanogene 6 (BAG6) and apoptosisinducing factor 1 (AIF1) which may involve in transporting of NSP2 to Endoplasmic reticulum (ER) or PRRSV-driven apoptosis were validated by Western blot. The interactome data between PRRSV NSP2 and cellular proteins contribute to the understanding of the roles of NSP2 in the replication and pathogenesis of PRRSV, and also provide novel cellular target proteins for elucidating the associated molecular mechanisms of the interaction of host cellular proteins with viral proteins in regulating the viral replication.">
    <entity charOffset="108-120" id="a4995af42a012dd1b7f8da3936d79d78d0e24405.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0009405" text="pathogenesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="309-317" id="a4995af42a012dd1b7f8da3936d79d78d0e24405.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="309-317" id="a4995af42a012dd1b7f8da3936d79d78d0e24405.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1025-1046" id="a4995af42a012dd1b7f8da3936d79d78d0e24405.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0005783" text="Endoplasmic reticulum" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1248-1260" id="a4995af42a012dd1b7f8da3936d79d78d0e24405.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0009405" text="pathogenesis" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
