<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="a4f95bc90ea589d614f0e2a70daf60fbd7d23c31">
  <chunk id="a4f95bc90ea589d614f0e2a70daf60fbd7d23c31.c0" text="Antigenic and Pathogenic Characteristics of QX-Type Avian Infectious Bronchitis Virus Strains Isolated in Southwestern China">
    <entity charOffset="69-79" id="a4f95bc90ea589d614f0e2a70daf60fbd7d23c31.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012387" text="Bronchitis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="a4f95bc90ea589d614f0e2a70daf60fbd7d23c31.c1" text="The QX-type avian infectious bronchitis virus (IBV) is still a prevalent genotype in Southwestern China. To analyze the antigenicity and pathogenicity characteristics of the dominant genotype strains (QX-type), S1 gene sequence analysis, virus cross-neutralization tests, and pathogenicity test of eight QX-type IBV isolates were conducted. Sequence analysis showed that the nucleotide homology between the eight strains was high, but distantly related to H120 and 4/91 vaccine strains. Cross-neutralization tests showed that all eight strains isolated from 2015 and 2017 belonged to the same serotype, but exhibited antigenic variations over time. The pathogenicity test of the five QX-type IBV isolates showed that only three strains, CK/CH/SC/DYW/16, CK/CH/SC/MS/17, and CK/CH/SC/GH/15, had a high mortality rate with strong respiratory and renal pathogenicity, whereas CK/CH/SC/PZ/17 and CK/CH/SC/DYYJ/17 caused only mild clinical symptoms and tissue lesions. Our results indicate that the prevalent QX-type IBVs displayed antigenic variations and pathogenicity difference. These findings may provide reference for research on the evolution of IBV and vaccine preparation of infectious bronchitis (IB).">
    <entity charOffset="29-39" id="a4f95bc90ea589d614f0e2a70daf60fbd7d23c31.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012387" text="bronchitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="921-925" id="a4f95bc90ea589d614f0e2a70daf60fbd7d23c31.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012825" text="mild" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1190-1200" id="a4f95bc90ea589d614f0e2a70daf60fbd7d23c31.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0012387" text="bronchitis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="a4f95bc90ea589d614f0e2a70daf60fbd7d23c31.c2" text="The spike 1 (S1) gene is highly variable among IBV strains and encodes epitopes, which can induce the production of specific neutralizing antibodies [7] . The partial or the full-length of the S gene has been used in the molecular characterization of IBV isolates. The antigenic relatedness and receptor binding with host cells are influenced by hypervariable regions (HVRs) in the S1 gene [8-10]; further, the S gene and 5a accessory gene are responsible for the attenuation of virulent IBV via a suitable reverse-genetic system [11] . Therefore, the differences in the genotypes, antigenicity, and pathogenicity existing among IBVs are mainly related to the S1 subunit of the IBV spike protein.">
    <entity charOffset="304-311" id="a4f95bc90ea589d614f0e2a70daf60fbd7d23c31.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="a4f95bc90ea589d614f0e2a70daf60fbd7d23c31.c3" text="Since the early 1980s, IBV has been continuously isolated in China, and QX genotype has become the prevalent genotype [12] [13] [14] . Our previous study showed that isolates obtained from Southwestern China between 2008 and 2016 mainly belong to the QX genotype [12, 15] . Other reports have shown that QX-type IBVs epidemic is a major problem in the poultry industry in Europe, Japan, Korea, Russia, Africa, and the Middle East [16] [17] [18] . However, even with the wide use of IBV vaccines, such as H120 and 4/91 for QX-type IBV infection, immune failure occurred frequently [4, 19] . QX-like IBV has become a challenge to the prevention and control IBV. Therefore, it is crucial to gain a better understanding of the antigenicity and pathogenesis of QX-like IBV. Previously, comparative studies have been conducted to elucidate differential pathogenicity among two QX-like IBVs with 94.1% similarities of the S1 gene [20] . Very minor changes in the IBV genome can lead to differences in pathogenicity [21] ; therefore, comparative studies involving more QX-type IBVs are required. The present study was conducted with the aim to elucidate the S1 gene differences of eight QX-type IBVs isolated from vaccinated chicken flocks in Southwestern China and describe its antigenicity and pathogenicity characteristics.">
    <entity charOffset="740-752" id="a4f95bc90ea589d614f0e2a70daf60fbd7d23c31.c3.e0" ontology_id="GO_0009405" text="pathogenesis" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
