<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="a5d44eaf14b7ed5402af3501540147d36b314824">
  <chunk id="a5d44eaf14b7ed5402af3501540147d36b314824.c0" text="Large Eddy Simulation of Air Escape through a Hospital Isolation Room Single Hinged Doorway-Validation by Using Tracer Gases and Simulated Smoke Videos"/>
  <chunk id="a5d44eaf14b7ed5402af3501540147d36b314824.c1" text="The use of hospital isolation rooms has increased considerably in recent years due to the worldwide outbreaks of various emerging infectious diseases. However, the passage of staff through isolation room doors is suspected to be a cause of containment failure, especially in case of hinged doors. It is therefore important to minimize inadvertent contaminant airflow leakage across the doorway during such movements. To this end, it is essential to investigate the behavior of such airflows, especially the overall volume of air that can potentially leak across the doorway during door-opening and human passage. Experimental measurements using full-scale mock-ups are expensive and labour intensive. A useful alternative approach is the application of Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD) modelling using a time-resolved Large Eddy Simulation (LES) method. In this study simulated air flow patterns are qualitatively compared with experimental ones, and the simulated total volume of air that escapes is compared with the experimentally measured volume. It is shown that the LES method is able to reproduce, at room scale, the complex transient airflows generated during door-opening/closing motions and the passage of a human figure through the doorway between two rooms. This was a basic test case that was performed in an isothermal environment without ventilation. However, the advantage of the CFD approach is that the addition of ventilation airflows and a temperature difference between the rooms is, in principle, a relatively simple task. A standard method to observe flow structures is dosing smoke into the flow. In this paper we introduce graphical methods to simulate smoke experiments by LES, making it very easy to compare the CFD simulation to the experiments. The results demonstrate that the transient CFD simulation is a promising tool to compare different isolation room scenarios without the need to construct full-scale experimental models. The CFD model is able to reproduce the complex airflows and estimate the volume of air escaping as a function of time. In this test, the calculated migrated air volume in the CFD model differed by 20% from the experimental tracer gas measurements. In the case containing only a hinged door operation, without passage, the difference was only 10%.">
    <entity charOffset="465-473" id="a5d44eaf14b7ed5402af3501540147d36b314824.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0007610" text="behavior" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1134-1143" id="a5d44eaf14b7ed5402af3501540147d36b314824.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0025153" text="transient" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1809-1818" id="a5d44eaf14b7ed5402af3501540147d36b314824.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0025153" text="transient" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="2192-2195" id="a5d44eaf14b7ed5402af3501540147d36b314824.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0034005" text="gas" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="a5d44eaf14b7ed5402af3501540147d36b314824.c1.e0" e2="a5d44eaf14b7ed5402af3501540147d36b314824.c1.e1" id="a5d44eaf14b7ed5402af3501540147d36b314824.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="a5d44eaf14b7ed5402af3501540147d36b314824.c1.e0" e2="a5d44eaf14b7ed5402af3501540147d36b314824.c1.e2" id="a5d44eaf14b7ed5402af3501540147d36b314824.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="a5d44eaf14b7ed5402af3501540147d36b314824.c1.e1" e2="a5d44eaf14b7ed5402af3501540147d36b314824.c1.e3" id="a5d44eaf14b7ed5402af3501540147d36b314824.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="a5d44eaf14b7ed5402af3501540147d36b314824.c1.e2" e2="a5d44eaf14b7ed5402af3501540147d36b314824.c1.e3" id="a5d44eaf14b7ed5402af3501540147d36b314824.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
