<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="a65b8907068dde79fb7cc6e885a745607ed1f371">
  <chunk id="a65b8907068dde79fb7cc6e885a745607ed1f371.c0" text="Vaccination Method Affects Immune Response and Bacterial Growth but Not Protection in the Salmonella Typhimurium Animal Model of Typhoid">
    <entity charOffset="27-42" id="a65b8907068dde79fb7cc6e885a745607ed1f371.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0006955" text="Immune Response" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="57-63" id="a65b8907068dde79fb7cc6e885a745607ed1f371.c0.e1" ontology_id="GO_0040007" text="Growth" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="a65b8907068dde79fb7cc6e885a745607ed1f371.c1" text="Understanding immune responses elicited by vaccines, together with immune responses required for protection, is fundamental to designing effective vaccines and immunisation programs. This study examines the effects of the route of administration of a live attenuated vaccine on its interactions with, and stimulation of, the murine immune system as well as its ability to increase survival and provide protection from colonisation by a virulent challenge strain. We assess the effect of administration method using the murine model for typhoid, where animals are infected with S. Typhimurium. Mice were vaccinated either intravenously or orally with the same live attenuated S. Typhimurium strain and data were collected on vaccine strain growth, shedding and stimulation of antibodies and cytokines. Following vaccination, mice were challenged with a virulent strain of S. Typhimurium and the protection conferred by the different vaccination routes was measured in terms of challenge suppression and animal survival. The main difference in immune stimulation found in this study was the development of a secretory IgA response in orally-vaccinated mice, which was absent in IV vaccinated mice. While both strains showed similar protection in terms of challenge suppression in systemic organs (spleen and liver) as well as survival, they differed in terms of challenge suppression of virulent pathogens in gut-associated organs. This difference in gut colonisation presents important questions around the ability of vaccines to prevent shedding and transmission. These findings demonstrate that while protection conferred by two vaccines can appear to be the same, the mechanisms controlling the protection can differ and have important implications for infection dynamics within a population."/>
</document>
