<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903">
  <chunk id="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c0" text="A Systematic Analysis of Host Factors Reveals a Med23-Interferon-l Regulatory Axis against Herpes Simplex Virus Type 1 Replication"/>
  <chunk id="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1" text="Herpes simplex virus type 1 (HSV-1) is a neurotropic virus causing vesicular oral or genital skin lesions, meningitis and other diseases particularly harmful in immunocompromised individuals. To comprehensively investigate the complex interaction between HSV-1 and its host we combined two genome-scale screens for host factors (HFs) involved in virus replication. A yeast two-hybrid screen for protein interactions and a RNA interference (RNAi) screen with a druggable genome small interfering RNA (siRNA) library confirmed existing and identified novel HFs which functionally influence HSV-1 infection. Bioinformatic analyses found the 358 HFs were enriched for several pathways and multi-protein complexes. Of particular interest was the identification of Med23 as a strongly anti-viral component of the largely pro-viral Mediator complex, which links specific transcription factors to RNA polymerase II. The anti-viral effect of Med23 on HSV-1 replication was confirmed in gain-of-function gene overexpression experiments, and this inhibitory effect was specific to HSV-1, as a range of other viruses including Vaccinia virus and Semliki Forest virus were unaffected by Med23 depletion. We found Med23 significantly upregulated expression of the type III interferon family (IFN-l) at the mRNA and protein level by directly interacting with the transcription factor IRF7. The synergistic effect of Med23 and IRF7 on IFN-l induction suggests this is the major transcription factor for IFN-l expression. Genotypic analysis of patients suffering recurrent orofacial HSV-1 outbreaks, previously shown to be deficient in IFN-l secretion, found a significant correlation with a single nucleotide polymorphism in the IFN-l3 (IL28b) promoter strongly linked to Hepatitis C disease and treatment outcome. This paper describes a link between Med23 and IFN-l, provides evidence for the crucial role of IFN-l in HSV-1 immune control, and highlights the power of integrative genome-scale approaches to identify HFs critical for disease progression and outcome.">
    <entity charOffset="107-117" id="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0001287" text="meningitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="422-438" id="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0016246" text="RNA interference" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="440-444" id="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0016246" text="RNAi" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1160-1170" id="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0032321" text="unaffected" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1546-1555" id="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.e4" ontology_id="HP_0031796" text="recurrent" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1756-1765" id="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.e5" ontology_id="HP_0012115" text="Hepatitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.e0" e2="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.e1" id="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.e0" e2="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.e2" id="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.e1" e2="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.e3" id="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.e1" e2="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.e4" id="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.e1" e2="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.e5" id="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.e2" e2="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.e3" id="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.p5" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.e2" e2="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.e4" id="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.p6" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.e2" e2="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.e5" id="a7344a564121bf1e3f995911e78c17b1b2aee903.c1.p7" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
