<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="a7c6ab514af0b9e5edc73e08e496ceb65111cfa9">
  <chunk id="a7c6ab514af0b9e5edc73e08e496ceb65111cfa9.c0" text="A Canadian Critical Care Trials Group project in collaboration with the international forum for acute care trialists -Collaborative H1N1 Adjuvant Treatment pilot trial (CHAT): study protocol and design of a randomized controlled trial">
    <entity charOffset="96-101" id="a7c6ab514af0b9e5edc73e08e496ceb65111cfa9.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="a7c6ab514af0b9e5edc73e08e496ceb65111cfa9.c1" text="Background: Swine origin influenza A/H1N1 infection (H1N1) emerged in early 2009 and rapidly spread to humans. For most infected individuals, symptoms were mild and self-limited; however, a small number developed a more severe clinical syndrome characterized by profound respiratory failure with hospital mortality ranging from 10 to 30%. While supportive care and neuraminidase inhibitors are the main treatment for influenza, data from observational and interventional studies suggest that the course of influenza can be favorably influenced by agents not classically considered as influenza treatments. Multiple observational studies have suggested that HMGCoA reductase inhibitors (statins) can exert a class effect in attenuating inflammation. The Collaborative H1N1 Adjuvant Treatment (CHAT) Pilot Trial sought to investigate the feasibility of conducting a trial during a global pandemic in critically ill patients with H1N1 with the goal of informing the design of a larger trial powered to determine impact of statins on important outcomes.">
    <entity charOffset="156-160" id="a7c6ab514af0b9e5edc73e08e496ceb65111cfa9.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012825" text="mild" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="220-226" id="a7c6ab514af0b9e5edc73e08e496ceb65111cfa9.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="262-270" id="a7c6ab514af0b9e5edc73e08e496ceb65111cfa9.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0012829" text="profound" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="271-290" id="a7c6ab514af0b9e5edc73e08e496ceb65111cfa9.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0002878" text="respiratory failure" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
