<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="aa8a9f4a432fa52294b1fa674b3ffbeadeff563f">
  <chunk id="aa8a9f4a432fa52294b1fa674b3ffbeadeff563f.c0" text="Human Coronavirus NL63 Open Reading Frame 3 encodes a virion-incorporated N-glycosylated membrane protein">
    <entity charOffset="89-97" id="aa8a9f4a432fa52294b1fa674b3ffbeadeff563f.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0016020" text="membrane" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="aa8a9f4a432fa52294b1fa674b3ffbeadeff563f.c1" text="Background: Human pathogenic coronavirus NL63 (hCoV-NL63) is a group 1 (alpha) coronavirus commonly associated with respiratory tract infections. In addition to known non-structural and structural proteins all coronaviruses have one or more accessory proteins whose functions are mostly unknown. Our study focuses on hCoV-NL63 open reading frame 3 (ORF 3) which is a highly conserved accessory protein among coronaviruses. Results: In-silico analysis of the 225 amino acid sequence of hCoV-NL63 ORF 3 predicted a triple membranespanning protein. Expression in infected CaCo-2 and LLC-MK2 cells was confirmed by immunofluorescence and Western blot analysis. The protein was detected within the endoplasmatic reticulum/Golgi intermediate compartment (ERGIC) where coronavirus assembly and budding takes place. Subcellular localization studies using recombinant ORF 3 protein transfected in Huh-7 cells revealed occurrence in ERGIC, Golgi-and lysosomal compartments. By fluorescence microscopy of differently tagged envelope (E), membrane (M) and nucleocapsid (N) proteins it was shown that ORF 3 protein colocalizes extensively with E and M within the ERGIC. Using N-terminally FLAG-tagged ORF 3 protein and an antiserum specific to the C-terminus we verified the proposed topology of an extracellular N-terminus and a cytosolic C-terminus. By in-vitro translation analysis and subsequent endoglycosidase H digestion we showed that ORF 3 protein is N-glycosylated at the N-terminus. Analysis of purified viral particles revealed that ORF 3 protein is incorporated into virions and is therefore an additional structural protein.">
    <entity charOffset="749-754" id="aa8a9f4a432fa52294b1fa674b3ffbeadeff563f.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0005793" text="ERGIC" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="820-832" id="aa8a9f4a432fa52294b1fa674b3ffbeadeff563f.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0051179" text="localization" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="923-928" id="aa8a9f4a432fa52294b1fa674b3ffbeadeff563f.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0005793" text="ERGIC" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1013-1021" id="aa8a9f4a432fa52294b1fa674b3ffbeadeff563f.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0031975" text="envelope" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1027-1035" id="aa8a9f4a432fa52294b1fa674b3ffbeadeff563f.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0016020" text="membrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1044-1056" id="aa8a9f4a432fa52294b1fa674b3ffbeadeff563f.c1.e5" ontology_id="GO_0019013" text="nucleocapsid" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1150-1155" id="aa8a9f4a432fa52294b1fa674b3ffbeadeff563f.c1.e6" ontology_id="GO_0005793" text="ERGIC" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1286-1299" id="aa8a9f4a432fa52294b1fa674b3ffbeadeff563f.c1.e7" ontology_id="GO_0005576" text="extracellular" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1351-1362" id="aa8a9f4a432fa52294b1fa674b3ffbeadeff563f.c1.e8" ontology_id="GO_0006412" text="translation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1405-1414" id="aa8a9f4a432fa52294b1fa674b3ffbeadeff563f.c1.e9" ontology_id="GO_0007586" text="digestion" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="aa8a9f4a432fa52294b1fa674b3ffbeadeff563f.c2" text="Conclusions: This study is the first extensive expression analysis of a group 1 hCoV-ORF 3 protein. We give evidence that ORF 3 protein is a structural N-glycosylated and virion-incorporated protein."/>
</document>
