<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="aa92ab17aef0b2ef391bad5a3590956c72794948">
  <chunk id="aa92ab17aef0b2ef391bad5a3590956c72794948.c0" text="Estimating Infection Attack Rates and Severity in Real Time during an Influenza Pandemic: Analysis of Serial Cross-Sectional Serologic Surveillance Data">
    <entity charOffset="38-46" id="aa92ab17aef0b2ef391bad5a3590956c72794948.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012824" text="Severity" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="aa92ab17aef0b2ef391bad5a3590956c72794948.c1" text="Background: In an emerging influenza pandemic, estimating severity (the probability of a severe outcome, such as hospitalization, if infected) is a public health priority. As many influenza infections are subclinical, sero-surveillance is needed to allow reliable real-time estimates of infection attack rate (IAR) and severity.">
    <entity charOffset="58-66" id="aa92ab17aef0b2ef391bad5a3590956c72794948.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012824" text="severity" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="89-95" id="aa92ab17aef0b2ef391bad5a3590956c72794948.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="319-327" id="aa92ab17aef0b2ef391bad5a3590956c72794948.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0012824" text="severity" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="aa92ab17aef0b2ef391bad5a3590956c72794948.c2" text="Methods and Findings: We tested 14,766 sera collected during the first wave of the 2009 pandemic in Hong Kong using viral microneutralization. We estimated IAR and infection-hospitalization probability (IHP) from the serial cross-sectional serologic data and hospitalization data. Had our serologic data been available weekly in real time, we would have obtained reliable IHP estimates 1 wk after, 1-2 wk before, and 3 wk after epidemic peak for individuals aged 5-14 y, 15-29 y, and 30-59 y. The ratio of IAR to pre-existing seroprevalence, which decreased with age, was a major determinant for the timeliness of reliable estimates. If we began sero-surveillance 3 wk after community transmission was confirmed, with 150, 350, and 500 specimens per week for individuals aged 5-14 y, 15-19 y, and 20-29 y, respectively, we would have obtained reliable IHP estimates for these age groups 4 wk before the peak. For 30-59 y olds, even 800 specimens per week would not have generated reliable estimates until the peak because the ratio of IAR to pre-existing seroprevalence for this age group was low. The performance of serial cross-sectional sero-surveillance substantially deteriorates if test specificity is not near 100% or pre-existing seroprevalence is not near zero. These potential limitations could be mitigated by choosing a higher titer cutoff for seropositivity. If the epidemic doubling time is longer than 6 d, then serial cross-sectional serosurveillance with 300 specimens per week would yield reliable estimates when IAR reaches around 6%-10%.">
    <entity charOffset="39-43" id="aa92ab17aef0b2ef391bad5a3590956c72794948.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0004617" text="sera" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="aa92ab17aef0b2ef391bad5a3590956c72794948.c3" text="Conclusions: Serial cross-sectional serologic data together with clinical surveillance data can allow reliable real-time estimates of IAR and severity in an emerging pandemic. Sero-surveillance for pandemics should be considered.">
    <entity charOffset="142-150" id="aa92ab17aef0b2ef391bad5a3590956c72794948.c3.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012824" text="severity" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
