<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="ad79f4149f66651ceee0f251347fc5093294f68d">
  <chunk id="ad79f4149f66651ceee0f251347fc5093294f68d.c0" text="Multifunctional roles of leader protein of foot-and-mouth disease viruses in suppressing host antiviral responses"/>
  <chunk id="ad79f4149f66651ceee0f251347fc5093294f68d.c1" text="Foot-and-mouth disease virus (FMDV) leader protein (L pro ) is a papain-like proteinase, which plays an important role in FMDV pathogenesis. L pro exists as two forms, Lab and Lb, due to translation being initiated from two different start codons separated by 84 nucleotides. L pro self-cleaves from the nascent viral polyprotein precursor as the first mature viral protein. In addition to its role as a viral proteinase, L pro also has the ability to antagonize host antiviral effects. To promote FMDV replication, L pro can suppress host antiviral responses by three different mechanisms: (1) cleavage of eukaryotic translation initiation factor 4 γ (eIF4G) to shut off host protein synthesis; (2) inhibition of host innate immune responses through restriction of interferon-α/β production; and (3) L pro can also act as a deubiquitinase and catalyze deubiquitination of innate immune signaling molecules. In the light of recent functional and biochemical findings regarding L pro , this review introduces the basic properties of L pro and the mechanisms by which it antagonizes host antiviral responses. © 2015 Liu et al. This article is distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License (http:// creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/), which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons license, and indicate if changes were made. The Creative Commons Public Domain Dedication waiver (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/">
    <entity charOffset="187-198" id="ad79f4149f66651ceee0f251347fc5093294f68d.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0006412" text="translation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="618-629" id="ad79f4149f66651ceee0f251347fc5093294f68d.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0006412" text="translation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="618-640" id="ad79f4149f66651ceee0f251347fc5093294f68d.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0006413" text="translation initiation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="825-839" id="ad79f4149f66651ceee0f251347fc5093294f68d.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0004843" text="deubiquitinase" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="853-869" id="ad79f4149f66651ceee0f251347fc5093294f68d.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0016579" text="deubiquitination" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="887-896" id="ad79f4149f66651ceee0f251347fc5093294f68d.c1.e5" ontology_id="GO_0023052" text="signaling" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1329-1341" id="ad79f4149f66651ceee0f251347fc5093294f68d.c1.e6" ontology_id="GO_0000003" text="reproduction" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
