<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0">
  <chunk id="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c0" text="Evaluation of mouse enteroids as a model for Lawsonia intracellularis infection"/>
  <chunk id="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1" text="Lawsonia intracellularis, an obligate intracellular bacterium, is an important enteric pathogen in pig herds and horse farms worldwide. The hallmark feature of L. intracellularis infection is the proliferation of epithelial cells in intestinal crypts. A major limitation to the study of L. intracellularis infection is the lack of an in vitro model that reproduces the changes observed in proliferative enteropathy. Here we investigated the suitability of mouse enteroids as a model to study L. intracellularis infection. Mouse enteroids were microinjected with L. intracellularis, filter-sterilized L. intracellularis culture supernatant, or sterile cell culture media (DMEM). L. intracellularis antigen was detected in mouse enteroids by immunohistochemistry and was located mostly in the basal region of the epithelium. There was no differential growth of enteroids among treatment groups, and cellular proliferation was not increased in L. intracellularis-infected enteroids in relation to non-infected enteroids based on immunofluorescence staining. L. intracellularis infection did not induce changes in gene expression of Ki-67 (proliferation marker), Sox9 (marker for transit amplifying cells) and Muc2 (marker for goblet cells). These results indicate that although L. intracellularis antigen is detectable in mouse enteroids, indicating susceptibility to infection, mouse enteroids fail to replicate the cellular proliferation and gene expression changes observed in proliferative enteropathy. Nevertheless, we have successfully demonstrated that mouse enteroids can be used to model days-long intracellular pathogen infection, serving as potential models for the study of other pathogens of interest in veterinary medicine.">
    <entity charOffset="29-37" id="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0040280" text="obligate" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="38-51" id="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005622" text="intracellular" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="836-855" id="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0060560" text="differential growth" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="849-855" id="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0040007" text="growth" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1110-1125" id="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0010467" text="gene expression" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1441-1456" id="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.e5" ontology_id="GO_0010467" text="gene expression" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1604-1617" id="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.e6" ontology_id="GO_0005622" text="intracellular" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.e0" e2="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.e1" id="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.e0" e2="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.e2" id="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.e0" e2="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.e3" id="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.e0" e2="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.e4" id="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.e0" e2="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.e5" id="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.e0" e2="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.e6" id="ae165f6805cbb0b5c688d4d5e5a89b6b7c16fae0.c1.p5" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
