<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="af6dacec0a1ba933a47d7451ef69ea06f7029882">
  <chunk id="af6dacec0a1ba933a47d7451ef69ea06f7029882.c0" text="F1000Research Open Peer Review Ability of device to collect bacteria from cough aerosols generated by adults with cystic fibrosis [version 1; referees: 2 approved]">
    <entity charOffset="74-79" id="af6dacec0a1ba933a47d7451ef69ea06f7029882.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012735" text="cough" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="af6dacec0a1ba933a47d7451ef69ea06f7029882.c1" text="PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 2. Goddard AF, Staudinger BJ, Dowd SE, et al.: Direct sampling of cystic fibrosis lungs indicates that DNA-based analyses of upper-airway specimens can misrepresent lung microbiota. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2012; 109(34): 13769-13774. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 3. Lentino JR, Lucks DA: Nonvalue of Sputum Culture in the Management of Lower Respiratory Tract Infections. J Clin Microbiol. 1987; 25(5): 758-762. PubMed Abstract | Free Full Text 4. Rosenfeld M, Emerson J, Accurso F, et al.: Diagnostic accuracy of oropharyngeal cultures in infants and young children with cystic fibrosis. Pediatr Pulmonol. 1999; 28(5): 321-328.">
    <entity charOffset="402-436" id="af6dacec0a1ba933a47d7451ef69ea06f7029882.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002783" text="Lower Respiratory Tract Infections" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="af6dacec0a1ba933a47d7451ef69ea06f7029882.c2" text="PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 5. Gilchrist FJ, Salamat S, Clayton S, et al.: Bronchoalveolar lavage in children with cystic fibrosis: how many lobes should be sampled? Arch Dis Child. 2011; 96: 215-217. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 6. Willner D, Haynes MR, Furlan M, et al.: Spatial distribution of microbial communities in the cystic fibrosis lung. ISME J. 2012; 6(2): 471-474. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 7. Wimberley N, Faling LJ, Bartlett JG: A Fiberoptic Bronchoscopy Technique to Obtain Uncontaminated Lower Airway Secretions for Bacterial Culture. Am Rev Respir Dis. 1979; 119(3): 337-343. PubMed Abstract 8. Couch RB, Cate TR, Douglas RG Jr, et al.: Effect of Route of Inoculation on Experimental Respiratory Viral Disease in Volunteers and Evidence for Airborne Transmission. Bacteriol Rev. 1966; 30(3): 517-529. PubMed Abstract | Free Full Text 9. Couch RB, Cate TR, Gerone PJ, et al.: Production of Illness with a Small-Particle Aerosol of Coxsackie A 21 . J Clin Invest. 1965; 44(4): 535-542. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 10. Gerone PJ, Couch RB, Keefer GV, et al.: Assessment of Experimental and Natural Viral Aerosols. Bacteriol Rev. 1966; 30(3): 576-584."/>
  <chunk id="af6dacec0a1ba933a47d7451ef69ea06f7029882.c3" text="PubMed Abstract | Free Full Text 11. Lee N, Chan PK, Hui DS, et al.: Viral loads and duration of viral shedding in adult patients hospitalized with influenza. J Infect Dis. 2009; 200(4): 492-500. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 12. Wainwright CE, France MW, O'Rourke P, et al.: Cough-generated aerosols of Pseudomonas aeruginosa and other Gram-negative bacteria from patients with cystic fibrosis. Thorax. 2009; 64(11): 926-931. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 13. Knibbs LD, Johnson GR, Kidd TJ, et al.: Viability of Pseudomonas aeruginosa in cough aerosols generated by persons with cystic fibrosis. Thorax. 2014; 69(8): 740-745. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 14. Liljemark WF, Gibbons RJ: Proportional distribution and relative adherence of streptococcus miteor (mitis) on various surfaces in the human oral cavity. Infect Immun. 1972; 6(5): 852-859. PubMed Abstract | Free Full Text 15. Hart MC, Orzalesi MM, Cook CD: Relation between anatomic respiratory dead space and body size and lung volume. Spencer DA, et al.: To the editor: Bronchoalveolar lavage (BAL) in pediatric cystic fibrosis (CF): its clinical use modified by audit in a regional CF center. Pediatr Pulmonol. 2002; 33(3): 234. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 19. Lyczak JB, Cannon CL, Pier GB: Lung infections associated with cystic fibrosis. Clin Microbiol Rev. 2002; 15(2): 194-222. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 20. Ramsey BW, Wentz KR, Smith AL, et al.: Predictive value of oropharyngeal cultures for identifying lower airway bacteria in cystic fibrosis patients. Am Rev Respir Dis. 1991; 144(2): 331-337. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 21. Armstrong DS, Grimwood K, Carlin JB, et al.: Bronchoalveolar lavage or oropharyngeal cultures to identify lower respiratory pathogens in infants with cystic fibrosis. Pediatr Pulmonol. 1996; 21(5): 267-275. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 22. Harris JK, De Groote MA, Sagel SD, et al.: Molecular identification of bacteria in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid from children with cystic fibrosis. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2007; 104(51): 20529-20533. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 23. Zemanick ET, Wagner BD, Harris JK, et al.: Pulmonary exacerbations in cystic fibrosis with negative bacterial cultures. Pediatr Pulmonol. 2010; 45(6): 569-577. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 24. Oosterheert JJ, Bonten MJ, Buskens E, et al.: Algorithm to determine cost savings of targeting antimicrobial therapy based on results of rapid diagnostic testing. J Clin Microbiol. 2003; 41(10): 4708-4713. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 25. Emery SL, Erdman DD, Bowen MD, et al.: Real-time reverse transcriptionpolymerase chain reaction assay for SARS-associated coronavirus. Emer Infect Dis. 2004; 10(2): 311-316. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 26. Saiman L, Siegel J, Cystic Fibrosis Foundation: Infection control recommendations for patients with cystic fibrosis: microbiology, important pathogens, and infection control practices to prevent patient-to-patient transmission. Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol. 2003; 24(5 Suppl): S6-52. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 27. Yankaskas JR, Marshall BC, Sufian B, et al.: Cystic fibrosis adult care: consensus conference report. Chest. 2004; 125(1 Suppl): 1S-39S. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 28. Soyer OU, Dizdar EA, Keskin O, et al.: Comparison of two methods for exhaled breath condensate collection. Allergy. 2006; 61(8): 1016-1018. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 29. Fennelly KP, Martyny JW, Fulton KE, et al.: Cough-generated aerosols of Mycobacterium tuberculosis: a new method to study infectiousness. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2004; 169(5): 604-609. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 30. Fennelly KP, Jones-López EC, Ayakaka I, et al.: Variability of infectious aerosols produced during coughing by patients with pulmonary tuberculosis. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2012; 186(5): 450-457. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 31. Jones-López EC, Namugga O, Mumbowa F, et al.: Cough aerosols of Mycobacterium tuberculosis predict new infection: a household contact study. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2013; 187(9): 1007-1015. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 32. Mehta T, McGrath E, Bheemreddy S, et al.: Detection of oseltamivir resistance during treatment of 2009 H1N1 influenza virus infection in immunocompromised patients: utility of cycle threshold values of qualitative real-time reverse transcriptase PCR. J Clin Microbiol. 2010; 48(11): 4326-4328.">
    <entity charOffset="97-111" id="af6dacec0a1ba933a47d7451ef69ea06f7029882.c3.e0" ontology_id="GO_0019076" text="viral shedding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="573-578" id="af6dacec0a1ba933a47d7451ef69ea06f7029882.c3.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012735" text="cough" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="3951-3959" id="af6dacec0a1ba933a47d7451ef69ea06f7029882.c3.e2" ontology_id="HP_0012735" text="coughing" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="4156-4161" id="af6dacec0a1ba933a47d7451ef69ea06f7029882.c3.e3" ontology_id="HP_0012735" text="Cough" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="af6dacec0a1ba933a47d7451ef69ea06f7029882.c3.e0" e2="af6dacec0a1ba933a47d7451ef69ea06f7029882.c3.e1" id="af6dacec0a1ba933a47d7451ef69ea06f7029882.c3.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="af6dacec0a1ba933a47d7451ef69ea06f7029882.c3.e0" e2="af6dacec0a1ba933a47d7451ef69ea06f7029882.c3.e2" id="af6dacec0a1ba933a47d7451ef69ea06f7029882.c3.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="af6dacec0a1ba933a47d7451ef69ea06f7029882.c3.e0" e2="af6dacec0a1ba933a47d7451ef69ea06f7029882.c3.e3" id="af6dacec0a1ba933a47d7451ef69ea06f7029882.c3.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="af6dacec0a1ba933a47d7451ef69ea06f7029882.c4" text="PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 33. Espy MJ, Uhl JR, Sloan LM, et al.: Real-time PCR in clinical microbiology: applications for routine laboratory testing. Clin Microbiol Rev. 2006; 19(1): 165-256. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 34. Xu Z, Shen F, Li X, et al.: Molecular and microscopic analysis of bacteria and viruses in exhaled breath collected using a simple impaction and condensing method. PLoS One. 2012; 7(7): e41137. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 35. Houspie L, De Coster S, Keyaerts E, et al.: Exhaled breath condensate sampling is not a new method for detection of respiratory viruses. Virol J. 2011; 8: 98. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 36. Fabian P, McDevitt JJ, DeHaan WH, et al.: Influenza virus in human exhaled breath: an observational study. PLoS One. 2008; 3(7): e2691. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 37. Huynh KN, Oliver BG, Stelzer S, et al.: A new method for sampling and detection of exhaled respiratory virus aerosols. Clin Infect Dis. 2008; 46(1): 93-95. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text"/>
</document>
