<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="b07ebfcd149b785998d9a32a9b151e83e9f46c67">
  <chunk id="b07ebfcd149b785998d9a32a9b151e83e9f46c67.c0" text="Combination of clinical symptoms and blood biomarkers can improve discrimination between bacterial or viral community-acquired pneumonia in children">
    <entity charOffset="127-136" id="b07ebfcd149b785998d9a32a9b151e83e9f46c67.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="b07ebfcd149b785998d9a32a9b151e83e9f46c67.c1" text="Background: Differentiating bacterial from viral pneumonia is important for guiding targeted management and judicious use of antibiotics. We assessed if clinical characteristics and blood inflammatory biomarkers could be used to distinguish bacterial from viral pneumonia. Methods: Western Australian children (≤17 years) hospitalized with radiologically-confirmed community-acquired pneumonia were recruited and clinical symptoms and management data were collected. C-reactive protein (CRP), white cell counts (WCC) and absolute neutrophil counts (ANC) were measured as part of routine care. Clinical characteristics and biomarker levels were compared between cases with definite bacterial pneumonia (clinical empyema and/or bacteria detected in blood or pleural fluid), presumed viral pneumonia (presence of ≥1 virus in nasopharyngeal swab without criteria for definite bacterial pneumonia), and other pneumonia cases (pneumonia in the absence of criteria for either definite bacterial or presumed viral pneumonia). The area-under-curve (AUC) of the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve for varying biomarker levels were used to characterise their utility for discriminating definite bacterial from presumed viral pneumonia. For biomarkers with AUC &gt; 0.8 (fair discriminator), Youden index was measured to determine the optimal cut-off threshold, and sensitivity, specificity, predictive values (positive and negative) were calculated. We investigated whether better discrimination could be achieved by combining biomarker values with the presence/absence of symptoms.">
    <entity charOffset="49-58" id="b07ebfcd149b785998d9a32a9b151e83e9f46c67.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="262-271" id="b07ebfcd149b785998d9a32a9b151e83e9f46c67.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="384-393" id="b07ebfcd149b785998d9a32a9b151e83e9f46c67.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="691-700" id="b07ebfcd149b785998d9a32a9b151e83e9f46c67.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="787-796" id="b07ebfcd149b785998d9a32a9b151e83e9f46c67.c1.e4" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="904-913" id="b07ebfcd149b785998d9a32a9b151e83e9f46c67.c1.e5" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="921-930" id="b07ebfcd149b785998d9a32a9b151e83e9f46c67.c1.e6" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1225-1234" id="b07ebfcd149b785998d9a32a9b151e83e9f46c67.c1.e7" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="b07ebfcd149b785998d9a32a9b151e83e9f46c67.c2" text="(Continued on next page)"/>
</document>
