<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="b4ced0e08f5b03e84a5addaaf3557b3cdc1ef277">
  <chunk id="b4ced0e08f5b03e84a5addaaf3557b3cdc1ef277.c0" text="Nucleotide composition of the Zika virus RNA genome and its codon usage"/>
  <chunk id="b4ced0e08f5b03e84a5addaaf3557b3cdc1ef277.c1" text="Background: RNA viruses have genomes with a distinct nucleotide composition and codon usage. We present the global characteristics of the RNA genome of Zika virus (ZIKV), an emerging pathogen within the Flavivirus genus. ZIKV was first isolated in 1947 in Uganda, caused a widespread epidemic in South and Central America and the Caribbean in 2015 and has recently been associated with microcephaly in newborns. Methods: The nearly 11 kb positive-stranded RNA genome of ZIKV was analyzed for its nucleotide composition, also in the context of the folded RNA molecule. Nucleotide trends were investigated along the genome length by skew analyses and we analyzed the codons used for translation of the ZIKV proteins. Results: ZIKV RNA has a biased nucleotide composition in being purine-rich and pyrimidine-poor. This preference for purines is a general characteristic of the mosquito-borne and tick-borne flaviviruses. The virus-specific nucleotide bias is further enriched in the unpaired, single-stranded regions of the structured ZIKV RNA genome, thus further imposing this ZIKV-specific signature. The codons used for translation of the ZIKV proteins is also unusual, but we show that it is the underlying bias in nucleotide composition of the viral RNA that largely dictates these codon preferences.">
    <entity charOffset="306-313" id="b4ced0e08f5b03e84a5addaaf3557b3cdc1ef277.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0030645" text="Central" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="386-398" id="b4ced0e08f5b03e84a5addaaf3557b3cdc1ef277.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0000252" text="microcephaly" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="681-692" id="b4ced0e08f5b03e84a5addaaf3557b3cdc1ef277.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0006412" text="translation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1121-1132" id="b4ced0e08f5b03e84a5addaaf3557b3cdc1ef277.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0006412" text="translation" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="b4ced0e08f5b03e84a5addaaf3557b3cdc1ef277.c1.e0" e2="b4ced0e08f5b03e84a5addaaf3557b3cdc1ef277.c1.e2" id="b4ced0e08f5b03e84a5addaaf3557b3cdc1ef277.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="b4ced0e08f5b03e84a5addaaf3557b3cdc1ef277.c1.e0" e2="b4ced0e08f5b03e84a5addaaf3557b3cdc1ef277.c1.e3" id="b4ced0e08f5b03e84a5addaaf3557b3cdc1ef277.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="b4ced0e08f5b03e84a5addaaf3557b3cdc1ef277.c1.e1" e2="b4ced0e08f5b03e84a5addaaf3557b3cdc1ef277.c1.e2" id="b4ced0e08f5b03e84a5addaaf3557b3cdc1ef277.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="b4ced0e08f5b03e84a5addaaf3557b3cdc1ef277.c1.e1" e2="b4ced0e08f5b03e84a5addaaf3557b3cdc1ef277.c1.e3" id="b4ced0e08f5b03e84a5addaaf3557b3cdc1ef277.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="b4ced0e08f5b03e84a5addaaf3557b3cdc1ef277.c2" text="Conclusions: The ZIKV RNA genome has a biased nucleotide composition that dictates the codon usage of this flavivirus. We discuss the evolutionary scenarios and molecular mechanisms that may be responsible for these distinctive ZIKV RNA genome features."/>
</document>
