<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="b516e53a03a6dc4df9eb13c85d0a57ef71452125">
  <chunk id="b516e53a03a6dc4df9eb13c85d0a57ef71452125.c0" text="A protocol for a systematic literature review: comparing the impact of seasonal and meteorological parameters on acute respiratory infections in Indigenous and non-Indigenous peoples">
    <entity charOffset="113-118" id="b516e53a03a6dc4df9eb13c85d0a57ef71452125.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="119-141" id="b516e53a03a6dc4df9eb13c85d0a57ef71452125.c0.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011947" text="respiratory infections" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="b516e53a03a6dc4df9eb13c85d0a57ef71452125.c1" text="Background: Acute respiratory infections (ARI) are a leading cause of morbidity and mortality globally, and are often linked to seasonal and/or meteorological conditions. Globally, Indigenous peoples may experience a different burden of ARI compared to non-Indigenous peoples. This protocol outlines our process for conducting a systematic review to investigate whether associations between ARI and seasonal or meteorological parameters differ between Indigenous and non-Indigenous groups residing in the same geographical region. Methodology: A search string will be used to search PubMed ® , CAB Abstracts/CAB Direct © , and Science Citation Index ® aggregator databases. Articles will be screened using inclusion/exclusion criteria applied first at the title and abstract level, and then at the full article level by two independent reviewers. Articles maintained after full article screening will undergo risk of bias assessment and data will be extracted. Heterogeneity tests, meta-analysis, and forest and funnel plots will be used to synthesize the results of eligible studies. Discussion and registration: This protocol paper describes our systematic review methods to identify and analyze relevant ARI, season, and meteorological literature with robust reporting. The results are intended to improve our understanding of potential associations between seasonal and meteorological parameters and ARI and, if identified, whether this association varies by place, population, or other characteristics. The protocol is registered in the PROSPERO database (#38051).">
    <entity charOffset="12-17" id="b516e53a03a6dc4df9eb13c85d0a57ef71452125.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="Acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="18-40" id="b516e53a03a6dc4df9eb13c85d0a57ef71452125.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011947" text="respiratory infections" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="961-974" id="b516e53a03a6dc4df9eb13c85d0a57ef71452125.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0001425" text="Heterogeneity" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
