<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="b5af7319ee1fd5e9cc3cf8c5836b19a408ac519b">
  <chunk id="b5af7319ee1fd5e9cc3cf8c5836b19a408ac519b.c0" text="Inhibition of a Putative Dihydropyrimidinase from Pseudomonas aeruginosa PAO1 by Flavonoids and Substrates of Cyclic Amidohydrolases"/>
  <chunk id="b5af7319ee1fd5e9cc3cf8c5836b19a408ac519b.c1" text="Dihydropyrimidinase is a member of the cyclic amidohydrolase family, which also includes allantoinase, dihydroorotase, hydantoinase, and imidase. These metalloenzymes possess very similar active sites and may use a similar mechanism for catalysis. However, whether the substrates and inhibitors of other cyclic amidohydrolases can inhibit dihydropyrimidinase remains unclear. This study investigated the inhibition of dihydropyrimidinase by flavonoids and substrates of other cyclic amidohydrolases. Allantoin, dihydroorotate, 5hydantoin acetic acid, acetohydroxamate, orotic acid, and 3-amino-1,2,4-triazole could slightly inhibit dihydropyrimidinase, and the IC 50 values of these compounds were within the millimolar range. The inhibition of dihydropyrimidinase by flavonoids, such as myricetin, quercetin, kaempferol, galangin, dihydromyricetin, and myricitrin, was also investigated. Some of these compounds are known as inhibitors of allantoinase and dihydroorotase. Although the inhibitory effects of these flavonoids on dihydropyrimidinase were substrate-dependent, dihydromyricetin significantly inhibited dihydropyrimidinase with IC 50 values of 48 and 40 μM for the substrates dihydrouracil and 5-propyl-hydantoin, respectively. The results from the Lineweaver−Burk plot indicated that dihydromyricetin was a competitive inhibitor. Results from fluorescence quenching analysis indicated that dihydromyricetin could form a stable complex with dihydropyrimidinase with the K d value of 22.6 μM. A structural study using PatchDock showed that dihydromyricetin was docked in the active site pocket of dihydropyrimidinase, which was consistent with the findings from kinetic and fluorescence studies. This study was the first to demonstrate that naturally occurring product dihydromyricetin inhibited dihydropyrimidinase, even more than the substrate analogs (&gt;3 orders of magnitude). These flavonols, particularly myricetin, may serve as drug leads and dirty drugs (for multiple targets) for designing compounds that target several cyclic amidohydrolases. in the second step of the pyrimidine degradation pathway, respectively [1, 2] . Dihydropyrimidinase, a component in the chain of pyrimidine catabolism, is also capable of detoxifying xenobiotics with an imide functional group that ranges from linear imides to heterocyclic imides [3, 4, 5] and organic cyclic carbonates [6] . These different imide-hydrolyzing enzymes from microorganisms are normally known as hydantoinase because of their role as biocatalysts in the synthesis of D-and L-amino acids for the industrial production of the precursors of antibiotics [7, 8] . Although dihydropyrimidinase and hydantoinase generally have a similar active site, their overall sequence identity and substrate specificity differ [9] . Thus, some bacterial hydantoinases are still named and identified as dihydropyrimidinase because of the catalytic activity toward the natural substrates dihydrouracil and dihydrothymine.">
    <entity charOffset="1433-1439" id="b5af7319ee1fd5e9cc3cf8c5836b19a408ac519b.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0031915" text="stable" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="2100-2111" id="b5af7319ee1fd5e9cc3cf8c5836b19a408ac519b.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0009056" text="degradation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="2531-2540" id="b5af7319ee1fd5e9cc3cf8c5836b19a408ac519b.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0009058" text="synthesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="2895-2913" id="b5af7319ee1fd5e9cc3cf8c5836b19a408ac519b.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0003824" text="catalytic activity" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="b5af7319ee1fd5e9cc3cf8c5836b19a408ac519b.c1.e0" e2="b5af7319ee1fd5e9cc3cf8c5836b19a408ac519b.c1.e1" id="b5af7319ee1fd5e9cc3cf8c5836b19a408ac519b.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="b5af7319ee1fd5e9cc3cf8c5836b19a408ac519b.c1.e0" e2="b5af7319ee1fd5e9cc3cf8c5836b19a408ac519b.c1.e2" id="b5af7319ee1fd5e9cc3cf8c5836b19a408ac519b.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="b5af7319ee1fd5e9cc3cf8c5836b19a408ac519b.c1.e0" e2="b5af7319ee1fd5e9cc3cf8c5836b19a408ac519b.c1.e3" id="b5af7319ee1fd5e9cc3cf8c5836b19a408ac519b.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="b5af7319ee1fd5e9cc3cf8c5836b19a408ac519b.c2" text="Based on their functional and structural similarities, dihydropyrimidinase, hydantoinase, imidase, allantoinase, and dihydroorotase belong to the cyclic amidohydrolase family [10] . Even if these enzymes have similar functions, they have relatively low amino acid sequence identity. These metal-dependent enzymes catalyze the ring-opening hydrolysis of the cyclic amide bond of each substrate in either five-or six-membered rings in the metabolism of purines, pyrimidines, and many xenobiotics ( Fig 1A) [9, 11, 12, 13] . Almost all the active sites of dihydropyrimidinase, hydantoinase, allantoinase, and dihydroorotase contain four histidines, one aspartate, and one post-carboxylated lysine residue, which are required for metal binding and catalytic activity. The presence of a post-carboxylated lysine in hydantoinase is also required in binuclear metal center self-assembly [12] , and it increases the nucleophilicity of the hydroxide for catalysis [14] . Previous studies indicated that cyclic amidohydrolases should use a nearly identical mechanism for catalysis. However, the substrate selectivity and specificity of dihydropyrimidinase, hydantoinase, allantoinase, and dihydroorotase highly differ. For example, dihydroorotase does not hydrolyze dihydropyrimidine, hydantoin, and allantoin [15] . Fig 1. Substrate specificity of dihydropyrimidinase. (A) Substrate of dihydropyrimidinase, hydantoinase, imidase, allantoinase, and dihydroorotase.">
    <entity charOffset="437-447" id="b5af7319ee1fd5e9cc3cf8c5836b19a408ac519b.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0008152" text="metabolism" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="726-739" id="b5af7319ee1fd5e9cc3cf8c5836b19a408ac519b.c2.e1" ontology_id="GO_0046872" text="metal binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="732-739" id="b5af7319ee1fd5e9cc3cf8c5836b19a408ac519b.c2.e2" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="b5af7319ee1fd5e9cc3cf8c5836b19a408ac519b.c3" text="Kinetic analysis of dihydropyrimidinase was carried out using (B) dihydrouracil, (C) phthalimide, and (D) 5-propyl-hydantoin as a substrate. The maximal concentration of phthalimide was limited to 1 mM due to its poor solubility. Data points are an average of 2-3 determinations within 10% error."/>
</document>
