<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="ba4cb142734825c7a8f759f10edfbc58ff798f9c">
  <chunk id="ba4cb142734825c7a8f759f10edfbc58ff798f9c.c0" text="Cases Journal Life threatening pneumonia in a lupus patient: a case report">
    <entity charOffset="31-40" id="ba4cb142734825c7a8f759f10edfbc58ff798f9c.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="ba4cb142734825c7a8f759f10edfbc58ff798f9c.c1" text="We report a case of systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) in a 44-year old Caucasian woman complicated with pneumonia and severe respiratory failure requiring ICU treatment and mechanical ventilation. Symptoms developed in a generally well controlled SLE course after sudden stop in immunosupresant therapy (methotrexate, cyclosporin and methylprednisolone). A fulminant course of the disease, an interstitial pattern in a high resolution computed tomography (HRCT) and negative repeated sputum, blood and bronchoaspirate cultures enabled diagnosis of fulminant lupus pneumonitis. The response to pulses of cyclophosphamide and methylprednisolone was good but complicated with a significant leukopenia. HRCT confirmed significant remission of pulmonary changes. Fulminant lupus pneumonitis is a rare but potentially life threatening complication of SLE. Differential diagnosis requires exclusion of pneumonia induced by pathogens such as Pneumocystis jirovevecii (carinii) and Mycobacterium sp. Intensive immunosuppressive therapy and close cooperation between ICU, pulmonology and rheumatology departments is necessary in such a case to minimalize the risk of fatal outcome.">
    <entity charOffset="20-48" id="ba4cb142734825c7a8f759f10edfbc58ff798f9c.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002725" text="systemic lupus erythematosus" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="50-53" id="ba4cb142734825c7a8f759f10edfbc58ff798f9c.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0002725" text="SLE" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="105-114" id="ba4cb142734825c7a8f759f10edfbc58ff798f9c.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="119-125" id="ba4cb142734825c7a8f759f10edfbc58ff798f9c.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="126-145" id="ba4cb142734825c7a8f759f10edfbc58ff798f9c.c1.e4" ontology_id="HP_0002878" text="respiratory failure" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="248-251" id="ba4cb142734825c7a8f759f10edfbc58ff798f9c.c1.e5" ontology_id="HP_0002725" text="SLE" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="846-849" id="ba4cb142734825c7a8f759f10edfbc58ff798f9c.c1.e6" ontology_id="HP_0002725" text="SLE" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="896-905" id="ba4cb142734825c7a8f759f10edfbc58ff798f9c.c1.e7" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
