<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="ba7a8a3ea4005fb471ec2ff975634765f729c32f">
  <chunk id="ba7a8a3ea4005fb471ec2ff975634765f729c32f.c0" text="viruses Temperature Sensitive Mutations in Influenza A Viral Ribonucleoprotein Complex Responsible for the Attenuation of the Live Attenuated Influenza Vaccine">
    <entity charOffset="61-86" id="ba7a8a3ea4005fb471ec2ff975634765f729c32f.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_1990904" text="Ribonucleoprotein Complex" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="ba7a8a3ea4005fb471ec2ff975634765f729c32f.c1" text="Live attenuated influenza vaccines (LAIV) have prevented morbidity and mortality associated with influenza viral infections for many years and represent the best therapeutic option to protect against influenza viral infections in humans. However, the development of LAIV has traditionally relied on empirical methods, such as the adaptation of viruses to replicate at low temperatures. These approaches require an extensive investment of time and resources before identifying potential vaccine candidates that can be safely implemented as LAIV to protect humans. In addition, the mechanism of attenuation of these vaccines is poorly understood in some cases. Importantly, LAIV are more efficacious than inactivated vaccines because their ability to mount efficient innate and adaptive humoral and cellular immune responses. Therefore, the design of potential LAIV based on known properties of viral proteins appears to be a highly appropriate option for the treatment of influenza viral infections. For that, the viral RNA synthesis machinery has been a research focus to identify key amino acid substitutions that can lead to viral attenuation and their use in safe, immunogenic, and protective LAIV. In this review, we discuss the potential to manipulate the influenza viral RNA-dependent RNA polymerase (RdRp) complex to generate attenuated forms of the virus that can be used as LAIV for the treatment of influenza viral infections, one of the current and most effective prophylactic options for the control of influenza in humans.">
    <entity charOffset="1019-1032" id="ba7a8a3ea4005fb471ec2ff975634765f729c32f.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0032774" text="RNA synthesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1023-1032" id="ba7a8a3ea4005fb471ec2ff975634765f729c32f.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0009058" text="synthesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1307-1311" id="ba7a8a3ea4005fb471ec2ff975634765f729c32f.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0003968" text="RdRp" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="ba7a8a3ea4005fb471ec2ff975634765f729c32f.c2" text="The remaining prophylactic option is the live attenuated influenza vaccine (LAIV), which is associated with broader responses and protection by the induction of both innate and humoral B-and T-cell adaptive immune responses. In addition, its administration mimics the usual route of influenza virus infection that has been shown to provide more efficient cross-reactive cellular-mediated protection against heterologous influenza viruses, important in cases where the vaccine and circulating strains do not match [41, 42] . However, current LAIV remain restricted for use in healthy children and non-pregnant adults.">
    <entity charOffset="575-582" id="ba7a8a3ea4005fb471ec2ff975634765f729c32f.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0032322" text="healthy" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="ba7a8a3ea4005fb471ec2ff975634765f729c32f.c3" text="Viruses 2018, 10, x FOR PEER REVIEW 4 of 29 complex is a heterotrimeric structure of approximately 270 kilodaltons (kDa) that contains three protein subunits: the polymerase basic 2 and 1 (PB2 and PB1, respectively) and acidic (PA) proteins that, together with the viral NP, allow each vRNP to act as an independent transcription-replication element in infected cells ( Figure 1C) [62,66,67]. Figure 1. Influenza A virion structure, genome organization, and viral replication and transcription. (A) Virion structure: IAV are surrounded by a lipid bilayer containing the two viral glycoproteins hemagglutinin (HA) and neuraminidase (NA). Also, in the virion membrane is the ion channel matrix 2 (M2) protein. Under the viral lipid bilayer is a protein layer composed of the matrix 1 (M1) protein and the nuclear export protein (NEP). Inside the virion are the eight viral (v)RNA segments that are encapsidated by the viral nucleoprotein (NP) as viral ribonucleoprotein (vRNP) complexes. Associated with each vRNP is the viral RNA-dependent RNA polymerase (RdRp) complex made of the three polymerase subunits PB2, PB1, and PA that, together with the viral NP are the minimal components required for viral replication and transcription. Viral proteins in the virion particle (top) and in the vRNP (bottom) are indicated. The viral proteins showed in the illustration of the viral particle do not maintain the stoichiometric that is found in a mature virion. (B) Genome organization: IAV contain eight single-stranded, negative-sense, viral RNA segments (PB2, PB1, PA, HA, NP, NA, M, and NS). Each viral segment contains non-coding regions (NCR) at the 3′ and 5′ ends (black lines).">
    <entity charOffset="415-421" id="ba7a8a3ea4005fb471ec2ff975634765f729c32f.c3.e0" ontology_id="GO_0019012" text="virion" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="499-505" id="ba7a8a3ea4005fb471ec2ff975634765f729c32f.c3.e1" ontology_id="GO_0019012" text="Virion" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="650-656" id="ba7a8a3ea4005fb471ec2ff975634765f729c32f.c3.e2" ontology_id="GO_0019012" text="virion" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="650-665" id="ba7a8a3ea4005fb471ec2ff975634765f729c32f.c3.e3" ontology_id="GO_0055036" text="virion membrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="657-665" id="ba7a8a3ea4005fb471ec2ff975634765f729c32f.c3.e4" ontology_id="GO_0016020" text="membrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="803-817" id="ba7a8a3ea4005fb471ec2ff975634765f729c32f.c3.e5" ontology_id="GO_0051168" text="nuclear export" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="844-850" id="ba7a8a3ea4005fb471ec2ff975634765f729c32f.c3.e6" ontology_id="GO_0019012" text="virion" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1055-1059" id="ba7a8a3ea4005fb471ec2ff975634765f729c32f.c3.e7" ontology_id="GO_0003968" text="RdRp" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1256-1262" id="ba7a8a3ea4005fb471ec2ff975634765f729c32f.c3.e8" ontology_id="GO_0019012" text="virion" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1447-1453" id="ba7a8a3ea4005fb471ec2ff975634765f729c32f.c3.e9" ontology_id="GO_0019012" text="virion" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="ba7a8a3ea4005fb471ec2ff975634765f729c32f.c4" text="Also, at the 3′ and 5′ end of the viral RNAs are the packaging signals, responsible for the efficient encapsidation into nascent virions (white boxes). Numbers represent the nucleotide length of the 3′ or 5′ packaging signals in each of the viral RNA segments. (C) Viral genome replication, transcription and translation: IAV NP and the viral polymerase complex PB2, PB1, and PA associated with the viral RNA form the vRNP complexes that are responsible for viral replication and transcription. vRNP complexes initiate transcription from the viral promoters located within the NCR at the 3′ termini of each of the vRNAs. Transcription results in the synthesis of IAV mRNA that are translated to proteins. IAV polymerase complex is also involved in the replication of the vRNA into a complementary (c)RNA that serve as template for the amplification of vRNAs. Newly synthesized vRNPs, together with the structural viral proteins result in the formation of new IAV.">
    <entity charOffset="265-289" id="ba7a8a3ea4005fb471ec2ff975634765f729c32f.c4.e0" ontology_id="GO_0019079" text="Viral genome replication" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="650-659" id="ba7a8a3ea4005fb471ec2ff975634765f729c32f.c4.e1" ontology_id="GO_0009058" text="synthesis" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
