<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="bae5b0168a883973407af7229c5f3b59020cdfa4">
  <chunk id="bae5b0168a883973407af7229c5f3b59020cdfa4.c0" text="Aeromonas salmonicida Infection Only Moderately Regulates Expression of Factors Contributing to Toll-Like Receptor Signaling but Massively Activates the Cellular and Humoral Branches of Innate Immunity in Rainbow Trout (Oncorhynchus mykiss)">
    <entity charOffset="115-124" id="bae5b0168a883973407af7229c5f3b59020cdfa4.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0023052" text="Signaling" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="186-201" id="bae5b0168a883973407af7229c5f3b59020cdfa4.c0.e1" ontology_id="GO_0045087" text="Innate Immunity" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="bae5b0168a883973407af7229c5f3b59020cdfa4.c1" text="Toll-like receptors (TLRs) are known to detect a defined spectrum of microbial structures. However, the knowledge about the specificity of teleost Tlr factors for distinct pathogens is limited so far. We measured baseline expression profiles of 18 tlr genes and associated signaling factors in four immune-relevant tissues of rainbow trout Oncorhynchus mykiss. Intraperitoneal injection of a lethal dose of Aeromonas salmonicida subsp. salmonicida induced highly increased levels of cytokine mRNAs during a 72-hour postinfection (hpi) period. In contrast, only the fish-specific tlr22a2 and the downstream factor irak1 featured clearly increased transcript levels, while the mRNA concentrations of many other tlr genes decreased. Flow cytometry quantified cell trafficking after infection indicating a dramatic influx of myeloid cells into the peritoneum and a belated low level immigration of lymphoid cells. T and B lymphocytes were differentiated with RT-qPCR revealing that B lymphocytes emigrated from and T lymphocytes immigrated into head kidney. In conclusion, no specific TLR can be singled out as a dominant receptor for A. salmonicida. The recruitment of cellular factors of innate immunity rather than induced expression of pathogen receptors is hence of key importance for mounting a first immune defense against invading A. salmonicida.">
    <entity charOffset="273-282" id="bae5b0168a883973407af7229c5f3b59020cdfa4.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0023052" text="signaling" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="530-533" id="bae5b0168a883973407af7229c5f3b59020cdfa4.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0009978" text="hpi" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1186-1201" id="bae5b0168a883973407af7229c5f3b59020cdfa4.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0045087" text="innate immunity" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
