<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="c343dec852bdfd28c3b8d0f06482408ac5ce52bd">
  <chunk id="c343dec852bdfd28c3b8d0f06482408ac5ce52bd.c0" text="Pathogenic Effects of IFIT2 and Interferon-␤ during Fatal Systemic Candida albicans Infection"/>
  <chunk id="c343dec852bdfd28c3b8d0f06482408ac5ce52bd.c1" text="A balanced immune response to infection is essential to prevent the pathology and tissue damage that can occur from an unregulated or hyperactive host defense. Interferons (IFNs) are critical mediators of the innate defense to infection, and in this study we evaluated the contribution of a specific gene coding for IFIT2 induced by type I IFNs in a murine model of disseminated Candida albicans. Invasive candidiasis is a frequent challenge during immunosuppression or surgical medical interventions, and C. albicans is a common culprit that leads to high rates of mortality. When IFIT2 knockout mice were infected systemically with C. albicans, they were found to have improved survival and reduced fungal burden compared to wild-type mice. One of the mechanisms by which IFIT2 increases the pathological effects of invasive C. albicans appears to be suppression of NADPH oxidase activation. Loss of IFIT2 increases production of reactive oxygen species by leukocytes, and we demonstrate that IFIT2 is a binding partner of a critical regulatory subunit of NADPH oxidase, p67 phox . Since the administration of IFN has been used therapeutically to combat viral infections, cancer, and multiple sclerosis, we evaluated administration of IFN-␤ to mice prior to C. albicans infection. IFN-␤ treatment promoted pathology and death from C. albicans infection. We provide evidence that IFIT2 increases the pathological effects of invasive C. albicans and that administration of IFN-␤ has deleterious effects during infection.">
    <entity charOffset="11-26" id="c343dec852bdfd28c3b8d0f06482408ac5ce52bd.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0006955" text="immune response" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="423-431" id="c343dec852bdfd28c3b8d0f06482408ac5ce52bd.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0040282" text="frequent" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1006-1013" id="c343dec852bdfd28c3b8d0f06482408ac5ce52bd.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="c343dec852bdfd28c3b8d0f06482408ac5ce52bd.c1.e0" e2="c343dec852bdfd28c3b8d0f06482408ac5ce52bd.c1.e1" id="c343dec852bdfd28c3b8d0f06482408ac5ce52bd.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="c343dec852bdfd28c3b8d0f06482408ac5ce52bd.c1.e1" e2="c343dec852bdfd28c3b8d0f06482408ac5ce52bd.c1.e2" id="c343dec852bdfd28c3b8d0f06482408ac5ce52bd.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="c343dec852bdfd28c3b8d0f06482408ac5ce52bd.c2" text="The attributable mortality associated with systemic C. albicans infections in health care settings is significant, with estimates greater than 40%. This lifethreatening disease is common in patients with weakened immune systems, either due to disease or as a result of therapies. Type I interferons (IFN) are cytokines of the innate defense response that are used as immune modulators in the treatment of specific cancers, viral infections, and multiple sclerosis. In this study, we show using a murine model that the loss of a specific IFN-stimulated gene coding for IFIT2 improves survival following systemic C. albicans infection. This result infers a harmful effect of IFN during C. albicans infection and is supported by our finding that administration of IFN-␤ prior to invasive infection promotes fatal pathology. The findings contribute to our understanding of the innate immune response to C. albicans, and they suggest that IFN therapies present a risk factor for disseminated candidiasis.">
    <entity charOffset="333-349" id="c343dec852bdfd28c3b8d0f06482408ac5ce52bd.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0006952" text="defense response" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="873-895" id="c343dec852bdfd28c3b8d0f06482408ac5ce52bd.c2.e1" ontology_id="GO_0045087" text="innate immune response" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="880-895" id="c343dec852bdfd28c3b8d0f06482408ac5ce52bd.c2.e2" ontology_id="GO_0006955" text="immune response" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="c343dec852bdfd28c3b8d0f06482408ac5ce52bd.c3" text="Citation Stawowczyk M, Naseem S, Montoya V, Baker DP, Konopka J, Reich NC. 2018. Pathogenic effects of IFIT2 and interferon-β during fatal systemic Candida albicans infection. mBio 9:e00365-18. https://doi."/>
</document>
