<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="c6518c58374cc315647f2873a234cfa983746bfd">
  <chunk id="c6518c58374cc315647f2873a234cfa983746bfd.c0" text="Insights into N-calls of mitochondrial DNA sequencing using MitoChip v2.0">
    <entity charOffset="25-38" id="c6518c58374cc315647f2873a234cfa983746bfd.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0001427" text="mitochondrial" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="c6518c58374cc315647f2873a234cfa983746bfd.c1" text="Background: Developments in DNA resequencing microarrays include mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) sequencing and mutation detection. Failure by the microarray to identify a base, compared to the reference sequence, is designated an 'N-call.' This study re-examined the N-call distribution of mtDNA samples sequenced by the Affymetrix MitoChip v.2.0, based on the hypothesis that N-calls may represent insertions or deletions (indels) in mtDNA. Findings: We analysed 16 patient mtDNA samples using MitoChip. N-calls by the proprietary GSEQ software were significantly reduced when either of the freeware on-line algorithms ResqMi or sPROFILER was utilized. With sPROFILER, this decrease in N-calls had no effect on the homoplasmic or heteroplasmic mutation levels compared to GSEQ software, but ResqMi produced a significant change in mutation load, as well as producing longer N-cell stretches. For these reasons, further analysis using ResqMi was not attempted. Conventional DNA sequencing of the longer N-calls stretches from sPROFILER revealed 7 insertions and 12 point mutations. Moreover, analysis of single-base N-calls of one mtDNA sample found 3 other point mutations. Conclusions: Our study is the first to analyse N-calls produced from GSEQ software for the MitoChipv2.0. By narrowing the focus to longer stretches of N-calls revealed by sPROFILER, conventional sequencing was able to identify unique insertions and point mutations. Shorter N-calls also harboured point mutations, but the absence of deletions among N-calls suggests that probe confirmation affects binding and thus N-calling. This study supports the contention that the GSEQ is more capable of assigning bases when used in conjunction with sPROFILER.">
    <entity charOffset="65-78" id="c6518c58374cc315647f2873a234cfa983746bfd.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0001427" text="mitochondrial" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1568-1575" id="c6518c58374cc315647f2873a234cfa983746bfd.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="c6518c58374cc315647f2873a234cfa983746bfd.c1.e0" e2="c6518c58374cc315647f2873a234cfa983746bfd.c1.e1" id="c6518c58374cc315647f2873a234cfa983746bfd.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
