<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="c66d7cf6243be684d42751e19f4f9c27ca8a1f3b">
  <chunk id="c66d7cf6243be684d42751e19f4f9c27ca8a1f3b.c0" text="A Novel Vaccine Using Nanoparticle Platform to Present Immunogenic M2e against Avian Influenza Infection"/>
  <chunk id="c66d7cf6243be684d42751e19f4f9c27ca8a1f3b.c1" text="Using peptide nanoparticle technology, we have designed two novel vaccine constructs representing M2e in monomeric (Mono-M2e) and tetrameric (Tetra-M2e) forms. Groups of specific pathogen free (SPF) chickens were immunized intramuscularly with Mono-M2e or Tetra-M2e with and without an adjuvant. Two weeks after the second boost, chickens were challenged with 107.2 EID50 of H5N2 low pathogenicity avian influenza (LPAI) virus. M2e-specific antibody responses to each of the vaccine constructs were tested by ELISA. Vaccinated chickens exhibited increased M2e-specific IgG responses for each of the constructs as compared to a non-vaccinated group. However, the vaccine construct Tetra-M2e elicited a significantly higher antibody response when it was used with an adjuvant. On the other hand, virus neutralization assays indicated that immune protection is not by way of neutralizing antibodies. The level of protection was evaluated using quantitative real time PCR at 4, 6, and 8 days postchallenge with H5N2 LPAI by measuring virus shedding from trachea and cloaca. The Tetra-M2e with adjuvant offered statistically significant (P &lt; 0.05 ) protection against subtype H5N2 LPAI by reduction of the AI virus shedding. The results suggest that the self-assembling polypeptide nanoparticle shows promise as a potential platform for a development of a vaccine against AI.">
    <entity charOffset="441-449" id="c66d7cf6243be684d42751e19f4f9c27ca8a1f3b.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="441-449" id="c66d7cf6243be684d42751e19f4f9c27ca8a1f3b.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="722-730" id="c66d7cf6243be684d42751e19f4f9c27ca8a1f3b.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="722-730" id="c66d7cf6243be684d42751e19f4f9c27ca8a1f3b.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
