<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="c79cfa0bb8017217a2626f1b4aafdfdab162a8ce">
  <chunk id="c79cfa0bb8017217a2626f1b4aafdfdab162a8ce.c0" text="Quantitative Proteomics Reveal Peroxiredoxin Perturbation Upon Persistent Lymphocytic Choriomeningitis Virus Infection in Human Cells"/>
  <chunk id="c79cfa0bb8017217a2626f1b4aafdfdab162a8ce.c1" text="Experimental data indicate that during persistent infection, lymphocytic choriomeningitis virus (LCMV) may both directly or indirectly modulate regulatory cellular processes and alter cellular functions that are not critical for survival, but are essential for cell homeostasis. In order to shed more light on these processes, two-dimensional differential in-gel electrophoresis (2D-DIGE) and MALDI-TOF tandem mass spectrometry were used to determine the proteome response of the HeLa cell line to persistent LCMV infection. Quantitative analysis revealed 24 differentially abundant proteins. Functional analysis showed that LCMV-responsive proteins were primarily involved in metabolism, stress, and the defense response. Among identified proteins, we discovered significant changes for peroxiredoxins, a family of antioxidant enzymes. Decreased amount of these antioxidant proteins correlated with elevation of reactive oxygen species (ROS) in infected cells. Increased levels of ROS were accompanied by changes in the pattern of telomere restriction fragments (TRFs) in infected cells and mediated activation of hypoxia-inducible transcription factor-1 (HIF-1) and phosphatidylinositol 3kinase (PI3K)/Akt signaling pathways. Moreover, treatment with antioxidants resulted in reduced levels of viral nucleoprotein, indicating a connection between ROS-dependent signaling and viral replication.">
    <entity charOffset="1208-1217" id="c79cfa0bb8017217a2626f1b4aafdfdab162a8ce.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0023052" text="signaling" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1363-1372" id="c79cfa0bb8017217a2626f1b4aafdfdab162a8ce.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0023052" text="signaling" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
