<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="c83b149dc7f5339bd3efa3128d991bb9b802b909">
  <chunk id="c83b149dc7f5339bd3efa3128d991bb9b802b909.c0" text="Management and biosecurity practices on pig farms in the Western Highlands of Cameroon (Central Africa)">
    <entity charOffset="88-95" id="c83b149dc7f5339bd3efa3128d991bb9b802b909.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0030645" text="Central" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="c83b149dc7f5339bd3efa3128d991bb9b802b909.c1" text="African swine fever (ASF), erysipelas and many other infectious and parasitic diseases have seriously compromised the future of pig industry in the Western Highlands of Cameroon. Since implementation of biosecurity measures (BM) is known to reduce the risk of disease transmission, the objective of this study was to describe the pig farming management system as well as the biosecurity practices on pig farms in the Western Highlands of Cameroon. Therefore, 97 farms were investigated using a face-to-face interview-based questionnaire. Biosecurity practices were divided in three components: isolation, traffic control and sanitation. The results revealed that the majority of farms were extensive (73.22%), farrow-to-finish farms (59.79%) and essentially raising crossed-bred (72.75%). The most practiced BM regarding 'isolation' were as follows: maintenance of the minimum distance between farms (56.06%) and dispatching of animals of same age in the same room (97.16%); for 'traffic control', the measures included the following: assignment of specific tools and equipment (96.86%) to a specific piggery; concerning 'sanitation', daily cleaning (97.06%), as well as using disinfectants (89.13%) were mostly implemented. The measures less implemented for 'isolation' included fencing (11.83%), compliance with the all-in all-out principle (10.11%), use of specific clothing (6.03%) and quarantine (7.69%); for 'traffic control', the less adopted measures comprised visitor hands washed before animal handling (11.65%), respect of linear flow principle (13.52%). Concerning 'sanitation', these measures included functional footbath (29.90%), processing of drinking water (27.84%) and cleanout (18.14%). The biosecurity level was low, intermediate and high for 73.71, 21.55 and 4.73% of farms, respectively. This low level suggests that ASF and other diseases are likely to remain endemic. The most important measures of concern and to improve are as follows: not feeding kitchen waste to pigs; keeping other livestock species away from pigs; fencing pig barn; keeping newly arrived animals in quarantine, not exchanging boars; not selling sick animals.">
    <entity charOffset="14-19" id="c83b149dc7f5339bd3efa3128d991bb9b802b909.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0001945" text="fever" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="27-37" id="c83b149dc7f5339bd3efa3128d991bb9b802b909.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0001055" text="erysipelas" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="c83b149dc7f5339bd3efa3128d991bb9b802b909.c2" text="African swine fever, biosecurity, erysipelas, Menoua, pig husbandry | 83 KOUAM et Al."/>
</document>
