<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="c92099607cfae94a24e03a111d12994535cc2eae">
  <chunk id="c92099607cfae94a24e03a111d12994535cc2eae.c0" text="A new therapeutic strategy for lung tissue injury induced by influenza with CR2 targeting complement inhibitior"/>
  <chunk id="c92099607cfae94a24e03a111d12994535cc2eae.c1" text="Background: Influenza is a respiratory disease that seriously threatens human health. In fact, influenza virus itself does not make critical contribution to mortality induced by influenza, but &quot;cytokine storm&quot; produced by the excessive immune response triggered by the virus can result in inflammatory reaction of lung tissues and fatal lung tissue injury, and thus increase influenza mortality. Therefore, besides antiviral drugs, immunosuppression drugs should also be included in infection treatment. Presentation of the hypothesis: Complement is the center of inflammatory reaction. If complement system is over activated, the body will have strong inflammatory reaction or tissue injury, resulting in pathological process. Many studies have proved that, inflammatory injury of lung tissues caused by influenza virus is closely related to complement activation. Therefore, inhibiting complement activation can significantly reduce inflammatory injury in lung tissues. As complement is both a physiological defense and pathological damage medium, systematic inhibition may result in side effects including infection. Therefore, we design targeting complement inhibitors for complement activation sites, i.e. with CR2 as targeting vector, complement inhibitors like CD59 and Crry are targeted to inflammatory sites to specially inhibit the complement activation in local injury, thus local inflammatory reaction is inhibited.">
    <entity charOffset="236-251" id="c92099607cfae94a24e03a111d12994535cc2eae.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0006955" text="immune response" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="843-864" id="c92099607cfae94a24e03a111d12994535cc2eae.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0006956" text="complement activation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="888-909" id="c92099607cfae94a24e03a111d12994535cc2eae.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0006956" text="complement activation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1177-1198" id="c92099607cfae94a24e03a111d12994535cc2eae.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0006956" text="complement activation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1342-1363" id="c92099607cfae94a24e03a111d12994535cc2eae.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0006956" text="complement activation" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
