<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="cac106b063755a144ec1154f593d78d5a4f6f4c1">
  <chunk id="cac106b063755a144ec1154f593d78d5a4f6f4c1.c0" text="Porcine transmissible gastroenteritis virus nonstructural protein 2 contributes to inflammation via NF-κB activation"/>
  <chunk id="cac106b063755a144ec1154f593d78d5a4f6f4c1.c1" text="Transmissible gastroenteritis virus (TGEV) infection causes acute enteritis in swine of all ages, and especially in suckling piglets. Small intestinal inflammation is considered a central event in the pathogenesis of TGEV infections, and nuclear factor-kappa B (NF-κB) is a key transcription factor in the inflammatory response. However, it is unclear whether NF-κB is crucial for inducing inflammation during a TGEV infection. Our results show that NF-κB was activated in swine testicular (ST) cells and intestinal epithelial cell lines J2 (IPEC-J2) cells infected with TGEV, which is consistent with the up-regulation of pro-inflammatory cytokines. Treatment of TGEV-infected ST cells and IPEC-J2 cells with the NF-κB-specific inhibitor caused the down-regulation of pro-inflammatory cytokine expression, but did not significantly affect TGEV replication. Individual TGEV protein screening results demonstrated that Nsp2 exhibited a high potential for activating NF-κB and enhancing the expression of pro-inflammatory cytokines. Functional domain analyzes indicated that the first 120 amino acid residues of Nsp2 were essential for NF-κB activation. Taken together, these data suggested that NF-κB activation was a major contributor to TGEV infection-induced inflammation, and that Nsp2 was the key viral protein involved in the regulation of inflammation, with amino acids 1-120 playing a critical role in activating NF-κB. Abbreviations: TCID50: 50% tissue culture infectious dose; DMEM: Dulbecco's Modified Eagle Medium; eNOS: Endothelial nitric oxide synthase; FBS: fetal bovine serum; IFA: Indirect immunofluorescence; IκB: inhibitor of nuclear factor kappa-B; IL: interleukin; IPEC-J2: intestinal epithelial cell">
    <entity charOffset="60-65" id="cac106b063755a144ec1154f593d78d5a4f6f4c1.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="180-187" id="cac106b063755a144ec1154f593d78d5a4f6f4c1.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0030645" text="central" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="201-213" id="cac106b063755a144ec1154f593d78d5a4f6f4c1.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0009405" text="pathogenesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="cac106b063755a144ec1154f593d78d5a4f6f4c1.c1.e0" e2="cac106b063755a144ec1154f593d78d5a4f6f4c1.c1.e2" id="cac106b063755a144ec1154f593d78d5a4f6f4c1.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="cac106b063755a144ec1154f593d78d5a4f6f4c1.c1.e1" e2="cac106b063755a144ec1154f593d78d5a4f6f4c1.c1.e2" id="cac106b063755a144ec1154f593d78d5a4f6f4c1.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
