<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf">
  <chunk id="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c0" text="Identification and Characterization of Novel Rat Polyomavirus 2 in a Colony of X-SCID Rats by P-PIT assay"/>
  <chunk id="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1" text="Polyomaviruses (PyVs) are known to infect a wide range of vertebrates and invertebrates and are associated with a broad spectrum of diseases, including cancers, particularly in immune-suppressed hosts. A novel polyomavirus, designated rat polyomavirus 2 (RatPyV2), was identified from a breeding colony of rats having X-linked severe combined immunodeficiency. Using a human panpolyomavirus immunohistochemistry test (P-PIT), RatPyV2 was initially detected in the parotid salivary gland of a colony member. Rolling circle amplification using DNA from harderian and parotid glands identified a novel 5.1-kb polyomavirus genome closely related to human Washington University (WU) and Karolinska Institute (KI) and vole polyomaviruses but notably divergent from Rattus norvegicus PyV1 (RnorPyV1; also designated RatPyV1). Further screening showed RatPyV2 inclusion body infection in the lung epithelium and variably in other respiratory, reproductive, and glandular tissues of 12/12 (100%) rats. IMPORTANCE Although P-PIT was developed to detect diseases associated with known human polyomaviruses, the identification of a new polyomavirus in rats suggests that it may have utility as a broad-based screen for new, as well as known polyomaviruses. Our findings suggest that RatPyV2 may be a commensal infection of laboratory rats that can lead to disseminated disease in T cell immune-deficient rats. Infection of the X-SCID rats with RatPyV2 and Pneumocystis carinii is a potential model for coinfection pathogenesis and treatment options during transplant preclinical studies.">
    <entity charOffset="318-326" id="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0001417" text="X-linked" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="327-333" id="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="327-359" id="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0004430" text="severe combined immunodeficiency" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="852-866" id="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0016234" text="inclusion body" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1502-1514" id="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0009405" text="pathogenesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1.e0" e2="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1.e3" id="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1.e0" e2="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1.e4" id="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1.e1" e2="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1.e3" id="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1.e1" e2="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1.e4" id="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1.e2" e2="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1.e3" id="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1.e2" e2="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1.e4" id="cd1d0cb4b82d5479e2aa72ec3d3cde6aae4a4eaf.c1.p5" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
