<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="cd4889df1e36fd838d6835714cbf4fdfd7e7e32e">
  <chunk id="cd4889df1e36fd838d6835714cbf4fdfd7e7e32e.c0" text="Changes in clinical and laboratory features of Kawasaki disease noted over time in Daejeon, Korea"/>
  <chunk id="cd4889df1e36fd838d6835714cbf4fdfd7e7e32e.c1" text="Background: Kawasaki disease (KD) becomes one of the common diseases in Korea. Changes in clinical features and laboratory findings of KD were evaluated over a period of 10 years. Methods: We reviewed the medical records of KD patients and compared the clinical and laboratory features of two KD patient groups: those admitted from 2000 to 2004 (group A, 284 cases) and those admitted from 2010 to 2014 (group B, 331 cases)."/>
  <chunk id="cd4889df1e36fd838d6835714cbf4fdfd7e7e32e.c2" text="Results: There were a total of 615 KD patients (mean age: 29.7 months; male-to-female ratio = 1.6:1), including 228 incomplete KD patients. Incomplete KD patients had milder values in some laboratory indices. The preadmission and total fever durations were longer in group A than in group B. The proportion of incomplete KD was higher in group B, but incidence of coronary artery lesions (CALs) was lower. For laboratory indices, the C-reactive protein and follow-up platelet values were lower, and the hemoglobin and albumin values were higher in group B. The same clinical and laboratory findings were confirmed in the KD subgroups; those with the same fever duration of 5 or 6 days and same ages, those with complete KD, and those with incomplete KD in the two different time periods. Conclusions: Our findings suggest that clinical features of KD tend to be milder over time and manifest in a higher incidence of incomplete KD, lower incidence of CALs, and less severe laboratory findings in recent KD patients in Korea compared with their historic counterparts.">
    <entity charOffset="236-241" id="cd4889df1e36fd838d6835714cbf4fdfd7e7e32e.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0001945" text="fever" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="655-660" id="cd4889df1e36fd838d6835714cbf4fdfd7e7e32e.c2.e1" ontology_id="HP_0001945" text="fever" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="966-972" id="cd4889df1e36fd838d6835714cbf4fdfd7e7e32e.c2.e2" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
