<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="d0631859c5008f863d1b288755b97bb0b6dea4d6">
  <chunk id="d0631859c5008f863d1b288755b97bb0b6dea4d6.c0" text="Development of a Single Leg Knee Exoskeleton and Sensing Knee Center of Rotation Change for Intention Detection"/>
  <chunk id="d0631859c5008f863d1b288755b97bb0b6dea4d6.c1" text="In this study, we developed a single leg knee joint assistance robot. Commonly used exoskeletons have a left-right pair, but when only one leg of the wearer is uncomfortable, it is effective to wear the exoskeleton on only the uncomfortable leg. The designed exoskeleton uses a lightweight material and uses a wire-driven actuator, which reduces the weight of the driving section that is attached on the knee directly. Therefore, proposed exoskeleton reduces the force of inertia that the wearer experiences. In addition, the lower frame length of the exoskeleton can be changed to align with the complex movement of the knee. Furthermore, the length between the knee center of rotation and the ankle (LBKA) is measured by using this structure, and the LBKA values are used as the data for intention detection. These value helps to detect the intention because it changes faster than a motor encoder value. A neural network was trained using the motor encoder values, and LBKA values. Neural network detects the intention of three motions (stair ascending, stair descending, and walking), Training results showed that intention detection was good in various environments.">
    <entity charOffset="472-479" id="d0631859c5008f863d1b288755b97bb0b6dea4d6.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0030216" text="inertia" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="d0631859c5008f863d1b288755b97bb0b6dea4d6.c2" text="large radial displacement between two shafts [7], and link systems have also been used to self-align the exoskeleton [8]. The planar parallel robot possesses three degrees of freedom (DoFs) to enable self-alignment [9] . However, the disadvantage of these studies was that the volume of the actuator was large. There are the exoskeletons that have a prismatic degree of freedom to self-align with the complex movements of the knee [10] [11] [12] . Due to this structure, the exoskeleton does not limit the wearer's range of motion moreover there is no need to enlarge the volume of actuator. The difference between [10] [11] [12] and the exoskeleton suggested in this paper is that the proposed exoskeleton has the structure which measures the change of the center of rotation. Though the change of the center of rotation is measured in [12] , they use the displacement sensor which is attached on the tibia model. However, the proposed exoskeleton in this paper can be equipped to actual wearer because the sensor is attached inside the exoskeleton. In this paper, the movement of the center of rotation was measured and used to detect intention. As a result, the intention is detected by using the data obtained by only one leg."/>
</document>
