<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="d211a9ffb15714958d46365027d61af18c17a269">
  <chunk id="d211a9ffb15714958d46365027d61af18c17a269.c0" text="Co-Infection of Swine with Porcine Circovirus Type 2 and Other Swine Viruses"/>
  <chunk id="d211a9ffb15714958d46365027d61af18c17a269.c1" text="Porcine circovirus 2 (PCV2) is the etiological agent that causes porcine circovirus diseases and porcine circovirus-associated diseases (PCVD/PCVAD), which are present in every major swine-producing country in the world. PCV2 infections may downregulate the host immune system and enhance the infection and replication of other pathogens. However, the exact mechanisms of PCVD/PCVAD are currently unknown. To date, many studies have reported that several cofactors, such as other swine viruses or bacteria, vaccination failure, and stress or crowding, in combination with PCV2, lead to PCVD/PCVAD. Among these cofactors, co-infection of PCV2 with other viruses, such as porcine reproductive and respiratory syndrome virus, porcine parvovirus, swine influenza virus and classical swine fever virus have been widely studied for decades. In this review, we focus on the current state of knowledge regarding swine co-infection with different PCV2 genotypes or strains, as well as with PCV2 and other swine viruses.">
    <entity charOffset="785-790" id="d211a9ffb15714958d46365027d61af18c17a269.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0001945" text="fever" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="d211a9ffb15714958d46365027d61af18c17a269.c2" text="PCV2 is divided into five genotypes according to the Cap gene sequence: PCV2a, 2b, 2c, 2d, and 2e [2,21]. Moreover, the PCV2b genotype is classified into three clusters, 1A to 1C, and the PCV2a genotype is subdivided into five clusters, 2A to 2F [2,22-24]. Recently, a retrospective study of PCV2 infection between 1996 and 1999 in China revealed a novel genotype PCV2f which shared lower sequence identity with the other known genotypes [25]. Since the discovery of PCV2 in the late 1990s, the virus has continued to evolve, and two major genotype shifts have been observed. The first genotype shift in PCV2 was from PCV2a to PCV2b in 2004PCV2b in /2005. Since 2012, the predominant PCV2b has been gradually replaced by the PCV2d genotype in North America, China, South Korea and Uruguay [22,[26][27][28][29][30]. Besides, PCV2F becomes the predominant genotype in the PCV2a cluster in China [22]."/>
  <chunk id="d211a9ffb15714958d46365027d61af18c17a269.c3" text="It has been reported that concurrent infections with different PCV2 genotypes have been detected in the same pig, resulting in inter-and intra-genotype recombination [13, [31][32][33]. One hundred and eighteen PCV2-positive DNA samples isolated from diseased pigs were analyzed using a modified differential polymerase chain reaction (PCR) assay, and the results indicated that the coexistence rates of PCV2 genotypes were 32.2% (38/118) in sick pigs [13] . The sequencing results of 38 co-infected samples showed that the coexisting genotypes were PCV2a-PCV2b (12/38), PCV2a-PCV2d (15/38) and PCV2e-PCV2d (11/38) [13] . One group reported that the recombination rate of the PCV2 isolates was 27.7% (17/54) in the samples collected from 2006 to 2016 in China [34], and the recombination mainly occurred in the ORF1 gene of PCV2 [34,35]. Furthermore, co-infections with different PCV2 genotypes may cause more serious disease. In cells infected with replicating viruses, both PCV2a and PCV2b genotypes were equally present [31]. Further studies have demonstrated that pigs with dually heterologous inoculation or naturally infected with multiple PCV2 genotypes or strains displayed more severe lesions [36,37]. These results suggest that the coexistence of different strains of PCV2 might contribute to the development of more severe clinical symptoms in pigs and more recombination events between strains in the field [13, [35][36][37]. Therefore, more studies need to focus on analyzing the recombination trends of PCV2 strains, which may provide a better strategy for vaccine development and vaccination strategy.">
    <entity charOffset="1186-1192" id="d211a9ffb15714958d46365027d61af18c17a269.c3.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1326-1332" id="d211a9ffb15714958d46365027d61af18c17a269.c3.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="d211a9ffb15714958d46365027d61af18c17a269.c4" text="Co-Infection of PCV2 with Other Swine Viruses"/>
  <chunk id="d211a9ffb15714958d46365027d61af18c17a269.c5" text="Porcine circovirus 3 (PCV3) is a newly emerging virus belonging to the family Circoviridae, and it has a circular 2000 bp ssDNA genome that mainly encodes replicase and capsid proteins [38][39][40]. However, the sequence identity of PCV3 to PCV1 and PCV2 was only 31-48% on the amino acid level, respectively [41], indicating that PCV3 is distinct from PCV1 and PCV2. PCV3 was divided into three major clades (PCV3a, PCV3b and PCV3c) based on complete coding sequences [32,42]. Recently, other groups have found that PCV3 has a close relationship to bat circovirus [32,38,43]. Thus, it was hypothesized that PCV3 may have evolved from bats and then gradually adapted to infect pigs and other animals [43], which might pose a potential risk to public health due to its close relationship with bat circovirus [32,43]."/>
  <chunk id="d211a9ffb15714958d46365027d61af18c17a269.c6" text="PCV3 can be detected in multiple tissues with different positive rates in healthy and diseased pigs [40,44], and the positive rate of PCV3 has increased gradually in sows and stillborns [44,45]. Surprisingly, the infection rate of PCV3 in wild boars was similar or higher than that of domestic pigs, with the infection rates of 33% to 42.66%, indicating that the wild boar is a potential reservoir for PCV3 [40]. PCV3 has been associated with cardiac and multisystemic inflammation, PRDC, PDNS and reproductive failure [38][39][40]46], most of which are similar to that of PCVD/PCVAD caused by PCV2. Notably, PCV3-positive clinical samples were frequently found to be co-infected with PCV2, as the co-infection rates were 27.6-39.39% and 19.14% in pig farms and slaughter houses, respectively [46][47][48][49][50][51], suggesting mixed infection of PCV2 and PCV3 are common in pig populations. However, to date, isolation and propagation of PCV3 was unsuccessful in vitro [52],">
    <entity charOffset="74-81" id="d211a9ffb15714958d46365027d61af18c17a269.c6.e0" ontology_id="HP_0032322" text="healthy" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
