<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="d3693cdb4860d66db90f3e6249f4da09033448b1">
  <chunk id="d3693cdb4860d66db90f3e6249f4da09033448b1.c0" text="Psychometric assessments of Persian translations of three measures of conspiracist beliefs"/>
  <chunk id="d3693cdb4860d66db90f3e6249f4da09033448b1.c1" text="Several self-report measures of conspiracist beliefs have been developed in Western populations, but examination of their psychometric properties outside Europe and North America is limited. This study aimed to examine the psychometric properties of three widely-used measures of conspiracist beliefs in Iran. We translated the Belief in Conspiracy Theory Inventory (BCTI), Conspiracy Mentality Questionnaire (CMQ), and Generic Conspiracist Belief Scale (GCBS) into Persian. Factorial validity was examined using principal-axis factor analysis in a community sample from Tehran, Iran (N = 544). Further, the relationships between scores on these measures and hypothesized antecedents (i.e., education, schizotypal personality, information processing style, superstitious beliefs, religiosity, and political orientation) were examined. Overall, we failed to find support for the parent factor structures of two of the three scales (BCTI and GCBS) and evidence of construct validity for all three scales was limited. These results highlight the necessity of further psychometric work on existing measures of conspiracy theories in diverse culturo-linguistic groups and the development of context-specific measures of conspiracist beliefs. ] advocated a more conservative cut-off of .80, which was applied for newly adapted measures (i.e., BCTI, CMQ, and GCBS) in the present study. To assess convergent validity, we computed bivariate correlations between all study variables. According to Lipsey and Wilson [53, 54] , correlations of .10 are considered small, correlations of .25 are considered medium, and correlations of .40 are considered large. We used independent-samples t-tests to examine between-group differences between women and men. Cohen's d [54] was computed as a measure of effect size. Effects are considered as large if differences are greater than 0.80, moderate if differences are between 0.50 and 0.80, and small if differences are between 0.20 and 0.50. Although we report p &lt; .05 as our statistical significance level [55], we flag correlations where p &lt; .005. Interpretations of convergent validity were based on the magnitude of the effects, rather than solely on statistical significance. In case of multiple comparisons, we applied Bonferroni correction to compensate for Type I error.">
    <entity charOffset="1871-1879" id="d3693cdb4860d66db90f3e6249f4da09033448b1.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012826" text="moderate" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="d3693cdb4860d66db90f3e6249f4da09033448b1.c2" text="Results"/>
  <chunk id="d3693cdb4860d66db90f3e6249f4da09033448b1.c3" text="BCTI. The BCTI items were examined for normality of distribution and were found to be lower than limits; these items were, therefore, appropriate for factor analysis. The participantitem ratio was 36.3, much larger than the recommended minimums which typically range between 5 and 20 [48] . Therefore, the sample size was adequate for factor analysis. The size of Kaiser-Meyer-Olkin (KMO) measure of sampling adequacy suggested that the BCTI items had adequate common variance for factor analysis (KMO = .89). Bartlett's test of sphericity, χ 2 (105) = 2589.10, p &lt; .001, indicated that the correlation matrix was factorable. The results of the PAFA revealed three factors with λs larger than one (5.54, 1.44, and 1.21). However, inspection of the scree plot suggested one primary factor and a steep cut-off to the secondary factor. The results of parallel analysis showed that the first two eigenvalues (95% CI means = 1.38 and 1.29) for the random data were smaller than the real data, whereas the third permuted eigenvalue (95% CI mean = 1.23) was larger than the third eigenvalue for the real data (λ = 1.21). These findings suggest that two factors should be extracted, although it may be noted that all 15 items had good loadings on the primary factor (see Table 1 ). The two extracted factors cumulatively explained 46.6% of the total item variance. Only three items loaded on the second factor (loadings &gt; .45). Based on Tabachnick and Fidell's [50] recommendations, we eliminated cross-loading items (Items #1, #2, and #3), leaving 12 items adequately loading onto the first factor (see Table 1 ; Cronbach's α = .85)."/>
  <chunk id="d3693cdb4860d66db90f3e6249f4da09033448b1.c4" text="CMQ. Tests of normality of distribution showed that the CMQ items were lower than recommended limits. The participant-to-item ratio for CMQ was 108.8, which is larger than the recommended minimums. The size of KMO measure of sampling adequacy, KMO = .81, suggested that the CMQ items had adequate common variance for factor analysis, and Bartlett's test of sphericity, χ 2 (10) = 1289.37, p &lt; .001, indicated that the correlation matrix was factorable. The results of the PAFA revealed a single factor with λ = 3.25, which explained 64.9% of the variance. All 5 items had excellent loadings on this factor (see Table 2 ). Cronbach's α for the overall CMQ score, computed as the mean of all 5 items, was .86."/>
  <chunk id="d3693cdb4860d66db90f3e6249f4da09033448b1.c5" text="GCBS. The GCBS items were examined for normality of distribution and were found to be lower than limits. The participant-to-item ratio was 36.3, which is much larger than the recommended minimums. The size of the KMO (.89) and Bartlett's test of sphericity, χ 2 (105) = 3312.69, p &lt; .001, showed that the 15 GCBS items had adequate common variance for factor analysis. The results of the PAFA revealed three factors with λ &gt; 1.0 (6.02, 1.54, Conspiracy theories in Iran PLOS ONE | https://doi.org/10."/>
</document>
