<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="d400825a1ea10fb8d5bdbc96b2c00e866eb75f1d">
  <chunk id="d400825a1ea10fb8d5bdbc96b2c00e866eb75f1d.c0" text="Equine Arteritis Virus Does Not Induce Interferon Production in Equine Endothelial Cells: Identification of Nonstructural Protein 1 as a Main Interferon Antagonist">
    <entity charOffset="7-16" id="d400825a1ea10fb8d5bdbc96b2c00e866eb75f1d.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012089" text="Arteritis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="d400825a1ea10fb8d5bdbc96b2c00e866eb75f1d.c1" text="The objective of this study was to investigate the effect of equine arteritis virus (EAV) on type I interferon (IFN) production. Equine endothelial cells (EECs) were infected with the virulent Bucyrus strain (VBS) of EAV and expression of IFN-was measured at mRNA and protein levels by quantitative real-time RT-PCR and IFN bioassay using vesicular stomatitis virus expressing the green fluorescence protein (VSV-GFP), respectively. Quantitative RT-PCR results showed that IFN-mRNA levels in EECs infected with EAV VBS were not increased compared to those in mock-infected cells. Consistent with quantitative RT-PCR, Sendai virus-(SeV-) induced type I IFN production was inhibited by EAV infection. Using an IFN-promoter-luciferase reporter assay, we subsequently demonstrated that EAV nsps 1, 2, and 11 had the capability to inhibit type I IFN activation. Of these three nsps, nsp1 exhibited the strongest inhibitory effect. Taken together, these data demonstrate that EAV has the ability to suppress the type I IFN production in EECs and nsp1 may play a critical role to subvert the equine innate immune response.">
    <entity charOffset="68-77" id="d400825a1ea10fb8d5bdbc96b2c00e866eb75f1d.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012089" text="arteritis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="349-359" id="d400825a1ea10fb8d5bdbc96b2c00e866eb75f1d.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0010280" text="stomatitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1092-1114" id="d400825a1ea10fb8d5bdbc96b2c00e866eb75f1d.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0045087" text="innate immune response" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="d400825a1ea10fb8d5bdbc96b2c00e866eb75f1d.c1.e0" e2="d400825a1ea10fb8d5bdbc96b2c00e866eb75f1d.c1.e2" id="d400825a1ea10fb8d5bdbc96b2c00e866eb75f1d.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="d400825a1ea10fb8d5bdbc96b2c00e866eb75f1d.c1.e1" e2="d400825a1ea10fb8d5bdbc96b2c00e866eb75f1d.c1.e2" id="d400825a1ea10fb8d5bdbc96b2c00e866eb75f1d.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
