<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="d4190432c724cc90504db6a90053c0a61057eb7c">
  <chunk id="d4190432c724cc90504db6a90053c0a61057eb7c.c0" text="Detection of the Influenza A(H1N1)pdm09 Virus Carrying the K-15E, P83S and Q293H Mutations in Patients Who Have Undergone Bone Marrow Transplant"/>
  <chunk id="d4190432c724cc90504db6a90053c0a61057eb7c.c1" text="The 2009 pandemic influenza A(H1N1)pdm09 virus emerged and caused considerable morbidity and mortality in the third world, especially in Brazil. Although circulating strains of A(H1N1)pdm09 are A/California/04/2009-like (CA-04-like) viruses, various studies have suggested that some mutations in the viral hemagglutinin (HA) may be associated with enhanced severity and fatality. This phenomenon is particularly challenging for immunocompromised individuals, such as those who have undergone bone marrow transplant (BMT), because they are more likely to display worse clinical outcomes to influenza infection than non-immunocompromised individuals. We studied the clinical and viral aspects of post-BMT patients with confirmed A(H1N1)pdm09 diagnosis in the largest cancer hospital in Brazil. We found a viral strain with K-15E, P83S and Q293H polymorphisms in the HA, which is presumably more virulent, in these individuals. Despite that, these patients showed only mild symptoms of infection. Our findings complement the discovery of mild cases of infection with the A(H1N1)pdm09 virus with the K-15E, P83S and Q293H mutations in Brazil and oppose other studies that have linked these changes with increased disease severity. These results could be important for a better comprehension of the impact of the pandemic influenza in the context of BMT. Citation: Mesquita M, Resende P, Marttorelli A, Machado V, Sacramento CQ, et al. (2014) Detection of the Influenza A(H1N1)pdm09 Virus Carrying the K-15E, P83S and Q293H Mutations in Patients Who Have Undergone Bone Marrow Transplant. PLoS ONE 9(4): e94822.">
    <entity charOffset="357-365" id="d4190432c724cc90504db6a90053c0a61057eb7c.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012824" text="severity" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="765-771" id="d4190432c724cc90504db6a90053c0a61057eb7c.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0002664" text="cancer" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="966-970" id="d4190432c724cc90504db6a90053c0a61057eb7c.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0012825" text="mild" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1035-1039" id="d4190432c724cc90504db6a90053c0a61057eb7c.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0012825" text="mild" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1217-1225" id="d4190432c724cc90504db6a90053c0a61057eb7c.c1.e4" ontology_id="HP_0012824" text="severity" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
