<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="d739cf97cba31e655d6c7438b864d94297f59ba3">
  <chunk id="d739cf97cba31e655d6c7438b864d94297f59ba3.c0" text="Regulation of Innate Immune Responses by Bovine Herpesvirus 1 and Infected Cell Protein 0 (bICP0)"/>
  <chunk id="d739cf97cba31e655d6c7438b864d94297f59ba3.c1" text="Bovine herpesvirus 1 (BoHV-1) infected cell protein 0 (bICP0) is an important transcriptional regulatory protein that stimulates productive infection. In transient transfection assays, bICP0 also inhibits interferon dependent transcription. bICP0 can induce degradation of interferon stimulatory factor 3 (IRF3), a cellular transcription factor that is crucial for activating beta interferon (IFN-) promoter activity. Recent studies also concluded that interactions between bICP0 and IRF7 inhibit trans-activation of IFN- promoter activity. The C3HC4 zinc RING (really important new gene) finger located near the amino terminus of bICP0 is important for all known functions of bICP0. A recombinant virus that contains a single amino acid change in a well conserved cysteine residue of the C3HC4 zinc RING finger of bICP0 grows poorly in cultured cells, and does not reactivate from latency in cattle confirming that the C3HC4 zinc RING finger is crucial for viral growth and pathogenesis. A bICP0 deletion mutant does not induce plaques in permissive cells, but induces autophagy in a cell type dependent manner. In summary, the ability of bICP0 to stimulate productive infection, and repress IFN dependent transcription plays a crucial role in the BoHV-1 infection cycle.">
    <entity charOffset="154-163" id="d739cf97cba31e655d6c7438b864d94297f59ba3.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0025153" text="transient" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="258-269" id="d739cf97cba31e655d6c7438b864d94297f59ba3.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0009056" text="degradation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="966-972" id="d739cf97cba31e655d6c7438b864d94297f59ba3.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0040007" text="growth" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1072-1081" id="d739cf97cba31e655d6c7438b864d94297f59ba3.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0006914" text="autophagy" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="d739cf97cba31e655d6c7438b864d94297f59ba3.c1.e0" e2="d739cf97cba31e655d6c7438b864d94297f59ba3.c1.e1" id="d739cf97cba31e655d6c7438b864d94297f59ba3.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="d739cf97cba31e655d6c7438b864d94297f59ba3.c1.e0" e2="d739cf97cba31e655d6c7438b864d94297f59ba3.c1.e2" id="d739cf97cba31e655d6c7438b864d94297f59ba3.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="d739cf97cba31e655d6c7438b864d94297f59ba3.c1.e0" e2="d739cf97cba31e655d6c7438b864d94297f59ba3.c1.e3" id="d739cf97cba31e655d6c7438b864d94297f59ba3.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
