<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="d8e134d93a4666285518b7916316a97dcc258788">
  <chunk id="d8e134d93a4666285518b7916316a97dcc258788.c0" text="Vesicular stomatitis Virus-Based Vaccine protects Mice against Crimean-Congo Hemorrhagic Fever">
    <entity charOffset="10-20" id="d8e134d93a4666285518b7916316a97dcc258788.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0010280" text="stomatitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="89-94" id="d8e134d93a4666285518b7916316a97dcc258788.c0.e1" ontology_id="HP_0001945" text="Fever" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="d8e134d93a4666285518b7916316a97dcc258788.c1" text="hemorrhagic syndrome in humans but not in its animal host. The virus is widely distributed throughout southeastern Europe, the Middle East, Africa, and Asia. Disease management has proven difficult and there are no broadly licensed vaccines or therapeutics. Recombinant vesicular stomatitis viruses (rVSV) expressing foreign glycoproteins (GP) have shown promise as experimental vaccines for several viral hemorrhagic fevers. Here, we developed and assessed a replication competent rVSV vector expressing the CCHFV glycoprotein precursor (GPC), which encodes CCHFV structural glycoproteins. This construct drives strong expression of CCHFV-GP, in vitro. Using these vectors, we vaccinated STAT-1 knock-out mice, an animal model for CCHFV. The vector was tolerated and 100% efficacious against challenge from a clinical strain of CCHFV. Anti-CCHFV-GP IgG and neutralizing antibody titers were observed in surviving animals. This study demonstrates that a rVSV expressing only the CCHFV-GP has the potential to serve as a replication competent vaccine platform against CCHF infections.">
    <entity charOffset="280-290" id="d8e134d93a4666285518b7916316a97dcc258788.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0010280" text="stomatitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="871-879" id="d8e134d93a4666285518b7916316a97dcc258788.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="871-879" id="d8e134d93a4666285518b7916316a97dcc258788.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="d8e134d93a4666285518b7916316a97dcc258788.c1.e0" e2="d8e134d93a4666285518b7916316a97dcc258788.c1.e1" id="d8e134d93a4666285518b7916316a97dcc258788.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="d8e134d93a4666285518b7916316a97dcc258788.c1.e0" e2="d8e134d93a4666285518b7916316a97dcc258788.c1.e2" id="d8e134d93a4666285518b7916316a97dcc258788.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="d8e134d93a4666285518b7916316a97dcc258788.c2" text="Currently, there are several experimental vaccine candidates that have relied on the GPC as an antigenic component, which have been evaluated in immunocompromised signal transducer and activator of transcription 1 knock-out (STAT-1 −/− ), interferon α/β receptor knock-out (IFNAR), or interferon receptor antibody transiently suppressed (IS) mouse models for CCHFV, as they recapitulate clinical illness and are uniformly lethal models for CCHF [16] [17] [18] [19] [20] . Vaccine candidate approaches have focused on either DNA expression of CCHFV antigens in host tissues, replication deficient viral-like particles, inactivated whole virus preparations, subunit antigen preparations, or vectored vaccinia virus vaccines 16, [20] [21] [22] [23] [24] [25] . Two of these preparations, a prime and boost strategy using modified recombinant Vaccinia virus (strain: Ankara) [MVA] encoding the GPC, and a prime, boost, and boost strategy with a DNA based vaccine encoding separate NP, G N , and G C antigens, have provided promising results with up to 100% protection in the IFNAR mouse model for CCHFV 23, 25 . Although CCHFV-NP by itself as an antigen in the MVA vaccine platform has failed to provide protection 26 .">
    <entity charOffset="305-313" id="d8e134d93a4666285518b7916316a97dcc258788.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="305-313" id="d8e134d93a4666285518b7916316a97dcc258788.c2.e1" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="d8e134d93a4666285518b7916316a97dcc258788.c3" text="Recombinant vesicular stomatitis viruses (rVSV) have been developed and evaluated as promising experimental vaccines for several pathogens, often requiring only a single-dose to induce protection 27-31 . The rVSV platform has been experimentally evaluated for both durability and safety 32-34 , and two rVSV vaccines, one for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) 35 and a second for Zaire ebolavirus (EBOV), have been tested in human clinical trials [36] [37] [38] . For these reasons, we hypothesized that rVSV vectors expressing CCHFV-GPC could elicit a protective response in a lethal animal model for CCHF. The aim of our study was to design, generate, characterize, and evaluate a rVSV vector encoding the CCHFV-GPC as an experimental vaccine for CCHFV.">
    <entity charOffset="22-32" id="d8e134d93a4666285518b7916316a97dcc258788.c3.e0" ontology_id="HP_0010280" text="stomatitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="332-348" id="d8e134d93a4666285518b7916316a97dcc258788.c3.e1" ontology_id="HP_0002721" text="immunodeficiency" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
