<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="d9664a611b4984ab4c6a6000a55ae8b495f7e997">
  <chunk id="d9664a611b4984ab4c6a6000a55ae8b495f7e997.c0" text="Encouraging rational antibiotic use in childhood pneumonia: a focus on Vietnam and the Western Pacific Region"/>
  <chunk id="d9664a611b4984ab4c6a6000a55ae8b495f7e997.c1" text="Globally, pneumonia is considered to be the biggest killer of infants and young children (aged &lt;5 years) outside the neonatal period, with the greatest disease burden in low-and middle-income countries. Optimal management of childhood pneumonia is challenging in settings where clinicians have limited information regarding the local pathogen and drug resistance profiles. This frequently results in unnecessary and poorly targeted antibiotic use. Restricting antibiotic use is a global priority, particularly in Asia and the Western Pacific Region where excessive use is driving high rates of antimicrobial resistance. The authors conducted a comprehensive literature review to explore the antibiotic resistance profile of bacteria associated with pneumonia in the Western Pacific Region, with a focus on Vietnam. Current management practices were also considered, along with the diagnostic dilemmas faced by doctors and other factors that increase unnecessary antibiotic use. This review offers some suggestions on how these issues may be addressed.">
    <entity charOffset="10-19" id="d9664a611b4984ab4c6a6000a55ae8b495f7e997.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="235-244" id="d9664a611b4984ab4c6a6000a55ae8b495f7e997.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="347-362" id="d9664a611b4984ab4c6a6000a55ae8b495f7e997.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0042493" text="drug resistance" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="749-758" id="d9664a611b4984ab4c6a6000a55ae8b495f7e997.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="d9664a611b4984ab4c6a6000a55ae8b495f7e997.c1.e0" e2="d9664a611b4984ab4c6a6000a55ae8b495f7e997.c1.e2" id="d9664a611b4984ab4c6a6000a55ae8b495f7e997.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="d9664a611b4984ab4c6a6000a55ae8b495f7e997.c1.e1" e2="d9664a611b4984ab4c6a6000a55ae8b495f7e997.c1.e2" id="d9664a611b4984ab4c6a6000a55ae8b495f7e997.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="d9664a611b4984ab4c6a6000a55ae8b495f7e997.c1.e2" e2="d9664a611b4984ab4c6a6000a55ae8b495f7e997.c1.e3" id="d9664a611b4984ab4c6a6000a55ae8b495f7e997.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
