<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="d9c174a11b8d2bd0a4df65b17e576934f3cce31c">
  <chunk id="d9c174a11b8d2bd0a4df65b17e576934f3cce31c.c0" text="Development of a recombinant Newcastle disease virus-vectored vaccine for infectious bronchitis virus variant strains circulating in Egypt">
    <entity charOffset="85-95" id="d9c174a11b8d2bd0a4df65b17e576934f3cce31c.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012387" text="bronchitis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="d9c174a11b8d2bd0a4df65b17e576934f3cce31c.c1" text="Infectious bronchitis virus (IBV) causes a major disease problem for the poultry industry worldwide. The currently used live-attenuated vaccines have the tendency to mutate and/or recombine with circulating field strains resulting in the emergence of vaccine-derived variant viruses. In order to circumvent these issues, and to develop a vaccine that is more relevant to Egypt and its neighboring countries, a recombinant avirulent Newcastle disease virus (rNDV) strain LaSota was constructed to express the codon-optimized S glycoprotein of the Egyptian IBV variant strain IBV/Ck/EG/ CU/4/2014 belonging to GI-23 lineage, that is prevalent in Egypt and in the Middle East. A wild type and two modified versions of the IBV S protein were expressed individually by rNDV. A high level of S protein expression was detected in vitro by Western blot and immunofluorescence analyses. All rNDV-vectored IBV vaccine candidates were genetically stable, slightly attenuated and showed growth patterns comparable to that of parental rLaSota virus. Single-dose vaccination of 1-day-old SPF White Leghorn chicks with the rNDVs expressing IBV S protein provided significant protection against clinical disease after IBV challenge but did not show reduction in tracheal viral shedding. Single-dose vaccination also provided complete protection against virulent NDV challenge. However, prime-boost vaccination using rNDV expressing the wild type IBV S protein provided better protection, after IBV challenge, against clinical signs and significantly reduced tracheal viral shedding. These results indicate that the NDV-vectored IBV vaccines are promising bivalent vaccine candidates to control both infectious bronchitis and Newcastle disease in Egypt.">
    <entity charOffset="11-21" id="d9c174a11b8d2bd0a4df65b17e576934f3cce31c.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012387" text="bronchitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="975-981" id="d9c174a11b8d2bd0a4df65b17e576934f3cce31c.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0040007" text="growth" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1694-1704" id="d9c174a11b8d2bd0a4df65b17e576934f3cce31c.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0012387" text="bronchitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="d9c174a11b8d2bd0a4df65b17e576934f3cce31c.c1.e0" e2="d9c174a11b8d2bd0a4df65b17e576934f3cce31c.c1.e1" id="d9c174a11b8d2bd0a4df65b17e576934f3cce31c.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="d9c174a11b8d2bd0a4df65b17e576934f3cce31c.c1.e1" e2="d9c174a11b8d2bd0a4df65b17e576934f3cce31c.c1.e2" id="d9c174a11b8d2bd0a4df65b17e576934f3cce31c.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
