<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="dbd27297be0609a02729bd99ac744b997d9e647f">
  <chunk id="dbd27297be0609a02729bd99ac744b997d9e647f.c0" text="Egyptian rousette bats maintain long-term protective immunity against Marburg virus infection despite diminished antibody levels OPEN">
    <entity charOffset="113-121" id="dbd27297be0609a02729bd99ac744b997d9e647f.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="113-121" id="dbd27297be0609a02729bd99ac744b997d9e647f.c0.e1" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="dbd27297be0609a02729bd99ac744b997d9e647f.c1" text="Following infection of ERBs with MARV, virus-specific IgG antibodies are induced but rapidly wane and by 3 months post-infection the bats are seronegative. To determine whether reinfection of ERBs plays a role in MARV maintenance, we challenge groups of ERBs that were &quot;naturally&quot; or experimentally infected with MARV 17-24 months prior. No bats in either group exhibit evidence of MARV replication or shedding and all bats develop virus-specific secondary immune responses. This study demonstrates that infection of ERBs with MARV induces long-term protective immunity against reinfection and indicates that other factors, such as host population dynamics, drive MARV maintenance in nature."/>
  <chunk id="dbd27297be0609a02729bd99ac744b997d9e647f.c2" text="Bats (order Chiroptera) have been implicated as natural reservoir hosts for numerous zoonotic viruses including coronaviruses 1 , filoviruses 2 , lyssaviruses 3 and paramyxoviruses 4, 5 . Although much insight on the natural history of virus infection in bats has been gained from experimental infections 3, 6-11 and mathematical modeling 12-15 , with the exception of Nipah and rabies viruses 16, 17 , relatively little is known about the long-term dynamics of the host immune response following primary virus infection. Of particular interest is whether or not long-term protective immunity is established following virus infection. This gap in knowledge can be attributed to: 1) the difficulties associated with obtaining serial biological samples from individual bats comprising large colonial, interconnected populations and 2) the uncertainty of whether short-term experimental models of virus infection in bats recapitulate natural bat-virus infection dynamics. Nonetheless, obtaining empirical data on the long-term dynamics of the bat immune response following virus infection is critical to understanding how bat-borne viruses are maintained in nature and identifying factors leading to virus spillover into humans.">
    <entity charOffset="471-486" id="dbd27297be0609a02729bd99ac744b997d9e647f.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0006955" text="immune response" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1044-1059" id="dbd27297be0609a02729bd99ac744b997d9e647f.c2.e1" ontology_id="GO_0006955" text="immune response" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="dbd27297be0609a02729bd99ac744b997d9e647f.c3" text="The marburgviruses (family Filoviridae, genus Marburgvirus, Marburg virus (MARV) and Ravn virus (RAVV)) cause outbreaks of hemorrhagic disease in sub-Saharan Africa characterized by human-to-human transmission and high case fatality ratios 18 . The cave-roosting Egyptian rousette bat (ERB; Rousettus aegyptiacus) has been identified as a natural reservoir host for the marburgviruses and a source of virus emergence in humans 2, 19, 20 . A longitudinal ecological study of marburgvirus infection in large ERB populations at Python Cave and Kitaka Mine, Uganda revealed an age-associated cyclical pattern of virus infection in which pups (0.0% PCR prevalence) are seemingly protected from virus infection through maternal antibodies until becoming independent, young juveniles at roughly 3 months of age (2.7% PCR prevalence, 4.1% seroprevalence) 19 . Acute virus infection levels increase in the juvenile population, peaking at 6 months of age (12.4% PCR prevalence, 14.8% seroprevalence), coincidental with the timing of the biannual birthing seasons. Juveniles enter the adult population at 7-8 months of age; a population that experiences year-round, consistent levels of virus infection (2.4% PCR prevalence, 21.5% seroprevalence). A susceptible-exposed-infectious-resistant (SEIR) mathematical model of marburgvirus transmission in a closed ERB population of 40,000 individuals with a twice-yearly birth pulse Published: xx xx xxxx OPEN www.nature.com/scientificreports/ 2 SCientifiC REPORTS | 7: 8763 |">
    <entity charOffset="852-857" id="dbd27297be0609a02729bd99ac744b997d9e647f.c3.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="Acute" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
