<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62">
  <chunk id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c0" text="biomedicines Skipping Multiple Exons to Treat DMD-Promises and Challenges"/>
  <chunk id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c1" text="Duchenne muscular dystrophy (DMD) is a lethal disorder caused by mutations in the DMD gene. Antisense-mediated exon-skipping is a promising therapeutic strategy that makes use of synthetic nucleic acids to skip frame-disrupting exon(s) and allows for short but functional protein expression by restoring the reading frame. In 2016, the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) approved eteplirsen, which skips DMD exon 51 and is applicable to approximately 13% of DMD patients. Multiple exon skipping, which is theoretically applicable to 80-90% of DMD patients in total, have been demonstrated in animal models, including dystrophic mice and dogs, using cocktail antisense oligonucleotides (AOs). Although promising, current drug approval systems pose challenges for the use of a cocktail AO. For example, both exons 6 and 8 need to be skipped to restore the reading frame in dystrophic dogs. Therefore, the cocktail of AOs targeting these exons has a combined therapeutic effect and each AO does not have a therapeutic effect by itself. The current drug approval system is not designed to evaluate such circumstances, which are completely different from cocktail drug approaches in other fields. Significant changes are needed in the drug approval process to promote the cocktail AO approach.">
    <entity charOffset="9-27" id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0003560" text="muscular dystrophy" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c2" text="Biomedicines 2018, 6, 1 2 of 12 dystrophin and subsequent loss of its function [9] . The mutation is known as an out-of-frame mutation when it disrupts the open reading frame (ORF) and prevents dystrophin from being expressed [9] . Sometimes, the ORF is preserved despite the presence of a mutation, which is known as an in-frame mutation, culminating in a truncated yet functional dystrophin leading to a milder form of the disorder, called Becker muscular dystrophy (BMD) [10] . BMD patients exhibit a later onset of the symptoms with slow progression and have a longer lifespan than DMD patients. In some cases, the symptoms are mild such that the diagnosis is made only in the later stages of life [10] . The most commonly used option to ameliorate DMD symptoms is the administration of a high dose of glucocorticoids [11] . Although this strategy prolongs ambulation, there are extensive side effects deteriorating the quality of the patient's life [11] .">
    <entity charOffset="449-467" id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0003560" text="muscular dystrophy" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="510-515" id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c2.e1" ontology_id="HP_0003674" text="onset" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="537-553" id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c2.e2" ontology_id="HP_0003677" text="slow progression" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="632-636" id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c2.e3" ontology_id="HP_0012825" text="mild" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c3" text="Variation in the severity of the disorder opened gateways to various therapeutics in order to ameliorate the severity to a milder phenotype, which is BMD [12] . For example, patients exhibiting large deletions, sometimes encompassing almost half the gene, are associated with milder cases of BMD [13] . Skipping the mutated exon(s) and/or adjacent exon(s) corrects the open reading frame (ORF), thereby leading to subsequent expression of dystrophin in the sarcolemma is thought of as the molecular mechanism underlying the revertant fibers, rare dystrophin-positive fibers in DMD patients and animal models [14, 15] . Exon skipping therapy knocks up (rescues) the target protein using antisense oligonucleotides (AOs) by restoring the ORF [16] , although this strategy is not applicable to mutations present in the essential dystrophin domains since the exons cannot be skipped without altering the functionality of dystrophin. Exon skipping has been demonstrated to systemically rescue deletion, duplication, splice site and nonsense mutations in animal models [17] [18] [19] [20] [21] . The main aim of exon-skipping therapy is to slow down the progression of DMD by interfering with the splicing events thereby converting the severe symptoms to the milder ones as seen in BMD [16] . Thus, it has been an attractive therapeutic approach to treat DMD and many improvements have been made these years [22] . In 2016, the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) has conditionally approved Sarepta Therapeutics' AO called eteplirsen as a treatment for DMD, which targets exon 51 and is applicable for approximately 13% of patients [23] .">
    <entity charOffset="17-25" id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c3.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012824" text="severity" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="109-117" id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c3.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012824" text="severity" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="457-467" id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c3.e2" ontology_id="GO_0042383" text="sarcolemma" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1230-1236" id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c3.e3" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c3.e0" e2="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c3.e2" id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c3.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c3.e1" e2="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c3.e2" id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c3.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c3.e2" e2="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c3.e3" id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c3.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c4" text="One limitation of exon-skipping strategy, however, is the limited applicability. In addition, the stability and function of each truncated dystrophin protein are unclear [24] . Importantly, multiple exon skipping (or multi-exon skipping) could address both issues. First, multi-exon skipping is potentially applicable to 80-90% of DMD patients in total [24] . Second, multi-exon skipping enables us to choose the truncated dystrophin protein which is more functional [24] . For example, in screening several truncated dystrophins, it was found that the polyproline structure present in hinge 2 region of the rod domain of dystrophin influences the functional capacity. Replacing this region with hinge 3 significantly improved the functional capacity and prevented muscle degeneration [25] . Recently, multi-exon skipping has been demonstrated in mouse and dog models of DMD using cocktail AOs [24] . In addition, a Clustered Regularly Interspaced Short Palindromic Repeat/ CRISPR associated protein 9 (CRISPR/Cas9)-mediated approach has been employed to genetically remove multiple exons in the DMD gene [26, 27] . Here, the recent development of multi-exon skipping will be discussed in the coming sections. In addition, we will discuss the regulatory challenges associated with the cocktail AO approach.">
    <entity charOffset="765-784" id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c4.e0" ontology_id="HP_0003202" text="muscle degeneration" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c5" text="Restoration of the ORF by employing AOs to remove frame-disrupting exons in order to bypass the mutation and produce a truncated dystrophin protein is the ultimate goal of antisense-mediated exon-skipping [28] . Approximately 70% of DMD patients with deletions and 47% with nonsense mutations are estimated to be treated by single exon skipping, rising to 80-97% by multiple exon skipping [20, 29] . Additionally, multi-exon skipping offers the prospect of selecting the truncated dystrophin that optimizes the protein function or stability. For example, DMD exons 3-9 deletion and exons 45-55 deletion are both known to be associated with a remarkably mild BMD Biomedicines 2018, 6, 1 3 of 12 phenotype compared to smaller in-frame deletions in these regions [29] [30] [31] [32] [33] [34] [35] [36] . The systemic effects of antisense-mediated multi-exon skipping tested in some of the models include: mdx52 mice with exon 52 deletion for multi-skipping of exons 45-55 [17,37,38] and canine X-linked muscular dystrophy (CXMD) dogs for multi-skipping of exons 6-9 [39]. Additionally, a Clustered Regularly Interspaced Short Palindromic Repeat/CRISPR associated protein 9 (CRISPR/Cas9)-mediated approach has been demonstrated to remove Dmd exons 52-53 systemically in mdx4cv mice with a nonsense mutation in dystrophin exon 53 [26] . In the following subsections, we will cover these approaches.">
    <entity charOffset="653-657" id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c5.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012825" text="mild" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="992-1000" id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c5.e1" ontology_id="HP_0001417" text="X-linked" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1001-1019" id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c5.e2" ontology_id="HP_0003560" text="muscular dystrophy" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c6" text="AOs are short, synthetic nucleic acid sequences about 8-50 bp long, that selectively hybridize to target mRNA sequences (Figure 1 ) [40] . Modifications are made to the phosphate backbone and the sugar rings that can change the solubility, potency, binding and stability (Figure 1) [41]. These modifications increase the affinity of AOs to the target RNA and also protect AOs from nuclease degradation, preventing the interaction of spliceosome machinery with regions of the AO and thereby resulting in the initiation of splicing [42] .">
    <entity charOffset="249-256" id="dc1a1a0fec049e850789175fe06b1453c9114c62.c6.e0" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
