<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="dc3d3e12aa6087b1141910cf58ac7f37c8cd0793">
  <chunk id="dc3d3e12aa6087b1141910cf58ac7f37c8cd0793.c0" text="CD11c hi Dendritic Cells Regulate Ly-6C hi Monocyte Differentiation to Preserve Immune-privileged CNS in Lethal Neuroinflammation OPEN">
    <entity charOffset="43-67" id="dc3d3e12aa6087b1141910cf58ac7f37c8cd0793.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0030224" text="Monocyte Differentiation" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="dc3d3e12aa6087b1141910cf58ac7f37c8cd0793.c1" text="Notably, DC roles in regulating innate CD11b + Ly-6C hi monocyte functions during neuroinflammation have not yet been addressed. Using selective ablation of CD11c hi PDCA-1 int/lo DCs without alteration in CD11c int PDCA-1 hi plasmacytoid DC number, we found that CD11c hi DCs are essential to control neuroinflammation caused by infection with neurotropic Japanese encephalitis virus, through early and increased infiltration of CD11b + Ly-6C hi monocytes and higher expression of CC chemokines. More interestingly, selective CD11c hi DC ablation provided altered differentiation and function of infiltrated CD11b + Ly-6C hi monocytes in the CNS through Flt3-L and GM-CSF, which was closely associated with severely enhanced neuroinflammation. Furthermore, CD11b + Ly-6C hi monocytes generated in CD11c hi DC-ablated environment had a deleterious rather than protective role during neuroinflammation, and were more quickly recruited into inflamed CNS, depending on CCR2, thereby exacerbating neuroinflammation via enhanced supply of virus from the periphery. Therefore, our data demonstrate that CD11c hi DCs provide a critical and unexpected role to preserve the immune-privileged CNS in lethal neuroinflammation via regulating the differentiation, function, and trafficking of CD11b + Ly-6C hi monocytes.">
    <entity charOffset="366-378" id="dc3d3e12aa6087b1141910cf58ac7f37c8cd0793.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002383" text="encephalitis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
