<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff">
  <chunk id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c0" text="The Rational Design of Therapeutic Peptides for Aminopeptidase N using a Substrate-Based Approach OPEN"/>
  <chunk id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c1" text="The M1 family of metalloproteases represents a large number of exopeptidases that cleave single amino acid residues from the N-terminus of peptide substrates. One member of this family that has been well studied is aminopeptidase N (APN), a multifunctional protease known to cleave biologically active peptides and aide in coronavirus entry. The proteolytic activity of APN promotes cancer angiogenesis and metastasis making it an important target for cancer therapy. To understand the substrate specificity of APN for the development of targeted inhibitors, we used a global substrate profiling method to determine the P1-P4′ amino acid preferences. The key structural features of the APN pharmacophore required for substrate recognition were elucidated by x-ray crystallography. By combining these substrate profiling and structural data, we were able to design a selective peptide inhibitor of APN that was an effective therapeutic both in vitro and in vivo against APN-expressing prostate cancer models.">
    <entity charOffset="383-389" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002664" text="cancer" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="390-402" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0001525" text="angiogenesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="452-458" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0002664" text="cancer" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="984-999" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0012125" text="prostate cancer" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="993-999" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c1.e4" ontology_id="HP_0002664" text="cancer" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c1.e0" e2="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c1.e1" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c1.e1" e2="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c1.e2" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c1.e1" e2="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c1.e3" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c1.e1" e2="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c1.e4" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2" text="The M1 aminopeptidase family is a group of Zn 2+ -dependent peptidases expressed ubiquitously by both fetal and adults tissues. Protein levels of M1 aminopeptidases have been documented in the brain, pancreas, lung, intestines, prostate, heart, endothelial cells and in components of the immune system 1, 2 . Each M1 aminopeptidase demonstrates unique substrate specificity by preferring certain amino acids at the N-terminus of their endogenous substrates. For example, aminopeptidase B prefers basic amino acids, whereas aminopeptidase A prefers acidic amino acids 3 . The substrate specificities of the aminopeptidases allow each of them to selectively catalyze the activation or metabolism of bioactive peptides. The most studied member of the mammalian M1 aminopeptidase family is aminopeptidase N (APN), also known as CD13. APN exists as a dimeric 110 kDa cell surface protein with a small N-terminal intracellular domain, a single-pass transmembrane anchor, a small extracellular stalk, and a large ectodomain on the C-terminus 4 . Cleaving after neutral amino acids, as implied by the &quot;N&quot; in its name, APN degrades peptides that are involved in different physiological pathways, including pain sensation and mood disorder by inactivating enkephalin, as well as regulating blood pressure by cleaving angiotensin III 1, 5 . APN is considered to be a &quot;moonlighting ectoenzyme&quot;, possessing functions other than its role as a peptidase 1 . Independent of its enzymatic activity, APN can also act a receptor for viral infection and as an adhesion molecule 6 .">
    <entity charOffset="683-693" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0008152" text="metabolism" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="862-874" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.e1" ontology_id="GO_0009986" text="cell surface" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="907-920" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.e2" ontology_id="GO_0005622" text="intracellular" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="943-956" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.e3" ontology_id="GO_0016021" text="transmembrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="973-986" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.e4" ontology_id="GO_0005576" text="extracellular" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1197-1201" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.e5" ontology_id="HP_0012531" text="pain" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1514-1529" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.e6" ontology_id="GO_0016032" text="viral infection" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.e0" e2="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.e5" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.e1" e2="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.e5" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.e2" e2="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.e5" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.e3" e2="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.e5" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.e4" e2="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.e5" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.e5" e2="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.e6" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c2.p5" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c3" text="In cancer, APN is widely over-expressed on the surface of a number of different cell types, ranging from endothelial cells to solid tumor cells. Enzymatically active APN has been documented to play import roles in tumorigenesis, angiogenesis, cell migration, and metastasis 7-9 . As a result of its role in cancer development and metastasis, APN has been a major target for drug development. The direct enzymatic activity of APN has been targeted using the potent transition-state analogue inhibitor bestatin (ubenimex) in several clinical trials 8, 10 . Although bestatin inhibits nearly a dozen aminopeptidases, it has demonstrated therapeutic benefit in acute myeloid leukemia, gastric cancer, and squamous cell lung carcinomas [11] [12] [13] . Other small molecule inhibitors of APN, including the natural product curucumin, have been developed and are undergoing testing in the clinic and preclinical models 10 . As with bestatin, specificity has plagued these next-generation compounds due to the limited interactions small molecules can make with the APN pharmacophore. Additional strategies for the therapeutic targeting of APN have utilized tumor-homing peptides based on the NGR motif that bind to APN and deliver">
    <entity charOffset="3-9" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c3.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002664" text="cancer" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="132-137" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c3.e1" ontology_id="HP_0002664" text="tumor" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="307-313" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c3.e2" ontology_id="HP_0002664" text="cancer" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="657-662" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c3.e3" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="657-679" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c3.e4" ontology_id="HP_0004808" text="acute myeloid leukemia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="689-695" id="dd9a2b263b1b66db904ed8a18dd6eba55e64bfff.c3.e5" ontology_id="HP_0002664" text="cancer" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
