<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="de79ddbf8cff4bf83533c1c991cf5640dab43ea5">
  <chunk id="de79ddbf8cff4bf83533c1c991cf5640dab43ea5.c0" text="mRNA as novel technology for passive immunotherapy"/>
  <chunk id="de79ddbf8cff4bf83533c1c991cf5640dab43ea5.c1" text="While active immunization elicits a lasting immune response by the body, passive immunotherapy transiently equips the body with exogenously generated immunological effectors in the form of either target-specific antibodies or lymphocytes functionalized with target-specific receptors. In either case, administration or expression of recombinant proteins plays a fundamental role. mRNA prepared by in vitro transcription (IVT) is increasingly appreciated as a drug substance for delivery of recombinant proteins. With its biological role as transient carrier of genetic information translated into protein in the cytoplasm, therapeutic application of mRNA combines several advantages. For example, compared to transfected DNA, mRNA harbors inherent safety features. It is not associated with the risk of inducing genomic changes and potential adverse effects are only temporary due to its transient nature. Compared to the administration of recombinant proteins produced in bioreactors, mRNA allows supplying proteins that are difficult to manufacture and offers extended pharmacokinetics for short-lived proteins. Based on great progress in understanding and manipulating mRNA properties, efficacy data in various models have now demonstrated that IVT mRNA constitutes a potent and flexible platform technology. Starting with an introduction into passive immunotherapy, this review summarizes the current status of IVT mRNA technology and its application to such immunological interventions.">
    <entity charOffset="44-59" id="de79ddbf8cff4bf83533c1c991cf5640dab43ea5.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0006955" text="immune response" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="540-549" id="de79ddbf8cff4bf83533c1c991cf5640dab43ea5.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0025153" text="transient" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="550-557" id="de79ddbf8cff4bf83533c1c991cf5640dab43ea5.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0005215" text="carrier" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="888-897" id="de79ddbf8cff4bf83533c1c991cf5640dab43ea5.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0025153" text="transient" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="de79ddbf8cff4bf83533c1c991cf5640dab43ea5.c1.e0" e2="de79ddbf8cff4bf83533c1c991cf5640dab43ea5.c1.e1" id="de79ddbf8cff4bf83533c1c991cf5640dab43ea5.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="de79ddbf8cff4bf83533c1c991cf5640dab43ea5.c1.e0" e2="de79ddbf8cff4bf83533c1c991cf5640dab43ea5.c1.e3" id="de79ddbf8cff4bf83533c1c991cf5640dab43ea5.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="de79ddbf8cff4bf83533c1c991cf5640dab43ea5.c1.e1" e2="de79ddbf8cff4bf83533c1c991cf5640dab43ea5.c1.e2" id="de79ddbf8cff4bf83533c1c991cf5640dab43ea5.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="de79ddbf8cff4bf83533c1c991cf5640dab43ea5.c1.e2" e2="de79ddbf8cff4bf83533c1c991cf5640dab43ea5.c1.e3" id="de79ddbf8cff4bf83533c1c991cf5640dab43ea5.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
