<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="e0494e196f7f6d783c5c05ac339d19934c000c1f">
  <chunk id="e0494e196f7f6d783c5c05ac339d19934c000c1f.c0" text="Article 1510 (2017) Establishment and Application of a Universal Coronavirus Screening Method Using MALDI-TOF"/>
  <chunk id="e0494e196f7f6d783c5c05ac339d19934c000c1f.c1" text="There are four human coronaviruses (HCoVs), distributed worldwide, that are associated with a range of respiratory symptoms. The discovery of severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS)-CoV and Middle East respiratory syndrome (MERS)-CoV shows that HCoVs pose a significant threat to human health. Our work aims to develop a sensitive method (mCoV-MS) which can not only identify known HCoVs accurately, but also have the ability to provide clues for the emerging HCoVs. The method was performed using a MassARRAY matrix-assisted laser desorption/ionization time-of-flight mass spectrometry (MALDI-TOF MS) system. We developed a 17-plex analysis to detect six HCoVs in Panel A and another 17-plex analysis to detect Alphacoronavirus and Betacoronavirus in Panel B. All tested primers and probes for the mCoV-MS method were effective, with no cross-reactivity observed with other common respiratory viruses. To confirm the usefulness of the mCoV-MS method we screened 384 pharyngeal and/or anal swab samples collected from bats/rodents, and 131 nasal and throat swabs from human patients. The results showed good concordance with the results of metagenomic analysis or PCR-sequencing. The validation test showed mCoV-MS method can detect potentially pathogenic CoVs in Alphacoronavirus and Betacoronavirus and provide convincingly phylogenetic evidences about unknown CoVs. The mCoV-MS method is a sensitive assay that is relatively simple to carry out. We propose that this method be used to complement next generation sequencing technology for large-scale screening studies.">
    <entity charOffset="142-148" id="e0494e196f7f6d783c5c05ac339d19934c000c1f.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="149-154" id="e0494e196f7f6d783c5c05ac339d19934c000c1f.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
