<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="e0d0ceb2658c588ef2f3549f2b9a928b441d94a6">
  <chunk id="e0d0ceb2658c588ef2f3549f2b9a928b441d94a6.c0" text="Contribution of porcine aminopeptidase N to porcine deltacoronavirus infection"/>
  <chunk id="e0d0ceb2658c588ef2f3549f2b9a928b441d94a6.c1" text="Porcine deltacoronavirus (PDCoV), a member of genus Deltacoronavirus, is an emerging swine enteropathogenic coronavirus (CoV). Although outstanding efforts have led to the identification of Alphacoronavirus and Betacoronavirus receptors, the receptor for Deltacoronavirus is unclear. Here, we compared the amino acid sequences of several representative CoVs. Phylogenetic analysis showed that PDCoV spike (S) protein was close to the cluster containing transmissible gastroenteritis virus (TGEV), which utilizes porcine aminopeptidase N (pAPN) as a functional receptor. Ectopic expression of pAPN in non-susceptible BHK-21 cells rendered them susceptible to PDCoV. These results indicate that pAPN may be a functional receptor for PDCoV infection. However, treatment with APN-specific antibody and inhibitors did not completely block PDCoV infection in IPI-2I porcine intestinal epithelial cells. pAPN knockout in IPI-2I cells completely blocked TGEV infection but only slightly decreased PDCoV infection. Homologous modeling of pAPN with the S1 C-terminal domain (S1-CTD) of PDCoV or TGEV showed that TGEV S1-CTD adopted β-turns (β1-β2 and β3-β4), forming the tip of a β-barrel, to recognize pAPN. However, only the top residues in the β1-β2 turn of PDCoV S1-CTD had the possibility to support an interaction with pAPN, and the β3-β4 turn failed to contact pAPN. We also discuss the evolution and variation of PDCoV S1-CTD based on structure information, providing clues to explain the usage of pAPN by PDCoV. Taken together, the results presented herein reveal that pAPN is likely not a critical functional receptor for PDCoV, although it is involved in PDCoV infection.">
    <entity charOffset="785-793" id="e0d0ceb2658c588ef2f3549f2b9a928b441d94a6.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="785-793" id="e0d0ceb2658c588ef2f3549f2b9a928b441d94a6.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
