<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="e12fc1a31129f8aa683a597e3899199409cc67f6">
  <chunk id="e12fc1a31129f8aa683a597e3899199409cc67f6.c0" text="Detection and phylogenetic characterization of arbovirus dual-infections among persons during a chikungunya fever outbreak, Haiti 2014">
    <entity charOffset="108-113" id="e12fc1a31129f8aa683a597e3899199409cc67f6.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0001945" text="fever" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="e12fc1a31129f8aa683a597e3899199409cc67f6.c1" text="In the context of recent arbovirus epidemics, questions about the frequency of simultaneous infection of patients with different arbovirus species have been raised. In 2014, a major Chikungunya virus (CHIKV) epidemic impacted the Caribbean and South America. As part of ongoing screening of schoolchildren presenting with acute undifferentiated febrile illness in rural Haiti, we used RT-PCR to identify CHIKV infections in 82 of 100 children with this diagnosis during May-August 2014. Among these, eight were infected with a second arbovirus: six with Zika virus (ZIKV), one with Dengue virus serotype 2, and one with Mayaro virus (MAYV). These dual infections were only detected following culture of the specimen, suggesting low viral loads of the co-infecting species. Phylogenetic analyses indicated that the ZIKV and MAYV strains differ from those detected later in 2014 and 2015, respectively. Moreover, CHIKV and ZIKV strains from co-infected patients clustered monophyletically in their respective phylogeny, and clock calibration traced back the common ancestor of each clade to an overlapping timeframe of introduction of these arboviruses onto the island.">
    <entity charOffset="66-75" id="e12fc1a31129f8aa683a597e3899199409cc67f6.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0040279" text="frequency" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="322-327" id="e12fc1a31129f8aa683a597e3899199409cc67f6.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="e12fc1a31129f8aa683a597e3899199409cc67f6.c2" text="Chikungunya virus (CHIKV) was the cause of a major epidemic in Haiti from May through August, 2014, as the disease swept through the Caribbean and South and Central America. During the time-period of the epidemic, our group was monitoring a cohort of children in semi-rural Haiti, using molecular and virology methods to assess the etiology of acute undifferentiated febrile illness. We identified CHIKV infections in 82 of 100 PLOS Neglected Tropical Diseases | https://doi.children presenting with fever during this time-period; six of the children infected with CHIKV were found to be co-infected with Zika virus (ZIKV), one with Dengue virus serotype 2, and one with Mayaro virus. For the CHIKV and ZIKV infections, a molecular clock calibrated framework revealed results suggestive of simultaneous co-infection. Our data highlight the frequency of dual infections in arbovirus disease cases (with the possibility of simultaneous co-infection), and document the frequent movement of virus strains within the Caribbean and the American continents. Chikungunya virus co-infections, Haiti 2014 PLOS Neglected Tropical Diseases | https://doi.">
    <entity charOffset="157-164" id="e12fc1a31129f8aa683a597e3899199409cc67f6.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0030645" text="Central" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="344-349" id="e12fc1a31129f8aa683a597e3899199409cc67f6.c2.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="500-505" id="e12fc1a31129f8aa683a597e3899199409cc67f6.c2.e2" ontology_id="HP_0001945" text="fever" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="840-849" id="e12fc1a31129f8aa683a597e3899199409cc67f6.c2.e3" ontology_id="HP_0040279" text="frequency" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="966-974" id="e12fc1a31129f8aa683a597e3899199409cc67f6.c2.e4" ontology_id="HP_0040282" text="frequent" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
