<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a">
  <chunk id="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c0" text="Feline bocavirus-1 associated with outbreaks of hemorrhagic enteritis in household cats: potential first evidence of a pathological role, viral tropism and natural genetic recombination">
    <entity charOffset="144-151" id="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0009606" text="tropism" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1" text="Thailand. Use of polymerase chain reaction revealed the presence of the FBoV-1 DNA in several tissues, suggesting hematogenous viremia, with the viral nucleic acid, detected by in situ hybridization (ISH), was localized in intestinal cells and vascular endothelium of intestinal mucosa and serosa, and in necrosis areas primarily in various lymph nodes while FPLV-immunohistochemical analysis revealed viral localization only in cryptal cells, neurons, and limited to leukocytes in the mesenteric lymph node. Full-length coding genome analysis of the Thai FBoV-1 strains isolated from moribund cats revealed three distinct strains with a high between-strain genetic diversity, while genetic recombination in one of the three FBoV-1 strains within the NS1 gene. This is the first report identifying natural genetic recombination of the FBoV-1 and describing the pathology and viral tropism of FBoV-1 infection in cats. Although the role of FBoV-1 associated with systemic infection of these cats remained undetermined, a contributory role of enteric infection of FBoV-1 is possible. Synergistic effects of dual infection with FPLV and FBoV-1 are hypothesized, suggesting more likely severe clinical presentations.">
    <entity charOffset="210-219" id="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012838" text="localized" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="305-313" id="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0001906" text="necrosis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="408-420" id="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0051179" text="localization" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="881-888" id="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0009606" text="tropism" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1182-1188" id="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1.e4" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1.e0" e2="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1.e1" id="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1.e0" e2="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1.e2" id="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1.e0" e2="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1.e3" id="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1.e1" e2="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1.e4" id="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1.e2" e2="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1.e4" id="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1.e3" e2="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1.e4" id="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c1.p5" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c2" text="Bocavirus (BoV), a linear single stranded DNA (ssDNA) virus with an approximately 5.5 kb length genome belongs to the genus Bocaparvovirus in the family Parvoviridae. The BoV genome possesses three main open reading frames, ORF1-3, encoding the non-structural protein NS1, capsid protein VP1/2 and nuclear phosphoprotein NP1, respectively 1 . The BoVs have emerged and caused diseases in various animals and humans, including canine BoVs (CBoVs), porcine BoVs (PBoV), bovine parvovirus, gorilla BoV, California sea lion BoV, rodent BoV, feline BoVs (FBoVs) and human BoVs (HBoVs), and so suggests a potentially wide host range of BoVs 1-3 . Many researches have indicated the association of BoVs with various clinical symptoms. Respiratory and intestinal diseases have been observed frequently in BoV-infected hosts 4 , but other uncommon clinical presentations have also been reported. These include encephalomyelitis in a PBoV-infected pig, necrotizing encephalitis in HBoV-infected humans and hepatitis in CBoV-infected dogs 5-7 . Likewise, previous studies have reported the detection of the BoV genome in liver, lymph node, feces and blood of infected hosts, suggesting that BoVs could cause systemic infections 2 .">
    <entity charOffset="955-967" id="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002383" text="encephalitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="996-1005" id="e197a8c2fc80727b35e38ea7aca28d8e6edfb27a.c2.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012115" text="hepatitis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
