<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="e1c5d3a82f4296f2867ccca63989530f17a773d7">
  <chunk id="e1c5d3a82f4296f2867ccca63989530f17a773d7.c0" text="molecules Using UPLC-MS/MS for Characterization of Active Components in Extracts of Yupingfeng and Application to a Comparative Pharmacokinetic Study in Rat Plasma after Oral Administration"/>
  <chunk id="e1c5d3a82f4296f2867ccca63989530f17a773d7.c1" text="Yupingfeng (YPF), a famous traditional Chinese medicine, which contains a large array of compounds, has been effectually used in health protection. A two-dimensional liquid chromatography ( 2 D-LC) combined with quadrupole time-of-flight mass spectrometry (QTOF-MS) method was firstly established to separate and identify chemical components in YPF. A total of 33 compounds were identified, including 15 constituents (flavonoids and saponins) in Astragali radix; seven constituents (sesquiterpenoids and polysaccharide) in Atractylodis rhizoma; and 11 constituents (chromone and coumarins) in Saposhnikoviae radix. The corresponding fragmentation pathway of typical substances was investigated. Then, seven active constituents (astragaloside, calycosin, formononetin, cimicifugoside, 4-O-beta-D-glucosyl-5-O-methylvisamminol, sec-O-glucosylhamaudol, and atractylenolide II) derived from three medicinal plants were chosen to further investigate the pharmacokinetic behavior of YPF formula using ultrahigh-performance liquid chromatography with triple quadrupole mass spectrometry system. The method was sensitive, accurate and reliable. We also used the area under the plasma concentration-time curve from zero to infinity (AUC 0−∞ ) as weighting factor to make an integrated pharmacokinetic curve. Results show that the constituents of Saposhnikoviae radix have the best absorption and pharmacokinetic behavior and may play important role in leading to the changes of overall therapeutic effects of YPF. Further study is needed to confirm the association between them.">
    <entity charOffset="965-973" id="e1c5d3a82f4296f2867ccca63989530f17a773d7.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0007610" text="behavior" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1403-1411" id="e1c5d3a82f4296f2867ccca63989530f17a773d7.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0007610" text="behavior" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="e1c5d3a82f4296f2867ccca63989530f17a773d7.c2" text="Molecules 2017, 22, 810 2 of 17 repeated relapses of respiratory infection, allergic rhinitis, chronic bronchitis and so on. It also plays an important role when severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS) and avian influenza (H7N9) epidemic outbreak in China. It contains three unique medicinal plants ( Figure S1 ), Astragali radix, Atractylodis rhizoma and Saposhnikoviae radix, in a ratio of 3:1:1 by weight of dried plants. Furthermore, numerous pharmacological studies exhibited that there were varieties of flavonoids and saponins in Astragali radix [11] [12] [13] [14] [15] ; sesquiterpenoids in Atractylodis rhizoma; and chromones and coumarins [16] in Saposhnikoviae radix, which show anti-inflammatory, antiviral and immunosuppressive activities, as well as their glycoside counterparts [17] [18] [19] [20] . We may assume that these kinds of constituents could explain the effectiveness of YPF formula.">
    <entity charOffset="95-102" id="e1c5d3a82f4296f2867ccca63989530f17a773d7.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011010" text="chronic" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="95-113" id="e1c5d3a82f4296f2867ccca63989530f17a773d7.c2.e1" ontology_id="HP_0004469" text="chronic bronchitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="103-113" id="e1c5d3a82f4296f2867ccca63989530f17a773d7.c2.e2" ontology_id="HP_0012387" text="bronchitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="162-168" id="e1c5d3a82f4296f2867ccca63989530f17a773d7.c2.e3" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="169-174" id="e1c5d3a82f4296f2867ccca63989530f17a773d7.c2.e4" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="e1c5d3a82f4296f2867ccca63989530f17a773d7.c3" text="Some analytical techniques based on LC-MS have been reported for the detection of several high-abundance components and their counterparts in YPF in biological samples [21, 22] . Most of these reports are focused on one kind of compound in single herbal plant of YPF, especially Astragali radix and Saposhnikoviae radix, using the most abundant compounds such as saponins and their aglycones as chemical markers [23] . Only a small number of reports are available on the simultaneous analysis of the bioactive constituents in Atractylodis rhizoma, such as atractylenolide I-III [24-26], as its low content and similar retention behaviors make the detection difficult. To our knowledge, there is no report on the integrated pharmacokinetics of both these ingredients (including atractylenolide II) in three herbs has been published."/>
  <chunk id="e1c5d3a82f4296f2867ccca63989530f17a773d7.c4" text="Due to its high peak capacity and accurate mass measurement, two-dimensional liquid chromatography ( 2 D-LC) combine with quadrupole time-of-flight mass spectrometry (QTOF-MS) is a powerful technique, particularly in separation of complicated herbal extracts. It also can be used to identify unknown compounds. In this study, 2 D-LC-QTOF-MS was established to separate and identify chemical compounds in YPF, and 33 compounds were identified or tentatively characterized. The corresponding fragmentation pathway of typical substances was investigated. Then, a rapid, simple and validated method using ultrahigh-performance liquid chromatography with triple quadrupole mass spectrometry (UPLC-QqQ-MS) system was developed for simultaneously quantification of astragaloside, calycosin, formononetin, atractylenolide II, cimicifugoside, 4-O-beta-D-glucosyl-5-O-methylvisamminol, and sec-O-glucosylhamaudol in rat plasma with relatively low concentration. We applied this method to pharmacokinetic study of YPF orally administered, and used the area under the plasma concentration-time curve from zero to infinity (AUC 0−∞ ) as the weighting factor to make an integrated pharmacokinetic behavior for those main active ingredients, which was firstly elucidated.">
    <entity charOffset="1183-1191" id="e1c5d3a82f4296f2867ccca63989530f17a773d7.c4.e0" ontology_id="GO_0007610" text="behavior" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
