<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="e4d4fde9df50047757fa69030407e861748c0eb3">
  <chunk id="e4d4fde9df50047757fa69030407e861748c0eb3.c0" text="Complete genomic sequence analysis of infectious bronchitis virus Ark DPI strain and its evolution by recombination">
    <entity charOffset="49-59" id="e4d4fde9df50047757fa69030407e861748c0eb3.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012387" text="bronchitis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="e4d4fde9df50047757fa69030407e861748c0eb3.c1" text="An infectious bronchitis virus Arkansas DPI (Ark DPI) virulent strain was sequenced, analyzed and compared with many different IBV strains and coronaviruses. The genome of Ark DPI consists of 27,620 nucleotides, excluding poly (A) tail, and comprises ten open reading frames. Comparative sequence analysis of Ark DPI with other IBV strains shows striking similarity to the Conn, Gray, JMK, and Ark 99, which were circulating during that time period. Furthermore, comparison of the Ark genome with other coronaviruses demonstrates a close relationship to turkey coronavirus. Among non-structural genes, the 5'untranslated region (UTR), 3C-like proteinase (3CL pro ) and the polymerase (RdRp) sequences are 100% identical to the Gray strain. Among structural genes, S1 has 97% identity with Ark 99; S2 has 100% identity with JMK and 96% to Conn; 3b 99%, and 3C to N is 100% identical to Conn strain. Possible recombination sites were found at the intergenic region of spike gene, 3'end of S1 and 3a gene. Independent recombination events may have occurred in the entire genome of Ark DPI, involving four different IBV strains, suggesting that genomic RNA recombination may occur in any part of the genome at number of sites. Hence, we speculate that the Ark DPI strain originated from the Conn strain, but diverged and evolved independently by point mutations and recombination between field strains.">
    <entity charOffset="14-24" id="e4d4fde9df50047757fa69030407e861748c0eb3.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012387" text="bronchitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="685-689" id="e4d4fde9df50047757fa69030407e861748c0eb3.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0003968" text="RdRp" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="e4d4fde9df50047757fa69030407e861748c0eb3.c1.e0" e2="e4d4fde9df50047757fa69030407e861748c0eb3.c1.e1" id="e4d4fde9df50047757fa69030407e861748c0eb3.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
