<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="e59da8ad79490ad5270928bd54c9a4d0b417d1ee">
  <chunk id="e59da8ad79490ad5270928bd54c9a4d0b417d1ee.c0" text="Metagenomic next-generation sequencing of samples from pediatric febrile illness in Tororo, Uganda"/>
  <chunk id="e59da8ad79490ad5270928bd54c9a4d0b417d1ee.c1" text="Febrile illness is a major burden in African children, and non-malarial causes of fever are uncertain. In this retrospective exploratory study, we used metagenomic next-generation sequencing (mNGS) to evaluate serum, nasopharyngeal, and stool specimens from 94 children (aged 2-54 months) with febrile illness admitted to Tororo District Hospital, Uganda. The most common microbes identified were Plasmodium falciparum (51.1% of samples) and parvovirus B19 (4.4%) from serum; human rhinoviruses A and C (40%), respiratory syncytial virus (10%), and human herpesvirus 5 (10%) from nasopharyngeal swabs; and rotavirus A (50% of those with diarrhea) from stool. We also report the near complete genome of a highly divergent orthobunyavirus, tentatively named Nyangole virus, identified from the serum of a child diagnosed with malaria and pneumonia, a Bwamba orthobunyavirus in the nasopharynx of a child with rash and sepsis, and the genomes of two novel human rhinovirus C species. In this retrospective exploratory study, mNGS identified multiple potential pathogens, including 3 new viral species, associated with fever in Ugandan children.">
    <entity charOffset="82-87" id="e59da8ad79490ad5270928bd54c9a4d0b417d1ee.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0001945" text="fever" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="637-645" id="e59da8ad79490ad5270928bd54c9a4d0b417d1ee.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0002014" text="diarrhea" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="907-911" id="e59da8ad79490ad5270928bd54c9a4d0b417d1ee.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0000988" text="rash" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1115-1120" id="e59da8ad79490ad5270928bd54c9a4d0b417d1ee.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0001945" text="fever" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
