<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="e6e057796aa14fa1808ee7076da0109362acb7c9">
  <chunk id="e6e057796aa14fa1808ee7076da0109362acb7c9.c0" text="Effect of thermal control of dry fomites on regulating the survival of human pathogenic bacteria responsible for nosocomial infections"/>
  <chunk id="e6e057796aa14fa1808ee7076da0109362acb7c9.c1" text="We monitored the survival of human pathogenic bacteria [Escherichia coli (ATCC), extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing E. coli (Clinical isolate), New Delhi metallo-βlactamase-producing E. coli (clinical isolate), Staphylococcus aureus (ATCC)] on dry materials (vinyl chloride, aluminum, plastic, stainless steel) at distinct temperatures (room temperature or 15˚C-37˚C). These bacteria favored a lower temperature for their prolonged survival on the dry fomites, regardless of the material type. Interestingly, when mixed with S. aureus, E. coli survived for a longer time at a lower temperature. Cardiolipin, which can promote the survival of S. aureus in harsh environments, had no effect on maintaining the survival of E. coli. Although the trends remained unchanged, adjusting the humidity from 40% to 60% affected the survival of bacteria on dry surfaces. Scanning electron microscopic analysis revealed no morphological differences in these bacteria immediately before or after one day of dry conditions. In addition, ATP assessment, a method used to visualize hightouch surfaces in hospitals, was not effective at monitoring bacterial dynamics. A specialized handrail device fitted with a heater, which was maintained at normal human body core temperature, successfully prohibited the prolonged survival of bacteria [Enterococcus faecalis (ATCC), E. coli (ATCC), Pseudomonas aeruginosa (ATCC), S. aureus (ATCC), Acinetobacter baumannii (clinical isolate), and Serratia marcescens (clinical isolate)], with the exception of spore-forming Bacillus subtilis (from our laboratory collection) and the yeastlike fungus Candida albicans (from our laboratory collection)] on dry surfaces. Taken together, we concluded that the tested bacteria favor lower temperatures for their survival in dry environments. Therefore, the thermal control of dry fomites has the potential to control bacterial survival on high-touch surfaces in hospitals.">
    <entity charOffset="427-436" id="e6e057796aa14fa1808ee7076da0109362acb7c9.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0025297" text="prolonged" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="813-821" id="e6e057796aa14fa1808ee7076da0109362acb7c9.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0032320" text="affected" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1295-1304" id="e6e057796aa14fa1808ee7076da0109362acb7c9.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0025297" text="prolonged" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
