<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="e98b7f593cd7bdd1bff632f4770505561768b9c8">
  <chunk id="e98b7f593cd7bdd1bff632f4770505561768b9c8.c0" text="Quality of life reported by survivors after hospitalization for Middle East respiratory syndrome (MERS)"/>
  <chunk id="e98b7f593cd7bdd1bff632f4770505561768b9c8.c1" text="Introduction: Data are lacking on impact of Middle East Respiratory Syndrome (MERS) on health-related quality of life (HRQoL) among survivors. Methods: We conducted a cross-sectional survey of MERS survivors who required hospitalization in Saudi Arabia during 2016-2017, approximately 1 year after diagnosis. The Short-Form General Health Survey 36 (SF-36) was administered by telephone interview to assess 8 quality of life domains for MERS survivors and a sample of survivors of severe acute respiratory infection (SARI) without MERS. We compared mean SF-36 scores of MERS and non-MERS SARI survivors using independent t-test, and compared categorical variables using chi-square test. Adjusted analyses were performed using multiple linear regression. Results: Of 355 MERS survivors, 83 were eligible and 78 agreed to participate. MERS survivors were younger than non-MERS SARI survivors (mean ± SD): (44.9 years ±12.9) vs (50.0 years ±13.6), p = 0.031. Intensive care unit (ICU) admissions were similar for MERS and non-MERS SARI survivors (46.2% vs. 57.1%), p = 0.20. After adjusting for potential confounders, there were no significant differences between MERS and non-MERS SARI survivors in physical component or mental component summary scores. MERS ICU survivors scored lower than MERS survivors not admitted to an ICU for physical function (p = 0.05), general health (p = 0.01), vitality (p = 0.03), emotional role (p = 0.03) and physical component summary (p &lt; 0.02). Conclusions: Functional scores were similar for MERS and non-MERS SARI survivors. However, MERS survivors of critical illness reported lower quality of life than survivors of less severe illness. Efforts are needed to address the long-term medical and psychological needs of MERS survivors.">
    <entity charOffset="481-487" id="e98b7f593cd7bdd1bff632f4770505561768b9c8.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="488-493" id="e98b7f593cd7bdd1bff632f4770505561768b9c8.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="494-515" id="e98b7f593cd7bdd1bff632f4770505561768b9c8.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0011947" text="respiratory infection" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1658-1664" id="e98b7f593cd7bdd1bff632f4770505561768b9c8.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
