<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="ebe8d3845bdfbc11f865667d68399c4862551d30">
  <chunk id="ebe8d3845bdfbc11f865667d68399c4862551d30.c0" text="Coronavirus Gene 7 Counteracts Host Defenses and Modulates Virus Virulence"/>
  <chunk id="ebe8d3845bdfbc11f865667d68399c4862551d30.c1" text="Transmissible gastroenteritis virus (TGEV) genome contains three accessory genes: 3a, 3b and 7. Gene 7 is only present in members of coronavirus genus a1, and encodes a hydrophobic protein of 78 aa. To study gene 7 function, a recombinant TGEV virus lacking gene 7 was engineered (rTGEV-D7). Both the mutant and the parental (rTGEV-wt) viruses showed the same growth and viral RNA accumulation kinetics in tissue cultures. Nevertheless, cells infected with rTGEV-D7 virus showed an increased cytopathic effect caused by an enhanced apoptosis mediated by caspase activation. Macromolecular synthesis analysis showed that rTGEV-D7 virus infection led to host translational shut-off and increased cellular RNA degradation compared with rTGEV-wt infection. An increase of eukaryotic translation initiation factor 2 (eIF2a) phosphorylation and an enhanced nuclease, most likely RNase L, activity were observed in rTGEV-D7 virus infected cells. These results suggested that the removal of gene 7 promoted an intensified dsRNA-activated host antiviral response. In protein 7 a conserved sequence motif that potentially mediates binding to protein phosphatase 1 catalytic subunit (PP1c), a key regulator of the cell antiviral defenses, was identified. We postulated that TGEV protein 7 may counteract host antiviral response by its association with PP1c. In fact, pull-down assays demonstrated the interaction between TGEV protein 7, but not a protein 7 mutant lacking PP1c binding motif, with PP1. Moreover, the interaction between protein 7 and PP1 was required, during the infection, for eIF2a dephosphorylation and inhibition of cell RNA degradation. Inoculation of newborn piglets with rTGEV-D7 and rTGEV-wt viruses showed that rTGEV-D7 virus presented accelerated growth kinetics and pathology compared with the parental virus. Overall, the results indicated that gene 7 counteracted host cell defenses, and modified TGEV persistence increasing TGEV survival. Therefore, the acquisition of gene 7 by the TGEV genome most likely has provided a selective advantage to the virus.">
    <entity charOffset="360-366" id="ebe8d3845bdfbc11f865667d68399c4862551d30.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0040007" text="growth" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="589-598" id="ebe8d3845bdfbc11f865667d68399c4862551d30.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0009058" text="synthesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="703-718" id="ebe8d3845bdfbc11f865667d68399c4862551d30.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0006401" text="RNA degradation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="707-718" id="ebe8d3845bdfbc11f865667d68399c4862551d30.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0009056" text="degradation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="779-790" id="ebe8d3845bdfbc11f865667d68399c4862551d30.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0006412" text="translation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="779-801" id="ebe8d3845bdfbc11f865667d68399c4862551d30.c1.e5" ontology_id="GO_0006413" text="translation initiation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="819-834" id="ebe8d3845bdfbc11f865667d68399c4862551d30.c1.e6" ontology_id="GO_0016310" text="phosphorylation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1035-1053" id="ebe8d3845bdfbc11f865667d68399c4862551d30.c1.e7" ontology_id="GO_0051607" text="antiviral response" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1121-1128" id="ebe8d3845bdfbc11f865667d68399c4862551d30.c1.e8" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1140-1151" id="ebe8d3845bdfbc11f865667d68399c4862551d30.c1.e9" ontology_id="GO_0016791" text="phosphatase" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1298-1316" id="ebe8d3845bdfbc11f865667d68399c4862551d30.c1.e10" ontology_id="GO_0051607" text="antiviral response" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1466-1473" id="ebe8d3845bdfbc11f865667d68399c4862551d30.c1.e11" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1589-1606" id="ebe8d3845bdfbc11f865667d68399c4862551d30.c1.e12" ontology_id="GO_0016311" text="dephosphorylation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1630-1645" id="ebe8d3845bdfbc11f865667d68399c4862551d30.c1.e13" ontology_id="GO_0006401" text="RNA degradation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1634-1645" id="ebe8d3845bdfbc11f865667d68399c4862551d30.c1.e14" ontology_id="GO_0009056" text="degradation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1762-1768" id="ebe8d3845bdfbc11f865667d68399c4862551d30.c1.e15" ontology_id="GO_0040007" text="growth" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1882-1891" id="ebe8d3845bdfbc11f865667d68399c4862551d30.c1.e16" ontology_id="GO_0043657" text="host cell" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
