<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="ecf90eb55cfef5b0212b52caf031abb31a1f11cc">
  <chunk id="ecf90eb55cfef5b0212b52caf031abb31a1f11cc.c0" text="Genome-wide identification and characterization of long non-coding RNAs involved in the early somatic embryogenesis in Dimocarpus longan Lour">
    <entity charOffset="94-115" id="ecf90eb55cfef5b0212b52caf031abb31a1f11cc.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0010262" text="somatic embryogenesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="102-115" id="ecf90eb55cfef5b0212b52caf031abb31a1f11cc.c0.e1" ontology_id="GO_0009790" text="embryogenesis" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="ecf90eb55cfef5b0212b52caf031abb31a1f11cc.c1" text="Background: Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are involved in variable cleavage, transcriptional interference, regulation of DNA methylation and protein modification. However, the regulation of lncRNAs in plant somatic embryos remains unclear. The longan (Dimocarpus longan) somatic embryogenesis (SE) system is a good system for research on longan embryo development. Results: In this study, 7643 lncRNAs obtained during early SE in D. longan were identified by high-throughput sequencing, among which 6005 lncRNAs were expressed. Of the expressed lncRNAs, 4790 were found in all samples and 160 were specifically expressed in embryogenic callus (EC), 154 in incomplete embryogenic compact structures (ICpECs), and 376 in globular embryos (GEs). We annotated the 6005 expressed lncRNAs, and 1404 lncRNAs belonged to 506 noncoding RNA (ncRNA) families and 4682 lncRNAs were predicted to target proteincoding genes. The target genes included 5051 cis-regulated target genes (5712 pairs) and 1605 trans-regulated target genes (3618 pairs). KEGG analysis revealed that most of the differentially expressed target genes (mRNAs) of the lncRNAs were enriched in the &quot;plant-pathogen interaction&quot; and &quot;plant hormone signaling&quot; pathways during early longan SE. Real-time quantitative PCR confirmed that 20 selected lncRNAs showed significant differences in expression and that five lncRNAs were related to auxin response factors. Compared with the FPKM expression trends, 16 lncRNA expression trends were the same in qPCR. In lncRNA-miRNA-mRNA relationship prediction, 40 lncRNAs were predicted to function as eTMs for 15 miRNAs and 7 lncRNAs were identified as potential miRNA precursors. In addition, we verified the lncRNA-miRNA-mRNA regulatory relationships by transient expression of miRNAs (miR172a, miR159a.1 and miR398a).">
    <entity charOffset="122-137" id="ecf90eb55cfef5b0212b52caf031abb31a1f11cc.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0006306" text="DNA methylation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="126-137" id="ecf90eb55cfef5b0212b52caf031abb31a1f11cc.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0032259" text="methylation" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="272-293" id="ecf90eb55cfef5b0212b52caf031abb31a1f11cc.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0010262" text="somatic embryogenesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="280-293" id="ecf90eb55cfef5b0212b52caf031abb31a1f11cc.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0009790" text="embryogenesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1753-1762" id="ecf90eb55cfef5b0212b52caf031abb31a1f11cc.c1.e4" ontology_id="HP_0025153" text="transient" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="ecf90eb55cfef5b0212b52caf031abb31a1f11cc.c1.e0" e2="ecf90eb55cfef5b0212b52caf031abb31a1f11cc.c1.e4" id="ecf90eb55cfef5b0212b52caf031abb31a1f11cc.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="ecf90eb55cfef5b0212b52caf031abb31a1f11cc.c1.e1" e2="ecf90eb55cfef5b0212b52caf031abb31a1f11cc.c1.e4" id="ecf90eb55cfef5b0212b52caf031abb31a1f11cc.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="ecf90eb55cfef5b0212b52caf031abb31a1f11cc.c1.e2" e2="ecf90eb55cfef5b0212b52caf031abb31a1f11cc.c1.e4" id="ecf90eb55cfef5b0212b52caf031abb31a1f11cc.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="ecf90eb55cfef5b0212b52caf031abb31a1f11cc.c1.e3" e2="ecf90eb55cfef5b0212b52caf031abb31a1f11cc.c1.e4" id="ecf90eb55cfef5b0212b52caf031abb31a1f11cc.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="ecf90eb55cfef5b0212b52caf031abb31a1f11cc.c2" text="Conclusion: Analyses of lncRNAs during early longan SE showed that differentially expressed lncRNAs were involved in expression regulation at each SE stage, and may form a regulatory network with miRNAs and mRNAs. These findings provide new insights into lncRNAs and lay a foundation for future functional analysis of lncRNAs during early longan SE."/>
</document>
