<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="ede3bef01a48a154a93f1286b907cd5a53a086eb">
  <chunk id="ede3bef01a48a154a93f1286b907cd5a53a086eb.c0" text="Vesicular Transport of Progeny Parvovirus Particles through ER and Golgi Regulates Maturation and Cytolysis">
    <entity charOffset="0-19" id="ede3bef01a48a154a93f1286b907cd5a53a086eb.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0016192" text="Vesicular Transport" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="10-19" id="ede3bef01a48a154a93f1286b907cd5a53a086eb.c0.e1" ontology_id="GO_0006810" text="Transport" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="98-107" id="ede3bef01a48a154a93f1286b907cd5a53a086eb.c0.e2" ontology_id="GO_0019835" text="Cytolysis" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="ede3bef01a48a154a93f1286b907cd5a53a086eb.c1" text="Progeny particles of non-enveloped lytic parvoviruses were previously shown to be actively transported to the cell periphery through vesicles in a gelsolin-dependent manner. This process involves rearrangement and destruction of actin filaments, while microtubules become protected throughout the infection. Here the focus is on the intracellular egress pathway, as well as its impact on the properties and release of progeny virions. By colocalization with cellular marker proteins and specific modulation of the pathways through over-expression of variant effector genes transduced by recombinant adeno-associated virus vectors, we show that progeny PV particles become engulfed into COPII-vesicles in the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) and are transported through the Golgi to the plasma membrane. Besides known factors like sar1, sec24, rab1, the ERM family proteins, radixin and moesin play (an) essential role(s) in the formation/loading and targeting of virus-containing COPII-vesicles. These proteins also contribute to the transport through ER and Golgi of the well described analogue of cellular proteins, the secreted Gaussia luciferase in absence of virus infection. It is therefore likely that radixin and moesin also serve for a more general function in cellular exocytosis. Finally, parvovirus egress via ER and Golgi appears to be necessary for virions to gain full infectivity through post-assembly modifications (e.g. phosphorylation). While not being absolutely required for cytolysis and progeny virus release, vesicular transport of parvoviruses through ER and Golgi significantly accelerates these processes pointing to a regulatory role of this transport pathway.">
    <entity charOffset="110-124" id="ede3bef01a48a154a93f1286b907cd5a53a086eb.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0005938" text="cell periphery" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="333-346" id="ede3bef01a48a154a93f1286b907cd5a53a086eb.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005622" text="intracellular" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="708-729" id="ede3bef01a48a154a93f1286b907cd5a53a086eb.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0005783" text="endoplasmic reticulum" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1028-1037" id="ede3bef01a48a154a93f1286b907cd5a53a086eb.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0006810" text="transport" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1490-1499" id="ede3bef01a48a154a93f1286b907cd5a53a086eb.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0019835" text="cytolysis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1527-1546" id="ede3bef01a48a154a93f1286b907cd5a53a086eb.c1.e5" ontology_id="GO_0016192" text="vesicular transport" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1537-1546" id="ede3bef01a48a154a93f1286b907cd5a53a086eb.c1.e6" ontology_id="GO_0006810" text="transport" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1664-1673" id="ede3bef01a48a154a93f1286b907cd5a53a086eb.c1.e7" ontology_id="GO_0006810" text="transport" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
