<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="ef39c95cda9c94452dc64147ea7d9c825e03b8bb">
  <chunk id="ef39c95cda9c94452dc64147ea7d9c825e03b8bb.c0" text="Consumption and Protection of Wild Animals Used in Traditional Medicine"/>
  <chunk id="ef39c95cda9c94452dc64147ea7d9c825e03b8bb.c1" text="A wide array of wildlife species, including many animals, are used in traditional medicines across many medicinal systems, including in Traditional Chinese Medicine (TCM). Due to over-exploitation and habitat loss, the populations of many animals commonly used in TCM have declined and are unable to meet market demand. A number of measures have been taken to try to reduce the impact that this large and growing market for TCM may have on wild animal species. Consumer preferences and behavior are known to play an important role in the consumption and protection of wild animals used in traditional medicine, and thus are likely to be an important factor in the success of many of these mechanisms-particularly given the significant percentage of TCMs that are over-the-counter products (access to which is not mediated by practitioners). In this study we conducted questionnaires and designed stated preference experiments embodying different simulation scenarios using a random sample of the population in Beijing to elicit individuals' knowledge, perceptions and preferences toward wild or farmed animal materials and their substitutes used in traditional Chinese medicine. We found that respondents had a stated preference for wild materials over farm-raised and other alternatives because they believe that the effectiveness of wildsourced materials is more credible than that of other sources. However, we also found that, although respondents used TCM products, they had a poor understanding of the function or composition of either traditional Chinese medicines or proprietary Chinese medicines (PCM), and paid little attention to the composition of products when making purchasing decisions. Furthermore, awareness of the need for species protection, or &quot;conservation consciousness&quot; was found to play an important role in willingness to accept substitutions for wild animal materials, while traditional animal medicinal materials (TAMs) derived from wellknown endangered species, such as bear bile and tiger bone, show relatively higher substitutability. These results suggest that there is still hope for conservation measures which PLOS ONE | seek to promote a transition to farmed animal, plant and synthetic ingredients and provide clear directions for future social marketing, education and engagement efforts.">
    <entity charOffset="486-494" id="ef39c95cda9c94452dc64147ea7d9c825e03b8bb.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0007610" text="behavior" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="ef39c95cda9c94452dc64147ea7d9c825e03b8bb.c2" text="This study was conducted in Beijing in the summer of 2011. A stratified survey design was chosen to randomly select neighborhoods and households from a sample frame, according to Perception and Preference of Wild Animals in Traditional Medicine PLOS ONE |"/>
</document>
