<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="f14e7b5fff3c2ac074e61beacf4fb1bba524e438">
  <chunk id="f14e7b5fff3c2ac074e61beacf4fb1bba524e438.c0" text="molecules Anti-Inflammatory and Anti-Allergic Activities of Pentaherb Formula, Moutan Cortex (Danpi) and Gallic Acid"/>
  <chunk id="f14e7b5fff3c2ac074e61beacf4fb1bba524e438.c1" text="Pentaherb formula (PHF) has been proven to improve the quality of life of children with atopic dermatitis without side effects. The aim of this study was to elucidate the potential anti-inflammatory and anti-allergic activities of PHF, Moutan Cortex (Danpi/DP) and gallic acid (GA) using human basophils (KU812 cells), which are crucial effector cells in allergic inflammation. PHF, DP and GA could significantly suppress the expression of allergic inflammatory cytokine IL-33-upregulated intercellular adhesion molecule (ICAM)-1, and the release of chemokines CCL2, CCL5, CXCL8 and inflammatory cytokine IL-6 from KU812 cells (all p &lt; 0.05). With the combined use of dexamethasone (0.01 μg/mL) and GA (10 μg/mL), the suppression of ICAM-1 expression">
    <entity charOffset="88-105" id="f14e7b5fff3c2ac074e61beacf4fb1bba524e438.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0001047" text="atopic dermatitis" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="95-105" id="f14e7b5fff3c2ac074e61beacf4fb1bba524e438.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011123" text="dermatitis" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="f14e7b5fff3c2ac074e61beacf4fb1bba524e438.c2" text="Molecules 2013, 18 2484 and CCL5 and IL-6 release of IL-33-activated KU812 cells were significantly greater than the use of GA alone (all p &lt; 0.05). The suppression of the IL-33-induced activation of intracellular signalling molecules p38 mitogen activated protein kinase, nuclear factor-B and c-Jun amino-terminal kinase in GA-treated KU812 cells could be the underlying mechanism for the suppression on ICAM-1, chemokines and cytokines. The combined use of dexamethasone with the natural products PHF or DP or GA might therefore enhance the development of a novel therapeutic modality for allergic inflammatory diseases with high potency and fewer side effects.">
    <entity charOffset="200-213" id="f14e7b5fff3c2ac074e61beacf4fb1bba524e438.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0005622" text="intracellular" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="214-224" id="f14e7b5fff3c2ac074e61beacf4fb1bba524e438.c2.e1" ontology_id="GO_0023052" text="signalling" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
