<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="f2d560b5f6bd9fcad15c0b5e6e4284cfe9386e3c">
  <chunk id="f2d560b5f6bd9fcad15c0b5e6e4284cfe9386e3c.c0" text="Long-Acting HIV-1 Fusion Inhibitory Peptides and their Mechanisms of Action"/>
  <chunk id="f2d560b5f6bd9fcad15c0b5e6e4284cfe9386e3c.c1" text="The clinical application of HIV fusion inhibitor, enfuvirtide (T20), was limited mainly because of its short half-life. Here we designed and synthesized two PEGylated C34 peptides, PEG2kC34 and PEG5kC34, with the PEG chain length of 2 and 5 kDa, respectively, and evaluated their anti-HIV-1 activity and mechanisms of action. We found that these two PEGylated peptides could bind to the HIV-1 peptide N36 to form high affinity complexes with high α-helicity. The peptides PEG2kC34 and PEG5kC34 effectively inhibited HIV-1 Env-mediated cell-cell fusion with an effective concentration for 50% inhibition (EC 50 ) of about 36 nM. They also inhibited infection of the laboratory-adapted HIV-1 strain NL4-3 with EC 50 of about 4-5 nM, and against 47 HIV-1 clinical isolates circulating in China with mean EC 50 of PEG2kC34 and PEG5kC34 of about 26 nM and 32 nM, respectively. The plasma half-life (t 1/2 ) of PEG2kC34 and PEG5kC34 was 2.6 h and 5.1 h, respectively, and the t 1/2 of PEGylated C34 was about 2.4-fold and 4.6-fold longer than C34 (~1.1 h), respectively. These findings suggest that PEGylated C34 with broad-spectrum anti-HIV-1 activity and prolonged half-life can be further developed as a peptide fusion inhibitor-based long-acting anti-HIV drug for clinical use to treat HIV-infected patients who have failed to respond to current anti-retrovirus drugs.">
    <entity charOffset="535-551" id="f2d560b5f6bd9fcad15c0b5e6e4284cfe9386e3c.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0140253" text="cell-cell fusion" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1047-1050" id="f2d560b5f6bd9fcad15c0b5e6e4284cfe9386e3c.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0032117" text="haa" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1151-1160" id="f2d560b5f6bd9fcad15c0b5e6e4284cfe9386e3c.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0025297" text="prolonged" type="phenotype"/>
    <pair e1="f2d560b5f6bd9fcad15c0b5e6e4284cfe9386e3c.c1.e0" e2="f2d560b5f6bd9fcad15c0b5e6e4284cfe9386e3c.c1.e2" id="f2d560b5f6bd9fcad15c0b5e6e4284cfe9386e3c.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="f2d560b5f6bd9fcad15c0b5e6e4284cfe9386e3c.c1.e1" e2="f2d560b5f6bd9fcad15c0b5e6e4284cfe9386e3c.c1.e2" id="f2d560b5f6bd9fcad15c0b5e6e4284cfe9386e3c.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
