<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="f2f78c95ab378a31bd35dc1de84e0ec75eb7ce1b">
  <chunk id="f2f78c95ab378a31bd35dc1de84e0ec75eb7ce1b.c0" text="Epidemiology of HBoV1 infection and relationship with meteorological conditions in hospitalized pediatric patients with acute respiratory illness: a 7-year study in a subtropical region">
    <entity charOffset="120-125" id="f2f78c95ab378a31bd35dc1de84e0ec75eb7ce1b.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="f2f78c95ab378a31bd35dc1de84e0ec75eb7ce1b.c1" text="Background: Human bocavirus 1 (HBoV1) is an important cause of acute respiratory illness (ARI), yet the epidemiology and effect of meteorological conditions on infection is not fully understood. To investigate the distribution of HBoV1 and determine the effect of meteorological conditions, hospitalized pediatric patients were studied in a subtropical region of China. Methods: Samples from 11,399 hospitalized pediatric patients (≤14 years old), with ARI were tested for HBoV1 and other common respiratory pathogens using real-time PCR, between July 2009 and June 2016. In addition, local meteorological data were collected. Results: Of the 11,399 patients tested, 5606 (49.2%) were positive for at least one respiratory pathogen. Two hundred forty-eight of 11,399 (2.2%) were positive for HBoV1 infection. Co-infection was common in HBoV1-positive patients (45.2%, 112/248). A significant difference in the prevalence of HBoV1 was found in patients in different age groups (p &lt; 0.001), and the peak prevalence was found in patients aged 7-12 months (4.7%, 56/1203). Two HBoV1 prevalence peaks were found in summer (between June and September) and winter (between November and December). The prevalence of HBoV1 was significantly positively correlated with mean temperature and negatively correlated with mean relative humidity, and the mean temperature in the preceding month had better explanatory power than the current monthly temperature. Conclusions: This study provides a better understanding of the characteristics of HBoV1 infection in children in subtropical regions. Data from this study provide useful information for the future control and prevention of HBoV1 infections.">
    <entity charOffset="63-68" id="f2f78c95ab378a31bd35dc1de84e0ec75eb7ce1b.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
