<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="f3a378151096d647f4982841888e944c7aa031b1">
  <chunk id="f3a378151096d647f4982841888e944c7aa031b1.c0" text="Citation: Early Growth Response Gene-1 Suppresses Foot-and-Mouth Disease Virus Replication by Enhancing Type I Interferon Pathway Signal Transduction">
    <entity charOffset="16-22" id="f3a378151096d647f4982841888e944c7aa031b1.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0040007" text="Growth" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="130-149" id="f3a378151096d647f4982841888e944c7aa031b1.c0.e1" ontology_id="GO_0007165" text="Signal Transduction" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="137-149" id="f3a378151096d647f4982841888e944c7aa031b1.c0.e2" ontology_id="GO_0009293" text="Transduction" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="f3a378151096d647f4982841888e944c7aa031b1.c1" text="Early growth response gene-1 (EGR1) is a multifunctional transcription factor that is implicated in viral infection. In this study, we observed that foot-and-mouth disease virus (FMDV) infection significantly triggered EGR1 expression. Overexpression of EGR1 suppressed FMDV replication in porcine cells, and knockdown of EGR1 considerably promoted FMDV replication. A previously reported FMDV mutant virus (with two amino acids mutations in SAP domain) that displays a strong type I interferon (IFN) induction activity was used in this study. We found that SAP mutant FMDV infection induced a higher expression of EGR1 than wildtype FMDV infection, and also triggered higher IFNβ and IFN-stimulated genes (ISGs) expression than wildtype FMDV infection. This implied a link between EGR1 and type I IFN signaling. Further study showed that overexpression of EGR1 resulted in Sendai virus (SeV)-induced IFN-stimulated response element (ISRE) and NF-κB promoter activation. In addition, the SeV-induced ISGs expression was impaired in EGR1 knockdown cells. EGR1 upregulation promoted type I IFN signaling activation and suppressed FMDV and Seneca Valley virus replication. Suppression of the transcriptional activity of EGR1 did not affect its antiviral effect against FMDV. This study reveals a new mechanism evolved by EGR1 to enhance type I IFN signaling and suppress FMDV replication.">
    <entity charOffset="6-12" id="f3a378151096d647f4982841888e944c7aa031b1.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0040007" text="growth" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="802-811" id="f3a378151096d647f4982841888e944c7aa031b1.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0023052" text="signaling" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1092-1101" id="f3a378151096d647f4982841888e944c7aa031b1.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0023052" text="signaling" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1345-1354" id="f3a378151096d647f4982841888e944c7aa031b1.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0023052" text="signaling" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
