<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="f3b7f4469ac01f1ce916d24172570c43c537627e">
  <chunk id="f3b7f4469ac01f1ce916d24172570c43c537627e.c0" text="Glycyrrhizin Exerts Antioxidative Effects in H5N1 Influenza A Virus-Infected Cells and Inhibits Virus Replication and Pro-Inflammatory Gene Expression">
    <entity charOffset="135-150" id="f3b7f4469ac01f1ce916d24172570c43c537627e.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0010467" text="Gene Expression" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="f3b7f4469ac01f1ce916d24172570c43c537627e.c1" text="Glycyrrhizin is known to exert antiviral and anti-inflammatory effects. Here, the effects of an approved parenteral glycyrrhizin preparation (Stronger Neo-Minophafen C) were investigated on highly pathogenic influenza A H5N1 virus replication, H5N1-induced apoptosis, and H5N1-induced pro-inflammatory responses in lung epithelial (A549) cells. Therapeutic glycyrrhizin concentrations substantially inhibited H5N1-induced expression of the pro-inflammatory molecules CXCL10, interleukin 6, CCL2, and CCL5 (effective glycyrrhizin concentrations 25 to 50 mg/ml) but interfered with H5N1 replication and H5N1-induced apoptosis to a lesser extent (effective glycyrrhizin concentrations 100 mg/ml or higher). Glycyrrhizin also diminished monocyte migration towards supernatants of H5N1-infected A549 cells. The mechanism by which glycyrrhizin interferes with H5N1 replication and H5N1-induced pro-inflammatory gene expression includes inhibition of H5N1-induced formation of reactive oxygen species and (in turn) reduced activation of NFkB, JNK, and p38, redoxsensitive signalling events known to be relevant for influenza A virus replication. Therefore, glycyrrhizin may complement the arsenal of potential drugs for the treatment of H5N1 disease.">
    <entity charOffset="905-920" id="f3b7f4469ac01f1ce916d24172570c43c537627e.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0010467" text="gene expression" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1065-1075" id="f3b7f4469ac01f1ce916d24172570c43c537627e.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0023052" text="signalling" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
