<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="f3e85a35ab89c9a55eeb83c6e17f881d5c497d82">
  <chunk id="f3e85a35ab89c9a55eeb83c6e17f881d5c497d82.c0" text="Genome-wide host responses against infectious laryngotracheitis virus vaccine infection in chicken embryo lung cells"/>
  <chunk id="f3e85a35ab89c9a55eeb83c6e17f881d5c497d82.c1" text="Background: Infectious laryngotracheitis virus (ILTV; gallid herpesvirus 1) infection causes high mortality and huge economic losses in the poultry industry. To protect chickens against ILTV infection, chicken-embryo origin (CEO) and tissue-culture origin (TCO) vaccines have been used. However, the transmission of vaccine ILTV from vaccinated-to unvaccinated chickens can cause severe respiratory disease. Previously, host cell responses against virulent ILTV infections were determined by microarray analysis. In this study, a microarray analysis was performed to understand host-vaccine ILTV interactions at the host gene transcription level. Results: The 44 K chicken oligo microarrays were used, and the results were compared to those found in virulent ILTV infection. Total RNAs extracted from vaccine ILTV infected chicken embryo lung cells at 1, 2, 3 and 4 days post infection (dpi), compared to 0 dpi, were subjected to microarray assay using the two color hybridization method. Data analysis using JMP Genomics 5.0 and the Ingenuity Pathway Analysis (IPA) program showed that 213 differentially expressed genes could be grouped into a number of functional categories including tissue development, cellular growth and proliferation, cellular movement, and inflammatory responses. Moreover, 10 possible gene networks were created by the IPA program to show intermolecular connections. Interestingly, of 213 differentially expressed genes, BMP2, C8orf79, F10, and NPY were expressed distinctly in vaccine ILTV infection when compared to virulent ILTV infection.">
    <entity charOffset="380-386" id="f3e85a35ab89c9a55eeb83c6e17f881d5c497d82.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="420-429" id="f3e85a35ab89c9a55eeb83c6e17f881d5c497d82.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0043657" text="host cell" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1208-1223" id="f3e85a35ab89c9a55eeb83c6e17f881d5c497d82.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0016049" text="cellular growth" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1217-1223" id="f3e85a35ab89c9a55eeb83c6e17f881d5c497d82.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0040007" text="growth" type="gene_function"/>
    <pair e1="f3e85a35ab89c9a55eeb83c6e17f881d5c497d82.c1.e0" e2="f3e85a35ab89c9a55eeb83c6e17f881d5c497d82.c1.e1" id="f3e85a35ab89c9a55eeb83c6e17f881d5c497d82.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="f3e85a35ab89c9a55eeb83c6e17f881d5c497d82.c1.e0" e2="f3e85a35ab89c9a55eeb83c6e17f881d5c497d82.c1.e2" id="f3e85a35ab89c9a55eeb83c6e17f881d5c497d82.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="f3e85a35ab89c9a55eeb83c6e17f881d5c497d82.c1.e0" e2="f3e85a35ab89c9a55eeb83c6e17f881d5c497d82.c1.e3" id="f3e85a35ab89c9a55eeb83c6e17f881d5c497d82.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="f3e85a35ab89c9a55eeb83c6e17f881d5c497d82.c2" text="Conclusions: Comprehensive knowledge of gene expression and biological functionalities of host factors during vaccine ILTV infection can provide insight into host cellular defense mechanisms compared to those of virulent ILTV.">
    <entity charOffset="40-55" id="f3e85a35ab89c9a55eeb83c6e17f881d5c497d82.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0010467" text="gene expression" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
