<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="f46d2803581226a9a94026693e95db88e7c70641">
  <chunk id="f46d2803581226a9a94026693e95db88e7c70641.c0" text="A Porcine Adenovirus with Low Human Seroprevalence Is a Promising Alternative Vaccine Vector to Human Adenovirus 5 in an H5N1 Virus Disease Model"/>
  <chunk id="f46d2803581226a9a94026693e95db88e7c70641.c1" text="Human adenovirus 5 (AdHu5) vectors are robust vaccine platforms however the presence of naturally-acquired neutralizing antibodies may reduce vector efficacy and potential for re-administration. This study evaluates immune responses and protection following vaccination with a replication-incompetent porcine adenovirus 3 (PAV3) vector as an alternative vaccine to AdHu5 using an avian influenza H5N1 disease model. Vaccine efficacy was evaluated in BALB/c mice following vaccination with different doses of the PAV3 vector expressing an optimized A/Hanoi/30408/2005 H5N1 hemagglutinin antigen (PAV3-HA) and compared with an AdHu5-HA control. PAV3-HA rapidly generated antibody responses, with significant neutralizing antibody titers on day 21, and stronger cellular immune responses detected on day 8, compared to AdHu5-HA. The PAV3-HA vaccine, administered 8 days before challenge, demonstrated improved survival and lower virus load. Evaluation of long-term vaccine efficacy at 12 months post-vaccination showed better protection with the PAV3-HA than with the AdHu5-HA vaccine. Importantly, as opposed to AdHu5, PAV3 vector was not significantly neutralized by human antibodies pooled from over 10,000 individuals. Overall, PAV3-based vector is capable of mediating swift, strong immune responses and offer a promising alternative to AdHu5.">
    <entity charOffset="669-677" id="f46d2803581226a9a94026693e95db88e7c70641.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="669-677" id="f46d2803581226a9a94026693e95db88e7c70641.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="719-727" id="f46d2803581226a9a94026693e95db88e7c70641.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="719-727" id="f46d2803581226a9a94026693e95db88e7c70641.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
