<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="f50b6632623eb4fe2193588b4f2c217c7125872d">
  <chunk id="f50b6632623eb4fe2193588b4f2c217c7125872d.c0" text="Journal of Autoimmune Diseases Virus-mediated autoimmunity in Multiple Sclerosis">
    <entity charOffset="46-58" id="f50b6632623eb4fe2193588b4f2c217c7125872d.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002960" text="autoimmunity" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="f50b6632623eb4fe2193588b4f2c217c7125872d.c1" text="Epidemiological data suggest the notion that in Multiple Sclerosis (MS) is an acquired autoimmune disease and the cause may be an environmental factor(s), probably infectious, in genetically susceptible individuals. Several cases of viral induced demyelinatimg encephalomyelitis in human beings and in experimental models as well as the presence of IgG oligoclonal bands in the cerebrospinal fluid indicate that the infectious factor may be viral. However, the absence of a specific virus identification in MS central nervous system may hardly support this notion. On the other hand, the partial response of patients with MS to immunosuppressive and immunomodulatory therapy support the evidence of an autoimmune etiology for MS. However, the autoimmune hypothesis shares the same criticism with the infectious one in that no autoantigen(s) specific to and causative for MS has ever been identified. Nevertheless, the absence of identifiable infectious agent, especially viral does not rule out its presence at a certain time -point and the concomitant long term triggering of an autoimmune cascade of events thereafter. Several concepts have emerged in an attempt to explain the autoimmune mechanisms and ongoing neurodegeneration in MS on the basis of the infectious -viral hypothesis.">
    <entity charOffset="87-105" id="f50b6632623eb4fe2193588b4f2c217c7125872d.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002960" text="autoimmune disease" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="510-517" id="f50b6632623eb4fe2193588b4f2c217c7125872d.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0030645" text="central" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1214-1231" id="f50b6632623eb4fe2193588b4f2c217c7125872d.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0002180" text="neurodegeneration" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
