<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="f58cfab11be3906401550ffe0ba6e444d1056853">
  <chunk id="f58cfab11be3906401550ffe0ba6e444d1056853.c0" text="Human Enterovirus Nonstructural Protein 2C ATPase Functions as Both an RNA Helicase and ATP-Independent RNA Chaperone">
    <entity charOffset="104-117" id="f58cfab11be3906401550ffe0ba6e444d1056853.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0034336" text="RNA Chaperone" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="f58cfab11be3906401550ffe0ba6e444d1056853.c1" text="RNA helicases and chaperones are the two major classes of RNA remodeling proteins, which function to remodel RNA structures and/or RNA-protein interactions, and are required for all aspects of RNA metabolism. Although some virus-encoded RNA helicases/chaperones have been predicted or identified, their RNA remodeling activities in vitro and functions in the viral life cycle remain largely elusive. Enteroviruses are a large group of positivestranded RNA viruses in the Picornaviridae family, which includes numerous important human pathogens. Herein, we report that the nonstructural protein 2C ATPase of enterovirus 71 (EV71), which is the major causative pathogen of hand-foot-and-mouth disease and has been regarded as the most important neurotropic enterovirus after poliovirus eradication, functions not only as an RNA helicase that 3 0 -to-5 0 unwinds RNA helices in an adenosine triphosphate (ATP)-dependent manner, but also as an RNA chaperone that destabilizes helices bidirectionally and facilitates strand annealing and complex RNA structure formation independently of ATP. We also determined that the helicase activity is based on the EV71 2C ATPase middle domain, whereas the C-terminus is indispensable for its RNA chaperoning activity. By promoting RNA template recycling, 2C ATPase facilitated EV71 RNA synthesis in vitro; when 2C ATPase helicase activity was impaired, EV71 RNA replication and virion production were mostly abolished in cells, indicating that 2C ATPase -mediated RNA remodeling plays a critical role in the enteroviral life cycle. Furthermore, the RNA helicase and chaperoning activities of 2C ATPase are also conserved in coxsackie A virus 16 (CAV16), another important enterovirus. Altogether, our findings are the first to demonstrate the RNA helicase and chaperoning activities associated with enterovirus 2C ATPase , and our study provides both in vitro and cellular evidence for their potential roles during viral RNA replication. These findings increase our understanding of enteroviruses and the two types of RNA remodeling activities.">
    <entity charOffset="359-375" id="f58cfab11be3906401550ffe0ba6e444d1056853.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0019058" text="viral life cycle" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="940-953" id="f58cfab11be3906401550ffe0ba6e444d1056853.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0034336" text="RNA chaperone" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1115-1132" id="f58cfab11be3906401550ffe0ba6e444d1056853.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0004386" text="helicase activity" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1317-1330" id="f58cfab11be3906401550ffe0ba6e444d1056853.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0032774" text="RNA synthesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1321-1330" id="f58cfab11be3906401550ffe0ba6e444d1056853.c1.e4" ontology_id="GO_0009058" text="synthesis" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1356-1373" id="f58cfab11be3906401550ffe0ba6e444d1056853.c1.e5" ontology_id="GO_0004386" text="helicase activity" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1393-1408" id="f58cfab11be3906401550ffe0ba6e444d1056853.c1.e6" ontology_id="GO_0039703" text="RNA replication" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1413-1419" id="f58cfab11be3906401550ffe0ba6e444d1056853.c1.e7" ontology_id="GO_0019012" text="virion" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1956-1971" id="f58cfab11be3906401550ffe0ba6e444d1056853.c1.e8" ontology_id="GO_0039703" text="RNA replication" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="f58cfab11be3906401550ffe0ba6e444d1056853.c2" text="Enteroviruses contain a large number of closely related human pathogens, including poliovirus, EV71, and coxsackie viruses, and cause~3 billion infections annually. Among the nonstructural proteins of enteroviruses or picornaviruses, protein 2C ATPase is the most conserved and complex but the least understood. On the basis of sequence analyses, this protein has been predicted as a putative superfamily 3 (SF3) helicase that supposedly plays a pivotal role in enteroviral RNA replication. However, attempts to determine the helicase activity associated with 2C ATPase have been unsuccessful. We found that eukaryotically expressed EV71 or CAV16 2C ATPase does possess an ATP-dependent RNA helicase activity that 3 0 !5 0 unwinds RNA helices like other SF3 helicases; surprisingly, it also functions as an RNA chaperone that remodels RNA structures in an ATP-independent manner. Moreover, we determined the domain requirements for these two RNA remodeling activities associated with 2C ATPase and provide both in vitro and cellular evidence of their potential roles during viral RNA replication. Additionally, our study provides the first evidence that RNA helicase and chaperoning activities can be integrated within one protein, thereby introducing an extended view of RNA remodeling proteins.">
    <entity charOffset="526-543" id="f58cfab11be3906401550ffe0ba6e444d1056853.c2.e0" ontology_id="GO_0004386" text="helicase activity" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="673-708" id="f58cfab11be3906401550ffe0ba6e444d1056853.c2.e1" ontology_id="GO_0003724" text="ATP-dependent RNA helicase activity" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="691-708" id="f58cfab11be3906401550ffe0ba6e444d1056853.c2.e2" ontology_id="GO_0004386" text="helicase activity" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="807-820" id="f58cfab11be3906401550ffe0ba6e444d1056853.c2.e3" ontology_id="GO_0034336" text="RNA chaperone" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
