<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899">
  <chunk id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c0" text="Identification of Neutralizing Monoclonal Antibodies Targeting Novel Conformational Epitopes of the Porcine Epidemic Diarrhoea Virus Spike Protein">
    <entity charOffset="117-126" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002014" text="Diarrhoea" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c1" text=", by the generation of neutralizing monoclonal antibodies (NmAbs). Two NmAbs, P4B-1, and E10E-1-10 that recognized the ectodomain of the full-length recombinant PEDV S protein and exhibited neutralizing ability against the PEDV-PT virus were selected. Recombinant truncated S proteins were used to identify the target sequences for the NmAbs and P4B-1 was shown to recognize the C-terminus of CO-26K equivalent epitope (COE) at amino acids (a.a.) 575-639 of the PEDV S. Interestingly, E10E-1-10 could recognize a novel neutralizing epitope at a.a. 435-485 within the S1 A domain of the PEDV S protein, whose importance and function are yet to be determined. Moreover, both NmAbs could not bind to linearized S proteins, indicating that only conformational epitopes are recognized. This data could improve our understanding of the antigenic structures of the PEDV S protein and facilitate future development of novel epitope-based vaccines."/>
  <chunk id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c2" text="Porcine epidemic diarrhoea virus (PEDV) causes porcine epidemic diarrhoea (PED), a highly contagious disease characterized by acute watery diarrhoea, vomiting, and dehydration, and with a high mortality rate particularly in suckling piglets 1,2 . The first outbreak of PED was recorded in the European and Asian swine industries in the early 1970s and then spread to many countries 3,4 . In 2010, novel and highly virulent PEDV strains were identified in China, which later spread to several countries 1,5,6 . These new variants of PEDV have caused high morbidity and mortality in neonatal piglets, resulting in serious economic loss to the swine industry 1,7 . Thus, there is an urgent need for in-depth and comprehensive studies on the antigenicity and immunogenicity of PEDVs in order to facilitate disease control and eradication.">
    <entity charOffset="17-26" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c2.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002014" text="diarrhoea" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="64-73" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c2.e1" ontology_id="HP_0002014" text="diarrhoea" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="126-131" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c2.e2" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="139-148" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c2.e3" ontology_id="HP_0002014" text="diarrhoea" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c3" text="PEDV is a single-stranded RNA virus, approximately 28 kb in size, which belongs to the genus Alphacoronavirus 8 . The PEDV genome comprises of seven open reading frames (ORFs) that encode for non-structural proteins responsible for viral genome replication and transcription, as well as four structural proteins, namely spike (S), envelope (E), membrane (M), and nucleocapsid (N) proteins 8,9 . Among the structural proteins, the S glycoprotein plays a critical role in host affinity, virus-cell recognition, membrane fusion and entry 1,10,11 . Moreover, it contains multiple neutralizing epitopes that make it a suitable target for vaccines designed to neutralize PEDVs 12-14 .">
    <entity charOffset="232-256" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c3.e0" ontology_id="GO_0019079" text="viral genome replication" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="331-339" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c3.e1" ontology_id="GO_0031975" text="envelope" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="345-353" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c3.e2" ontology_id="GO_0016020" text="membrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="363-375" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c3.e3" ontology_id="GO_0019013" text="nucleocapsid" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="509-517" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c3.e4" ontology_id="GO_0016020" text="membrane" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="509-524" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c3.e5" ontology_id="GO_0061025" text="membrane fusion" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c4" text="Several neutralizing epitopes have been identified on the S protein of the PEDVs such as the CO-26K equivalent epitope (COE epitope) 12 , the antigen epitope motif recognized by the monoclonal antibody (mAb) 2C10 at the C-terminal end of the S protein 13 , and a neutralizing epitope named S1D 14,15 . Recently, five core cell attachment domains of the PEDV S1 protein, S1 0 , S1 A , S1 B , S1 C , and S1 D , were proposed based on the three-dimensional structures cryo-EM of Alphacoronaviruses 16,17 . The proposed S1 0 domain has a sialic acid binding domain 10 . The S1 B domain is a common location for receptor binding in coronaviruses and can be a potential neutralizing target for the new PEDV variant capable of eliciting the production of cross-neutralizing antibodies against different PEDV strains 17 . Furthermore, several linear B-cell epitopes of PEDV overlapping with S1D have been shown to neutralize both the historic strain as well as the new variant PEDV strains 18 . Till date, no neutralizing epitope has been identified in the S1 A domain of the historic or the new PEDV variant strains.">
    <entity charOffset="193-201" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c4.e0" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="193-201" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c4.e1" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="534-553" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c4.e2" ontology_id="GO_0033691" text="sialic acid binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="546-553" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c4.e3" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="616-623" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c4.e4" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c5" text="To understand the antigenicity of PEDV, we generated a panel of neutralizing mAbs (NmAbs) by immunizing BALB/c mice with inactivated PEDV viral particles. The neutralizing epitopes of the PEDV-PT S protein, recognized by two of the NmAbs, were characterized using a series of C-terminal truncated recombinant PEDV-PT S proteins under native and denaturing conditions. This approach allows us to identify conformational epitopes of PEDV-PT strain and helps in understanding the antigenicity and pathogenesis of the G2b PEDV.">
    <entity charOffset="494-506" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c5.e0" ontology_id="GO_0009405" text="pathogenesis" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c6" text="Generation and purification of anti-PEDV spike mAbs. To map the epitopes of the new variants of PEDV, the hybridomas originating from PEDV-immunized mice were generated that secreted mAbs into the culture supernatant. These mAbs were collected from the supernatant and were used for immunocytochemical (ICC) staining with the full-length PEDV spike-expressing human embryonic kidney (HEK) 293 cells. Three mAbs, P4B-1, E10E-1-10, and R7H-2, which had a binding titre greater than 1:160 for PEDV spike-expressing HEK293 cells, were selected and purified. One mAb, UNK-1, which had no binding affinity for the PEDV spike-expressing HEK293 cells, was also selected to be a negative control for the subsequent assays. After purification of the mAbs along with the protein L, which targets the Fc region of the mice-originated antibodies, the pure mAbs of P4B-1, E10E-1-10, R7H-2, and UNK-1 were obtained at 400 μg/mL, 250 μg/mL, 900 μg/mL, and 400 μg/mL, respectively.">
    <entity charOffset="453-460" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c6.e0" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="583-590" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c6.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="838-842" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c6.e2" ontology_id="GO_0034023" text="pure" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c7" text="Scientific RepoRts | (2019) 9:2529 | https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-019-39844-5 www.nature.com/scientificreports www.nature.com/scientificreports/ for 1 h. Then, the mAb-virus mixtures were transferred to the Vero cell monolayer in 96-well tissue culture plates and washed twice with PI medium prior to inoculation. Following incubation at 37 °C for 1 h, inocula were discarded and 100 μL fresh PI medium was added to each well. Plates were incubated at 37 °C for 48 h and cytopathic effects (CPE) were monitored every 24 h. PEDV spike-specific mAb selection and epitope mapping by ICC staining. To select PEDV spike-specific mAbs and for epitope mapping of these NmAbs, ICC staining of mAbs to full-length PEDV S and truncated S protein-expressing HEK293 cells were performed. HEK293 cells expressing truncated PEDV spike proteins were seeded onto 96-well culture plates at 80% confluency and fixed using 80% acetone. After air-drying and washing thrice with 200 μL PBS/well, wells were incubated with 200 μL of each purified mAb at 20 μg/mL for 1 h at room temperature. After incubation, wells were washed 3 times with PBS and neutralizing antibodies were detected using a polyclonal anti-rabbit/mouse immunoglobulin EnVision-DAB + system (Dako, CA, USA). After secondary antibody incubation and PBS wash, the signal was detected using 3,3′-diaminobenzidine (DAB) (Dako) according to the manufacturer's instructions. Reactions were evaluated using an inverted light/fluorescence microscope.">
    <entity charOffset="1204-1218" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c7.e0" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="immunoglobulin" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1274-1282" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c7.e1" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="1274-1282" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c7.e2" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c8" text="Epitope mapping by indirect enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA). The procedure of the indirect ELISA has been performed as described previously 33 with some modifications. Purified S 1-435 , S 1-485 , S 1-501 , S 1-509 , S 1-575 , S 1-639 and the full-length spike proteins of PEDV-PT were coated onto the Nunc maxi-soap platee (Thermo Fisher Scientific) at 0.034 mM dilution in coating buffer (KPL, SeraCare, MA, USA) at 4 °C for 16 h and were blocked by 300 μL blocking buffer (KPL, SeraCare) at RT for 1 h followed by washing six times with washing buffer (KPL, SeraCare). The purified NmAbs, P4B-1, E10E-1-10, and the non-PEDV recognizing mAb, UNK-1, were serially diluted from 2.5 μg/mL to 78.1 ng/mL and subsequently applied to the plates as primary antibodies. The anti-V5 tag antibody (Invitrogen) was serially diluted from 40,000X to 640,000X and added to the plates as the positive control. Following a 1-h incubation period and washing six times, the 1,000-fold diluted HRP-conjugated goat anti-mouse IgG antibodies (KPL, SeraCare) added to the plate and incubated for 1 h. After Scientific RepoRts | (2019) 9:2529 | https://doi.">
    <entity charOffset="790-798" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c8.e0" ontology_id="GO_0003823" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="790-798" id="f93f20813c626fb775bbb73b1c14c906cd61e899.c8.e1" ontology_id="GO_0042571" text="antibody" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
