<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="fc151568de57c0456578757131c3b49b86286b3c">
  <chunk id="fc151568de57c0456578757131c3b49b86286b3c.c0" text="Inhibition of RNA Helicases of ssRNA + Virus Belonging to Flaviviridae, Coronaviridae and Picornaviridae Families"/>
  <chunk id="fc151568de57c0456578757131c3b49b86286b3c.c1" text="Many viral pathogens encode the motor proteins named RNA helicases which display various functions in genome replication. General strategies to design specific and selective drugs targeting helicase for the treatment of viral infections could act via one or more of the following mechanisms: inhibition of the NTPase activity, by interferences with ATP binding and therefore by limiting the energy required for the unwinding and translocation, or by allosteric mechanism and therefore by stabilizing the conformation of the enzyme in low helicase activity state; inhibition of nucleic acids binding to the helicase; inhibition of coupling of ATP hydrolysis to unwinding; inhibition of unwinding by sterically blocking helicase translocation. Recently, by in vitro screening studies, it has been reported that several benzotriazole, imidazole, imidazodiazepine, phenothiazine, quinoline, anthracycline, triphenylmethane, tropolone, pyrrole, acridone, small peptide, and Bananin derivatives are endowed with helicase inhibition of pathogen viruses belonging to Flaviviridae, Coronaviridae, and Picornaviridae families.">
    <entity charOffset="349-360" id="fc151568de57c0456578757131c3b49b86286b3c.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0005524" text="ATP binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="353-360" id="fc151568de57c0456578757131c3b49b86286b3c.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="538-555" id="fc151568de57c0456578757131c3b49b86286b3c.c1.e2" ontology_id="GO_0004386" text="helicase activity" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="591-598" id="fc151568de57c0456578757131c3b49b86286b3c.c1.e3" ontology_id="GO_0005488" text="binding" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
