<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="fc5cc0fedf50af659b515f25de57a6c7d841d342">
  <chunk id="fc5cc0fedf50af659b515f25de57a6c7d841d342.c0" text="Yu Ping Feng San, an Ancient Chinese Herbal Decoction, Regulates the Expression of Inducible Nitric Oxide Synthase and Cyclooxygenase-2 and the Activity of Intestinal Alkaline Phosphatase in Cultures">
    <entity charOffset="176-187" id="fc5cc0fedf50af659b515f25de57a6c7d841d342.c0.e0" ontology_id="GO_0016791" text="Phosphatase" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="fc5cc0fedf50af659b515f25de57a6c7d841d342.c1" text="Yu Ping Feng San (YPFS), a Chinese herbal decoction comprising Astragali Radix (AR; Huangqi), Atractylodis Macrocephalae Rhizoma (AMR; Baizhu), and Saposhnikoviae Radix (SR; Fangfeng), has been used clinically to treat inflammatory bowel diseases (IBD). Previously, we demonstrated a dual role of YPFS in regulating cytokine release in cultured macrophages. In this study, we elucidated the anti-inflammatory effect of YPFS that is mediated through modulating the expression of three key enzymes involved in IBD: inducible nitric oxide synthase (iNOS), cyclooxygenase-2 (COX-2), and intestinal alkaline phosphatase (IALP). In a lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced chronic-inflammation model of cultured murine macrophages, YPFS treatment suppressed the activation of iNOS and COX-2 expression in a dose-dependent manner. Conversely, application of YPFS in cultured small intestinal enterocytes markedly induced the expression of IALP in a time-dependent manner, which might strengthen the intestinal detoxification system. A duality of YPFS in modulating the expression of iNOS and COX-2 was determined here. The expression of iNOS and COX-2 in macrophages was induced by YPFS, and this activation was partially blocked by the NF-kB-specific inhibitor BAY 11-7082, indicating a role of NF-kB signaling. These YPFS-induced changes in gene regulation strongly suggest that the anti-inflammatory effects of YPFS are mediated through the regulation of inflammatory enzymes.">
    <entity charOffset="603-614" id="fc5cc0fedf50af659b515f25de57a6c7d841d342.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0016791" text="phosphatase" type="gene_function"/>
    <entity charOffset="997-1011" id="fc5cc0fedf50af659b515f25de57a6c7d841d342.c1.e1" ontology_id="GO_0098754" text="detoxification" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
