<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="fd19cfef82dc2fd1ee48be9b10563d681610c000">
  <chunk id="fd19cfef82dc2fd1ee48be9b10563d681610c000.c0" text="Lys-315 at the Interfaces of Diagonal Subunits of δ-Crystallin Plays a Critical Role in the Reversibility of Folding and Subunit Assembly"/>
  <chunk id="fd19cfef82dc2fd1ee48be9b10563d681610c000.c1" text="δ-Crystallin is the major structural protein in avian eye lenses and is homologous to the urea cycle enzyme argininosuccinate lyase. This protein is structurally assembled as double dimers. Lys-315 is the only residue which is arranged symmetrically at the diagonal subunit interfaces to interact with each other. This study found that wild-type protein had both dimers and monomers present in 2-4 M urea whilst only monomers of the K315A mutant were observed under the same conditions, as judged by sedimentation velocity analysis. The assembly of monomeric K315A mutant was reversible in contrast to wild-type protein.">
    <entity charOffset="90-100" id="fd19cfef82dc2fd1ee48be9b10563d681610c000.c1.e0" ontology_id="GO_0000050" text="urea cycle" type="gene_function"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="fd19cfef82dc2fd1ee48be9b10563d681610c000.c2" text="Molecular dynamics simulations showed that the dissociation of primary dimers is prior to the diagonal dimers in wild-type protein. These results suggest the critical role of Lys-315 in stabilization of the diagonal dimer structure. Guanidinium hydrochloride (GdmCl) denatured wild-type or K315A mutant protein did not fold into functional protein. However, the urea dissociated monomers of K315A mutant protein in GdmCl were reversible folding through a multiple steps mechanism as measured by tryptophan and ANS fluorescence. Two partly unfolded intermediates were detected in the pathway. Refolding of the intermediates resulted in a conformation with greater amounts of hydrophobic regions exposed which was prone to the formation of protein aggregates. The formation of aggregates was not prevented by the addition of α-crystallin. These results highlight that the conformational status of the monomers is critical for determining whether reversible oligomerization or aggregate formation occurs."/>
  <chunk id="fd19cfef82dc2fd1ee48be9b10563d681610c000.c3" text="responsible for the conversion of argininosuccinate into arginine and fumarate in the urea cycle. δ-Crystallin and ASL share about 70% amino acid sequence identity and function as homotetramers, with four identical multi-subunit active sites [1-6]."/>
  <chunk id="fd19cfef82dc2fd1ee48be9b10563d681610c000.c4" text="δ-Crystallin and ASL have similar X-ray crystal structures. Each monomer consists of three domains. The helices in domain 2 of each monomer associate to form a central helix bundle, comprising the core structure of the protein ( Fig 1A) [4,5,7-10]. The active sites of the enzyme are located in a cleft between three different monomers [4] . The quaternary structure of δ-crystallin consists of a double dimer. The contact surface between the two dimers is smaller than the interface within the primary dimer of the structure [11] . Hydrogen bonding, salt bridges and hydrophobic interactions are the major forces which stabilize the quaternary structure of the protein.">
    <entity charOffset="160-167" id="fd19cfef82dc2fd1ee48be9b10563d681610c000.c4.e0" ontology_id="HP_0030645" text="central" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="fd19cfef82dc2fd1ee48be9b10563d681610c000.c5" text="In the presence of guanidinium chloride (GdmCl), tetrameric δ-crystallin is unfolded via a multistep pathway involving subunit dissociation into a monomeric molten globule intermediate, followed by denaturation [12, 13] . The dimeric form is transiently detected during this unfolding/refolding process. These dimers are unstable and they are prone to self-associate into protein aggregates, and this process competes with the formation of native tetramers [8] . Hence, the assembly of two dimers acts as a kinetic barrier in the refolding pathway [14] . The proper assembly of double dimers is thus important for producing a stable δ-crystallin quaternary structure.">
    <entity charOffset="626-632" id="fd19cfef82dc2fd1ee48be9b10563d681610c000.c5.e0" ontology_id="HP_0031915" text="stable" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="fd19cfef82dc2fd1ee48be9b10563d681610c000.c6" text="The N-terminus of δ-crystallin has been identified as being critical for the proper assembly of the double dimers [8]. In the quaternary structure, the first 25 N-terminal amino acid residues protrude into the neighboring monomer and interact with a hydrophobic cavity. When this sequence of amino acids was deleted the protein became unstable and was prone to form protein aggregates. The salt bridge formed by residues of R302 and E330, located in the helix bundle at the dimer-dimer interface, is also important interaction for stabilization of the quaternary structure of δ-crystallin. When this interaction was disrupted by site-directed mutagenesis, the exchange rate of subunits was dramatically accelerated [15] . The interactions of E327 with both K299 and R302 and the interaction of E267 with Y158 at the dimer interface were found to stabilize the quaternary structure of δ-crystallin in a cooperative manner. Mutations of the residues involved in both these interactions caused the majority of dimers to dissociate, whilst only partial dissociation was observed when these interactions were individually disrupted, as judged by sedimentation velocity experiments [11] ."/>
  <chunk id="fd19cfef82dc2fd1ee48be9b10563d681610c000.c7" text="Inspection of the structure of δ-crystallin showed that the primary interactions between two symmetrically associated monomers in diagonal positions were provided by residues located at the top and bottom sides of the helical bundles ( Fig 1B) . K315 is one of the residues symmetrical located at this interface, interacting with the same residue in other monomers by hydrogen bonds (Fig 1C and 1D ). Substitution of this residue with leucine resulted in part dissociation of the quaternary structure. In contrast, the K315A mutant protein was relatively stable. This protein was unfolded into an intermediate with a stable conformation at 3 M urea [11] . This phenomenon was not observed for the K315L mutant protein, which was unfolded under the same conditions. The results lead to the hypothesis that the bulky and charged side-chain of K315 might affect the stability of the intermediate during the process of protein unfolding. When wild-type δ-crystallin was unfolded in GdmCl, the first transition for subunit dissociation resulted in a monomeric intermediate with a molten globule conformation [12, 13] . During the refolding of 5 M GdmCl denatured δ-crystallin a marked hysteresis was observed, suggesting that the quaternary structure of that inappropriate assembled species might be related to the conformation of the refolded monomers [14, 16] . The presence of stable intermediate during unfolding of K315A mutant protein in the presence of urea suggests that the interactions provided by this residue at the interfaces might provide an energy barrier for subunit dissociation. Refolding of K315A Mutant δ-Crystallin PLOS ONE | DOI:10.1371/journal.pone.0145957 January 5, 2016 2 / 21 dichroism; AEW, average emission wavelength; λ max , maximum emission wavelength; C m , half concentration of denaturant required in protein unfolding; MD, molecular dynamics. Refolding of K315A Mutant δ-Crystallin PLOS ONE |">
    <entity charOffset="555-561" id="fd19cfef82dc2fd1ee48be9b10563d681610c000.c7.e0" ontology_id="HP_0031915" text="stable" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="617-623" id="fd19cfef82dc2fd1ee48be9b10563d681610c000.c7.e1" ontology_id="HP_0031915" text="stable" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1375-1381" id="fd19cfef82dc2fd1ee48be9b10563d681610c000.c7.e2" ontology_id="HP_0031915" text="stable" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
