<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="fd28e6d03eef27b0454f13ca539dc1498242a4c2">
  <chunk id="fd28e6d03eef27b0454f13ca539dc1498242a4c2.c0" text=""/>
  <chunk id="fd28e6d03eef27b0454f13ca539dc1498242a4c2.c1" text="In December 2019, a new type viral pneumonia cases occurred in Wuhan, Hubei Province; and then named &quot;2019 novel coronavirus (2019-nCoV)&quot; by the World Health Organization (WHO) on 12 January 2020. For it is a never been experienced respiratory disease before and with infection ability widely and quickly, it attracted the world's attention but without treatment and control manual. For the request from frontline clinicians and public health professionals of 2019-nCoV infected pneumonia management, an evidence-based guideline urgently needs to be developed. Therefore, we drafted this guideline according to the rapid advice guidelines methodology and general rules of WHO guideline development; we also added the first-hand management data of Zhongnan Hospital of Wuhan University. This guideline includes the guideline methodology, epidemiological characteristics, disease screening and population prevention, diagnosis, treatment and control (including traditional Chinese Medicine), nosocomial infection prevention and control, and disease nursing of the 2019-nCoV. Moreover, we also provide a whole process of a successful treatment case of the severe 2019-nCoV infected pneumonia and experience and lessons of hospital rescue for 2019-nCoV infections. This rapid advice guideline is suitable for the first frontline doctors and nurses, managers of hospitals and healthcare sections, community residents, public health persons, relevant researchers, and all person who are interested in the 2019-nCoV.">
    <entity charOffset="35-44" id="fd28e6d03eef27b0454f13ca539dc1498242a4c2.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="479-488" id="fd28e6d03eef27b0454f13ca539dc1498242a4c2.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1153-1159" id="fd28e6d03eef27b0454f13ca539dc1498242a4c2.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0012828" text="severe" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1179-1188" id="fd28e6d03eef27b0454f13ca539dc1498242a4c2.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0002090" text="pneumonia" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
