<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="ff81f65bce47ed0a1a6e586dc196c6543e97d861">
  <chunk id="ff81f65bce47ed0a1a6e586dc196c6543e97d861.c0" text="molecules Asymmetric Primaquine and Halogenaniline Fumardiamides as Novel Biologically Active Michael Acceptors"/>
  <chunk id="ff81f65bce47ed0a1a6e586dc196c6543e97d861.c1" text="Novel primaquine (PQ) and halogenaniline asymmetric fumardiamides 4a-f, potential Michael acceptors, and their reduced analogues succindiamides 5a-f were prepared by simple three-step reactions: coupling reaction between PQ and mono-ethyl fumarate (1a) or mono-methyl succinate (1b), hydrolysis of PQ-dicarboxylic acid mono-ester conjugates 2a,b to corresponding acids 3a,b, and a coupling reaction with halogenanilines. 1-[bis(Dimethylamino)methylene]-1H-1,2,3-triazolo[4,5-b]pyridinium 3-oxide hexafluorophosphate (HATU) was used as a coupling reagent along with Hünig s base. Compounds 4 and 5 were evaluated against a panel of bacteria, several Mycobacterium strains, fungi, a set of viruses, and nine different human tumor cell lines. p-Chlorofumardiamide 4d showed significant activity against Staphylococcus aureus, Streptococcus pneumoniae and Acinetobacter baumannii, but also against Candida albicans (minimum inhibitory concentration (MIC) 6.1-12.5 µg/mL). Together with p-fluoro and p-CF 3 fumardiamides 4b,f, compound 4d showed activity against Mycobacterium marinum and 4b,f against M. tuberculosis. In biofilm eradication assay, most of the bacteria, particularly S. aureus, showed susceptibility to fumardiamides. m-CF 3 and m-chloroaniline fumardiamides 4e and 4c showed significant antiviral activity against reovirus-1, sindbis virus and Punta Toro virus (EC 50 = 3.1-5.5 µM), while 4e was active against coxsackie virus B4 (EC 50 = 3.1 µM). m-Fluoro derivative 4a exerted significant cytostatic activity (IC 50 = 5.7-31.2 µM). Acute lymphoblastic leukemia cells were highly susceptible towards m-substituted derivatives 4a,c,e (IC 50 = 6.7-8.9 µM). Biological evaluations revealed that fumardiamides 4 were more active than succindiamides 5 indicating importance of Michael conjugated system.">
    <entity charOffset="722-727" id="ff81f65bce47ed0a1a6e586dc196c6543e97d861.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002664" text="tumor" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1547-1552" id="ff81f65bce47ed0a1a6e586dc196c6543e97d861.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0011009" text="Acute" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1547-1575" id="ff81f65bce47ed0a1a6e586dc196c6543e97d861.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0006721" text="Acute lymphoblastic leukemia" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1567-1575" id="ff81f65bce47ed0a1a6e586dc196c6543e97d861.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0001909" text="leukemia" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
