<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="0257e6797e12beb91a4a4fcd7130f90d84260718">
  <chunk id="0257e6797e12beb91a4a4fcd7130f90d84260718.c0" text="Integrated sequence and immunology filovirus database at Los Alamos">
    <entity charOffset="57-60" id="0257e6797e12beb91a4a4fcd7130f90d84260718.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_35371" text="Los" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="0257e6797e12beb91a4a4fcd7130f90d84260718.c1" text="authors contributed equally to this work. Citation details: Yusim,K., Yoon,H., Foley,B. et al. Integrated sequence and immunology filovirus database at Los Alamos.">
    <entity charOffset="152-155" id="0257e6797e12beb91a4a4fcd7130f90d84260718.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_35371" text="Los" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="0257e6797e12beb91a4a4fcd7130f90d84260718.c2" text="The Ebola outbreak of 2013-15 infected more than 28 000 people and claimed more lives than all previous filovirus outbreaks combined. Governmental agencies, clinical teams, and the world scientific community pulled together in a multifaceted response ranging from prevention and disease control, to evaluating vaccines and therapeutics in human trials. As this epidemic is finally coming to a close, refocusing on long-term prevention strategies becomes paramount. Given the very real threat of future filovirus outbreaks, and the inherent uncertainty of the next outbreak virus and geographic location, it is prudent to consider the extent and implications of known natural diversity in advancing vaccines and therapeutic approaches. To facilitate such consideration, we have updated and enhanced the content of the filovirus portion of Los Alamos Hemorrhagic Fever Viruses Database. We have integrated and performed baseline analysis of all family Filoviridae sequences deposited into GenBank, with associated immune response data, and metadata, and we have added new computational tools with web-interfaces to assist users with analysis. Here, we (i) describe the main features of updated database, (ii) provide integrated views and some basic analyses summarizing evolutionary patterns as they relate to geo-temporal data captured in the database and (iii) highlight the most conserved regions in the proteome that may be useful for a T cell vaccine strategy.">
    <entity charOffset="838-841" id="0257e6797e12beb91a4a4fcd7130f90d84260718.c2.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_35371" text="Los" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="0257e6797e12beb91a4a4fcd7130f90d84260718.c3" text="Database URL: www.hfv.lanl.gov"/>
</document>
