<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="02a009e42054081b441d0f4b203679c4b0cae38d">
  <chunk id="02a009e42054081b441d0f4b203679c4b0cae38d.c0" text="Three asymptomatic animal infection models of hemorrhagic fever with renal syndrome caused by hantaviruses"/>
  <chunk id="02a009e42054081b441d0f4b203679c4b0cae38d.c1" text="Hantaan virus (HTNV) and Puumala virus (PUUV) are rodent-borne hantaviruses that are the primary causes of hemorrhagic fever with renal syndrome (HFRS) in Europe and Asia. The development of well characterized animal models of HTNV and PUUV infection is critical for the evaluation and the potential licensure of HFRS vaccines and therapeutics. In this study we present three animal models of HTNV infection (hamster, ferret and marmoset), and two animal models of PUUV infection (hamster, ferret). Infection of hamsters with a~3 times the infectious dose 99% (ID 99 ) of HTNV by the intramuscular and~1 ID 99 of HTNV by the intranasal route leads to a persistent asymptomatic infection, characterized by sporadic viremia and high levels of viral genome in the lung, brain and kidney. In contrast, infection of hamsters with~2 ID 99 of PUUV by the intramuscular or~1 ID 99 of PUUV by the intranasal route leads to seroconversion with no detectable viremia, and a transient detection of viral genome. Infection of ferrets with a high dose of either HTNV or PUUV by the intramuscular route leads to seroconversion and gradual weight loss, though kidney function remained unimpaired and serum viremia and viral dissemination to organs was not detected. In marmosets a 1,000 PFU HTNV intramuscular challenge led to robust seroconversion and neutralizing antibody production. Similarly to the ferret model of HTNV infection, no renal impairment, serum viremia or viral dissemination to organs was detected in marmosets. This is the first report of hantavirus infection in ferrets and marmosets.">
    <entity charOffset="1271-1274" id="02a009e42054081b441d0f4b203679c4b0cae38d.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_55308" text="PFU" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
