<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="0c842a151c9e010a7c70151d029c91a118bde887">
  <chunk id="0c842a151c9e010a7c70151d029c91a118bde887.c0" text="Cellular Innate Immunity against PRRSV and Swine Influenza Viruses"/>
  <chunk id="0c842a151c9e010a7c70151d029c91a118bde887.c1" text="Porcine respiratory disease complex (PRDC) is a polymicrobial syndrome that results from a combination of infectious agents, such as environmental stressors, population size, management strategies, age, and genetics. PRDC results in reduced performance as well as increased mortality rates and production costs in the pig industry worldwide. This review focuses on the interactions of two enveloped RNA viruses-porcine reproductive and respiratory syndrome virus (PRRSV) and swine influenza virus (SwIV)-as major etiological agents that contribute to PRDC within the porcine cellular innate immunity during infection. The innate immune system of the porcine lung includes alveolar and parenchymal/interstitial macrophages, neutrophils (PMN), conventional dendritic cells (DC) and plasmacytoid DC, natural killer cells, and γδ T cells, thus the in vitro and in vivo interactions between those cells and PRRSV and SwIV are reviewed. Likewise, the few studies regarding PRRSV-SwIV co-infection are illustrated together with the different modulation mechanisms that are induced by the two viruses. Alterations in responses by natural killer (NK), PMN, or γδ T cells have not received much attention within the scientific community as their counterpart antigen-presenting cells and there are numerous gaps in the knowledge regarding the role of those cells in both infections. This review will help in paving the way for future directions in PRRSV and SwIV research and enhancing the understanding of the innate mechanisms that are involved during infection with these viruses.">
    <entity charOffset="399-402" id="0c842a151c9e010a7c70151d029c91a118bde887.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1332-1336" id="0c842a151c9e010a7c70151d029c91a118bde887.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="0c842a151c9e010a7c70151d029c91a118bde887.c1.e0" e2="0c842a151c9e010a7c70151d029c91a118bde887.c1.e1" id="0c842a151c9e010a7c70151d029c91a118bde887.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
