<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="1516a62bffb7478ad5cbec0bde15290baf5384a3">
  <chunk id="1516a62bffb7478ad5cbec0bde15290baf5384a3.c0" text="Apoptotic Response through a High Mobility Box 1 Protein-Dependent Mechanism in LPS/GalN-Induced Mouse Liver Failure and Glycyrrhizin-Mediated Inhibition"/>
  <chunk id="1516a62bffb7478ad5cbec0bde15290baf5384a3.c1" text="HMGB1 is a nuclear component involved in nucleosome stabilization and transcription regulation, but extracellularly it is able to serve as a potential late mediator of lethality. In the present study, we explored inflammation-promoting activity of HMGB1 and blockade of extracellular release of HMGB1 by glycyrrhizin (GL) in LPS/GalN-triggered mouse liver injury. At 1 to 10 h after LPS/GalN-treatment, mice were anesthetized to collect blood from heart puncture, and serum transaminase and HMGB1 were evaluated. Administration of LPS/GalN precipitated tissue injury associated with time-dependent alteration in HMGB1 serum levels. At 8 h nuclear immunoreactive products were remarkably reduced and extracellular HMGB1 expression was found exclusively in the pericentral foci. The treatment with GL significantly down-regulated the serum levels of ALT, AST, and HMGB1 in addition to the strong inhibition of tissue injury and extracellular immunoreactivity to HMGB1 and to acetylated-lysine. Furthermore, GL brought about a significant decrease in the number of apoptotic hepatocytes labeled with TUNEL-method. On the basis of these results, three apoptosis-associated genes were identified with microarray analysis and real-time PCR. The ChIP-assay revealed the binding of HMGB1 protein to Gsto1 promoter sequence in LPS/GalN-treated mice and the remarkable decrease in combined HMGB1 protein by GL. The current findings claim that a single injection of LPS/GalN might stimulate apoptosis of hepatocytes through the binding of HMGB1 protein to Gsto1 promoter region and that GL-treatment might prevent the apoptosis and inflammatory infiltrates caused with LPS/ GalN-injection by disturbing the binding of HMGB1 protein to Gsto1 promoter sequence.">
    <entity charOffset="304-316" id="1516a62bffb7478ad5cbec0bde15290baf5384a3.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_15939" text="glycyrrhizin" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1280-1287" id="1516a62bffb7478ad5cbec0bde15290baf5384a3.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1386-1393" id="1516a62bffb7478ad5cbec0bde15290baf5384a3.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1534-1541" id="1516a62bffb7478ad5cbec0bde15290baf5384a3.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1713-1720" id="1516a62bffb7478ad5cbec0bde15290baf5384a3.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="1516a62bffb7478ad5cbec0bde15290baf5384a3.c1.e0" e2="1516a62bffb7478ad5cbec0bde15290baf5384a3.c1.e1" id="1516a62bffb7478ad5cbec0bde15290baf5384a3.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="1516a62bffb7478ad5cbec0bde15290baf5384a3.c1.e0" e2="1516a62bffb7478ad5cbec0bde15290baf5384a3.c1.e2" id="1516a62bffb7478ad5cbec0bde15290baf5384a3.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="1516a62bffb7478ad5cbec0bde15290baf5384a3.c1.e0" e2="1516a62bffb7478ad5cbec0bde15290baf5384a3.c1.e3" id="1516a62bffb7478ad5cbec0bde15290baf5384a3.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="1516a62bffb7478ad5cbec0bde15290baf5384a3.c1.e0" e2="1516a62bffb7478ad5cbec0bde15290baf5384a3.c1.e4" id="1516a62bffb7478ad5cbec0bde15290baf5384a3.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
