<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="15d784a335abf0ea0266e9a2406b8d87f25c8f2f">
  <chunk id="15d784a335abf0ea0266e9a2406b8d87f25c8f2f.c0" text="T Cell-Derived IL-10 Impairs Host Resistance to Mycobacterium tuberculosis Infection"/>
  <chunk id="15d784a335abf0ea0266e9a2406b8d87f25c8f2f.c1" text="Tuberculosis (TB), caused by Mycobacterium tuberculosis infection, is a leading cause of mortality and morbidity, causing ∼1.5 million deaths annually. CD4 + T cells and several cytokines, such as the Th1 cytokine IFN-g, are critical in the control of this infection. Conversely, the immunosuppressive cytokine IL-10 has been shown to dampen Th1 cell responses to M. tuberculosis infection impairing bacterial clearance. However, the critical cellular source of IL-10 during M. tuberculosis infection is still unknown. Using IL-10 reporter mice, we show in this article that during the first 14 d of M. tuberculosis infection, the predominant cells expressing IL-10 in the lung were Ly6C + monocytes. However, after day 21 postinfection, IL-10-expressing T cells were also highly represented. Notably, mice deficient in T cell-derived IL-10, but not mice deficient in monocyte-derived IL-10, showed a significant reduction in lung bacterial loads during chronic M. tuberculosis infection compared with fully IL-10-competent mice, indicating a major role for T cell-derived IL-10 in TB susceptibility. IL-10-expressing cells were detected among both CD4 + and CD8 + T cells, expressed high levels of CD44 and Tbet, and were able to coproduce IFN-g and IL-10 upon ex vivo stimulation. Furthermore, during M. tuberculosis infection, Il10 expression in CD4 + T cells was partially regulated by both IL-27 and type I IFN signaling. Together, our data reveal that, despite the multiple immune sources of IL-10 during M. tuberculosis infection, activated effector T cells are the major source accounting for IL-10-induced TB susceptibility.">
    <entity charOffset="1049-1053" id="15d784a335abf0ea0266e9a2406b8d87f25c8f2f.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1548-1556" id="15d784a335abf0ea0266e9a2406b8d87f25c8f2f.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_35224" text="effector" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="15d784a335abf0ea0266e9a2406b8d87f25c8f2f.c1.e0" e2="15d784a335abf0ea0266e9a2406b8d87f25c8f2f.c1.e1" id="15d784a335abf0ea0266e9a2406b8d87f25c8f2f.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
