<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="17787dbfbb012b537726971936c74cab0aa701b1">
  <chunk id="17787dbfbb012b537726971936c74cab0aa701b1.c0" text="Surveillance and response systems for elimination of tropical diseases: summary of a thematic series in Infectious Diseases of Poverty"/>
  <chunk id="17787dbfbb012b537726971936c74cab0aa701b1.c1" text="The peer-reviewed journal Infectious Diseases of Poverty provides a new platform to engage with, and disseminate in an open-access format, science outside traditional disciplinary boundaries. The current piece reviews a thematic series on surveillance-response systems for elimination of tropical diseases. Overall, 22 contributions covering a broad array of diseases are featuredi.e. clonorchiasis, dengue, hepatitis, human immunodeficiency virus/acquired immune deficiency syndrome (HIV/AIDS), H7N9 avian influenza, lymphatic filariasis, malaria, Middle East respiratory syndrome (MERS), rabies, schistosomiasis and tuberculosis (TB). There are five scoping reviews, a commentary, a letter to the editor, an opinion piece and an editorial pertaining to the theme &quot;Elimination of tropical disease through surveillance and response&quot;. The remaining 13 articles are original contributions mainly covering (i) drug resistance; (ii) innovation and validation in the field of mathematical modelling; (iii) elimination of infectious diseases; and (iv) social media reports on disease outbreak notifications released by national health authorities. Analysis of the authors' affiliations reveals that scientists from the People's Republic of China (P.R. China) are prominently represented. Possible explanations include the fact that the 2012 and 2014 international conferences pertaining to surveillance-response mechanisms were both hosted by the National Institute of Parasitic Diseases (NIPD) in Shanghai, coupled with P.R. China's growing importance with regard to the control of infectious diseases. Within 4 to 22 months of publication, three of the 22 contributions were viewed more than 10 000 times each. With sustained efforts focusing on relevant and strategic information towards control and elimination of infectious diseases, Infectious Diseases of Poverty has become a leading journal in the field of surveillance and response systems in infectious diseases and beyond.">
    <entity charOffset="685-691" id="17787dbfbb012b537726971936c74cab0aa701b1.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_6446" text="letter" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="907-911" id="17787dbfbb012b537726971936c74cab0aa701b1.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_23888" text="drug" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="17787dbfbb012b537726971936c74cab0aa701b1.c1.e0" e2="17787dbfbb012b537726971936c74cab0aa701b1.c1.e1" id="17787dbfbb012b537726971936c74cab0aa701b1.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
