<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="17bbe32558609da8c1aceab2b751383aa9c3c18b">
  <chunk id="17bbe32558609da8c1aceab2b751383aa9c3c18b.c0" text="Functional Characterization of Plasmodium falciparum Surface-Related Antigen as a Potential Blood-Stage Vaccine Target The Journal of Infectious Diseases ® 2018;218:778-90">
    <entity charOffset="69-76" id="17bbe32558609da8c1aceab2b751383aa9c3c18b.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_59132" text="Antigen" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="17bbe32558609da8c1aceab2b751383aa9c3c18b.c1" text="Plasmodium falciparum erythrocyte invasion is a multistep process that involves a spectrum of interactions that are not well characterized. We have characterized a 113-kDa immunogenic protein, PF3D7_1431400 (PF14_0293), that possesses coiled-coil structures. The protein is localized on the surfaces of both merozoites and gametocytes, hence the name Plasmodium falciparum surface-related antigen (PfSRA). The processed 32-kDa fragment of PfSRA binds normal human erythrocytes with different sensitivities to enzyme treatments. Temporal imaging from initial attachment to internalization of viable merozoites revealed that a fragment of PfSRA, along with PfMSP1 19, is internalized after invasion. Moreover, parasite growth inhibition assays showed that PfSRA P1 antibodies potently inhibited erythrocyte invasion of both sialic acid-dependent and -independent parasite strains. Also, immunoepidemiological studies show that malaria-infected populations have naturally acquired antibodies against PfSRA. Overall, the results demonstrate that PfSRA has the structural and functional characteristics of a very promising target for vaccine development.">
    <entity charOffset="184-191" id="17bbe32558609da8c1aceab2b751383aa9c3c18b.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="263-270" id="17bbe32558609da8c1aceab2b751383aa9c3c18b.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="389-396" id="17bbe32558609da8c1aceab2b751383aa9c3c18b.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_59132" text="antigen" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="17bbe32558609da8c1aceab2b751383aa9c3c18b.c1.e0" e2="17bbe32558609da8c1aceab2b751383aa9c3c18b.c1.e2" id="17bbe32558609da8c1aceab2b751383aa9c3c18b.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="17bbe32558609da8c1aceab2b751383aa9c3c18b.c1.e1" e2="17bbe32558609da8c1aceab2b751383aa9c3c18b.c1.e2" id="17bbe32558609da8c1aceab2b751383aa9c3c18b.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
