<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="190bc9d8aadbfb5c848ccdb9f4fa98610780ba56">
  <chunk id="190bc9d8aadbfb5c848ccdb9f4fa98610780ba56.c0" text="Saikosaponin-d Enhances the Anticancer Potency of TNF-via Overcoming Its Undesirable Response of Activating NF-Kappa B Signalling in Cancer Cells"/>
  <chunk id="190bc9d8aadbfb5c848ccdb9f4fa98610780ba56.c1" text="Tumor necrosis factor-alpha (TNF-) was reported as anticancer therapy due to its cytotoxic effect against an array of tumor cells. However, its undesirable responses of TNF-on activating NF-B signaling and pro-metastatic property limit its clinical application in treating cancers. Therefore, sensitizing agents capable of overcoming this undesirable effect must be valuable for facilitating the usage of TNF--mediated apoptosis therapy for cancer patients. Previously, saikosaponin-d (Ssd), a triterpene saponin derived from the medicinal plant, Bupleurum falcatum L. (Umbelliferae), showed to exhibit a variety of pharmacological activities such as antiinflammation, antibacteria, antivirus and anticancer. Recently, we found that Ssd could inhibit the activated T lymphocytes via suppression of NF-B, NF-AT and AP-1 signaling. Here, we showed that Ssd significantly potentiated TNF--mediated cell death in HeLa and HepG2 cancer cells via suppression of TNF--induced NF-B activation and its target genes expression involving cancer cell proliferation, invasion, angiogenesis and survival. Also, Ssd revealed a significant potency of abolishing TNF--induced cancer cell invasion and angiogenesis in HUVECs while inducing apoptosis via enhancing the loss of mitochondrial membrane potential in HeLa cells. Collectively, these findings indicate that Ssd has a significant potential to be developed as a combined adjuvant remedy with TNF-for cancer patients.">
    <entity charOffset="494-504" id="190bc9d8aadbfb5c848ccdb9f4fa98610780ba56.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_35191" text="triterpene" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="505-512" id="190bc9d8aadbfb5c848ccdb9f4fa98610780ba56.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_26605" text="saponin" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1411-1419" id="190bc9d8aadbfb5c848ccdb9f4fa98610780ba56.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_60809" text="adjuvant" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="190bc9d8aadbfb5c848ccdb9f4fa98610780ba56.c1.e0" e2="190bc9d8aadbfb5c848ccdb9f4fa98610780ba56.c1.e1" id="190bc9d8aadbfb5c848ccdb9f4fa98610780ba56.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="190bc9d8aadbfb5c848ccdb9f4fa98610780ba56.c1.e0" e2="190bc9d8aadbfb5c848ccdb9f4fa98610780ba56.c1.e2" id="190bc9d8aadbfb5c848ccdb9f4fa98610780ba56.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="190bc9d8aadbfb5c848ccdb9f4fa98610780ba56.c1.e1" e2="190bc9d8aadbfb5c848ccdb9f4fa98610780ba56.c1.e2" id="190bc9d8aadbfb5c848ccdb9f4fa98610780ba56.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
