<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="1f31c7be736309949bbd0cf4a0c39841f3f67bd6">
  <chunk id="1f31c7be736309949bbd0cf4a0c39841f3f67bd6.c0" text="Novel approaches for Spatial and Molecular Surveillance of Porcine Reproductive and Respiratory Syndrome Virus (PRRSv) in the United States"/>
  <chunk id="1f31c7be736309949bbd0cf4a0c39841f3f67bd6.c1" text="The US swine industry has been impaired over the last 25 years by the far-reaching financial losses caused by the porcine reproductive and respiratory syndrome (PRRS). Here, we explored the relations between the spatial risk of PRRS outbreaks and its phylodynamic history in the U.S during 1998-2016 using ORF5 sequences collected from swine farms in the Midwest region. We used maximum entropy and Bayesian phylodynamic models to generate risk maps for PRRS outbreaks and reconstructed the evolutionary history of three selected phylogenetic clades (A, B and C). High-risk areas for PRRS were best-predicted by pig density and climate seasonality and included Minnesota, Iowa and South Dakota. Phylodynamic models demonstrated that the geographical spread of the three clades followed a heterogeneous spatial diffusion process. Furthermore, PRRS viruses were characterized by typical seasonality in their population size. However, endemic strains were characterized by a substantially slower population growth and evolutionary rates, as well as smaller spatial dispersal rates when compared to emerging strains. We demonstrated the prospects of combining inferences derived from two unique analytical methods to inform decisions related to risk-based interventions of an important pathogen affecting one of the largest food animal industries in the world.">
    <entity charOffset="560-563" id="1f31c7be736309949bbd0cf4a0c39841f3f67bd6.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_27869" text="Caa" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1320-1324" id="1f31c7be736309949bbd0cf4a0c39841f3f67bd6.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33290" text="food" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="1f31c7be736309949bbd0cf4a0c39841f3f67bd6.c1.e0" e2="1f31c7be736309949bbd0cf4a0c39841f3f67bd6.c1.e1" id="1f31c7be736309949bbd0cf4a0c39841f3f67bd6.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
