<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="1f60f032bad1fcfb8d48b20527c347ec774d255e">
  <chunk id="1f60f032bad1fcfb8d48b20527c347ec774d255e.c0" text="Clinical Practice and Cases"/>
  <chunk id="1f60f032bad1fcfb8d48b20527c347ec774d255e.c1" text="Early antibiotic administration is critical in cases of sepsis and severe community-acquired pneumonia, which is frequently due to Streptococcus pneumoniae, Staphylococcus aureus, Legionella species, or influenza. We describe the case of a 29-year-old previously healthy man who presented to an urban emergency department (ED) in the North Central U.S. with fever, hip pain, severe hypoxemia, and diffuse pulmonary infiltrates. He was intubated and received piperacillin/tazobactam, levofloxacin, vancomycin, and oseltamivir; given his fulminant presentation and predicted high mortality, doxycycline, methylprednisolone, and amphotericin B were also administered empirically in the ED. A respiratory culture eventually grew Blastomyces dermatitidis, and the patient survived. Severe acute respiratory distress syndrome due to fulminant pneumonitis carries a high mortality. Faced with this scenario and no room for error, it is important that the emergency physician cover for all possible pathogens, including zoonotic bacteria and endemic fungi. [Clin Pract Cases Emerg Med. 2017;1(2): 136-139.] ">
    <entity charOffset="6-16" id="1f60f032bad1fcfb8d48b20527c347ec774d255e.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33281" text="antibiotic" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="271-274" id="1f60f032bad1fcfb8d48b20527c347ec774d255e.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_37684" text="man" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="626-640" id="1f60f032bad1fcfb8d48b20527c347ec774d255e.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_2682" text="amphotericin B" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="1f60f032bad1fcfb8d48b20527c347ec774d255e.c1.e0" e2="1f60f032bad1fcfb8d48b20527c347ec774d255e.c1.e1" id="1f60f032bad1fcfb8d48b20527c347ec774d255e.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="1f60f032bad1fcfb8d48b20527c347ec774d255e.c1.e0" e2="1f60f032bad1fcfb8d48b20527c347ec774d255e.c1.e2" id="1f60f032bad1fcfb8d48b20527c347ec774d255e.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="1f60f032bad1fcfb8d48b20527c347ec774d255e.c1.e1" e2="1f60f032bad1fcfb8d48b20527c347ec774d255e.c1.e2" id="1f60f032bad1fcfb8d48b20527c347ec774d255e.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
