<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="23f1565e1f4f6a5e0c92d96dc454299a9e37400b">
  <chunk id="23f1565e1f4f6a5e0c92d96dc454299a9e37400b.c0" text="Oxymatrine Inhibits Influenza A Virus Replication and Inflammation via TLR4, p38 MAPK and NF-κB Pathways">
    <entity charOffset="0-10" id="23f1565e1f4f6a5e0c92d96dc454299a9e37400b.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_2672" text="Oxymatrine" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="23f1565e1f4f6a5e0c92d96dc454299a9e37400b.c1" text="Oxymatrine (OMT) is a strong immunosuppressive agent that has been used in the clinic for many years. In the present study, by using plaque inhibition, luciferase reporter plasmids, qRT-PCR, western blotting, and ELISA assays, we have investigated the effect and mechanism of OMT on influenza A virus (IAV) replication and IAV-induced inflammation in vitro and in vivo. The results showed that OMT had excellent anti-IAV activity on eight IAV strains in vitro. OMT could significantly decrease the promoter activity of TLR3, TLR4, TLR7, MyD88, and TRAF6 genes, inhibit IAV-induced activations of Akt, ERK1/2, p38 MAPK, and NF-κB pathways, and suppress the expressions of inflammatory cytokines and MMP-2/-9. Activators of TLR4, p38 MAPK and NF-κB pathways could significantly antagonize the anti-IAV activity of OMT in vitro, including IAV replication and IAV-induced cytopathogenic effect (CPE). Furthermore, OMT could reduce the loss of body weight, significantly increase the survival rate of IAV-infected mice, decrease the lung index, pulmonary inflammation and lung viral titter, and improve pulmonary histopathological changes. In conclusion, OMT possesses anti-IAV and anti-inflammatory activities, the mechanism of action may be linked to its ability to inhibit IAV-induced activations of TLR4, p38 MAPK, and NF-κB pathways.">
    <entity charOffset="0-10" id="23f1565e1f4f6a5e0c92d96dc454299a9e37400b.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_2672" text="Oxymatrine" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="29-52" id="23f1565e1f4f6a5e0c92d96dc454299a9e37400b.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_35705" text="immunosuppressive agent" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1224-1230" id="23f1565e1f4f6a5e0c92d96dc454299a9e37400b.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_5133" text="action" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="23f1565e1f4f6a5e0c92d96dc454299a9e37400b.c1.e0" e2="23f1565e1f4f6a5e0c92d96dc454299a9e37400b.c1.e1" id="23f1565e1f4f6a5e0c92d96dc454299a9e37400b.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="23f1565e1f4f6a5e0c92d96dc454299a9e37400b.c1.e0" e2="23f1565e1f4f6a5e0c92d96dc454299a9e37400b.c1.e2" id="23f1565e1f4f6a5e0c92d96dc454299a9e37400b.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="23f1565e1f4f6a5e0c92d96dc454299a9e37400b.c1.e1" e2="23f1565e1f4f6a5e0c92d96dc454299a9e37400b.c1.e2" id="23f1565e1f4f6a5e0c92d96dc454299a9e37400b.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
