<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="2835b0f9f06e3e829cfa7d3f1e3805af94249d65">
  <chunk id="2835b0f9f06e3e829cfa7d3f1e3805af94249d65.c0" text="Oral Immunization of Chickens With Recombinant Lactobacillus plantarum Vaccine Against Early ALV-J Infection"/>
  <chunk id="2835b0f9f06e3e829cfa7d3f1e3805af94249d65.c1" text="In this study, a novel oral vaccine of recombinant Lactobacillus plantarum (L. plantarum) containing the gp85 protein was explored, and the effects of this vaccine on the prevention of subgroup J Avian Leukosis Virus (ALV-J) infection were assessed. In the current study, the gp85 protein of ALV-J was expressed on the surface of L. plantarum with the surface-display motif, pgsA, by constructing a shuttle vector pMG36e:pgsA:gp85. Surface localization of the fusion protein was verified by western blotting and flow cytometry. Subsequently, Specific Pathogen Free Hy-Line Brown layer chickens were orally vaccinated with the recombinant L. plantarum and presented with high levels of serum immunoglobulin G (IgG) and secretory immunoglobulin A (sIgA) titers in bile and duodenal-mucosal fluid. After challenged with ALV-J of a 3 × 10 3 50% tissue culture infective dose (TCID50), serum samples of the chickens were collected and viremia was analyzed. Results showed that, compared to the L. plantarum and PBS control group, the recombinant L. plantarum group showed a significant rise in antibody levels after inoculation, and provide improved protection against ALV-J according to viremia detection. These results indicate that oral immunization with the recombinant L. plantarum provided an effective means for eliciting protective immune response against early ALV-J infection.">
    <entity charOffset="110-117" id="2835b0f9f06e3e829cfa7d3f1e3805af94249d65.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="281-288" id="2835b0f9f06e3e829cfa7d3f1e3805af94249d65.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="467-474" id="2835b0f9f06e3e829cfa7d3f1e3805af94249d65.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
