<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="2c468e84bbaa10edb38eb112ab8088e74073c02f">
  <chunk id="2c468e84bbaa10edb38eb112ab8088e74073c02f.c0" text="Monitoring the Systemic Human Memory B Cell Compartment of Melanoma Patients for Anti-Tumor IgG Antibodies"/>
  <chunk id="2c468e84bbaa10edb38eb112ab8088e74073c02f.c1" text="Melanoma, a potentially lethal skin cancer, is widely thought to be immunogenic in nature. While there has been much focus on T cell-mediated immune responses, limited knowledge exists on the role of mature B cells. We describe an approach, including a cell-based ELISA, to evaluate mature IgG antibody responses to melanoma from human peripheral blood B cells. We observed a significant increase in antibody responses from melanoma patients (n = 10) to primary and metastatic melanoma cells compared to healthy volunteers (n = 10) (P,0.0001). Interestingly, we detected a significant reduction in antibody responses to melanoma with advancing disease stage in our patient cohort (n = 21) (P,0.0001). Overall, 28% of melanoma patient-derived B cell cultures (n = 1,800) compared to 2% of cultures from healthy controls (n = 600) produced antibodies that recognized melanoma cells. Lastly, a patient-derived melanoma-specific monoclonal antibody was selected for further study. This antibody effectively killed melanoma cells in vitro via antibody-mediated cellular cytotoxicity. These data demonstrate the presence of a mature systemic B cell response in melanoma patients, which is reduced with disease progression, adding to previous reports of tumor-reactive antibodies in patient sera, and suggesting the merit of future work to elucidate the clinical relevance of activating humoral immune responses to cancer.">
    <entity charOffset="192-196" id="2c468e84bbaa10edb38eb112ab8088e74073c02f.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="673-679" id="2c468e84bbaa10edb38eb112ab8088e74073c02f.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_34935" text="cohort" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="2c468e84bbaa10edb38eb112ab8088e74073c02f.c1.e0" e2="2c468e84bbaa10edb38eb112ab8088e74073c02f.c1.e1" id="2c468e84bbaa10edb38eb112ab8088e74073c02f.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
