<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e">
  <chunk id="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c0" text="Redox Biology of Respiratory Viral Infections"/>
  <chunk id="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c1" text="Respiratory viruses cause infections of the upper or lower respiratory tract and they are responsible for the common cold-the most prevalent disease in the world. In many cases the common cold results in severe illness due to complications, such as fever or pneumonia. Children, old people, and immunosuppressed patients are at the highest risk and require fast diagnosis and therapeutic intervention. However, the availability and efficiencies of existing therapeutic approaches vary depending on the virus. Investigation of the pathologies that are associated with infection by respiratory viruses will be paramount for diagnosis, treatment modalities, and the development of new therapies. Changes in redox homeostasis in infected cells are one of the key events that is linked to infection with respiratory viruses and linked to inflammation and subsequent tissue damage. Our review summarizes current knowledge on changes to redox homeostasis, as induced by the different respiratory viruses."/>
  <chunk id="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c2" text="Viruses 2018, 10, 392 2 of 27 scavenging enzymes and pathways are described further below and in the following comprehensive reviews [7, 8] ."/>
  <chunk id="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3" text="Markers of redox misbalance in blood and tissues are often taken into account in the pathology of various diseases. Chronic viral hepatitis B and C are generally associated with oxidative stress, and levels of ROS and oxidized metabolites correlate with the severity of liver damage and with the risk of the development of related pathologies-fibrosis and hepatocellular carcinoma [9] . Moreover, currently redox biology pays much attention to localization of ROS sources, since local changes in ROS levels may influence signaling pathways by activating &quot;redox switches&quot; [10, 11] . In lungs, redox homeostasis is crucial in the pathology of asthma [12] . Lung infection with respiratory viruses is, in general, associated with cytokine production, inflammation, cell death, and other pathological processes, which could be triggered by enhanced ROS production. Investigation of the influence of these infections on ROS-producing and ROS-scavenging enzymes and systems may allow for the identification of those that are crucial for replication of the pathogens and occurrence of virus-associated disease. Our review aims to summarize the known data on the role of redox biology in the pathologies that are associated with infection with respiratory viruses.">
    <entity charOffset="210-213" id="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_26523" text="ROS" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="227-238" id="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_25212" text="metabolites" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="460-463" id="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_26523" text="ROS" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="496-499" id="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_26523" text="ROS" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="845-848" id="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_26523" text="ROS" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1155-1159" id="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e0" e2="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e1" id="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e0" e2="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e5" id="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e1" e2="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e2" id="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e1" e2="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e3" id="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e1" e2="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e4" id="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e1" e2="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e5" id="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.p5" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e2" e2="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e5" id="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.p6" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e3" e2="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e5" id="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.p7" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e4" e2="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.e5" id="2d5a036da3eec69cf318ee695e8bd53347a61a1e.c3.p8" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
