<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="2d78b0600b84cfd57e11ba249ee58c159fe517ae">
  <chunk id="2d78b0600b84cfd57e11ba249ee58c159fe517ae.c0" text="Open Access RESEARCH The relationship between antibody status to bovine corona virus and bovine respiratory syncytial virus and disease incidence, reproduction and herd characteristics in dairy herds">
    <entity charOffset="5-11" id="2d78b0600b84cfd57e11ba249ee58c159fe517ae.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_34922" text="Access" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="72-78" id="2d78b0600b84cfd57e11ba249ee58c159fe517ae.c0.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_37409" text="corona" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="2d78b0600b84cfd57e11ba249ee58c159fe517ae.c0.e0" e2="2d78b0600b84cfd57e11ba249ee58c159fe517ae.c0.e1" id="2d78b0600b84cfd57e11ba249ee58c159fe517ae.c0.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="2d78b0600b84cfd57e11ba249ee58c159fe517ae.c1" text="Background: Bovine respiratory syncytial virus (BRSV) and bovine corona virus (BCV) affects cattle worldwide. Our objective was to evaluate the effects of these infections on general health and reproduction parameters measurable on herd level and to explore the association between antibody status and some herd characteristics. Methods: We collected a pooled milk sample from five primiparous cows from 79 Swedish dairy herds in September 2006. The samples were analysed for immunoglobulin G antibodies to BCV and BRSV with indirect enzyme-linked immunosorbent assays. Herd level data from 1 September 2005 to 30 August 2006 were accessed retrospectively. The location of the herds was mapped using a geographical information system. Results: Ten herds were antibody negative to both viruses and were compared with 69 herds positive to BCV or BRSV or both. Positive herds had a higher (P = 0.001) bulk tank milk somatic cell count (BMSCC) compared with negative herds. The medians for all other analyzed health and reproductive parameters were consistently in favour of the herds negative to both viruses although the differences were not statistically significant. A higher proportion (P = 0.01) of herds used professional technicians for artificial insemination, rather than farm personnel, amongst the 33 herds negative to BCV compared with the 46 positive herds. Conclusions: Our result shows that herds that were antibody positive to BCV and/or BRSV had a higher BMSCC compared with herds negative to BCV and BRSV. There was also tendency that negative herds had a better general herd health compared with positive. A higher proportion amongst the BCV negative herds used external technicians for AI instead of farm personnel, indicating that it is possible to avoid infection although having regular visits. Negative herds were located in close proximity to positive herds, indicating that local spread and airborne transmission between herds might not be of great importance and that herds can stay free from these infection transmission although virus is circulating in the area.">
    <entity charOffset="65-71" id="2d78b0600b84cfd57e11ba249ee58c159fe517ae.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_37409" text="corona" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="744-747" id="2d78b0600b84cfd57e11ba249ee58c159fe517ae.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_25879" text="Ten" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="2d78b0600b84cfd57e11ba249ee58c159fe517ae.c1.e0" e2="2d78b0600b84cfd57e11ba249ee58c159fe517ae.c1.e1" id="2d78b0600b84cfd57e11ba249ee58c159fe517ae.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
