<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="31491f82bfaa808144e856d7a21308cfa971b558">
  <chunk id="31491f82bfaa808144e856d7a21308cfa971b558.c0" text="Replication of MERS and SARS coronaviruses in bat cells offers insights to their ancestral origins"/>
  <chunk id="31491f82bfaa808144e856d7a21308cfa971b558.c1" text="Previous findings of Middle East Respiratory Syndrome coronavirus (MERS-CoV)-related viruses in bats, and the ability of Tylonycteris-BatCoV HKU4 spike protein to utilize MERS-CoV receptor, human dipeptidyl peptidase 4 hDPP4, suggest a bat ancestral origin of MERS-CoV. We developed 12 primary bat cell lines from seven bat species, including Tylonycteris pachypus, Pipistrellus abramus and Rhinolophus sinicus (hosts of Tylonycteris-BatCoV HKU4, Pipistrellus-BatCoV HKU5, and SARS-related-CoV respectively), and tested their susceptibilities to MERS-CoVs, SARS-CoV, and human coronavirus 229E (HCoV-229E). Five cell lines, including P. abramus and R. sinicus but not T. pachypus cells, were susceptible to human MERS-CoV EMC/2012. However, three tested camel MERS-CoV strains showed different infectivities, with only two strains capable of infecting three and one cell lines respectively. SARS-CoV can only replicate in R. sinicus cells, while HCoV-229E cannot replicate in any bat cells. Bat dipeptidyl peptidase 4 (DPP4) sequences were closely related to those of human and non-human primates but distinct from dromedary DPP4 sequence. Critical residues for binding to MERS-CoV spike protein were mostly conserved in bat DPP4. DPP4 was expressed in the five bat cells susceptible to MERS-CoV, with significantly higher mRNA expression levels than those in non-susceptible cells (P = 0.0174), supporting that DPP4 expression is critical for MERS-CoV infection in bats. However, overexpression of T. pachypus DPP4 failed to confer MERS-CoV susceptibility in T. pachypus cells, suggesting other cellular factors in determining viral replication. The broad cellular tropism of MERS-CoV should prompt further exploration of host diversity of related viruses to identify its ancestral origin.">
    <entity charOffset="152-159" id="31491f82bfaa808144e856d7a21308cfa971b558.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1188-1195" id="31491f82bfaa808144e856d7a21308cfa971b558.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1323-1327" id="31491f82bfaa808144e856d7a21308cfa971b558.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_33699" text="mRNA" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="31491f82bfaa808144e856d7a21308cfa971b558.c1.e0" e2="31491f82bfaa808144e856d7a21308cfa971b558.c1.e2" id="31491f82bfaa808144e856d7a21308cfa971b558.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="31491f82bfaa808144e856d7a21308cfa971b558.c1.e1" e2="31491f82bfaa808144e856d7a21308cfa971b558.c1.e2" id="31491f82bfaa808144e856d7a21308cfa971b558.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
