<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="33b0c24cb03b515296b278e96fd7de32151b9511">
  <chunk id="33b0c24cb03b515296b278e96fd7de32151b9511.c0" text="viruses Exploiting the Legacy of the Arbovirus Hunters"/>
  <chunk id="33b0c24cb03b515296b278e96fd7de32151b9511.c1" text="In recent years, it has become evident that a generational gap has developed in the community of arbovirus research. This apparent gap is due to the dis-investment of training for the next generation of arbovirologists, which threatens to derail the rich history of virus discovery, field epidemiology, and understanding of the richness of diversity that surrounds us. On the other hand, new technologies have resulted in an explosion of virus discovery that is constantly redefining the virosphere and the evolutionary relationships between viruses. This paradox presents new challenges that may have immediate and disastrous consequences for public health when yet to be discovered arboviruses emerge. In this review we endeavor to bridge this gap by providing a historical context for the work being conducted today and provide continuity between the generations. To this end, we will provide a narrative of the thrill of scientific discovery and excitement and the challenges lying ahead. original viruses (known and unknown) that came along with the staff from the former RF Virus Laboratory in New York, but over the years, as new viruses were submitted for study or were isolated by YARU investigators, they were also added to the WRCA collection [14] . As the former RF personnel retired, new researchers were recruited to YARU as full Yale University faculty [1]. Because of its prestige and university affiliation, many visiting scientists, graduate students, and other trainees from the U.S. and a variety of other countries came to YARU during this period to learn arboviral techniques, to do original research, and to identify samples collected by them during outbreaks or field studies. These samples were also added to the WRCA collection. Many of these visitors, as well as some of the younger YARU faculty, eventually moved on to assume prominent positions in academia, government service, or the corporate world. Shope [14] and Downs [1] have described some of the significant activities, accomplishments, and international collaborations during the early years of YARU."/>
  <chunk id="33b0c24cb03b515296b278e96fd7de32151b9511.c2" text="Without continued support from the RF or from Yale University, the YARU staff, like other university scientists in the U.S., had to compete for grants and contracts to support their research. health [15] . Shope was also an early proponent of the effect of ecological and global climate changes on arboviral and other vector-borne diseases [15, 16] , and he often served on national and international committees addressing this problem."/>
  <chunk id="33b0c24cb03b515296b278e96fd7de32151b9511.c3" text="Consultancies, service on government committees and free diagnostic laboratory support (the old RF model) could not provide sufficient funds to maintain and recruit new personnel, upgrade equipment, or support a major research program at a university in the U.S. In turn, leaders at Yale Medical School decided that arbovirology was passé and that other areas, such as HIV/AIDS, environmental health, and molecular biology, offered better funding and research opportunities for the 1980s. Thus, YARU gradually lost university support, faculty positions, and space. In 1995, after 30 years at Yale, Shope retired. Along with his colleague Robert Tesh, he moved to the newly established Center for Tropical Diseases at the University of Texas Medical Branch in Galveston [17] . The extensive WRCA virus and reagent collections went with them. Their departure and the loss of the WRCA collections was soon followed by the departure of other, younger, faculty associates, resulting in the eventual demise of YARU as a center for arbovirus research and discovery.">
    <entity charOffset="510-514" id="33b0c24cb03b515296b278e96fd7de32151b9511.c3.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_25434" text="lost" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="805-812" id="33b0c24cb03b515296b278e96fd7de32151b9511.c3.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33893" text="reagent" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="33b0c24cb03b515296b278e96fd7de32151b9511.c3.e0" e2="33b0c24cb03b515296b278e96fd7de32151b9511.c3.e1" id="33b0c24cb03b515296b278e96fd7de32151b9511.c3.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
