<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc">
  <chunk id="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c0" text="miR-26a Inhibits Feline Herpesvirus 1 Replication by Targeting SOCS5 and Promoting Type I Interferon Signaling">
    <entity charOffset="90-100" id="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_52999" text="Interferon" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c1" text="In response to viral infection, host cells activate various antiviral responses to inhibit virus replication. While feline herpesvirus 1 (FHV-1) manipulates the host early innate immune response in many different ways, the host could activate the antiviral response to counteract it through some unknown mechanisms. MicroRNAs (miRNAs) which serve as a class of regulatory factors in the host, participate in the regulation of the host innate immune response against virus infection. In this study, we found that the expression levels of miR-26a were significantly upregulated upon FHV-1 infection. Furthermore, FHV-1 infection induced the expression of miR-26a via a cGAS-dependent pathway, and knockdown of cellular cGAS significantly blocked the expression of miR-26a induced by poly (dA:dT) or FHV-1 infection. Next, we investigated the biological function of miR-26a during viral infection. miR-26a was able to increase the phosphorylation of STAT1 and promote type I IFN signaling, thus inhibiting viral replication. The mechanism study showed that miR-26a directly targeted host SOCS5. Knockdown of SOCS5 increased the phosphorylation of STAT1 and enhanced the type I IFN-mediated antiviral response, and overexpression of suppressor of the cytokine signalling 5 (SOCS5) decreased the phosphorylation of STAT1 and inhibited the type I IFN-mediated antiviral response. Meanwhile, with the knockdown of SOCS5, the upregulated expression of phosphorylated STAT1 and the anti-virus effect induced by miR-26a were significantly inhibited. Taken together, our data demonstrated a new strategy of host miRNAs against FHV-1 infection by enhancing IFN antiviral signaling.">
    <entity charOffset="60-69" id="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_22587" text="antiviral" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="247-256" id="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_22587" text="antiviral" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="840-859" id="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_24432" text="biological function" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1187-1196" id="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_22587" text="antiviral" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1354-1363" id="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_22587" text="antiviral" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1649-1658" id="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_22587" text="antiviral" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c1.e0" e2="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c1.e2" id="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c1.e1" e2="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c1.e2" id="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c1.e2" e2="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c1.e3" id="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c1.e2" e2="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c1.e4" id="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c1.e2" e2="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c1.e5" id="37215fa618869df1820d22f28bace99ea9ceb1fc.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
