<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="386c21f11ae0c9199c26218e334373932f3fa0c0">
  <chunk id="386c21f11ae0c9199c26218e334373932f3fa0c0.c0" text="Profile of international air passengers intercepted with illegal animal products in baggage at Guarulhos and Galeão airports in Brazil"/>
  <chunk id="386c21f11ae0c9199c26218e334373932f3fa0c0.c1" text="Protection against biological material entering a country or region through airports is important because, through them, infectious agents can quickly reach exotic destinations and be disseminated. Illegal products of animal origin may contain hazardous infectious agents that can compromise animal and public health. The aim of this study was to identify associations between possession of illegal animal products in baggage and demographic characteristics of the passengers, as well as characteristics of their travel plans in the two main Brazilian international airports. A total of 457 passengers were divided into two groups: passengers identified as carrying illegal animal products and control. Passengers identified as carrying illegal animal products not stated on the accompanied baggage declaration completed a questionnaire, to aid in profiling. Nationality, origin, age and residency of passengers were analyzed using chi square, logistic regression and odds ratios. Passengers from Eastern Europe were the most likely to enter with animal products as were those aged between 35 and 55 years. When evaluating the departure point, the highest frequency was seen in those coming from Portugal. Passenger group, reasons for travel, amount and type of baggage were available only for passengers identified as carrying illegal animal products, noting that they prefer traveling alone, for leisure, bringing few bags. Such information can contribute to the early identification of passengers that have illegal animal products in baggage at Brazilian airports.">
    <entity charOffset="932-935" id="386c21f11ae0c9199c26218e334373932f3fa0c0.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_136604" text="chi" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
