<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="3c082fd7a87e4e55f001e749fa9ce2a3481b0f5f">
  <chunk id="3c082fd7a87e4e55f001e749fa9ce2a3481b0f5f.c0" text="A bibliometric analysis of literature on malaria vector resistance: (1996 -2015)"/>
  <chunk id="3c082fd7a87e4e55f001e749fa9ce2a3481b0f5f.c1" text="Background: Emergence of insecticide resistance in malaria vectors is a real threat to future goals of elimination and control of malaria. Therefore, the objective of this study was to assess research trend on insecticide resistance of Anopheles mosquito. In specific, number of publications, countries, institutions, and authors' research profile, citation analysis, international collaborations, and impact of journals publishing documents on insecticide resistance will be presented. It was conducted via Scopus search engine which was used to retrieve relevant data. Keywords used were based on literature available on this topic. The duration of study was set from 1996-2015.">
    <entity charOffset="25-36" id="3c082fd7a87e4e55f001e749fa9ce2a3481b0f5f.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_24852" text="insecticide" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="210-221" id="3c082fd7a87e4e55f001e749fa9ce2a3481b0f5f.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_24852" text="insecticide" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="445-456" id="3c082fd7a87e4e55f001e749fa9ce2a3481b0f5f.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_24852" text="insecticide" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="3c082fd7a87e4e55f001e749fa9ce2a3481b0f5f.c2" text="Results: A total of 616 documents, mainly as original research articles (n = 569; 92.37%) were retrieved. The average number of citations per article was 26.36. Poisson log-linear regression analysis indicated that there was a 6.00% increase in the number of publications for each extra article on pyrethroid resistance. A total of 82 different countries and 1922 authors participated in publishing retrieved articles. The United Kingdom (UK) ranked first in number of publications followed by the United States of America (USA) and France. The top ten productive countries included seven African countries. The UK had collaborations mostly with Benin (relative link strength = 46). A total of 1817 institution/ organizations participated in the publication of retrieved articles. The most active institution/ organization was Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine. Retrieved articles were published in 134 different scientific peer reviewed journals. The journal that published most on this topic was Malaria Journal (n = 101; 16.4%). Four of the top active authors were from South Africa and two were from the UK. Three of the top ten cited articles were published in Insect Molecular Biology journal. Six articles were about pyrethroid resistance and at least two were about DDT resistance. Conclusion: Publications on insecticide resistance in malaria vector has gained momentum in the past decade. International collaborations enhanced the knowledge about the situation of vector resistance in countries with endemic malaria. Molecular biology of insecticide resistance is the key issue in understanding and overcoming this emerging problems.">
    <entity charOffset="1278-1281" id="3c082fd7a87e4e55f001e749fa9ce2a3481b0f5f.c2.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16130" text="DDT" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1322-1333" id="3c082fd7a87e4e55f001e749fa9ce2a3481b0f5f.c2.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_24852" text="insecticide" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1552-1563" id="3c082fd7a87e4e55f001e749fa9ce2a3481b0f5f.c2.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_24852" text="insecticide" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="3c082fd7a87e4e55f001e749fa9ce2a3481b0f5f.c2.e0" e2="3c082fd7a87e4e55f001e749fa9ce2a3481b0f5f.c2.e1" id="3c082fd7a87e4e55f001e749fa9ce2a3481b0f5f.c2.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="3c082fd7a87e4e55f001e749fa9ce2a3481b0f5f.c2.e0" e2="3c082fd7a87e4e55f001e749fa9ce2a3481b0f5f.c2.e2" id="3c082fd7a87e4e55f001e749fa9ce2a3481b0f5f.c2.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
