<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d">
  <chunk id="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c0" text="Polypeptide N-acetylgalactosaminyltransferase 2 regulates cellular metastasis-associated behavior in gastric cancer">
    <entity charOffset="0-11" id="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_15841" text="Polypeptide" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c1" text="Aberrant glycosylation of cell surface glycoprotein due to specific alterations of glycosyltransferase activity is usually associated with invasion and metastasis of cancer, particularly of gastric carcinomas. Polypeptide N-acetylgalactosaminyltransferase 2 (ppGalNAc-T2), which catalyzes initiation of mucin-type O-glycosylation, is also involved in tumor migration and invasion. However, a comprehensive understanding of how ppGalNAc-T2 correlates with the metastasic potential of human gastric cancer is not currently available. In the present study, ppGalNAc-T2 was detected in a variety of human poorly differentiated tumor cells, and expression appeared to be higher in SGC7901 gastric cancer cells. In addition, we investigated the potential effects of ppGalNAc-T2 on growth and metastasis-associated behavior in SGC7901 cells after stable transfection with ppGalNAc-T2 sense and antisense vectors. We found that cell proliferation, adhesion and invasion were decreased in ppGalNAc-T2 overexpressed cells but increased in ppGalNAc-T2 downregulated cells. Therefore, we attempted to clarify the mechanisms underlying the anti-metastatic activities of ppGalNAc-T2. Further investigation indicated that overexpression of ppGalNAc-T2 is involved in the inhibition of matrix metalloproteinase (MMP)-2 expression at both the protein and mRNA levels, which may be associated with ppGalNAc-T2 suppressing the expression of transforming growth factor (TGF)-β1. However, it did not exhibit any apparent correlation with MMP-14 expression levels. Our data show the effect of ppGalNAc-T2 on proliferation, adhesion or invasion of SGC7901 gastric cancer cells, suggesting that ppGalNAc-T2 may exert anti-proliferative and anti-metastatic activity through the decrease of MMP-2 and TGF-β1. These results indicate that ppGalNAc-T2 may be used as a novel therapeutic target for human gastric cancer treatment.">
    <entity charOffset="39-51" id="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_17089" text="glycoprotein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="210-221" id="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_15841" text="Polypeptide" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1326-1333" id="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1338-1342" id="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_33699" text="mRNA" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c1.e0" e2="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c1.e1" id="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c1.e0" e2="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c1.e2" id="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c1.e0" e2="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c1.e3" id="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c1.e1" e2="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c1.e2" id="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c1.e1" e2="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c1.e3" id="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c1.e2" e2="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c1.e3" id="3d2fae37d61a2e45cf0dff9bc0abee361bbf9a8d.c1.p5" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
