<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="41743a48f1acec724d627f76e02e85137debc076">
  <chunk id="41743a48f1acec724d627f76e02e85137debc076.c0" text="IRAK-M alters the polarity of macrophages to facilitate the survival of Mycobacterium tuberculosis"/>
  <chunk id="41743a48f1acec724d627f76e02e85137debc076.c1" text="Background: Intracellular bacterium, Mycobacterium tuberculosis (M. tb), infects specifically macrophages as host cells. IRAK-M, a member of IRAK family, is a negative regulator in TLR signaling and specifically expresses in monocytes and macrophages. The role of IRAK-M in intracellular growth of M. tb and macrophage polarization was explored, for deeply understanding the pathogenesis of M. tb, the significance of IRAK-M to innate immunity and pathogen-host interaction. Methods: IRAK-M expression was detected in M. tb infected macrophages and in human lung tissue of pulmonary tuberculosis with immunofluorescence staining, Western blot and immunohistochemistry. IRAK-M knock-down and over-expressing cell strains were constructed and intracellular survival of M. tb was investigated by acid-fast staining and colony forming units. Molecular markers of M1-type (pSTAT1 and iNOS) and M2-type (pSTAT6 and Arg-1) macrophages were detected using Western blot in IRAK-M knockdown U937 cells infected with M. tb H37Rv. U937 cells were stimulated with immunostimulant CpG7909 into M1 status and then infected with M. tb H37Rv. Expression of IRAK-M, IRAK-4 and iNOS was detected with immunofluorescence staining and Western blot, to evaluate the effect of IRAK-M to CpG directed M1-type polarization of macrophages during M. tb infection. Molecules related with macrophage's bactericidal ability such as Hif-1 and phosphorylated ERK1/2 were detected with immunohistochemistry and Western blot. Results: IRAK-M increased in M. tb infected macrophage cells and also in human lung tissue of pulmonary tuberculosis. IRAK-M over-expression resulted in higher bacterial load, while IRAK-M interference resulted in lower bacterial load in M. tb infected cells. During M. tb infection, IRAK-M knockdown induced M1-type, while inhibited M2-type polarization of macrophage. M1-type polarization of U937 cells induced by CpG7909 was inhibited by M. tb infection, which was reversed by IRAK-M knockdown in U937 cells. IRAK-M affected Hif-1 and MAPK signaling cascade during M. tb infection. Conclusions: Conclusively, IRAK-M might alter the polarity of macrophages, to facilitate intracellular survival of M. tb and affect Th1-type immunity of the host, which is helpful to understanding the pathogenesis of M. tb.">
    <entity charOffset="256-260" id="41743a48f1acec724d627f76e02e85137debc076.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1051-1066" id="41743a48f1acec724d627f76e02e85137debc076.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_50847" text="immunostimulant" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1337-1346" id="41743a48f1acec724d627f76e02e85137debc076.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_25367" text="Molecules" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="41743a48f1acec724d627f76e02e85137debc076.c1.e0" e2="41743a48f1acec724d627f76e02e85137debc076.c1.e1" id="41743a48f1acec724d627f76e02e85137debc076.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="41743a48f1acec724d627f76e02e85137debc076.c1.e0" e2="41743a48f1acec724d627f76e02e85137debc076.c1.e2" id="41743a48f1acec724d627f76e02e85137debc076.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="41743a48f1acec724d627f76e02e85137debc076.c1.e1" e2="41743a48f1acec724d627f76e02e85137debc076.c1.e2" id="41743a48f1acec724d627f76e02e85137debc076.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
