<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="434ab543a48b7fb395d181ffb947814bd1b506c4">
  <chunk id="434ab543a48b7fb395d181ffb947814bd1b506c4.c0" text="The Roles of Histidines and Charged Residues as Potential Triggers of a Conformational Change in the Fusion Loop of Ebola Virus Glycoprotein">
    <entity charOffset="128-140" id="434ab543a48b7fb395d181ffb947814bd1b506c4.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_17089" text="Glycoprotein" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="434ab543a48b7fb395d181ffb947814bd1b506c4.c1" text="Ebola virus (EBOV) enters cells from late endosomes/lysosomes under mildly acidic conditions. Entry by fusion with the endosomal membrane requires the fusion loop (FL, residues 507-560) of the EBOV surface glycoprotein to undergo a pH-dependent conformational change. To find the pH trigger for this reaction we mutated multiple conserved histidines and charged and uncharged hydrophilic residues in the FL and measured their activity by liposome fusion and cell entry of virus-like particles. The FL location in the membrane was assessed by NMR using soluble and lipid-bound paramagnetic relaxation agents. While we could not identify a single residue to be alone responsible for pH triggering, we propose that a distributed pH effect over multiple residues induces the conformational change that enhances membrane insertion and triggers the fusion activity of the EBOV FL. 3 / 14 residues are highlighted using the same color scheme as in Fig 1. In addition, residues constituting the hydrophobic patch are highlighted in yellow. Resonances of residues that are too weak to observe after quenching with the paramagnetic agents and prolines are marked with an &quot;X&quot;. b) Structure of the EBOV FL at pH 5.5 (PDB code: 2LCY) in backbone and surface representation. Residues are color-coded according to their disposition in the membrane as measured by paramagnetic relaxation NMR. Red indicates residues with deep hydrophobic and green indicates residues with interfacial lipid interactions. Blue residues are exposed to water. Grey corresponds to residues marked with an &quot;X&quot; in panel a. Fig 4. Circular dichoism spectra of the a) wild-type, b) H516A, c) H516R, and d) H516Y mutant EBOV FLs as a function of pH in POPC/POPG liposomes. The H516A and H516R mutants precipitated under acidic conditions below pH 4.5.">
    <entity charOffset="206-218" id="434ab543a48b7fb395d181ffb947814bd1b506c4.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_17089" text="glycoprotein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1468-1473" id="434ab543a48b7fb395d181ffb947814bd1b506c4.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_18059" text="lipid" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="434ab543a48b7fb395d181ffb947814bd1b506c4.c1.e0" e2="434ab543a48b7fb395d181ffb947814bd1b506c4.c1.e1" id="434ab543a48b7fb395d181ffb947814bd1b506c4.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
