<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="454c099b504f30d078e4fff12a3212dcc5567e97">
  <chunk id="454c099b504f30d078e4fff12a3212dcc5567e97.c0" text=""/>
  <chunk id="454c099b504f30d078e4fff12a3212dcc5567e97.c1" text="The Burden of Communicable Diseases in Europe (BCoDE) study aimed to calculate disability-adjusted life years (DALYs) for 31 selected diseases in the European Union (EU) and European Economic Area (EEA). Methods: DALYs were estimated using an incidence-based and pathogen-based approach. Incidence was estimated through assessment of data availability and quality, and a correction was applied for under-estimation. Calculation of DALYs was performed with the BCoDE software toolkit without applying time discounting and age-weighting. Results: We estimated that one in 14 inhabitants experienced an infectious disease episode for a total burden of 1.38 million DALYs (95% uncertainty interval (UI): 1.25-1.5) between 2009 and 2013; 76% of which was related to the acute phase of the infection and its short-term complications. Influenza had the highest burden (30% of the total burden), followed by tuberculosis, human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection/ AIDS and invasive pneumococcal disease (IPD). Men had the highest burden measured in DALYs (60% of the total), adults 65 years of age and over had 24% and children less than 5 years of age had 11%. Age groupspecific burden showed that infants (less than 1 year of age) and elderly people (80 years of age and over) experienced the highest burden. Conclusions: These results provide baseline estimates for evaluating infectious disease prevention and control strategies.">
    <entity charOffset="1158-1161" id="454c099b504f30d078e4fff12a3212dcc5567e97.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_84123" text="Age" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="454c099b504f30d078e4fff12a3212dcc5567e97.c2" text="The study promotes an evidence-based approach to describing population health and assessing surveillance data availability and quality, and provides information for the planning and prioritisation of limited resources in infectious disease prevention and control."/>
</document>
