<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="49e262acc674f6765222a7b46b8eb1c78aeda947">
  <chunk id="49e262acc674f6765222a7b46b8eb1c78aeda947.c0" text="Attenuation of replication by a 29 nucleotide deletion in SARS- coronavirus acquired during the early stages of human-to-human transmission OPEN">
    <entity charOffset="35-45" id="49e262acc674f6765222a7b46b8eb1c78aeda947.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_36976" text="nucleotide" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="49e262acc674f6765222a7b46b8eb1c78aeda947.c1" text="A 29 nucleotide deletion in open reading frame 8 (ORF8) is the most obvious genetic change in severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus (SARS-CoV) during its emergence in humans. In spite of intense study, it remains unclear whether the deletion actually reflects adaptation to humans. Here we engineered full, partially deleted (−29 nt), and fully deleted ORF8 into a SARS-CoV infectious cDNA clone, strain Frankfurt-1. Replication of the resulting viruses was compared in primate cell cultures as well as Rhinolophus bat cells made permissive for SARS-CoV replication by lentiviral transduction of the human angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 receptor. Cells from cotton rat, goat, and sheep provided control scenarios that represent host systems in which SARS-CoV is neither endemic nor epidemic. Independent of the cell system, the truncation of ORF8 (29 nt deletion) decreased replication up to 23fold. The effect was independent of the type I interferon response. The 29 nt deletion in SARS-CoV is a deleterious mutation acquired along the initial human-to-human transmission chain. The resulting loss of fitness may be due to a founder effect, which has rarely been documented in processes of viral emergence. These results have important implications for the retrospective assessment of the threat posed by SARS.">
    <entity charOffset="5-15" id="49e262acc674f6765222a7b46b8eb1c78aeda947.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_36976" text="nucleotide" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="950-960" id="49e262acc674f6765222a7b46b8eb1c78aeda947.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_52999" text="interferon" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="49e262acc674f6765222a7b46b8eb1c78aeda947.c1.e0" e2="49e262acc674f6765222a7b46b8eb1c78aeda947.c1.e1" id="49e262acc674f6765222a7b46b8eb1c78aeda947.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="49e262acc674f6765222a7b46b8eb1c78aeda947.c2" text="Emerging zoonotic viruses such as Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome coronavirus (SARS-CoV) are a considerable concern for public health 1 . Bats of the genus Rhinolophus are the bona-fide animal reservoir for SARS-and SARS-related CoV (SARSr-CoV) 2 . Epidemics may emerge from wild animal reservoirs in which a plethora of viral variants exists. After initial cross-host infection, the occurrence of positive selection with adaptive changes"/>
</document>
