<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="4a326f7b32461745b6e168b454a214839b704865">
  <chunk id="4a326f7b32461745b6e168b454a214839b704865.c0" text="A Clathrin Independent Macropinocytosis-Like Entry Mechanism Used by Bluetongue Virus-1 during Infection of BHK Cells"/>
  <chunk id="4a326f7b32461745b6e168b454a214839b704865.c1" text="Acid dependent infection of Hela and Vero cells by BTV-10 occurs from within early-endosomes following virus uptake by clathrin-mediated endocytosis (Forzan et al., 2007: J Virol 81: 4819-4827). Here we report that BTV-1 infection of BHK cells is also dependent on a low endosomal pH; however, virus entry and infection were not inhibited by dominant-negative mutants of Eps15, AP180 or the 'aa' splice variant of dynamin-2, which were shown to inhibit clathrin-mediated endocytosis. In addition, infection was not inhibited by depletion of cellular cholesterol, which suggests that virus entry is not mediated by a lipid-raft dependent process such as caveolae-mediated endocytosis. Although virus entry and infection were not inhibited by the dominant-negative dynamin-2 mutant, entry was inhibited by the general dynamin inhibitor, dynasore, indicating that virus entry is dynamin dependent. During entry, BTV-1 co-localised with LAMP-1 but not with transferrin, suggesting that virus is delivered to late-endosomal compartments without first passing through early-endosomes. BTV-1 entry and infection were inhibited by EIPA and cytochalasin-D, known macropinocytosis inhibitors, and during entry virus co-localised with dextran, a known marker for macropinocytosis/fluid-phase uptake. Our results extend earlier observations with BTV-10, and show that BTV-1 can infect BHK cells via an entry mechanism that is clathrin and cholesterol-independent, but requires dynamin, and shares certain characteristics in common with macropinocytosis.">
    <entity charOffset="0-4" id="4a326f7b32461745b6e168b454a214839b704865.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_37527" text="Acid" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1123-1127" id="4a326f7b32461745b6e168b454a214839b704865.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_136538" text="EIPA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1171-1181" id="4a326f7b32461745b6e168b454a214839b704865.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_35222" text="inhibitors" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="4a326f7b32461745b6e168b454a214839b704865.c1.e0" e2="4a326f7b32461745b6e168b454a214839b704865.c1.e1" id="4a326f7b32461745b6e168b454a214839b704865.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="4a326f7b32461745b6e168b454a214839b704865.c1.e0" e2="4a326f7b32461745b6e168b454a214839b704865.c1.e2" id="4a326f7b32461745b6e168b454a214839b704865.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="4a326f7b32461745b6e168b454a214839b704865.c1.e1" e2="4a326f7b32461745b6e168b454a214839b704865.c1.e2" id="4a326f7b32461745b6e168b454a214839b704865.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="4a326f7b32461745b6e168b454a214839b704865.c2" text="Citation: Gold S, Monaghan P, Mertens P, Jackson T (2010) A Clathrin Independent Macropinocytosis-Like Entry Mechanism Used by Bluetongue Virus-1 during Infection of BHK Cells. PLoS ONE 5(6): e11360.">
    <entity charOffset="10-14" id="4a326f7b32461745b6e168b454a214839b704865.c2.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_29287" text="Gold" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="182-185" id="4a326f7b32461745b6e168b454a214839b704865.c2.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_58972" text="ONE" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="4a326f7b32461745b6e168b454a214839b704865.c2.e0" e2="4a326f7b32461745b6e168b454a214839b704865.c2.e1" id="4a326f7b32461745b6e168b454a214839b704865.c2.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
