<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="4cbd54dab5ad14f6d8c5ad9fb9bc223cb4431ba3">
  <chunk id="4cbd54dab5ad14f6d8c5ad9fb9bc223cb4431ba3.c0" text="Epidemiology of Pathogen-Specific Respiratory Infections among Three US Populations"/>
  <chunk id="4cbd54dab5ad14f6d8c5ad9fb9bc223cb4431ba3.c1" text="Background: Diagnostic tests for respiratory infections can be costly and timeconsuming. Improved characterization of specific respiratory pathogens by identifying frequent signs, symptoms and demographic characteristics, along with improving our understanding of coinfection rates and seasonality, may improve treatment and prevention measures. Methods: Febrile respiratory illness (FRI) and severe acute respiratory infection (SARI) surveillance was conducted from October 2011 through March 2013 among three US populations: civilians near the US-Mexico border, Department of Defense (DoD) beneficiaries, and military recruits. Clinical and demographic questionnaire data and respiratory swabs were collected from participants, tested by PCR for nine different respiratory pathogens and summarized. Age stratified characteristics of civilians positive for influenza and recruits positive for rhinovirus were compared to other and no/unknown pathogen. Seasonality and coinfection rates were also described.">
    <entity charOffset="587-590" id="4cbd54dab5ad14f6d8c5ad9fb9bc223cb4431ba3.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_23870" text="DoD" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="801-804" id="4cbd54dab5ad14f6d8c5ad9fb9bc223cb4431ba3.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_84123" text="Age" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="4cbd54dab5ad14f6d8c5ad9fb9bc223cb4431ba3.c1.e0" e2="4cbd54dab5ad14f6d8c5ad9fb9bc223cb4431ba3.c1.e1" id="4cbd54dab5ad14f6d8c5ad9fb9bc223cb4431ba3.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="4cbd54dab5ad14f6d8c5ad9fb9bc223cb4431ba3.c2" text="Results: A total of 1444 patients met the FRI or SARI case definition and were enrolled in this study. Influenza signs and symptoms varied across age groups of civilians. Recruits with rhinovirus had higher percentages of pneumonia, cough, shortness of breath, congestion, cough, less fever and longer time to seeking care and were more likely to be male compared to those in the no/unknown pathogen group. Coinfections were found in 6% of all FRI/SARI cases tested and were most frequently seen among children and with rhinovirus infections. Clear seasonal trends were identified for influenza, rhinovirus, and respiratory syncytial virus."/>
</document>
