<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a">
  <chunk id="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c0" text="Animal board invited review: advances in proteomics for animal and food sciences animal">
    <entity charOffset="67-71" id="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33290" text="food" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1" text="Animal production and health (APH) is an important sector in the world economy, representing a large proportion of the budget of all member states in the European Union and in other continents. APH is a highly competitive sector with a strong emphasis on innovation and, albeit with country to country variations, on scientific research. Proteomics (the study of all proteins present in a given tissue or fluidi.e. the proteome) has an enormous potential when applied to APH. Nevertheless, for a variety of reasons and in contrast to disciplines such as plant sciences or human biomedicine, such potential is only now being tapped. To counter such limited usage, 6 years ago we created a consortium dedicated to the applications of Proteomics to APH, specifically in the form of a Cooperation in Science and Technology (COST) Action, termed FA1002 -Proteomics in Farm Animals: www.costfaproteomics.org. In 4 years, the consortium quickly enlarged to a total of 31 countries in Europe, as well as Israel, Argentina, Australia and New Zealand. This article has a triple purpose. First, we aim to provide clear examples on the applications and benefits of the use of proteomics in all aspects related to APH. Second, we provide insights and possibilities on the new trends and objectives for APH proteomics applications and technologies for the years to come. Finally, we provide an overview and balance of the major activities and accomplishments of the COST Action on Farm Animal Proteomics. These include activities such as the organization of seminars, workshops and major scientific conferences, organization of summer schools, financing Short-Term Scientific Missions (STSMs) and the generation of scientific literature. Overall, the Action has attained all of the proposed objectives and has made considerable difference by putting proteomics on the global map for animal and veterinary researchers in general and by contributing significantly to reduce the East-West and North-South gaps existing in the European farm animal research. Future activities of significance in the field of scientific research, involving members of the action, as well as others, will likely be established in the future.">
    <entity charOffset="367-375" id="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="826-832" id="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_5133" text="Action" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1457-1463" id="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_5133" text="Action" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1737-1743" id="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_5133" text="Action" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="2136-2142" id="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_5133" text="action" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.e0" e2="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.e1" id="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.e0" e2="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.e2" id="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.e0" e2="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.e3" id="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.e0" e2="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.e4" id="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.e1" e2="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.e4" id="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.e2" e2="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.e4" id="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.p5" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.e3" e2="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.e4" id="4f0e7fc5e32e927fd76e1f5c156cb9caee8eda2a.c1.p6" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
