<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c">
  <chunk id="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c0" text="Enhanced inflammation in New Zealand white rabbits when MERS-CoV reinfection occurs in the absence of neutralizing antibody Author summary"/>
  <chunk id="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c1" text="The Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus (MERS-CoV) is a zoonotic betacoronavirus that was first detected in humans in 2012 as a cause of severe acute respiratory disease. As of July 28, 2017, there have been 2,040 confirmed cases with 712 reported deaths. While many infections have been fatal, there have also been a large number of mild or asymptomatic cases discovered through monitoring and contact tracing. New Zealand white rabbits are a possible model for asymptomatic infection with MERS-CoV. In order to discover more about non-lethal infections and to learn whether a single infection with MERS-CoV would protect against reinfection, we inoculated rabbits with MERS-CoV and monitored the antibody and inflammatory response. Following intranasal infection, rabbits developed a transient dose-dependent pulmonary infection with moderately high levels of viral RNA, viral antigen, and perivascular inflammation in multiple lung lobes that was not associated with clinical signs. The rabbits developed antibodies against viral proteins that lacked neutralizing activity and the animals were not protected from reinfection. In fact, reinfection resulted in enhanced pulmonary inflammation, without an associated increase in viral RNA titers. Interestingly, passive transfer of serum from previously infected rabbits to naïve rabbits was associated with enhanced inflammation upon infection. We further found this inflammation was accompanied by increased recruitment of complement proteins compared to primary infection. However, reinfection elicited neutralizing antibodies that protected rabbits from subsequent viral challenge. Our data from the rabbit model suggests that people exposed to MERS-CoV who fail to develop a neutralizing antibody response, or persons whose neutralizing antibody titers have waned, may be at risk for severe lung disease on re-exposure to MERS-CoV.">
    <entity charOffset="877-880" id="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1042-1050" id="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1244-1247" id="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1495-1503" id="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c1.e0" e2="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c1.e1" id="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c1.e0" e2="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c1.e3" id="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c1.e1" e2="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c1.e2" id="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c1.e2" e2="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c1.e3" id="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c2" text="PLOS Pathogens | https://doi.New Zealand white rabbits display an increase in lung inflammation following reinfection with MERS-CoV that is associated with non-neutralizing antibodies and complement proteins. The development of neutralizing antibodies resulted in protection from infection. These findings may have implications for individuals that fail to develop a neutralizing antibody response, or for those whose response wanes over time, upon re-exposure to MERS-CoV. Enhanced inflammation after MERS reinfection in rabbits PLOS Pathogens | https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.ppat.1006565 August 17, 2017 2 / 25 Competing interests: The authors have declared that no competing interests exist Fig 1. Schematic of rabbit infection studies. Rabbits were inoculated intranasally with EMC/2012 strain of MERS-CoV (green arrows) and tissue samples were collected for viral titration and histopathology at necropsy (blue arrows). Three rabbits were necropsied at each time point. Numbers indicate days since virus administration for primary, (secondary), or [tertiary] infections. Enhanced inflammation after MERS reinfection in rabbits PLOS Pathogens | https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.ppat.1006565 August 17, 2017 4 / 25"/>
  <chunk id="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c3" text="Fig 4. Viral RNA titers and histopathology in the lungs of rabbits following reinfection with MERS-CoV. Viral RNA titers in the lungs of rabbits following reinfection with EMC/2012 (A). Images show H&amp;E (left) and IHC for the Enhanced inflammation after MERS reinfection in rabbits PLOS Pathogens | https://doi.">
    <entity charOffset="13-16" id="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c3.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="110-113" id="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c3.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="182-185" id="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c3.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_28515" text="Aaa" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c3.e0" e2="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c3.e2" id="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c3.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c3.e1" e2="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c3.e2" id="555a36d1c3822baa8b6a2612b86ed5df5b1dbf7c.c3.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
