<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="5645bc52d703b021b132a5bb5ca1702809db4cb5">
  <chunk id="5645bc52d703b021b132a5bb5ca1702809db4cb5.c0" text="Comparison of ePlex Respiratory Pathogen Panel with Laboratory- Developed Real-Time PCR Assays for Detection of Respiratory Pathogens"/>
  <chunk id="5645bc52d703b021b132a5bb5ca1702809db4cb5.c1" text="Infections of the respiratory tract can be caused by a diversity of pathogens, both viral and bacterial. Rapid microbiological diagnosis ensures appropriate antimicrobial therapy as well as effective implementation of isolation precautions. The ePlex respiratory pathogen panel (RP panel) is a novel molecular biologybased assay, developed by GenMark Diagnostics, Inc. (Carlsbad, CA), to be performed within a single cartridge for the diagnosis of 25 respiratory pathogens (viral and bacterial). The objective of this study was to compare the performance of the RP panel with those of laboratory-developed real-time PCR assays, using a variety of previously collected clinical respiratory specimens. A total of 343 clinical specimens as well as 29 external quality assessment (EQA) specimens and 2 different Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus isolates have been assessed in this study. The RP panel showed an agreement of 97.4% with the real-time PCR assay regarding 464 pathogens found in the clinical specimens. All pathogens present in clinical samples and EQA samples with a threshold cycle (C T ) value of Ͻ30 were detected correctly using the RP panel. The RP panel detected 17 additional pathogens, 7 of which could be confirmed by discrepant testing. In conclusion, this study shows excellent performance of the RP panel in comparison to real-time PCR assays for the detection of respiratory pathogens. The ePlex system provided a large amount of useful diagnostic data within a short time frame, with minimal hands-on time, and can therefore potentially be used for rapid diagnostic sample-to-answer testing, in either a laboratory or a decentralized setting.">
    <entity charOffset="157-170" id="5645bc52d703b021b132a5bb5ca1702809db4cb5.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33281" text="antimicrobial" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="5645bc52d703b021b132a5bb5ca1702809db4cb5.c2" text="Citation Nijhuis RHT, Guerendiain D, Claas ECJ, Templeton KE. 2017. Comparison of ePlex respiratory pathogen panel with laboratory-developed real-time PCR assays for detection of respiratory pathogens. J Clin"/>
</document>
