<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="5669349639eae4f58b4fecca26fcc271094c70ba">
  <chunk id="5669349639eae4f58b4fecca26fcc271094c70ba.c0" text="Detection and Characterization of Homologues of Human Hepatitis Viruses and Pegiviruses in Rodents and Bats in Vietnam"/>
  <chunk id="5669349639eae4f58b4fecca26fcc271094c70ba.c1" text="Rodents and bats are now widely recognised as important sources of zoonotic virus infections in other mammals, including humans. Numerous surveys have expanded our knowledge of diverse viruses in a range of rodent and bat species, including their origins, evolution, and range of hosts. In this study of pegivirus and human hepatitis-related viruses, liver and serum samples from Vietnamese rodents and bats were examined by PCR and sequencing. Nucleic acids homologous to human hepatitis B, C, E viruses were detected in liver samples of 2 (1.3%) of 157 bats, 38 (8.1%), and 14 (3%) of 470 rodents, respectively. Hepacivirus-like viruses were frequently detected (42.7%) in the bamboo rat, Rhizomys pruinosus, while pegivirus RNA was only evident in 2 (0.3%) of 638 rodent serum samples. Complete or near-complete genome sequences of HBV, HEV and pegivirus homologues closely resembled those previously reported from rodents and bats. However, complete coding region sequences of the rodent hepacivirus-like viruses substantially diverged from all of the currently classified variants and potentially represent a new species in the Hepacivirus genus. Of the viruses identified, their routes of transmission and potential to establish zoonoses remain to be determined.">
    <entity charOffset="445-458" id="5669349639eae4f58b4fecca26fcc271094c70ba.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33696" text="Nucleic acids" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="453-458" id="5669349639eae4f58b4fecca26fcc271094c70ba.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_37527" text="acids" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="727-730" id="5669349639eae4f58b4fecca26fcc271094c70ba.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="5669349639eae4f58b4fecca26fcc271094c70ba.c1.e0" e2="5669349639eae4f58b4fecca26fcc271094c70ba.c1.e1" id="5669349639eae4f58b4fecca26fcc271094c70ba.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5669349639eae4f58b4fecca26fcc271094c70ba.c1.e0" e2="5669349639eae4f58b4fecca26fcc271094c70ba.c1.e2" id="5669349639eae4f58b4fecca26fcc271094c70ba.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5669349639eae4f58b4fecca26fcc271094c70ba.c1.e1" e2="5669349639eae4f58b4fecca26fcc271094c70ba.c1.e2" id="5669349639eae4f58b4fecca26fcc271094c70ba.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
