<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="63f776d8ae5084cc5a3aa5e09aa55f1a302b1b1f">
  <chunk id="63f776d8ae5084cc5a3aa5e09aa55f1a302b1b1f.c0" text="Identification and Survey of a Novel Avian Coronavirus in Ducks"/>
  <chunk id="63f776d8ae5084cc5a3aa5e09aa55f1a302b1b1f.c1" text="The rapid discovery of novel viruses using next generation sequencing (NGS) technologies including DNA-Seq and RNA-Seq, has greatly expanded our understanding of viral diversity in recent years. The timely identification of novel viruses using NGS technologies is also important for us to control emerging infectious diseases caused by novel viruses. In this study, we identified a novel duck coronavirus (CoV), distinct with chicken infectious bronchitis virus (IBV), using RNA-Seq. The novel duck-specific CoV was a potential novel species within the genus Gammacoronavirus, as indicated by sequences of three regions in the viral 1b gene. We also performed a survey of CoVs in domestic fowls in China using reverse-transcription polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR), targeting the viral nucleocapsid (N) gene. A total of 102 CoV positives were identified through the survey. Phylogenetic analysis of the viral N sequences suggested that CoVs in domestic fowls have diverged into several region-specific or host-specific clades or subclades in the world, and IBVs can infect ducks, geese and pigeons, although they mainly circulate in chickens. Moreover, this study provided novel data supporting the notion that some hostspecific CoVs other than IBVs circulate in ducks, geese and pigeons, and indicated that the novel duck-specific CoV identified through RNA-Seq in this study is genetically closer to some CoVs circulating in wild water fowls. Taken together, this study shed new insight into the diversity, distribution, evolution and control of avian CoVs.">
    <entity charOffset="1434-1439" id="63f776d8ae5084cc5a3aa5e09aa55f1a302b1b1f.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_15377" text="water" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
