<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="65c8138a4905491ab3bcd6aa58320408abecc9e7">
  <chunk id="65c8138a4905491ab3bcd6aa58320408abecc9e7.c0" text="Identification of Novel Rosavirus Species That Infects Diverse Rodent Species and Causes Multisystemic Dissemination in Mouse Model Identification of Novel Rosavirus Species That Infects Diverse Rodent Species and Causes Multisystemic Dissemination in Mouse Model"/>
  <chunk id="65c8138a4905491ab3bcd6aa58320408abecc9e7.c1" text="While novel picornaviruses are being discovered in rodents, their host range and pathogenicity are largely unknown. We identified two novel picornaviruses, rosavirus B from the street rat, Norway rat, and rosavirus C from five different wild rat species (chestnut spiny rat, greater bandicoot rat, Indochinese forest rat, roof rat and Coxing's white-bellied rat) in China. Analysis of 13 complete genome sequences showed that &quot;Rosavirus B&quot; and &quot;Rosavirus C&quot; represent two potentially novel picornavirus species infecting different rodents. Though being most closely related to rosavirus A, rosavirus B and C possessed distinct protease cleavage sites and variations in Yn-Xm-AUG sequence in 5'UTR and myristylation site in VP4. Anti-rosavirus B VP1 antibodies were detected in Norway rats, whereas anti-rosavirus C VP1 and neutralizing antibodies were detected in Indochinese forest rats and Coxing's white-bellied rats. While the highest prevalence was observed in Coxing's white-bellied rats by RT-PCR, the detection of rosavirus C from different rat species suggests potential interspecies transmission. Rosavirus C isolated from 3T3 cells causes multisystemic diseases in a mouse model, with high viral loads and positive viral antigen expression in organs of infected mice after oral or intracerebral inoculation. Histological examination revealed alveolar fluid exudation, interstitial infiltration, alveolar fluid exudate and wall thickening in lungs, and hepatocyte degeneration and lymphocytic/monocytic inflammatory infiltrates with giant cell formation in liver sections of sacrificed mice. Since rosavirus A2 has been detected in fecal samples of children, further studies should elucidate the pathogenicity and emergence potential of different rosaviruses.">
    <entity charOffset="1232-1239" id="65c8138a4905491ab3bcd6aa58320408abecc9e7.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_59132" text="antigen" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="65c8138a4905491ab3bcd6aa58320408abecc9e7.c2" text="We identified two novel picornaviruses, rosavirus B and C, infecting street and wild rats respectively in China. While rosavirus B was detected from Norway rats, rosavirus C was detected from five different wild rat species (chestnut spiny rat, greater bandicoot rat, Indochinese forest rat, roof rat and Coxing's white-bellied rat) by RT-PCR. Anti-rosavirus B antibodies were detected in Norway rats, whereas anti-rosavirus C antibodies were detected in Indochinese forest rats and Coxing's white-bellied rats, supporting potential interspecies transmission of rosavirus C. Genome analysis supported the classification of rosavirus B and C as two novel picornavirus species, with genome features distinct from rosavirus A. Rosavirus C isolated from 3T3 cells causes multisystemic diseases in a mouse model, with viruses and pathologies detected in various organs of infected mice after oral or intracerebral inoculation. Our results extend our knowledge on the host range and pathogenicity of rodent picornaviruses."/>
  <chunk id="65c8138a4905491ab3bcd6aa58320408abecc9e7.c3" text="Novel Rosavirus in Rodents"/>
  <chunk id="65c8138a4905491ab3bcd6aa58320408abecc9e7.c4" text="A total of 2450 respiratory and alimentary samples from 1232 rodents of six different species were obtained (Table 1) . Initial screening by RT-PCR for a 159-bp fragment of 3D pol gene of picornaviruses was positive in 18 respiratory and 24 alimentary samples from 37 rodents of six different species. The sequences from these positive samples had &lt;84% aa identities to the corresponding segments of 3D pol genes of known picornaviruses, suggesting the presence of potential novel picornaviruses. Subsequent RT-PCR using specific primers targeting these potential novel picornaviruses on the 2450 samples was positive in 62 respiratory and 70 alimentary samples from 92 rodents. The sequences from these 132 samples had &lt;86% aa identities to the corresponding segments of 3D pol genes of known picornaviruses, being most closely related to Rosavirus A. Moreover, these sequences fell into two distinct clusters, one formed by sequences from wild rodents of five different species from Hong Kong (chestnut spiny rat, greater bandicoot rat, Indochinese forest rats and roof rat) and Hunan and Guangxi (Coxing's white-bellied rat), and the other formed by sequences from street rodents from Hong Kong (Norway rat) ( Table 1 and Fig 1) . This suggested the presence of two potentially novel picornavirus species, &quot;Rosavirus B&quot; and &quot;Rosavirus C. &quot; Viral sequences belonging to &quot;Rosavirus B&quot; were only detected from the street rodent species, Norway rat (Rattus norvegicus), whereas sequences belonging to &quot;Rosavirus C&quot; were detected from five different wild rodent species, greater bandicoot rat (Bandicota indica), chestnut spiny rat (Niviventer fulvescens), roof rat (Rattus rattus) and Indochinese forest rat (Rattus andamanensis) from Hong Kong, and Coxing's white-bellied rat (Niviventer coxingi) from Hunan and Guangxi. Among the five wild rodent species, rosavirus C showed the highest detection rate in Coxing's white-bellied rats. qRT-PCR showed that the viral load of rosavirus B and C in the positive samples ranged from 1.7 ×10 4 to 1.6×10 8 copies/ml."/>
  <chunk id="65c8138a4905491ab3bcd6aa58320408abecc9e7.c5" text="Roof rat"/>
</document>
