<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0">
  <chunk id="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c0" text="Microbial Cell Factories Live bacterial vaccines -a review and identification of potential hazards"/>
  <chunk id="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c1" text="The use of live bacteria to induce an immune response to itself or to a carried vaccine component is an attractive vaccine strategy. Advantages of live bacterial vaccines include their mimicry of a natural infection, intrinsic adjuvant properties and their possibility to be administered orally. Derivatives of pathogenic and non-pathogenic food related bacteria are currently being evaluated as live vaccines. However, pathogenic bacteria demands for attenuation to weaken its virulence. The use of bacteria as vaccine delivery vehicles implies construction of recombinant strains that contain the gene cassette encoding the antigen. With the increased knowledge of mucosal immunity and the availability of genetic tools for heterologous gene expression the concept of live vaccine vehicles gains renewed interest. However, administration of live bacterial vaccines poses some risks. In addition, vaccination using recombinant bacteria results in the release of live recombinant organisms into nature. This places these vaccines in the debate on application of genetically modified organisms. In this review we give an overview of live bacterial vaccines on the market and describe the development of new live vaccines with a focus on attenuated bacteria and food-related lactic acid bacteria. Furthermore, we outline the safety concerns and identify the hazards associated with live bacterial vaccines and try to give some suggestions of what to consider during their development.">
    <entity charOffset="227-235" id="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_60809" text="adjuvant" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="341-345" id="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33290" text="food" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1273-1284" id="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_28358" text="lactic acid" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1280-1284" id="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_37527" text="acid" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c1.e0" e2="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c1.e1" id="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c1.e0" e2="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c1.e2" id="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c1.e0" e2="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c1.e3" id="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c1.e1" e2="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c1.e2" id="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c1.e1" e2="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c1.e3" id="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c1.e2" e2="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c1.e3" id="67727dc7bb076ef6ddeb55c754af98e672ee60e0.c1.p5" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
