<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="6b1684f4f6c7966725627602b6771c2f1224df89">
  <chunk id="6b1684f4f6c7966725627602b6771c2f1224df89.c0" text="Journal of perinatology : official journal of the California Perinatal Association"/>
  <chunk id="6b1684f4f6c7966725627602b6771c2f1224df89.c1" text="Objectives: To analyze trends in mortalities and causes of death among under-5 children in Beijing, China between 1992 and 2015, and to forecast U5MRs in the period of 2016-2020."/>
  <chunk id="6b1684f4f6c7966725627602b6771c2f1224df89.c2" text="Methods: This is an entire population-based epidemiological study. Data was collected based on &quot;Children's Death Reporting Card&quot; through Beijing Under-5 mortality rate Surveillance Network. Trends in mortality rates and leading causes of death were analyzed using statistical description and chi-square test with SPSS 19.0. An ARIMA model was fitted to forecast the U5MRs between 2016 and 2020 with EViews 8.0."/>
  <chunk id="6b1684f4f6c7966725627602b6771c2f1224df89.c3" text=": During 1992-2015, a total of 1,881,952 livebirths and 12,541 deaths were under surveillance. Mortality rates in neonates, infants and under-5 children had overall decreasing trends (P&lt;0.01) from 1992 to 2015, decreasing by 84.06%, 80.04% and 80.17%. However, U5MR increased 7.20% from 2013 to 2015. Birth asphyxia, congenital heart disease, prematurity/low birth weight and other congenital abnormalities were in the top 5 causes of death during 24 years. The greatest and fastest rate reduction was pneumonia which reduced 92.26% with AARR of 10.53%. However, distribution of death causes was different in children of different ages. Accidental asphyxia and septicemia were in the top 5 of death in 28 days-1 years old children, whereas for children 1-4 years old was accidental death. U5MRs in Beijing are projected to be 2.88‰, 2.87‰, 2.90‰, 2.97‰ and 3.09‰ in the period of 2016-2020 through the predictive model. Conclusion: Beijing has achieved great progress in reducing U5MRs from 1992 to 2015. However, U5MRs may show a slightly upward trend from 2016 to 2020 as influenced by the &quot;Selective Two-child Policy&quot;. The future points of child health care are the management of birth asphyxia, congenital heart disease, prematurity/low birth weight and other congenital abnormalities. Importantly, specific prevention measures should be implemented for children in different age groups. 36(1):41-6. 18. Liu X, Liu G, Wang P, et al. Prevalence of congenital heart disease and its related risk indicators among 90,796 Chinese infants aged less than 6 months in Tianjin. International journal of epidemiology. 2015;44(3):884-93. 19. Engle WA, Kominiarek MA. Late preterm infants, early term infants, and timing of elective deliveries. Clinics in perinatology. 2008;35(2):325-41. 20. Lee AC, Mullany LC, Tielsch JM, et al. Risk factors for neonatal mortality due to birth asphyxia in southern Nepal: a prospective, community-based cohort study. Pediatrics. 2008;121(5):e1381-90. 21. Persson M, Johansson S, Villamor E, et al. Maternal overweight and obesity and risks of severe birth-asphyxia-related complications in term infants: a population-based cohort study in Sweden. PLoS medicine.">
    <entity charOffset="1932-1938" id="6b1684f4f6c7966725627602b6771c2f1224df89.c3.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_34935" text="cohort" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="2152-2158" id="6b1684f4f6c7966725627602b6771c2f1224df89.c3.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_34935" text="cohort" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
