<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="6bcf5a5f877be9a08113db6aec4a409f8d111895">
  <chunk id="6bcf5a5f877be9a08113db6aec4a409f8d111895.c0" text="Respiratory failure presenting in H1N1 influenza with Legionnaires disease: two case reports"/>
  <chunk id="6bcf5a5f877be9a08113db6aec4a409f8d111895.c1" text="Introduction: Media sensationalism on the H1N1 outbreak may have influenced decisional processes and clinical diagnosis. Case Presentation: We report two cases of patients who presented in 2009 with coexisting H1N1 virus and Legionella infections: a 69-year-old Caucasian man and a 71-year-old Caucasian woman. In our cases all the signs and symptoms, including vomiting, progressive respiratory disease leading to respiratory failure, refractory hypoxemia, leukopenia, lymphopenia, thrombocytopenia, and elevated levels of creatine kinase and hepatic aminotransferases, were consistent with critical illness due to 2009 H1N1 virus infection. Other infectious disorders may mimic H1N1 viral infection especially Legionnaires' disease. Because the swine flu H1N1 pandemic occurred in Autumn in Italy, Legionnaires disease was to be highly suspected since the peak incidence usually occurs in early fall. We do think that our immediate suspicion of Legionella infection based on clinical history and X-ray abnormalities was fundamental for a successful resolution. Conclusion: Our two case reports suggest that patients with H1N1 should be screened for Legionella, which is not currently common practice. This is particularly important since the signs and symptoms of both infections are similar.">
    <entity charOffset="272-275" id="6bcf5a5f877be9a08113db6aec4a409f8d111895.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_37684" text="man" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="524-532" id="6bcf5a5f877be9a08113db6aec4a409f8d111895.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16919" text="creatine" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="783-789" id="6bcf5a5f877be9a08113db6aec4a409f8d111895.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_145500" text="Autumn" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="6bcf5a5f877be9a08113db6aec4a409f8d111895.c1.e0" e2="6bcf5a5f877be9a08113db6aec4a409f8d111895.c1.e1" id="6bcf5a5f877be9a08113db6aec4a409f8d111895.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="6bcf5a5f877be9a08113db6aec4a409f8d111895.c1.e0" e2="6bcf5a5f877be9a08113db6aec4a409f8d111895.c1.e2" id="6bcf5a5f877be9a08113db6aec4a409f8d111895.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="6bcf5a5f877be9a08113db6aec4a409f8d111895.c1.e1" e2="6bcf5a5f877be9a08113db6aec4a409f8d111895.c1.e2" id="6bcf5a5f877be9a08113db6aec4a409f8d111895.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
