<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="7969e6c3564904ffb7928747d52f3edcc7f97fff">
  <chunk id="7969e6c3564904ffb7928747d52f3edcc7f97fff.c0" text="Polymerase cross-linking spiral reaction (PCLSR) for detection of African swine fever virus (ASFV) in pigs and wild boars"/>
  <chunk id="7969e6c3564904ffb7928747d52f3edcc7f97fff.c1" text="The study reports the development of a polymerase cross-linking spiral reaction (PCLSR) for the detection of African swine fever virus (ASFV) DNA in blood collected from infected pigs and wild boars. The method uses 3 specifically designed primers. Two outer-spiral primers comprising of 3′ sequences complementary to ASFV p72 gene sequence and 5′end sequences complementary to exogenous gene of black widow alpha-latrotoxin as well as additional ASFV specific cross-linking primer. The method is specific exclusively to ASFV DNA without cross-reactions with cDNA of classical swine fever virus (CSFV), porcine reproductive respiratory syndrome (PRRSV) or porcine epidemic diarrhea virus (PEDV). The sensitivity of this technique reached 7.2 × 10 2 copies per μl −1 of plasmid containing p72 gene. The PCLSR was conducted at 65 °C creating cross-linked complex structures. The results of PCLSR were visualized using SYBR Green I dye, gel electrophoresis while the reaction progress was traced using real-time PCR system that resulted in registration of fluorescent curves and melting peaks at 85.3 °C. The developed PCLSR was examined using blood or tissue samples collected from selected 17 ASF cases from infected wild boars and 3 outbreaks in pigs. Further tests have been also conducted using 55 tissue samples from 23 outbreaks and 22 cases. These results showed that PCLSR might be further used for preliminary and cost-effective detection and surveillance of ASFV.">
    <entity charOffset="142-145" id="7969e6c3564904ffb7928747d52f3edcc7f97fff.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="526-529" id="7969e6c3564904ffb7928747d52f3edcc7f97fff.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="916-928" id="7969e6c3564904ffb7928747d52f3edcc7f97fff.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_51461" text="SYBR Green I" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="7969e6c3564904ffb7928747d52f3edcc7f97fff.c1.e0" e2="7969e6c3564904ffb7928747d52f3edcc7f97fff.c1.e2" id="7969e6c3564904ffb7928747d52f3edcc7f97fff.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="7969e6c3564904ffb7928747d52f3edcc7f97fff.c1.e1" e2="7969e6c3564904ffb7928747d52f3edcc7f97fff.c1.e2" id="7969e6c3564904ffb7928747d52f3edcc7f97fff.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
