<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="7d38e11db887bf824a89621f65d384ef45e14955">
  <chunk id="7d38e11db887bf824a89621f65d384ef45e14955.c0" text="Development and Evaluation of a SYBR Green-Based Real Time RT-PCR Assay for Detection of the Emerging Avian Influenza A (H7N9) Virus"/>
  <chunk id="7d38e11db887bf824a89621f65d384ef45e14955.c1" text="Most recently a novel avian-origin influenza A (H7N9) virus emerged in China and has been associated with lots of human infection and fatal cases. Genetic analysis of the viral genome revealed that this reassortant virus might be better adapted to humans than other avian influenza viruses. Molecular diagnostic methods are thus urgently needed in public health laboratories. In this study, a SYBR green-based one-step real time reverse transcription-PCR (RT-PCR) was developed to detect the novel H7N9 virus. The primer pairs on the basis of the hemagglutinin and neuraminidase gene sequences of H7N9 viruses amplified subtype-specific fragments with Tm values of 80.7760.06uC for H7 and 81.2060.17uC for N9 respectively. The standard curves showed a dynamic linear range across 6 log units of RNA copy number (10 6 to 10 1 copies/ ml) with a detection limit of 10 copies per reaction for both H7 and N9 assays by using serial ten-fold diluted in-vitro transcribed viral RNA. In addition, no cross-reactivity was observed with seasonal H1N1, H1N1 pdm09, H3N2, H5N1 and H9N2 viruses as well as other human respiratory viruses. When the assay was further evaluated in H7N9 virus infected clinical samples, positive amplification signals were obtained in all of the specimens with the accordance between H7 and N9 assays. Therefore, the established SYBR green-based real time RT-PCR assay could provide a rapid, sensitive, specific and reliable alternative approach with lower costs for high throughput screening of suspected samples from humans, animals and environments in first line public health laboratories. Citation: Zhu Z, Fan H, Qi X, Qi Y, Shi Z, et al. (2013) Development and Evaluation of a SYBR Green-Based Real Time RT-PCR Assay for Detection of the Emerging Avian Influenza A (H7N9) Virus. PLoS ONE 8(11): e80028. (MZ) PLOS ONE | www.plosone.org">
    <entity charOffset="795-798" id="7d38e11db887bf824a89621f65d384ef45e14955.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="972-975" id="7d38e11db887bf824a89621f65d384ef45e14955.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1808-1811" id="7d38e11db887bf824a89621f65d384ef45e14955.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_58972" text="ONE" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1837-1840" id="7d38e11db887bf824a89621f65d384ef45e14955.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_58972" text="ONE" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="7d38e11db887bf824a89621f65d384ef45e14955.c1.e0" e2="7d38e11db887bf824a89621f65d384ef45e14955.c1.e2" id="7d38e11db887bf824a89621f65d384ef45e14955.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="7d38e11db887bf824a89621f65d384ef45e14955.c1.e0" e2="7d38e11db887bf824a89621f65d384ef45e14955.c1.e3" id="7d38e11db887bf824a89621f65d384ef45e14955.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="7d38e11db887bf824a89621f65d384ef45e14955.c1.e1" e2="7d38e11db887bf824a89621f65d384ef45e14955.c1.e2" id="7d38e11db887bf824a89621f65d384ef45e14955.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="7d38e11db887bf824a89621f65d384ef45e14955.c1.e1" e2="7d38e11db887bf824a89621f65d384ef45e14955.c1.e3" id="7d38e11db887bf824a89621f65d384ef45e14955.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
