<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="7e0925a800d4d09380ac44584b5be257d83531d3">
  <chunk id="7e0925a800d4d09380ac44584b5be257d83531d3.c0" text="Molecular Diagnosis of Pneumonia Using Multiplex Real-Time PCR Assay RespiFinder ® SMART 22 FAST in a Group of Moroccan Infants"/>
  <chunk id="7e0925a800d4d09380ac44584b5be257d83531d3.c1" text="Background. In Morocco, pediatric pneumonia remains a serious public health problem, as it constitutes the first cause of mortality due to infectious diseases. e etiological diagnosis of acute respiratory tract infections is difficult. erefore, it is necessary to use Multiplex real-time polymerase chain reaction assay tests in a routine setting for exact and fast identification. Objectives. In this paper, we present the clinical results of pediatric pneumonia and describe their etiology by using molecular diagnosis. Study design: Tracheal secretion was collected from infants presenting respiratory distress isolated or associated with systemic signs, attending the unit of Neonatology between December 1, 2016, and Mai 31, 2018. Samples were tested with the multiplex RespiFinder ® SMART 22 FAST which potentially detects 18 viruses and 4 bacteria. Results. Of the 86 infants considered in this study (mean age 31 ± 19 days) suspected of acute respiratory tract infections, 71 (83%) were positive for one or multiple viruses or/and bacteria. e majority of acute respiratory tract infections had a viral origin (95%): respiratory syncytial viruses (A and B) (49%), rhinovirus (21%), coronaviruses 229E (11%), humain metapneumovirus (5%), influenza A (3%), influenza H1N1 (1%), adenovirus (2%), and parainfluenza virus type 4 (2%). Among our patients, 6% had Mycoplasma pneumoniae. Coinfections were not associated with severe respiratory symptoms. Conclusion. e clinical spectrum of respiratory infections is complex and often nonspecific. us, the early and fast detection of related causative agents is crucial. e use of multiplex real time polymerase chain reaction may help choose an accurate treatment, reduce the overall use of unnecessary antibiotics, preserve intestinal flora, and decrease nosocomial infection by reducing the length of hospitalization."/>
</document>
