<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef">
  <chunk id="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c0" text="Protection against Virulent Infectious Bronchitis Virus Challenge Conferred by a Recombinant Baculovirus Co-Expressing S1 and N Proteins">
    <entity charOffset="128-136" id="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="Proteins" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c1" text="Avian infectious bronchitis virus (IBV) is the causative agent of infectious bronchitis, which results in considerable economic losses. It is imperative to develop safe and efficient candidate vaccines to control IBV infection. In the current study, recombinant baculoviruses co-expressing the S1 and N proteins and mono-expressing S1 or N proteins of the GX-YL5 strain of IBV were constructed and prepared into subunit vaccines rHBM-S1-N, rHBM-S1 and rHBM-N. The levels of immune protection of these subunit vaccines were evaluated by inoculating specific pathogen-free (SPF) chickens at 14 days of age, giving them a booster with the same dose 14 days later and challenging them with a virulent GX-YL5 strain of IBV 14 days post-booster (dpb). The commercial vaccine strain H120 was used as a control. The IBV-specific antibody levels, as well as the percentages of CD4+ and CD8+ T lymphocytes, were detected within 28 days post-vaccination (dpv). The morbidity, mortality and re-isolation of the virus from the tracheas and kidneys of challenged birds were evaluated at five days post-challenge (dpc). The results showed that the IBV-specific antibody levels and the percentages of CD4+ and CD8+ T lymphocytes were higher in the rHBM-S1-N vaccinated birds compared to birds vaccinated with the rHBM-S1 and rHBM-N vaccines. At 5 dpc, the mortality, morbidity and virus re-isolation rate of the birds vaccinated with the rHBM-S1-N vaccine were slightly higher than those vaccinated with the H120 control vaccine but were lower than those vaccinated with the rHBM-S1 and rHBM-N vaccines. The present study demonstrated that the protection of the recombinant baculovirus co-expressing S1 and N proteins was better than that of recombinant baculoviruses mono-expressing the S1 or N protein. Thus, the recombinant baculovirus co-expressing S1 and N proteins could serve as a potential IBV vaccine and this demonstrates that the bivalent subunit vaccine including the S1 and N proteins might be a strategy for the development of an IBV subunit vaccine.">
    <entity charOffset="303-311" id="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="340-348" id="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="572-575" id="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_88542" text="SPF" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1693-1701" id="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1846-1854" id="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1973-1981" id="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c1.e0" e2="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c1.e2" id="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c1.e1" e2="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c1.e2" id="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c1.e2" e2="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c1.e3" id="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c1.e2" e2="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c1.e4" id="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c1.e2" e2="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c1.e5" id="7f923809d6875b38e21636801b4a50f8fbac6aef.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
