<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="85bab4f8869727adbe47f5ddc6e18af508dc57a0">
  <chunk id="85bab4f8869727adbe47f5ddc6e18af508dc57a0.c0" text="eIF2α-CHOP-BCl-2/JNK and IRE1α-XBP1/JNK signaling promote apoptosis and inflammation and support the proliferation of Newcastle disease virus"/>
  <chunk id="85bab4f8869727adbe47f5ddc6e18af508dc57a0.c1" text="Newcastle disease virus (NDV) causes severe infectious disease in poultry and selectively kills tumor cells, by inducing apoptosis and cytokines secretion. In this report, we study the mechanisms underlying NDV-induced apoptosis by investigating the unfolded protein response (UPR). We found that NDV infection activated all three branches of the UPR signaling (PERK-eIF2α, ATF6, and IRE1α) and triggered apoptosis, in avian cells (DF-1 and CEF) and in various human cancer cell types (HeLa, Cal27, HN13, A549, H1299, Huh7, and HepG2). Interestingly, the suppression of either apoptosis or UPR led to impaired NDV proliferation. Meanwhile, the inhibition of UPR by 4-PBA protected cells from NDV-induced apoptosis. Further study revealed that activation of PERK-eIF2α induced the expression of transcription factor CHOP, which subsequently promoted apoptosis by downregulating BCL-2/MCL-1, promoting JNK signaling and suppressing AKT signaling. In parallel, IRE1α mediated the splicing of XBP1 mRNA and resulted in the translation and nuclear translocation of XBP1s, thereby promoting the transcription of ER chaperones and components of ERassociated degradation (ERAD). Furthermore, IRE1α promoted apoptosis and cytokines secretion via the activation of JNK signaling. Knock down and overexpression studies showed that CHOP, IRE1α, XBP1, and JNK supported efficient virus proliferation. Our study demonstrates that the induction of eIF2α-CHOP-BCL-2/JNK and IRE1α-XBP1/JNK signaling cascades promote apoptosis and cytokines secretion, and these signaling cascades support NDV proliferation.">
    <entity charOffset="259-266" id="85bab4f8869727adbe47f5ddc6e18af508dc57a0.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="994-998" id="85bab4f8869727adbe47f5ddc6e18af508dc57a0.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33699" text="mRNA" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="85bab4f8869727adbe47f5ddc6e18af508dc57a0.c1.e0" e2="85bab4f8869727adbe47f5ddc6e18af508dc57a0.c1.e1" id="85bab4f8869727adbe47f5ddc6e18af508dc57a0.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
