<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="88c599b1de8a17cd519f9f72aaaea28392f697f0">
  <chunk id="88c599b1de8a17cd519f9f72aaaea28392f697f0.c0" text="a section of the journal Frontiers in Microbiology Citation: The Capsid Protein VP1 of Coxsackievirus B Induces Cell Cycle Arrest by Up-Regulating Heat Shock Protein 70">
    <entity charOffset="72-79" id="88c599b1de8a17cd519f9f72aaaea28392f697f0.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="Protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="158-165" id="88c599b1de8a17cd519f9f72aaaea28392f697f0.c0.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="Protein" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="88c599b1de8a17cd519f9f72aaaea28392f697f0.c1" text="Manipulating cell cycle is one of the common strategies used by viruses to generate favorable cellular environment to facilitate viral replication. Coxsackievirus B (CVB) is one of the major viral pathogens of human myocarditis and cardiomyopathy. Because of its small genome, CVB depends on cellular machineries for productive replication. However, how the structural and non-structural components of CVB would manipulate cell cycle is not clearly understood. In this study, we demonstrated that the capsid protein VP1 of CVB type 3 (CVB3) induced cell cycle arrest at G1 phase. G1 arrest was the result of the decrease level of cyclin E and the accumulation of p27 Kip1 . Study on the gene expression profile of the cells expressing VP1 showed that the expression of both heat shock protein 70-1 (Hsp70-1) and Hsp70-2 was significantly up-regulated. Knockdown of Hsp70 resulted in the increased level of cyclin E and the reduction of p27 Kip1 . We further demonstrated that the phosphorylation of the heat shock factor 1, which directly promotes the expression of Hsp70, was also increased in the cell expressing VP1. Moreover, we show that CVB3 infection also induced G1 arrest, likely due to dysregulating Hsp70, cyclin E, and p27, while knockdown of Hsp70 dramatically inhibited viral replication. Cell cycle arrest at G1 phase facilitated CVB3 infection, since viral replication in the cells synchronized at G1 phase dramatically increased. Taken together, this study demonstrates that the VP1 of CVB3 induces cell cycle arrest at G1 phase through up-regulating Hsp70. Our findings suggest that the capsid protein VP1 of CVB is capable of manipulating cellular activities during viral infection.">
    <entity charOffset="508-515" id="88c599b1de8a17cd519f9f72aaaea28392f697f0.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="785-792" id="88c599b1de8a17cd519f9f72aaaea28392f697f0.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1612-1619" id="88c599b1de8a17cd519f9f72aaaea28392f697f0.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
