<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="8e6ef0f551beb549a3e0d523f5b1472cd11110f4">
  <chunk id="8e6ef0f551beb549a3e0d523f5b1472cd11110f4.c0" text="A novel group of avian astroviruses from Neotropical passerine birds broaden the diversity and host range of Astroviridae"/>
  <chunk id="8e6ef0f551beb549a3e0d523f5b1472cd11110f4.c1" text="Metagenomics is helping to expand the known diversity of viruses, especially of those with poorly studied hosts in remote areas. the Neotropical region harbors a considerable diversity of avian species that may play a role as both host and short-distance vectors of unknown viruses. Viral metagenomics of cloacal swabs from 50 Neotropical birds collected in French Guiana revealed the presence of four complete astrovirus genomes. they constitute an early diverging novel monophyletic clade within the Avastrovirus phylogeny, representing a putative new astrovirus species (provisionally designated as Avastrovirus 5) according to the International Committee on Taxonomy of Viruses (ICTV) classification criteria. their genomic organization shares some characteristics with Avastrovirus but also with Mamastrovirus. The pan-astrovirus RT-PCR analysis of the cloacal samples of 406 wild Neotropical birds showed a community-level prevalence of 4.9% (5.1% in passerines, the highest described so far in this order of birds). By screening birds of a remote region, we expanded the known host range of astroviruses to the avian families Cardinalidae, Conopophagidae, Furnariidae, thamnophilidae, Turdidae and Tyrannidae. Our results provide important first insights into the unexplored viral communities, the ecology, epidemiology and features of host-pathogen interactions that shape the evolution of avastroviruses in a remote Neotropical rainforest.">
    <entity charOffset="218-222" id="8e6ef0f551beb549a3e0d523f5b1472cd11110f4.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="8e6ef0f551beb549a3e0d523f5b1472cd11110f4.c2" text="The last decades have witnessed a broadening of the global diversity of viruses thanks to rapidly evolving random amplification sequencing technology. Next Generation Sequencing (NGS) has revolutionized our knowledge by not only uncovering the diversity of viruses at an unprecedented rate, but also by allowing to gain insight into their ecology and distribution, helping to disentangle the network that connects viruses with their hosts and the geographical scenario in which such interactions take place 1 . However, deciphering the global virome and its structure becomes challenging not just because of the technical difficulties associated with the screening of diverse viruses, but because their many hosts are often understudied, particularly those from remote areas. The Neotropical region is one such example; being among the most biodiverse realms on Earth, Neotropical rainforests are candidates to host and conserve relevant parts of the virosphere diversity 2 . However, the knowledge of Neotropical viral diversity and their hosts is in its infancy. Given that zoonotic viruses are considered the most probable causative agents of emerging diseases 3 and that mammal and avian species are their main hosts 4,5 , the study of the wildlife viral diversity and their ecological context in these remote areas will provide important information for public and animal health to prevent potential new emerging viral epidemics 2,6 . For example, the great diversity of the Neotropical fauna harbors the risk of emergence of new infections in domestic animals and"/>
</document>
