<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd">
  <chunk id="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c0" text="Interactions of Respiratory Viruses and the Nasal Microbiota during the First Year of Life in Healthy Infants"/>
  <chunk id="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c1" text="Traditional culture techniques have shown that increased bacterial colonization is associated with viral colonization; however, the influence of viral colonization on the whole microbiota composition is less clear. We thus aimed to understand the interaction of viral infections and the nasal microbiota in early life to appraise their roles in disease development. Thirty-two healthy, unselected infants were included in this prospective longitudinal cohort study within the first year of life. Biweekly nasal swabs (n ϭ 559) were taken, and the microbiota was analyzed by 16S rRNA pyrosequencing, and 10 different viruses and 2 atypical bacteria were characterized by real-time PCR (combination of seven duplex samples). In contrast to asymptomatic human rhinovirus (HRV) colonization, symptomatic HRV infections were associated with lower alpha diversity (Shannon diversity index [SDI]), higher bacterial density (PCR concentration), and a difference in beta diversities (Jaccard and Bray-Curtis index) of the microbiota. In addition, infants with more frequent HRV infections had a lower SDI at the end of the study period. Overall, changes in the microbiota associated with symptomatic HRV infections were characterized by a loss of microbial diversity. The interaction between HRV infections and the nasal microbiota in early life might be of importance for later disease development and indicate a potential approach for future interventions.">
    <entity charOffset="452-458" id="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_34935" text="cohort" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="578-582" id="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_18111" text="rRNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="842-847" id="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_30216" text="alpha" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="957-961" id="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_10545" text="beta" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c1.e0" e2="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c1.e1" id="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c1.e0" e2="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c1.e2" id="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c1.e0" e2="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c1.e3" id="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c1.e1" e2="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c1.e2" id="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c1.e1" e2="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c1.e3" id="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c1.e2" e2="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c1.e3" id="94ccf97f5df377bf432fa3a831e38f11985965bd.c1.p5" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
