<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="96f74d611693ebad68d8cd10862e9a972bd3bdc5">
  <chunk id="96f74d611693ebad68d8cd10862e9a972bd3bdc5.c0" text="ARTICLE Evaluation of candidate vaccine approaches for MERS-CoV"/>
  <chunk id="96f74d611693ebad68d8cd10862e9a972bd3bdc5.c1" text="The emergence of Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus (MERS-CoV) as a cause of severe respiratory disease highlights the need for effective approaches to CoV vaccine development. Efforts focused solely on the receptor-binding domain (RBD) of the viral Spike (S) glycoprotein may not optimize neutralizing antibody (NAb) responses. Here we show that immunogens based on full-length S DNA and S1 subunit protein elicit robust serumneutralizing activity against several MERS-CoV strains in mice and non-human primates. Serological analysis and isolation of murine monoclonal antibodies revealed that immunization elicits NAbs to RBD and, non-RBD portions of S1 and S2 subunit. Multiple neutralization mechanisms were demonstrated by solving the atomic structure of a NAb-RBD complex, through sequencing of neutralization escape viruses and by constructing MERS-CoV S variants for serological assays. Immunization of rhesus macaques confers protection against MERS-CoV-induced radiographic pneumonia, as assessed using computerized tomography, supporting this strategy as a promising approach for MERS-CoV vaccine development.">
    <entity charOffset="270-282" id="96f74d611693ebad68d8cd10862e9a972bd3bdc5.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_17089" text="glycoprotein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="391-394" id="96f74d611693ebad68d8cd10862e9a972bd3bdc5.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="410-417" id="96f74d611693ebad68d8cd10862e9a972bd3bdc5.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="96f74d611693ebad68d8cd10862e9a972bd3bdc5.c1.e0" e2="96f74d611693ebad68d8cd10862e9a972bd3bdc5.c1.e1" id="96f74d611693ebad68d8cd10862e9a972bd3bdc5.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="96f74d611693ebad68d8cd10862e9a972bd3bdc5.c1.e0" e2="96f74d611693ebad68d8cd10862e9a972bd3bdc5.c1.e2" id="96f74d611693ebad68d8cd10862e9a972bd3bdc5.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="96f74d611693ebad68d8cd10862e9a972bd3bdc5.c1.e1" e2="96f74d611693ebad68d8cd10862e9a972bd3bdc5.c1.e2" id="96f74d611693ebad68d8cd10862e9a972bd3bdc5.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
