<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="98e6190d06a8d8774c690be39634a1d64a926dc3">
  <chunk id="98e6190d06a8d8774c690be39634a1d64a926dc3.c0" text="Genetic Diversity and Differentiation at Structurally Varying MHC Haplotypes and Microsatellites in Bottlenecked Populations of Endangered Crested Ibis"/>
  <chunk id="98e6190d06a8d8774c690be39634a1d64a926dc3.c1" text="Investigating adaptive potential and understanding the relative roles of selection and genetic drift in populations of endangered species are essential in conservation. Major histocompatibility complex (MHC) genes characterized by spectacular polymorphism and fitness association have become valuable adaptive markers. Herein we investigate the variation of all MHC class I and II genes across seven populations of an endangered bird, the crested ibis, of which all current individuals are offspring of only two pairs. We inferred seven multilocus haplotypes from linked alleles in the Core Region and revealed structural variation of the class II region that probably evolved through unequal crossing over. Based on the low polymorphism, structural variation, strong linkage, and extensive shared alleles, we applied the MHC haplotypes in population analysis. The genetic variation and population structure at MHC haplotypes are generally concordant with those expected from microsatellites, underlining the predominant role of genetic drift in shaping MHC variation in the bottlenecked populations. Nonetheless, some populations showed elevated differentiation at MHC, probably due to limited gene flow. The seven populations were significantly differentiated into three groups and some groups exhibited genetic monomorphism, which can be attributed to founder effects. We therefore propose various strategies for future conservation and management.">
    <entity charOffset="1021-1025" id="98e6190d06a8d8774c690be39634a1d64a926dc3.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="98e6190d06a8d8774c690be39634a1d64a926dc3.c2" text="as genetic drift [7] [8] [9] [10] . There are three nonexclusive mechanisms for PMS: (1) heterozygotes may be favored because they can recognize a greater range of antigens than homozygotes (heterozygote advantage); (2) rare alleles may have a selective advantage as few pathogens are adapted to them (frequency-dependent selection); (3) spatial/temporal heterogeneity in the pathogen load and variation may maintain MHC diversity at the global scale (fluctuating selection) [11] . Evaluating the relative roles of natural selection and genetic drift in driving the maintenance or loss of MHC diversity is challenging, and discordant results have been reported. Some studies found similar population structures between MHC and neutral loci, and it was proposed that genetic drift may overwhelm selection in shaping MHC variation, especially in small and bottlenecked populations [1, 12, 13] . Elevated MHC differentiation across populations has also been reported, supporting the dominant role of fluctuating selection [14] [15] [16] . Moreover, limited gene flow among populations can promote local adaptation to consistent pathogen communities, and this spatial variation in pathogen selection regimes may also create more structure in MHC genes [8, 17, 18] .">
    <entity charOffset="164-172" id="98e6190d06a8d8774c690be39634a1d64a926dc3.c2.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_59132" text="antigens" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="989-993" id="98e6190d06a8d8774c690be39634a1d64a926dc3.c2.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="98e6190d06a8d8774c690be39634a1d64a926dc3.c2.e0" e2="98e6190d06a8d8774c690be39634a1d64a926dc3.c2.e1" id="98e6190d06a8d8774c690be39634a1d64a926dc3.c2.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="98e6190d06a8d8774c690be39634a1d64a926dc3.c3" text="Previous studies of MHC variation were mainly focused at the allele level. However, particularly in birds and reptiles, alleles from different MHC loci are sometimes highly similar and even identical to each other because of frequent gene duplication, conversion, and recombination [15, [19] [20] [21] , and the gene copy numbers may also vary among individuals [21] [22] [23] [24] [25] . These issues all imply that genotypes and variation estimated on the basis of alleles alone would be unreliable and potentially biased [21] . Even when the MHC loci are reliably separated, analysis based on valid genotypes alone, without considering the linkage among loci (which is often strong), may also bias the results [21] . For example, different results were obtained on the basis of MHC linkage groups compared to individual alleles in populations of the Egyptian vulture [26] . Similarly, certain infections in badgers were associated with MHC class II-class I haplotypes rather than allele presence [27] . Levels of individual fitness can be differentiated more profoundly using multilocus haplotypes. Thus, population analysis using multilocus MHC haplotype with consideration of the sharing of alleles, the copy number variation (CNV), and the linkage among loci may provide more comprehensive knowledge and credible evaluation of the adaptive variation and species fitness. Moreover, it is essential to examine both MHC class I and II genes, in recognition of their different functions, although only a few studies do this. To the best of our knowledge, no avian population study has adopted the MHC class I-class II multilocus haplotype as an adaptive marker.">
    <entity charOffset="862-869" id="98e6190d06a8d8774c690be39634a1d64a926dc3.c3.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_133232" text="vulture" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="98e6190d06a8d8774c690be39634a1d64a926dc3.c4" text="The crested ibis (Nipponia nippon, Pelecaniformes; hereafter referred to as Nini), which is listed as &quot;Endangered&quot; according to IUCN criteria [28], was once believed to be extinct in the wild until a tiny population of seven birds (two breeding pairs and three nestlings) was rediscovered in 1981 at Yangxian, China [29] . Since then, the Chinese government have made great efforts to protect this wild population (in-situ conservation) and have also established several captive populations at different sites (ex-situ conservation) (Figure 1, Table 1) . Surprisingly, the total number of crested ibis has now increased from seven to over 2000. However, previous studies using mitochondrial DNA and microsatellite markers on small Nini populations revealed extremely low levels of polymorphism [30, 31] . By analyzing the genomes of 57 historic and 8 modern samples, a recent study revealed ancestral loss of genetic variation and high deleterious mutation owing to genetic drift and inbreeding depression in current populations [32] . There have been a growing number of reports regarding various infections [33] [34] [35] [36] and high mortality [29, 33] in this bird, indicating frequent threats from pathogens and undetermined fitness. However, there has not yet been any large-scale genetic assessment on Nini populations. It is imperative that such an assessment is completed, preferably by using MHC markers characterized by high polymorphism and fitness relatedness. This could provide insight into the adaptive diversity and differentiation in the recovering populations, thereby better evaluating species fitness and guiding future conservation. Fortunately, the gene architecture of the MHC region has been well illustrated in the crested ibis:~500 kb MHC region contains five class I genes including one major locus (UAA), three minor loci (UBA, UCA1, and UCA2), and one non-classical locus (UDA), but the UAA locus is located beyond the Class I Region and gathered with the class II genes in the compact Core of the Nini-IIβ sequences amplified by 3UT1 and 3UT2 and long-range segments amplified by P1-P4, P6, and P7 for each haplotype. Table S5 . Recombination events between the full-length sequences of Nini-IIβ genes, identified using RDP. Table S6 . Allele frequencies (%) of microsatellite loci across seven populations of crested ibis. Table S7 . Pairwise F ST values between populations for MHC (below diagonal) and microsatellites (above diagonal). Table S8 . Results of the hierarchical AMOVA for the crested ibis.">
    <entity charOffset="691-694" id="98e6190d06a8d8774c690be39634a1d64a926dc3.c4.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
