<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="9db78243c51590cfaaef835ded1163dc55d67cc0">
  <chunk id="9db78243c51590cfaaef835ded1163dc55d67cc0.c0" text="Sustained Viremia and High Viral Load in Respiratory Tract Secretions Are Predictors for Death in Immunocompetent Adults with Adenovirus Pneumonia"/>
  <chunk id="9db78243c51590cfaaef835ded1163dc55d67cc0.c1" text="The predictors for fatal adenovirus (AdV) pneumonia among immunocompetent adults are unclear. Laboratory-confirmed, hospitalized AdV pneumonia adults were prospectively enrolled in Beijing Chao-Yang hospital from March to June 2013. Clinical data and serial whole blood and respiratory tract secretions from such patients were collected. Quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction was performed to quantify the viral load. A total of 14 AdV pneumonia cases were consecutively enrolled, and four of them were fatal. Ten cases were caused by AdV-55, three by AdV-7 and one by AdV-3. There were no differences in age, gender or underlying diseases between the patients in the fatal cases and surviving cases. At admission (on day 5-7 after illness onset), the patients in fatal cases presented higher initial viral loads in respiratory tract secretions (8.578 ± 2.115 vs 6.263 ± 1.225 Log 10 copies/ml, p = 0.023). All patients in fatal cases presented with viremia on day 12-14 (100% vs 66.7%, p = 0.017). A higher initial viral load in the respiratory tract and sustained viremia (more than 2 weeks) may be predictors for fatal clinical outcomes. Fig 4.">
    <entity charOffset="521-524" id="9db78243c51590cfaaef835ded1163dc55d67cc0.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_25879" text="Ten" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="9db78243c51590cfaaef835ded1163dc55d67cc0.c2" text="The kinetics of Adv loads in sequential sputum and whole blood, CK-MB and CTNI level from a 29-year-old male survival patient with myocarditis. On the y-axis, viral load level is presented with log 10 DNA copy numbers per ml of sample, and myocardial enzyme level is expressed as log 2 CK-MB ng/ml and log 2 CTNI ng/ml. CK-MB = Creatine Kinase-MB, CTNI = Cardiac troponin I.">
    <entity charOffset="201-204" id="9db78243c51590cfaaef835ded1163dc55d67cc0.c2.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="328-336" id="9db78243c51590cfaaef835ded1163dc55d67cc0.c2.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16919" text="Creatine" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="9db78243c51590cfaaef835ded1163dc55d67cc0.c2.e0" e2="9db78243c51590cfaaef835ded1163dc55d67cc0.c2.e1" id="9db78243c51590cfaaef835ded1163dc55d67cc0.c2.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
