<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="a30cef8b3428aa804aa2cbf0ec0303827bb09514">
  <chunk id="a30cef8b3428aa804aa2cbf0ec0303827bb09514.c0" text="Biodistribution and residence time of adenovector serotype 5 in normal and immunodeficient mice and rats detected with bioluminescent imaging OPEN"/>
  <chunk id="a30cef8b3428aa804aa2cbf0ec0303827bb09514.c1" text="As concerns increase about adenovirus type 5 (Ad5) being a safe gene transfer vector, it is important to evaluate its distribution, residence time, and possible toxicity in immunodeficient populations. To characterize the potential risk associated with different Ad5 vector delivery modes, we used immunocompetent and immunodeficient Rag2 −/− animals to establish mouse and rat models that could be monitored with bioluminescent imaging following intramuscular or intravascular infection with an engineered replication-incompetent Ad5 virus carrying the firefly luciferase gene (Ad5-Fluc). The Ad5 vector was less well-tolerated by Rag2 −/− animals than by wildtype ones, with delayed residence time, wider virus dissemination, less weight gain, and relatively severe pathological changes. In intravascularly Ad5-Fluc-infected Rag2 −/− mice, systemic virus dissemination extended from the abdomen to the limbs and head on day 9 post-infection. Additionally, significant increases in plasma TNF-α and IFN-γ, which may be important factors in the heightened immunopathology in the liver and brain, were detected in the Rag2 −/− mice 30 days after intravascular delivery. The Ad5 vector was better tolerated after intramuscular delivery than after intravascular delivery. Ad5-Fluc/Rag2 −/− mice and rats can be used as reliable models of an immunodeficient population in which to evaluate the safety of Ad5vectored vaccines or gene therapy products."/>
  <chunk id="a30cef8b3428aa804aa2cbf0ec0303827bb09514.c2" text="Adenovirus type 5 (Ad5) is widely used experimentally and clinically for gene delivery in oncology, cardioangiology, and regenerative medicine and is also used as a vaccine vector 1-3 . Replicating and non-replicating adenoviruses have been shown to be safe vectors in numerous clinical studies 4 . However, serious concerns regarding the safety of the Ad5 vector arose when a clinical trial was halted in response to its fatal adverse effects on an ornithine-transcarbamylase-deficient patient in 1999 5 . Therefore, a comprehensive understanding of the virological and biological features that define the infectivity and possible toxicity of Ad5 in different individuals is urgently required. Immunosuppression occurs in various types of patients, including those infected with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), the recipients of organ transplantation, and those with hypogammaglobulinaemia 6, 7 . All of these patients are generally characterized by an increased and distinctive susceptibility to various types of pathogens, depending on the nature of the immune defect 8 . However, the behaviour, including biodistribution and residence time, of the Ad5 vector (Adv5) in the context of immunodeficiency is poorly understood.">
    <entity charOffset="134-142" id="a30cef8b3428aa804aa2cbf0ec0303827bb09514.c2.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_23888" text="medicine" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="a30cef8b3428aa804aa2cbf0ec0303827bb09514.c3" text="We previously constructed a replication-competent vaccinia Tiantan strain infection model using an in vivo bioluminescent imaging (BLI) method and found that immunodeficient rats were more susceptible to vaccinia virus than Sprague Dawley (SD) rats and also displayed prolonged infections 9 . The BLI technology has the advantages of rapidity, simplicity, and quantitative precision, which allows the dissemination and clearance of viral vectors in intact and living animals to be carefully evaluated 10 . The aim of this study was to characterize the risk Published: xx xx xxxx OPEN www.nature.com/scientificreports/"/>
</document>
