<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="a3778f543ef74ff3a0dd90250221b77ee38d7533">
  <chunk id="a3778f543ef74ff3a0dd90250221b77ee38d7533.c0" text="Inverse folding of RNA pseudoknot structures">
    <entity charOffset="19-22" id="a3778f543ef74ff3a0dd90250221b77ee38d7533.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="a3778f543ef74ff3a0dd90250221b77ee38d7533.c1" text="Background: RNA exhibits a variety of structural configurations. Here we consider a structure to be tantamount to the noncrossing Watson-Crick and G-U-base pairings (secondary structure) and additional cross-serial base pairs. These interactions are called pseudoknots and are observed across the whole spectrum of RNA functionalities. In the context of studying natural RNA structures, searching for new ribozymes and designing artificial RNA, it is of interest to find RNA sequences folding into a specific structure and to analyze their induced neutral networks. Since the established inverse folding algorithms, RNAinverse, RNA-SSD as well as INFO-RNA are limited to RNA secondary structures, we present in this paper the inverse folding algorithm Inv which can deal with 3-noncrossing, canonical pseudoknot structures. Results: In this paper we present the inverse folding algorithm Inv. We give a detailed analysis of Inv, including pseudocodes. We show that Inv allows to design in particular 3-noncrossing nonplanar RNA pseudoknot 3noncrossing RNA structures-a class which is difficult to construct via dynamic programming routines. Inv is freely available at http://www.combinatorics.cn/cbpc/inv.html. Conclusions: The algorithm Inv extends inverse folding capabilities to RNA pseudoknot structures. In comparison with RNAinverse it uses new ideas, for instance by considering sets of competing structures. As a result, Inv is not only able to find novel sequences even for RNA secondary structures, it does so in the context of competing structures that potentially exhibit cross-serial interactions.">
    <entity charOffset="12-15" id="a3778f543ef74ff3a0dd90250221b77ee38d7533.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="315-318" id="a3778f543ef74ff3a0dd90250221b77ee38d7533.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="371-374" id="a3778f543ef74ff3a0dd90250221b77ee38d7533.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="440-443" id="a3778f543ef74ff3a0dd90250221b77ee38d7533.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="471-474" id="a3778f543ef74ff3a0dd90250221b77ee38d7533.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="671-674" id="a3778f543ef74ff3a0dd90250221b77ee38d7533.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1024-1027" id="a3778f543ef74ff3a0dd90250221b77ee38d7533.c1.e6" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1052-1055" id="a3778f543ef74ff3a0dd90250221b77ee38d7533.c1.e7" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1282-1285" id="a3778f543ef74ff3a0dd90250221b77ee38d7533.c1.e8" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1483-1486" id="a3778f543ef74ff3a0dd90250221b77ee38d7533.c1.e9" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
