<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="b460e5b511b4e2c3233f9476cd4e0616d6f405ac">
  <chunk id="b460e5b511b4e2c3233f9476cd4e0616d6f405ac.c0" text="Lung epithelial cells have virus-specific and shared gene expression responses to infection by diverse respiratory viruses"/>
  <chunk id="b460e5b511b4e2c3233f9476cd4e0616d6f405ac.c1" text="The severity of respiratory viral infections is partially determined by the cellular response mounted by infected lung epithelial cells. Disease prevention and treatment is dependent on our understanding of the shared and unique responses elicited by diverse viruses, yet few studies compare host responses to viruses from different families while controlling other experimental parameters. Murine models are commonly used to study the pathogenesis of respiratory viral infections, and in vitro studies using murine cells provide mechanistic insight into the pathogenesis observed in vivo. We used microarray analysis to compare changes in gene expression of murine lung epithelial cells infected individually by three respiratory viruses causing mild (rhinovirus, RV1B), moderate (coronavirus, MHV-1), and severe (influenza A virus, PR8) disease in mice. RV1B infection caused numerous gene expression changes, but the differential effect peaked at 12 hours post-infection. PR8 altered an intermediate number of genes whose expression continued to change through 24 hours. MHV-1 had comparatively few effects on host gene expression. The viruses elicited highly overlapping responses in antiviral genes, though MHV-1 induced a lower type I interferon response than the other two viruses. Signature genes were identified for each virus and included host defense genes for PR8, tissue remodeling genes for RV1B, and transcription factors for MHV-1. Our comparative approach identified universal and specific transcriptional signatures of virus infection that can be used to distinguish shared and virus-specific mechanisms of pathogenesis in the respiratory tract.">
    <entity charOffset="1188-1197" id="b460e5b511b4e2c3233f9476cd4e0616d6f405ac.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_22587" text="antiviral" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1241-1251" id="b460e5b511b4e2c3233f9476cd4e0616d6f405ac.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_52999" text="interferon" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="b460e5b511b4e2c3233f9476cd4e0616d6f405ac.c1.e0" e2="b460e5b511b4e2c3233f9476cd4e0616d6f405ac.c1.e1" id="b460e5b511b4e2c3233f9476cd4e0616d6f405ac.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
