<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="bab6dd24b41528b0a321874ef4827c873846e335">
  <chunk id="bab6dd24b41528b0a321874ef4827c873846e335.c0" text="medicina Utilisation of and Attitude towards Traditional and Complementary Medicine among Ebola Survivors in Sierra Leone">
    <entity charOffset="75-83" id="bab6dd24b41528b0a321874ef4827c873846e335.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_23888" text="Medicine" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="bab6dd24b41528b0a321874ef4827c873846e335.c1" text="Background and objectives: In addition to conventional healthcare, Ebola survivors are known to seek traditional and complementary healthcare (T&amp;CM) options to meet their healthcare needs. However, little is known about the general beliefs of Ebola survivors regarding T&amp;CM and the impact of these beliefs in influencing their decisions around T&amp;CM use. This study examines Ebola survivors' attitudes towards T&amp;CM use in Sierra Leone. Materials and Methods: We conducted a nationwide quantitative cross-sectional study of 358 Ebola survivors in Sierra Leone between January and August 2018. We used descriptive analysis, chi-square tests and backward stepwise binary logistic regression for data analysis. Results: Close to half of the survivors (n = 163, 45.5%) had used T&amp;CM since their discharge from an Ebola treatment centre. Survivors who viewed T&amp;CM as boosting their immune system/resistance were 3.89 times (95%CI: 1.57-9.63, p = 0.003) more likely to use T&amp;CM than those who did not view T&amp;CM as boosting their immune system/resistance. Additionally, survivors who viewed T&amp;CM as having fewer side effects than conventional medicine were more likely to use T&amp;CM [OR = 5.03 (95%CI: 1.92-13.19, p = 0.001)]. Ebola survivors were more influenced to use T&amp;CM based on their personal experience of the effectiveness of T&amp;CM than by clinical evidence [OR = 13.72 (95%CI: 6.10-30.84, P &lt; 0.001)]. Ebola survivors who perceived T&amp;CM as providing them with more control than conventional medicine over their health/body were more likely to use T&amp;CM , p = 0.001)] as opposed to those who did not perceive T&amp;CM in this way. Conclusions: Considering the widespread use of T&amp;CM, an understanding of Ebola survivors' attitudes/beliefs towards T&amp;CM is useful to healthcare providers and policymakers with regard to public education and practitioner-survivors communication, T&amp;CM regulation and research in Sierra Leone. Ebola survivors appear to turn to T&amp;CM not only for treatment, but also to fill gaps in conventional health care services.">
    <entity charOffset="1134-1142" id="bab6dd24b41528b0a321874ef4827c873846e335.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_23888" text="medicine" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1489-1497" id="bab6dd24b41528b0a321874ef4827c873846e335.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_23888" text="medicine" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
