<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="bf256a0f8fd3ff2faa39f340180e7e19bfa4c295">
  <chunk id="bf256a0f8fd3ff2faa39f340180e7e19bfa4c295.c0" text="The Soluble Form of the EIAV Receptor Encoded by an Alternative Splicing Variant Inhibits EIAV Infection of Target Cells"/>
  <chunk id="bf256a0f8fd3ff2faa39f340180e7e19bfa4c295.c1" text="Equine lentivirus receptor 1 (ELR1) has been identified as the sole receptor for equine infectious anemia virus (EIAV) and is a member of the tumor necrosis factor receptor (TNFR) superfamily. In addition to the previously described membraneassociated form of ELR1, two other major alternative splicing variant mRNAs were identified in equine monocyte-derived macrophages (eMDMs). One major spliced species (ELR1-IN) contained an insertion of 153 nt, which resulted in a premature stop codon situated 561 nt upstream of the predicted membrane spanning domain. The other major species (ELR1-DE) has a deletion of 109 nt that causes a shift of the open reading frame and generates a stop codon 312 nt downstream. Because ELR1-DE presumably encodes a peptide of a mere 23 residues, only ELR1-IN was further analyzed. The expression of a soluble form of ELR1 (sELR1) by ELR1-IN was confirmed by Western blot and immunofluorescence analyses. Similar to ELR1, the transcription level of ELR1-IN varied among individual horses and at different time points in the same individuals. The ratio of ELR1-IN mRNA species to ELR1 mRNA was approximately 1:2.5. Pre-incubation of the recombinant sELR1 with EIAV significantly inhibited EIAV infection in equine macrophages, the primary in vivo target cell of the virus. Fetal equine dermal (FED) cells are susceptible to EIAV in vitro, and the replication of EIAV in FED cells transiently transfected with ELR1-IN was markedly reduced when compared with replication in cells transfected with the empty vector. Finally, the expression levels of both forms of the EIAV receptor were significantly regulated by infection with this virus. Taken together, our data indicate that sELR1 acts as a secreted cellular factor that inhibits EIAV infection in host cells.">
    <entity charOffset="748-755" id="bf256a0f8fd3ff2faa39f340180e7e19bfa4c295.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16670" text="peptide" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1095-1099" id="bf256a0f8fd3ff2faa39f340180e7e19bfa4c295.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33699" text="mRNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1116-1120" id="bf256a0f8fd3ff2faa39f340180e7e19bfa4c295.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_33699" text="mRNA" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="bf256a0f8fd3ff2faa39f340180e7e19bfa4c295.c1.e0" e2="bf256a0f8fd3ff2faa39f340180e7e19bfa4c295.c1.e1" id="bf256a0f8fd3ff2faa39f340180e7e19bfa4c295.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="bf256a0f8fd3ff2faa39f340180e7e19bfa4c295.c1.e0" e2="bf256a0f8fd3ff2faa39f340180e7e19bfa4c295.c1.e2" id="bf256a0f8fd3ff2faa39f340180e7e19bfa4c295.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
