<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="c047b0340f79e0d34787e5f3500605b8c20e827d">
  <chunk id="c047b0340f79e0d34787e5f3500605b8c20e827d.c0" text="Local Evolutionary Patterns of Human Respiratory Syncytial Virus Derived from Whole-Genome Sequencing"/>
  <chunk id="c047b0340f79e0d34787e5f3500605b8c20e827d.c1" text="RSV molecular epidemiology, evolution, and transmission requires detailed sequence data and can inform new strategies for virus control and vaccine development. We have generated 27 complete or nearly complete genomes of RSV from hospitalized children attending a rural coastal district hospital in Kilifi, Kenya, over a 10-year period using a novel full-genome deep-sequencing process. Phylogenetic analysis of the new genomes demonstrated the existence and cocirculation of multiple genotypes in both RSV A and B groups in Kilifi. Comparison of local versus global strains demonstrated that most RSV A variants observed locally in Kilifi were also seen in other parts of the world, while the Kilifi RSV B genomes encoded a high degree of variation that was not observed in other parts of the world. The nucleotide substitution rates for the individual open reading frames (ORFs) were highest in the regions encoding the attachment (G) glycoprotein and the NS2 protein. The analysis of RSV full genomes, compared to subgenomic regions, provided more precise estimates of the RSV sequence changes and revealed important patterns of RSV genomic variation and global movement. The novel sequencing method and the new RSV genomic sequences reported here expand our knowledge base for large-scale RSV epidemiological and transmission studies.">
    <entity charOffset="805-815" id="c047b0340f79e0d34787e5f3500605b8c20e827d.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_36976" text="nucleotide" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="937-949" id="c047b0340f79e0d34787e5f3500605b8c20e827d.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_17089" text="glycoprotein" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="c047b0340f79e0d34787e5f3500605b8c20e827d.c1.e0" e2="c047b0340f79e0d34787e5f3500605b8c20e827d.c1.e1" id="c047b0340f79e0d34787e5f3500605b8c20e827d.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="c047b0340f79e0d34787e5f3500605b8c20e827d.c2" text="IMPORTANCE"/>
  <chunk id="c047b0340f79e0d34787e5f3500605b8c20e827d.c3" text="Citation Agoti CN, Otieno JR, Munywoki PK, Mwihuri AG, Cane PA, Nokes DJ, Kellam P, Cotten M. 2015. Local evolutionary patterns of human respiratory syncytial virus derived from whole-genome sequencing. FIG 2 Phylogenetic analysis of the Kilifi RSVA and RSVB genomes. (A) MrBayes tree of representative global RSVA genome sequences together and the 11 novel Kilifi RSVA genome sequences. (B) MrBayes tree of representative global RSVB genome sequences and the 16 novel Kilifi RSVA genome sequences. Trees were inferred using the Bayesian methods in MrBayes (http://mrbayes.sourceforge.net/index.php) under the GTR model of evolution. The numbers next to the branches indicate the posterior probabilities. The Kilifi taxa are indicated in red font. Thinned global reference sets for RSVA and RSVB were prepared from all available RSV genomes clustering at 0.99% identity using uclust (32)."/>
</document>
