<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="c0617473da97a9dd36b02d46fe80b144f2138f0a">
  <chunk id="c0617473da97a9dd36b02d46fe80b144f2138f0a.c0" text="Cellular trafficking determines the exon skipping activity of Pip6a-PMO in mdx skeletal and cardiac muscle cells"/>
  <chunk id="c0617473da97a9dd36b02d46fe80b144f2138f0a.c1" text="Cell-penetrating peptide-mediated delivery of phosphorodiamidate morpholino oligomers (PMOs) has shown great promise for exon-skipping therapy of Duchenne Muscular Dystrophy (DMD). Pip6a-PMO, a recently developed conjugate, is particularly efficient in a murine DMD model, although mechanisms responsible for its increased biological activity have not been studied. Here, we evaluate the cellular trafficking and the biological activity of Pip6a-PMO in skeletal muscle cells and primary cardiomyocytes. Our results indicate that Pip6a-PMO is taken up in the skeletal muscle cells by an energy-and caveolae-mediated endocytosis. Interestingly, its cellular distribution is different in undifferentiated and differentiated skeletal muscle cells (vesicular versus nuclear). Likewise, Pip6a-PMO mainly accumulates in cytoplasmic vesicles in primary cardiomyocytes, in which clathrinmediated endocytosis seems to be the predominant uptake pathway. These differences in cellular trafficking correspond well with the exonskipping data, with higher activity in myotubes than in myoblasts or cardiomyocytes. These differences in cellular trafficking thus provide a possible mechanistic explanation for the variations in exonskipping activity and restoration of dystrophin protein in heart muscle compared with skeletal muscle tissues in DMD models. Overall, Pip6a-PMO appears as the most efficient conjugate to date (low nanomolar EC 50 ), even if limitations remain from endosomal escape.">
    <entity charOffset="76-85" id="c0617473da97a9dd36b02d46fe80b144f2138f0a.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_132554" text="oligomers" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1263-1270" id="c0617473da97a9dd36b02d46fe80b144f2138f0a.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="c0617473da97a9dd36b02d46fe80b144f2138f0a.c1.e0" e2="c0617473da97a9dd36b02d46fe80b144f2138f0a.c1.e1" id="c0617473da97a9dd36b02d46fe80b144f2138f0a.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
