<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="c4a909da9b4ab2d9a0a9f4305e1cdc4bc66f9d03">
  <chunk id="c4a909da9b4ab2d9a0a9f4305e1cdc4bc66f9d03.c0" text="Discovery and Characterization of Novel RNA Viruses in Aquatic North American Wild Birds">
    <entity charOffset="40-43" id="c4a909da9b4ab2d9a0a9f4305e1cdc4bc66f9d03.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="c4a909da9b4ab2d9a0a9f4305e1cdc4bc66f9d03.c1" text="Wild birds are recognized viral reservoirs but our understanding about avian viral diversity is limited. We describe here three novel RNA viruses that we identified in oropharyngeal/cloacal swabs collected from wild birds. The complete genome of a novel gull metapneumovirus (GuMPV B29) was determined. Phylogenetic analyses indicated that this virus could represent a novel avian metapneumovirus (AMPV) sub-group, intermediate between AMPV-C and the subgroup of the other AMPVs. This virus was detected in an American herring (1/24, 4.2%) and great black-backed (4/26, 15.4%) gulls. A novel gull coronavirus (GuCoV B29) was detected in great black-backed (3/26, 11.5%) and American herring (2/24, 8.3%) gulls. Phylogenetic analyses of GuCoV B29 suggested that this virus could represent a novel species within the genus Gammacoronavirus, close to other recently identified potential novel avian coronaviral species. One GuMPV-GuCoV co-infection was detected. A novel duck calicivirus (DuCV-2 B6) was identified in mallards (2/5, 40%) and American black ducks (7/26, 26.9%). This virus, of which we identified two different types, was fully sequenced and was genetically closest to other caliciviruses identified in Anatidae, but more distant to other caliciviruses from birds in the genus Anas. These discoveries increase our knowledge about avian virus diversity and host distributions.">
    <entity charOffset="134-137" id="c4a909da9b4ab2d9a0a9f4305e1cdc4bc66f9d03.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
