<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="c923009c37cf93d35e69ec161afaf3cc334e03a7">
  <chunk id="c923009c37cf93d35e69ec161afaf3cc334e03a7.c0" text="Viral aetiology of bronchiolitis in hospitalised children in Qatar"/>
  <chunk id="c923009c37cf93d35e69ec161afaf3cc334e03a7.c1" text="Background: Bronchiolitis is considered one of the earliest and most common causes of hospitalisation in young children. Development of molecular technologies allowed a better understanding of bronchiolitis aetiology. Results from cohort studies evaluating the association between single, multiple viral infections and clinical outcomes are conflicting. Data on viral bronchiolitis in children were found to be limited in Qatar. This study aimed to determine frequency and seasonal trends of viral pathogens causing acute bronchiolitis, and to explore association between viral pathogens, disease severity and length of stay (LOS). Methods: This is a retrospective descriptive study, including children admitted in 2010 and 2011 with acute bronchiolitis. Presenting history, physical examination and respiratory viral co-infections as detected by molecular assays were analysed. Results: At least one virus was detected in 315/369 (85.4%) of included children with single and multiple viruses in 67 and 33% of cases respectively. Respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) was the most detected virus, accounting for 51. 2% followed by rhinovirus (RV) in 25.5% of cases. Fall and summer admissions were associated with longer LOS. On multivariate logistic regression analysis, retraction (OR 3.96; 95% CI 1.64,9.59) and age group 1-3 months (OR 3.09; 95% CI 1.06,9.05) were associated with longer LOS. Crepitation (OR 9.15; 95% CI 1.58,53.13), retraction (OR 4.10; 95% CI 1.05,16.12) and respiratory rate (OR 1.46; 95% CI 1.28,1.66) were associated with moderate to severe bronchiolitis. Identifying the viral agent did not influence disease severity or LOS.">
    <entity charOffset="231-237" id="c923009c37cf93d35e69ec161afaf3cc334e03a7.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_34935" text="cohort" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="c923009c37cf93d35e69ec161afaf3cc334e03a7.c2" text="Clinical presentation is of more relevance to LOS and disease severity than the detected viruses. Future studies should investigate the interplay between climate characteristics, population's factors and the most detectable circulating viruses.">
    <entity charOffset="46-49" id="c923009c37cf93d35e69ec161afaf3cc334e03a7.c2.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_35371" text="LOS" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
