<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="ca73d739c9c8c6ddb081d0badcea76f821ae147a">
  <chunk id="ca73d739c9c8c6ddb081d0badcea76f821ae147a.c0" text="Rescue of the 1947 Zika Virus Prototype Strain with a Cytomegalovirus Promoter- Driven cDNA Clone"/>
  <chunk id="ca73d739c9c8c6ddb081d0badcea76f821ae147a.c1" text="The recent Zika virus (ZIKV) outbreak has been linked to severe pathogenesis. Here, we report the construction of a plasmid carrying a cytomegalovirus (CMV) promoter-expressed prototype 1947 Uganda MR766 ZIKV cDNA that can initiate infection following direct plasmid DNA transfection of mammalian cells. Incorporation of a synthetic intron in the nonstructural protein 1 (NS1) region of the ZIKV polyprotein reduced viral cDNA-associated toxicity in bacteria. High levels of infectious virus were produced following transfection of the plasmid bearing the wildtype MR766 ZIKV genome, but not one with a disruption to the viral nonstructural protein 5 (NS5) polymerase active site. Multicycle growth curve and plaque assay experiments indicated that the MR766 virus resulting from plasmid transfection exhibited growth characteristics that were more similar to its parental isolate than previously published 2010 Cambodia and 2015 Brazil cDNA-rescued ZIKV. This ZIKV infectious clone will be useful for investigating the genetic determinants of ZIKV infection and pathogenesis and should be amenable to construction of diverse infectious clones expressing reporter proteins and representing a range of ZIKV isolates. Citation Schwarz MC, Sourisseau M, Espino MM, Gray ES, Chambers MT, Tortorella D, Evans MJ. 2016. Rescue of the 1947 Zika virus prototype strain with a cytomegalovirus promoter-driven cDNA clone. mSphere 1(5): e00246-16.">
    <entity charOffset="267-270" id="ca73d739c9c8c6ddb081d0badcea76f821ae147a.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="361-368" id="ca73d739c9c8c6ddb081d0badcea76f821ae147a.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="641-648" id="ca73d739c9c8c6ddb081d0badcea76f821ae147a.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1164-1172" id="ca73d739c9c8c6ddb081d0badcea76f821ae147a.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="ca73d739c9c8c6ddb081d0badcea76f821ae147a.c1.e0" e2="ca73d739c9c8c6ddb081d0badcea76f821ae147a.c1.e1" id="ca73d739c9c8c6ddb081d0badcea76f821ae147a.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="ca73d739c9c8c6ddb081d0badcea76f821ae147a.c1.e0" e2="ca73d739c9c8c6ddb081d0badcea76f821ae147a.c1.e2" id="ca73d739c9c8c6ddb081d0badcea76f821ae147a.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="ca73d739c9c8c6ddb081d0badcea76f821ae147a.c1.e0" e2="ca73d739c9c8c6ddb081d0badcea76f821ae147a.c1.e3" id="ca73d739c9c8c6ddb081d0badcea76f821ae147a.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="ca73d739c9c8c6ddb081d0badcea76f821ae147a.c1.e1" e2="ca73d739c9c8c6ddb081d0badcea76f821ae147a.c1.e3" id="ca73d739c9c8c6ddb081d0badcea76f821ae147a.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="ca73d739c9c8c6ddb081d0badcea76f821ae147a.c1.e2" e2="ca73d739c9c8c6ddb081d0badcea76f821ae147a.c1.e3" id="ca73d739c9c8c6ddb081d0badcea76f821ae147a.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
