<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="cb763a61411514366d16bb2571461b6df1361517">
  <chunk id="cb763a61411514366d16bb2571461b6df1361517.c0" text="Tropism and Induction of Cytokines in Human Embryonic-Stem Cells-Derived Neural Progenitors upon Inoculation with Highly- Pathogenic Avian H5N1 Influenza Virus"/>
  <chunk id="cb763a61411514366d16bb2571461b6df1361517.c1" text="Central nervous system (CNS) dysfunction caused by neurovirulent influenza viruses is a dreaded complication of infection, and may play a role in some neurodegenerative conditions, such as Parkinson-like diseases and encephalitis lethargica. Although CNS infection by highly pathogenic H5N1 virus has been demonstrated, it is unknown whether H5N1 infects neural progenitor cells, nor whether such infection plays a role in the neuroinflammation and neurodegeneration. To pursue this question, we infected human neural progenitor cells (hNPCs) differentiated from human embryonic stem cells in vitro with H5N1 virus, and studied the resulting cytopathology, cytokine expression, and genes involved in the differentiation. Human embryonic stem cells (BG01) were maintained and differentiated into the neural progenitors, and then infected by H5N1 virus (A/Chicken/Thailand/CUK2/04) at a multiplicity of infection of 1. At 6, 24, 48, and 72 hours post-infection (hpi), cytopathic effects were observed. Then cells were characterized by immunofluorescence and electron microscopy, supernatants quantified for virus titers, and sampled cells studied for candidate genes.The hNPCs were susceptible to H5N1 virus infection as determined by morphological observation and immunofluorescence. The infection was characterized by a significant up-regulation of TNF-α gene expression, while expressions of IFN-α2, IFN-β1, IFN-γ and IL-6 remained unchanged compared to mock-infected controls. Moreover, H5N1 infection did not appear to alter expression of neuronal and astrocytic markers of hNPCs, such as β-III tubulin and GFAP, respectively. The results indicate that hNPCs support H5N1 virus infection and may play a role in the neuroinflammation during acute viral encephalitis.">
    <entity charOffset="138-142" id="cb763a61411514366d16bb2571461b6df1361517.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="415-419" id="cb763a61411514366d16bb2571461b6df1361517.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1056-1064" id="cb763a61411514366d16bb2571461b6df1361517.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_10545" text="electron" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1706-1710" id="cb763a61411514366d16bb2571461b6df1361517.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="cb763a61411514366d16bb2571461b6df1361517.c1.e0" e2="cb763a61411514366d16bb2571461b6df1361517.c1.e2" id="cb763a61411514366d16bb2571461b6df1361517.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="cb763a61411514366d16bb2571461b6df1361517.c1.e1" e2="cb763a61411514366d16bb2571461b6df1361517.c1.e2" id="cb763a61411514366d16bb2571461b6df1361517.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="cb763a61411514366d16bb2571461b6df1361517.c1.e2" e2="cb763a61411514366d16bb2571461b6df1361517.c1.e3" id="cb763a61411514366d16bb2571461b6df1361517.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
