<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="d17ba127439d63e04c399c19a06fa63998d65e6d">
  <chunk id="d17ba127439d63e04c399c19a06fa63998d65e6d.c0" text="Immunosuppressive Drugs Modulate the Replication of Hepatitis B Virus (HBV) in a Hydrodynamic Injection Mouse Model">
    <entity charOffset="18-23" id="d17ba127439d63e04c399c19a06fa63998d65e6d.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_23888" text="Drugs" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="d17ba127439d63e04c399c19a06fa63998d65e6d.c1" text="Hepatitis B virus (HBV) reactivation and recurrence are common in patients under immunosuppression and can be controlled by hepatitis B immunoglobulin, antivirals, and hepatitis B vaccine. However, the detailed analysis of HBV infection under immunosuppression is essential for the prophylaxis and therapy for HBV reactivation and recurrence. In this study, HBV replication and T cell responses were analyzed in a HBV-transfected mouse model under immunosuppressive therapy. During the treatment, HBV replication was at a high level in mice treated with dexamethasone, cyclosporine, and cyclophosphamide, whereas was terminated in mice treated with mycophenolate mofetil. After the withdrawal, HBV replication was at low or high levels in the dexamethasone-treated mice or in both cyclosporine-and cyclophosphamidetreated mice. The early withdrawal of cyclosporine allowed the recovery of suppressed T cell responses and led to subsequent HBV clearance, while the adoptive immune transfer to the mice with HBV persistence led to HBV suppression. Taken together, long-term HBV persistence under immunosuppression depends on the immunosuppressive drugs used and on the treatment duration and is mediated by the suppressed intrahepatic CD8 T cell response. These data may be helpful for individualized immunosuppressive therapy in patients with high risk of HBV reactivation and recurrence, and the mouse system is suitable for studying HBV reactivation and recurrence under immunosuppression.">
    <entity charOffset="569-581" id="d17ba127439d63e04c399c19a06fa63998d65e6d.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_4031" text="cyclosporine" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="649-662" id="d17ba127439d63e04c399c19a06fa63998d65e6d.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_168396" text="mycophenolate" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="852-864" id="d17ba127439d63e04c399c19a06fa63998d65e6d.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_4031" text="cyclosporine" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1145-1150" id="d17ba127439d63e04c399c19a06fa63998d65e6d.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_23888" text="drugs" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="d17ba127439d63e04c399c19a06fa63998d65e6d.c1.e0" e2="d17ba127439d63e04c399c19a06fa63998d65e6d.c1.e1" id="d17ba127439d63e04c399c19a06fa63998d65e6d.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="d17ba127439d63e04c399c19a06fa63998d65e6d.c1.e0" e2="d17ba127439d63e04c399c19a06fa63998d65e6d.c1.e3" id="d17ba127439d63e04c399c19a06fa63998d65e6d.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="d17ba127439d63e04c399c19a06fa63998d65e6d.c1.e1" e2="d17ba127439d63e04c399c19a06fa63998d65e6d.c1.e2" id="d17ba127439d63e04c399c19a06fa63998d65e6d.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="d17ba127439d63e04c399c19a06fa63998d65e6d.c1.e1" e2="d17ba127439d63e04c399c19a06fa63998d65e6d.c1.e3" id="d17ba127439d63e04c399c19a06fa63998d65e6d.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="d17ba127439d63e04c399c19a06fa63998d65e6d.c1.e2" e2="d17ba127439d63e04c399c19a06fa63998d65e6d.c1.e3" id="d17ba127439d63e04c399c19a06fa63998d65e6d.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
