<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="d4d885e748fc8335d359da08f2ef0370103f98c7">
  <chunk id="d4d885e748fc8335d359da08f2ef0370103f98c7.c0" text="A general strategy to inhibiting viral −1 frameshifting based on upstream attenuation duplex formation"/>
  <chunk id="d4d885e748fc8335d359da08f2ef0370103f98c7.c1" text="Viral −1 programmed ribosomal frameshifting (PRF) as a potential antiviral target has attracted interest because many human viral pathogens, including human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) and coronaviruses, rely on −1 PRF for optimal propagation. Efficient eukaryotic −1 PRF requires an optimally placed stimulator structure downstream of the frameshifting site and different strategies targeting viral −1 PRF stimulators have been developed. However, accessing particular −1 PRF stimulator information represents a bottle-neck in combating the emerging epidemic viral pathogens such as Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus (MERS-CoV). Recently, an RNA hairpin upstream of frameshifting site was shown to act as a cis-element to attenuate −1 PRF with mechanism unknown. Here, we show that an upstream duplex formed in-trans, by annealing an antisense to its complementary mRNA sequence upstream of frameshifting site, can replace an upstream hairpin to attenuate −1 PRF efficiently. This finding indicates that the formation of a proximal upstream duplex is the main determining factor responsible for −1 PRF attenuation and provides mechanistic insight. Additionally, the antisense-mediated upstream duplex approach downregulates −1 PRF stimulated by distinct −1 PRF stimulators, including those of MERS-CoV, suggesting its general application potential as a robust means to evaluating viral −1 PRF inhibition as soon as the sequence information of an emerging human coronavirus is available.">
    <entity charOffset="65-74" id="d4d885e748fc8335d359da08f2ef0370103f98c7.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_22587" text="antiviral" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="655-658" id="d4d885e748fc8335d359da08f2ef0370103f98c7.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="878-882" id="d4d885e748fc8335d359da08f2ef0370103f98c7.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_33699" text="mRNA" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="d4d885e748fc8335d359da08f2ef0370103f98c7.c1.e0" e2="d4d885e748fc8335d359da08f2ef0370103f98c7.c1.e1" id="d4d885e748fc8335d359da08f2ef0370103f98c7.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="d4d885e748fc8335d359da08f2ef0370103f98c7.c1.e0" e2="d4d885e748fc8335d359da08f2ef0370103f98c7.c1.e2" id="d4d885e748fc8335d359da08f2ef0370103f98c7.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="d4d885e748fc8335d359da08f2ef0370103f98c7.c1.e1" e2="d4d885e748fc8335d359da08f2ef0370103f98c7.c1.e2" id="d4d885e748fc8335d359da08f2ef0370103f98c7.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
