<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="d6941e8307d78b087937f9ee4324969ef7e1b623">
  <chunk id="d6941e8307d78b087937f9ee4324969ef7e1b623.c0" text="Efficacy of Antiviral Drugs against Feline Immunodeficiency Virus">
    <entity charOffset="12-21" id="d6941e8307d78b087937f9ee4324969ef7e1b623.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_22587" text="Antiviral" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="12-27" id="d6941e8307d78b087937f9ee4324969ef7e1b623.c0.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_36044" text="Antiviral Drugs" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="22-27" id="d6941e8307d78b087937f9ee4324969ef7e1b623.c0.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_23888" text="Drugs" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="d6941e8307d78b087937f9ee4324969ef7e1b623.c0.e0" e2="d6941e8307d78b087937f9ee4324969ef7e1b623.c0.e1" id="d6941e8307d78b087937f9ee4324969ef7e1b623.c0.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="d6941e8307d78b087937f9ee4324969ef7e1b623.c0.e0" e2="d6941e8307d78b087937f9ee4324969ef7e1b623.c0.e2" id="d6941e8307d78b087937f9ee4324969ef7e1b623.c0.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="d6941e8307d78b087937f9ee4324969ef7e1b623.c0.e1" e2="d6941e8307d78b087937f9ee4324969ef7e1b623.c0.e2" id="d6941e8307d78b087937f9ee4324969ef7e1b623.c0.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="d6941e8307d78b087937f9ee4324969ef7e1b623.c1" text="Feline immunodeficiency virus (FIV) is one of the most common infectious agents affecting cats worldwide .FIV and human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) share many properties: both are lifelong persistent lentiviruses that are similar genetically and morphologically and both viruses propagate in T-lymphocytes, macrophages, and neural cells. Experimentally infected cats have measurable immune suppression, which sometimes progresses to an acquired immunodeficiency syndrome. A transient initial state of infection is followed by a long latent stage with low virus replication and absence of clinical signs. In the terminal stage, both viruses can cause severe immunosuppression. Thus, FIV infection in cats has become an important natural model for studying HIV infection in humans, especially for evaluation of antiviral compounds. Of particular importance for chemotherapeutic studies is the close similarity between the reverse transcriptase (RT) of FIV and HIV, which results in high in vitro susceptibility of FIV to many RT-targeted antiviral compounds used in the treatment of HIV-infected patients. Thus, the aim of this article is to provide an up-to-date review of studies on antiviral treatment of FIV, focusing on commercially available compounds for human or animal use.">
    <entity charOffset="810-819" id="d6941e8307d78b087937f9ee4324969ef7e1b623.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_22587" text="antiviral" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1037-1046" id="d6941e8307d78b087937f9ee4324969ef7e1b623.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_22587" text="antiviral" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1184-1193" id="d6941e8307d78b087937f9ee4324969ef7e1b623.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_22587" text="antiviral" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
