<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="d8271398b9073fbb1ad449e72697e6ae8f71d3d8">
  <chunk id="d8271398b9073fbb1ad449e72697e6ae8f71d3d8.c0" text="Passive Broad-Spectrum Influenza Immunoprophylaxis"/>
  <chunk id="d8271398b9073fbb1ad449e72697e6ae8f71d3d8.c1" text="Influenza is a perennial problem affecting millions of people annually with the everpresent threat of devastating pandemics. Active prophylaxis by vaccination against influenza virus is currently the main countermeasure supplemented with antivirals. However, disadvantages of this strategy include the impact of antigenic drift, necessitating constant updating of vaccine strain composition, and emerging antiviral drug resistance. The development of other options for influenza prophylaxis, particularly with broad acting agents able to provide protection in the period between the onset of a pandemic and the development of a strain specific vaccine, is of great interest. Exploitation of broad-spectrum mediators could provide barricade protection in the early critical phase of influenza virus outbreaks. Passive immunity has the potential to provide immediate antiviral effects, inhibiting virus replication, reducing virus shedding, and thereby protecting vulnerable populations in the event of an impending influenza pandemic. Here, we review passive broad-spectrum influenza prophylaxis options with a focus on harnessing natural host defenses, including interferons and antibodies.">
    <entity charOffset="405-414" id="d8271398b9073fbb1ad449e72697e6ae8f71d3d8.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_22587" text="antiviral" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="405-419" id="d8271398b9073fbb1ad449e72697e6ae8f71d3d8.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_36044" text="antiviral drug" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="415-419" id="d8271398b9073fbb1ad449e72697e6ae8f71d3d8.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_23888" text="drug" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="865-874" id="d8271398b9073fbb1ad449e72697e6ae8f71d3d8.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_22587" text="antiviral" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="d8271398b9073fbb1ad449e72697e6ae8f71d3d8.c1.e0" e2="d8271398b9073fbb1ad449e72697e6ae8f71d3d8.c1.e1" id="d8271398b9073fbb1ad449e72697e6ae8f71d3d8.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="d8271398b9073fbb1ad449e72697e6ae8f71d3d8.c1.e0" e2="d8271398b9073fbb1ad449e72697e6ae8f71d3d8.c1.e2" id="d8271398b9073fbb1ad449e72697e6ae8f71d3d8.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="d8271398b9073fbb1ad449e72697e6ae8f71d3d8.c1.e1" e2="d8271398b9073fbb1ad449e72697e6ae8f71d3d8.c1.e2" id="d8271398b9073fbb1ad449e72697e6ae8f71d3d8.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="d8271398b9073fbb1ad449e72697e6ae8f71d3d8.c1.e1" e2="d8271398b9073fbb1ad449e72697e6ae8f71d3d8.c1.e3" id="d8271398b9073fbb1ad449e72697e6ae8f71d3d8.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="d8271398b9073fbb1ad449e72697e6ae8f71d3d8.c1.e2" e2="d8271398b9073fbb1ad449e72697e6ae8f71d3d8.c1.e3" id="d8271398b9073fbb1ad449e72697e6ae8f71d3d8.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
