<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="d8a0e6a4cc626dfe6090ea49ce8b920eee3f98e1">
  <chunk id="d8a0e6a4cc626dfe6090ea49ce8b920eee3f98e1.c0" text="Cohort profile: Studies of Work Environment and Disease Epidemiology-Infections (SWEDE- I), a prospective cohort on employed adults in Sweden">
    <entity charOffset="0-6" id="d8a0e6a4cc626dfe6090ea49ce8b920eee3f98e1.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_34935" text="Cohort" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="88-91" id="d8a0e6a4cc626dfe6090ea49ce8b920eee3f98e1.c0.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16411" text="Iaa" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="106-112" id="d8a0e6a4cc626dfe6090ea49ce8b920eee3f98e1.c0.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_34935" text="cohort" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="d8a0e6a4cc626dfe6090ea49ce8b920eee3f98e1.c0.e0" e2="d8a0e6a4cc626dfe6090ea49ce8b920eee3f98e1.c0.e1" id="d8a0e6a4cc626dfe6090ea49ce8b920eee3f98e1.c0.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="d8a0e6a4cc626dfe6090ea49ce8b920eee3f98e1.c0.e0" e2="d8a0e6a4cc626dfe6090ea49ce8b920eee3f98e1.c0.e2" id="d8a0e6a4cc626dfe6090ea49ce8b920eee3f98e1.c0.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="d8a0e6a4cc626dfe6090ea49ce8b920eee3f98e1.c0.e1" e2="d8a0e6a4cc626dfe6090ea49ce8b920eee3f98e1.c0.e2" id="d8a0e6a4cc626dfe6090ea49ce8b920eee3f98e1.c0.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="d8a0e6a4cc626dfe6090ea49ce8b920eee3f98e1.c1" text="The aim of this article is to provide a detailed description of the SWEDE-I cohort, a prospective study designed to investigate work-related risk factors for transmission of viral infections. A total of 2,237 subjects aged 25-64, working and residing in Eskilstuna (central Sweden), enrolled in the study in August 2011. They filled in five detailed questionnaires including information on demography, personal characteristics, work tasks, work place, contact patterns, family structure, health status, physical activity and diet. During a 9-month follow-up period, the participants self-reported-via internet or telephone-any onset of fever, upper respiratory tract infection, or gastroenteritis immediately as they occurred. For each disease episode, the participants were asked to submit a self-sampled nasal swab for viral diagnosis. In total, 1,733 disease reports were recorded and 1,843 nasal swabs were received, of which 48% tested positive for one or more of 14 analyzed viruses. The cohort has been used to date to study diet, sleep and physical activity as determinants for upper respiratory tract infections. Analyses of contact patterns and occupational circumstances as risk factors for the transmission of infections are ongoing. The SWEDE-I study should be seen as a first pioneering effort to provide new insight in the epidemiology and prevention of viral infections. Potential joint collaborations can be discussed with the principal investigators.">
    <entity charOffset="76-82" id="d8a0e6a4cc626dfe6090ea49ce8b920eee3f98e1.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_34935" text="cohort" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="994-1000" id="d8a0e6a4cc626dfe6090ea49ce8b920eee3f98e1.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_34935" text="cohort" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
