<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="de207527ab4b8826e6e8901d63e768c19691b178">
  <chunk id="de207527ab4b8826e6e8901d63e768c19691b178.c0" text="Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus: review of the current situation in the world"/>
  <chunk id="de207527ab4b8826e6e8901d63e768c19691b178.c1" text="This article reviews the current epidemiology and clinical presentation of Middle East Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus (MERS-CoV) infection and describes the preparedness plan of several countries. The MERS-CoV was first reported in 2012 and has since infected more than 1600 patients in 26 countries, mostly in Saudi Arabia and the Middle East. The epidemiology of the infection is compatible with multiple introductions of the virus into humans from an animal reservoir, probably dromedary camels. The clinical presentation ranges from no symptoms to severe pneumonitis and respiratory failure. Most confirmed cases so far were part of MERS-CoV clusters in hospital settings, affecting mainly middle-aged men and patients with a chronic disease or immuno-suppressed status. There is no vaccine or anti-viral medication available. Viral epidemics can occur anywhere in today's &quot;global village&quot;. MERS-CoV is a relatively new virus, and this work is intended to add to the still-sparse data on its epidemiology, modes of transmission, natural history, and clinical features as well as to describe the preparedness plan for MERS-CoV infection in several countries. Effective national and international preparedness plans are essential to predict and control outbreaks, improve patient management, and ensure global health security.">
    <entity charOffset="648-656" id="de207527ab4b8826e6e8901d63e768c19691b178.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33731" text="clusters" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="962-965" id="de207527ab4b8826e6e8901d63e768c19691b178.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_40799" text="add" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="de207527ab4b8826e6e8901d63e768c19691b178.c1.e0" e2="de207527ab4b8826e6e8901d63e768c19691b178.c1.e1" id="de207527ab4b8826e6e8901d63e768c19691b178.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
