<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="df82c611eb38c4c9dbef1a86da01ca432e61c8f7">
  <chunk id="df82c611eb38c4c9dbef1a86da01ca432e61c8f7.c0" text="Pathobiological and Genomic Characterization of a Cold-Adapted Infectious Bronchitis Virus (BP-caKII)"/>
  <chunk id="df82c611eb38c4c9dbef1a86da01ca432e61c8f7.c1" text="We established a cold-adapted infectious bronchitis virus (BP-caKII) by passaging a field virus through specific pathogen-free embryonated eggs 20 times at 32 • C. We characterized its growth kinetics and pathogenicity in embryonated eggs, and its tropism and persistence in different tissues from chickens; then, we evaluated pathogenicity by using a new premature reproductive tract pathogenicity model. Furthermore, we determined the complete genomic sequence of BP-caKII to understand the genetic changes related to cold adaptation. According to our results, BP-caKII clustered with the KII genotype viruses K2 and KM91, and showed less pathogenicity than K2, a live attenuated vaccine strain. BP-caKII showed delayed viremia, resulting in its delayed dissemination to the kidneys and cecal tonsils compared to K2 and KM91, the latter of which is a pathogenic field strain. A comparative genomics study revealed similar nucleotide sequences between BP-caKII, K2 and KM91 but clearly showed different mutations among them. BP-caKII shared several mutations with K2 (nsp13, 14, 15 and 16) following embryo adaptation but acquired multiple additional mutations in nonstructural proteins (nsp3, 4 and 12), spike proteins and nucleocapsid proteins following cold adaptation. Thus, the establishment of BP-caKII and the identified mutations in this study may provide insight into the genetic background of embryo and cold adaptations, and the attenuation of coronaviruses.">
    <entity charOffset="924-934" id="df82c611eb38c4c9dbef1a86da01ca432e61c8f7.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_36976" text="nucleotide" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1179-1187" id="df82c611eb38c4c9dbef1a86da01ca432e61c8f7.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1212-1220" id="df82c611eb38c4c9dbef1a86da01ca432e61c8f7.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1238-1246" id="df82c611eb38c4c9dbef1a86da01ca432e61c8f7.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="df82c611eb38c4c9dbef1a86da01ca432e61c8f7.c1.e0" e2="df82c611eb38c4c9dbef1a86da01ca432e61c8f7.c1.e1" id="df82c611eb38c4c9dbef1a86da01ca432e61c8f7.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="df82c611eb38c4c9dbef1a86da01ca432e61c8f7.c1.e0" e2="df82c611eb38c4c9dbef1a86da01ca432e61c8f7.c1.e2" id="df82c611eb38c4c9dbef1a86da01ca432e61c8f7.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="df82c611eb38c4c9dbef1a86da01ca432e61c8f7.c1.e0" e2="df82c611eb38c4c9dbef1a86da01ca432e61c8f7.c1.e3" id="df82c611eb38c4c9dbef1a86da01ca432e61c8f7.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
