<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="e0e0a545d003e79b46773517d09ac3e7af93ba3f">
  <chunk id="e0e0a545d003e79b46773517d09ac3e7af93ba3f.c0" text="Human adenovirus among hospitalized children with respiratory tract infections in"/>
  <chunk id="e0e0a545d003e79b46773517d09ac3e7af93ba3f.c1" text="Background: Human adenoviruses (HAdVs) cause a wide range of diseases. However, the genotype diversity and epidemiological information relating to HAdVs among hospitalized children with respiratory tract infections (RTIs) is limited. Here, we describe the epidemiology and genotype distribution of HAdVs associated with RTIs in Beijing, China. Methods: Nasopharyngeal aspirates (NPA) were collected from hospitalized children with RTIs from April 2017 to March 2018. HAdVs were detected by a TaqMan-based quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction (qPCR) assay, and the hexon gene was used for phylogenetic analysis. Epidemiological data were analyzed using statistical product and service solutions (SPSS) 21.0 software. Results: HAdV was detected in 72 (5.64%) of the 1276 NPA specimens, with most (86.11%, 62/72) HAdV-positives cases detected among children &lt; 6 years of age. HAdV-B3 (56.06%, 37/66) and HAdV-C2 (19.70%, 13/66) were the most frequent. Of the 72 HAdV-infected cases, 27 (37.50%) were co-infected with other respiratory viruses, most commonly parainfluenza virus (12.50%, 9/72) and rhinovirus (9.72%, 7/72). The log number of viral load ranged from 3.30 to 9.14 copies per mL of NPA, with no significant difference between the HAdV mono-and co-infection groups. The main clinical symptoms in the HAdV-infected patients were fever and cough, and 62 (86.11%, 62/72) were diagnosed with pneumonia. Additionally, HAdVs were detected throughout the year with a higher prevalence in summer. Conclusions: HAdV prevalence is related to age and season. HAdV-B and HAdV-C circulated simultaneously among the hospitalized children with RTIs in Beijing, and HAdV-B type 3 and HAdV-C type 2 were the most frequent.">
    <entity charOffset="379-382" id="e0e0a545d003e79b46773517d09ac3e7af93ba3f.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_60833" text="NPA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="576-581" id="e0e0a545d003e79b46773517d09ac3e7af93ba3f.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_82344" text="hexon" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="781-784" id="e0e0a545d003e79b46773517d09ac3e7af93ba3f.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_60833" text="NPA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1203-1206" id="e0e0a545d003e79b46773517d09ac3e7af93ba3f.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_60833" text="NPA" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="e0e0a545d003e79b46773517d09ac3e7af93ba3f.c1.e0" e2="e0e0a545d003e79b46773517d09ac3e7af93ba3f.c1.e1" id="e0e0a545d003e79b46773517d09ac3e7af93ba3f.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="e0e0a545d003e79b46773517d09ac3e7af93ba3f.c1.e1" e2="e0e0a545d003e79b46773517d09ac3e7af93ba3f.c1.e2" id="e0e0a545d003e79b46773517d09ac3e7af93ba3f.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="e0e0a545d003e79b46773517d09ac3e7af93ba3f.c1.e1" e2="e0e0a545d003e79b46773517d09ac3e7af93ba3f.c1.e3" id="e0e0a545d003e79b46773517d09ac3e7af93ba3f.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
