<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134">
  <chunk id="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c0" text="Heterologous Prime-Boost Regimens with a Recombinant Chimpanzee Adenoviral Vector and Adjuvanted F4 Protein Elicit Polyfunctional HIV-1-Specific T-Cell Responses in Macaques">
    <entity charOffset="100-107" id="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="Protein" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c1" text="HIV-1-specific CD4 + and CD8 + T lymphocytes are important for HIV-1 replication control. F4/AS01 consists of F4 recombinant fusion protein (containing clade B Gag/p24, Pol/RT, Nef and Gag/p17) formulated in AS01 Adjuvant System, and was shown to induce F4specific polyfunctional CD4 + T-cell responses in humans. While replication-incompetent recombinant HIV-1/SIV antigen-expressing human adenoviral vectors can elicit highfrequency antigen-specific CD8 + T-cell responses, their use is hampered by widespread pre-existing immunity to human serotypes. Non-human adenovirus serotypes associated with lower prevalence may offer an alternative strategy. We evaluated the immunogenicity of AdC7-GRN ('A'), a recombinant chimpanzee adenovirus type 7 vector expressing clade B Gag, RT and Nef, and F4/AS01 ('P'), when delivered intramuscularly in homologous (PP or AA) and heterologous (AAPP or PPAA) prime-boost regimens, in macaques and mice. Vaccine-induced HIV-1-antigen-specific T cells in peripheral blood (macaques), liver, spleen, and intestinal and genital mucosa (mice) were characterized by intracellular cytokine staining. Vaccine-specific IgG antibodies (macaques) were detected using ELISA. In macaques, only the heterologous prime-boost regimens induced polyfunctional, persistent and balanced CD4 + and CD8 + T-cell responses specific to each HIV-1 vaccine antigen. AdC7-GRN priming increased the polyfunctionality of F4/AS01-induced CD4 + T cells. Approximately 50% of AdC7-GRN-induced memory CD8 + T cells exhibited an effectormemory phenotype. HIV-1-specific antibodies were detected with each regimen. In mice, antigen-specific CD4 + and CD8 + T-cell responses were detected in the mucosal and systemic anatomical compartments assessed. When administered in heterologous primeboost regimens, AdC7-GRN and F4/AS01 candidate vaccines acted complementarily in inducing potent and persistent peripheral blood HIV-1-specific CD4 + and CD8 + T-cell responses and antibodies in macaques. Besides, adenoviral vector priming modulated the PLOS ONE |">
    <entity charOffset="132-139" id="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="213-221" id="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_60809" text="Adjuvant" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="883-887" id="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_73324" text="AAPP" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="2051-2054" id="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_58972" text="ONE" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c1.e0" e2="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c1.e1" id="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c1.e0" e2="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c1.e2" id="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c1.e0" e2="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c1.e3" id="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c1.e1" e2="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c1.e2" id="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c1.e1" e2="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c1.e3" id="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c1.e2" e2="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c1.e3" id="f0f627b8e856fdf97cf414ac42f3536ff1a33134.c1.p5" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
