<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="f0f89b444071b6fa4be64b86e5d70a4cab8cb492">
  <chunk id="f0f89b444071b6fa4be64b86e5d70a4cab8cb492.c0" text="Longitudinal analysis of the antibody repertoire of a Zika virus-infected patient revealed dynamic changes in antibody response"/>
  <chunk id="f0f89b444071b6fa4be64b86e5d70a4cab8cb492.c1" text="The Zika virus (ZIKV) is a mosquito-borne flavivirus that causes neonatal abnormalities and other disorders. Antibodies to the ZIKV envelope (E) protein can block infection. In this study, next-generation sequencing (NGS) of immunoglobulin heavy chain (IgH) mRNA transcripts was combined with single-cell PCR cloning of E-binding monoclonal antibodies for analysing antibody response in a patient from the early stages of infection to more than one year after the clearance of the virus. The patient's IgH repertoire 14 and 64 days after symptom onset showed dramatic dominant clonal expansion but low clonal diversity. IgH repertoire 6 months after disease-free status had few dominant clones but increased diversity. E-binding antibodies appeared abundantly in the repertoire during the early stages of infection but quickly declined after clearance of the virus. Certain VH genes such as VH5-10-1 and VH4-39 appeared to be preferentially enlisted for a rapid antibody response to ZIKV infection. Most of these antibodies require relatively few somatic hypermutations to acquire the ability to bind to the E protein, pointing to a possible mechanism for rapid defence against ZIKV infection. This study provides a unique and holistic view of the dynamic changes and characteristics of the antibody response to ZIKV infection.">
    <entity charOffset="145-152" id="f0f89b444071b6fa4be64b86e5d70a4cab8cb492.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="258-262" id="f0f89b444071b6fa4be64b86e5d70a4cab8cb492.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33699" text="mRNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1110-1117" id="f0f89b444071b6fa4be64b86e5d70a4cab8cb492.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="f0f89b444071b6fa4be64b86e5d70a4cab8cb492.c1.e0" e2="f0f89b444071b6fa4be64b86e5d70a4cab8cb492.c1.e1" id="f0f89b444071b6fa4be64b86e5d70a4cab8cb492.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="f0f89b444071b6fa4be64b86e5d70a4cab8cb492.c1.e1" e2="f0f89b444071b6fa4be64b86e5d70a4cab8cb492.c1.e2" id="f0f89b444071b6fa4be64b86e5d70a4cab8cb492.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
