<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="f226ecb8f7484ca7943245de562c6f2f08be80a4">
  <chunk id="f226ecb8f7484ca7943245de562c6f2f08be80a4.c0" text="Phylogeographic investigation of 2014 porcine epidemic diarrhea virus (PEDV) transmission in Taiwan"/>
  <chunk id="f226ecb8f7484ca7943245de562c6f2f08be80a4.c1" text="The porcine epidemic diarrhea virus (PEDV) that emerged and spread throughout Taiwan in 2014 triggered significant concern in the country's swine industry. Acknowledging the absence of a thorough investigation at the geographic level, we used 2014 outbreak sequence information from the Taiwan government's open access databases plus GenBank records to analyze PEDV dissemination among Taiwanese pig farms. Genetic sequences, locations, and dates of identified PEDV-positive cases were used to assess spatial, temporal, clustering, GIS, and phylogeographic factors affecting PEDV dissemination. Our conclusion is that S gene sequences from 2014 PEDV-positive clinical samples collected in Taiwan were part of the same Genogroup 2 identified in the US in 2013. According to phylogenetic and phylogeographic data, viral strains collected in different areas were generally independent of each other, with certain clusters identified across different communities. Data from GIS and multiple potential infection factors were used to pinpoint cluster dissemination in areas with large numbers of swine farms in southern Taiwan. The data indicate that the 2014 Taiwan PEDV epidemic resulted from the spread of multiple strains, with strong correlations identified with pig farm numbers and sizes (measured as animal concentrations), feed mill numbers, and the number of slaughterhouses in a specifically defined geographic area.">
    <entity charOffset="910-918" id="f226ecb8f7484ca7943245de562c6f2f08be80a4.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33731" text="clusters" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1037-1044" id="f226ecb8f7484ca7943245de562c6f2f08be80a4.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33731" text="cluster" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="f226ecb8f7484ca7943245de562c6f2f08be80a4.c1.e0" e2="f226ecb8f7484ca7943245de562c6f2f08be80a4.c1.e1" id="f226ecb8f7484ca7943245de562c6f2f08be80a4.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
