<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="f32dc6c0ebf9a1623dc3b3b3eb15cfbaf12755d4">
  <chunk id="f32dc6c0ebf9a1623dc3b3b3eb15cfbaf12755d4.c0" text="First detection and genetic characterization of canine Kobuvirus in domestic dogs in Thailand"/>
  <chunk id="f32dc6c0ebf9a1623dc3b3b3eb15cfbaf12755d4.c1" text="Background: Canine Kobuvirus (CaKoV) has been detected both in healthy and diarrheic dogs and in asymptomatic wild carnivores. In this study, we conducted a survey of CaKoV at small animal hospitals in Bangkok and vicinity of Thailand during September 2016 to September 2018. Results: Three hundred and seven rectal swab samples were collected from healthy dogs (n = 55) and dogs with gastroenteritis symptoms (n = 252). Of 307 swab samples tested by using one-step RT-PCR specific to 3D gene, we found CaKoV positivity at 17.59% (54/307). CaKoVs could be detected in both sick (19.44%) and healthy (9.09%) animals. In relation to age group, CaKoV could be frequently detected in younger dogs (25.45%). Our result showed no seasonal pattern of CaKoV infection in domestic dogs. In this study, we characterized CaKoVs by whole genome sequencing (n = 4) or 3D and VP1 gene sequencing (n = 8). Genetic and phylogenetic analyses showed that whole genomes of Thai CaKoVs were closely related to Chinese CaKoVs with highest 99.5% amino acid identity suggesting possible origin of CaKoVs in Thailand. Conclusions: In conclusion, this study was the first to report the detection and genetic characteristics of CaKoVs in domestic dogs in Thailand. CaKoVs could be detected in both sick and healthy dogs. The virus is frequently detected in younger dogs. Thai CaKoVs were genetically closely related and grouped with Chinese CaKoVs. Our result raises the concerns to vet practitioners that diarrhea in dogs due to canine Kobuvirus infection should not be ignored.">
    <entity charOffset="1024-1029" id="f32dc6c0ebf9a1623dc3b3b3eb15cfbaf12755d4.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_46882" text="amino" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1024-1034" id="f32dc6c0ebf9a1623dc3b3b3eb15cfbaf12755d4.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33704" text="amino acid" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1030-1034" id="f32dc6c0ebf9a1623dc3b3b3eb15cfbaf12755d4.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_37527" text="acid" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="f32dc6c0ebf9a1623dc3b3b3eb15cfbaf12755d4.c1.e0" e2="f32dc6c0ebf9a1623dc3b3b3eb15cfbaf12755d4.c1.e1" id="f32dc6c0ebf9a1623dc3b3b3eb15cfbaf12755d4.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="f32dc6c0ebf9a1623dc3b3b3eb15cfbaf12755d4.c1.e0" e2="f32dc6c0ebf9a1623dc3b3b3eb15cfbaf12755d4.c1.e2" id="f32dc6c0ebf9a1623dc3b3b3eb15cfbaf12755d4.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="f32dc6c0ebf9a1623dc3b3b3eb15cfbaf12755d4.c1.e1" e2="f32dc6c0ebf9a1623dc3b3b3eb15cfbaf12755d4.c1.e2" id="f32dc6c0ebf9a1623dc3b3b3eb15cfbaf12755d4.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
