<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="f81e9eb1b488b5a21f7bfbe5ece67dbd80425f86">
  <chunk id="f81e9eb1b488b5a21f7bfbe5ece67dbd80425f86.c0" text="A Novel Immunochromatographic Strip for Antigen Detection of Avian Infectious Bronchitis Virus">
    <entity charOffset="40-47" id="f81e9eb1b488b5a21f7bfbe5ece67dbd80425f86.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_59132" text="Antigen" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="f81e9eb1b488b5a21f7bfbe5ece67dbd80425f86.c1" text="Avian infectious bronchitis virus (IBV) causes considerable economic losses in the poultry industry worldwide, including Taiwan. IBV is among the most important pathogens in chickens, and it spreads rapidly among flocks. In addition to dozens of known serotypes, new viral variants have emerged due to the viral evolution and antigenic variation in IBVs. Therefore, the development of a sensitive, specific, and easily performed assay is crucial for the rapid detection and surveillance of IBV infections. A rapid and simple immunochromatographic strip (ICS) was developed in this study by employing monoclonal antibodies against spike and nucleocapsid proteins of IBV as the tracer and the capture antibody. The ICS showed high specificity in detecting IBV antigens, including several IBV genotypes and novel variants, as opposed to three other common avian respiratory viruses. The detection limit of the strip reached 10 4.4 50% embryo-infective dose. Moreover, in the experimental chicken model, the strip test demonstrated consistency in detecting IBV with RT-PCR gene detection. Taken together, this antigen detection strip has the potential to serve as an on-farm rapid test for IBV; therefore, it may facilitate surveillance and control of the disease.">
    <entity charOffset="653-661" id="f81e9eb1b488b5a21f7bfbe5ece67dbd80425f86.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="676-682" id="f81e9eb1b488b5a21f7bfbe5ece67dbd80425f86.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_35204" text="tracer" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1106-1113" id="f81e9eb1b488b5a21f7bfbe5ece67dbd80425f86.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_59132" text="antigen" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="f81e9eb1b488b5a21f7bfbe5ece67dbd80425f86.c1.e0" e2="f81e9eb1b488b5a21f7bfbe5ece67dbd80425f86.c1.e1" id="f81e9eb1b488b5a21f7bfbe5ece67dbd80425f86.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="f81e9eb1b488b5a21f7bfbe5ece67dbd80425f86.c1.e0" e2="f81e9eb1b488b5a21f7bfbe5ece67dbd80425f86.c1.e2" id="f81e9eb1b488b5a21f7bfbe5ece67dbd80425f86.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="f81e9eb1b488b5a21f7bfbe5ece67dbd80425f86.c1.e1" e2="f81e9eb1b488b5a21f7bfbe5ece67dbd80425f86.c1.e2" id="f81e9eb1b488b5a21f7bfbe5ece67dbd80425f86.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
