<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="fc221d8af0a962a17778721217b1f9f914f353b4">
  <chunk id="fc221d8af0a962a17778721217b1f9f914f353b4.c0" text="Characterization of anti-MERS-CoV antibodies against various recombinant structural antigens of MERS-CoV in an imported case in China">
    <entity charOffset="84-92" id="fc221d8af0a962a17778721217b1f9f914f353b4.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_59132" text="antigens" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="fc221d8af0a962a17778721217b1f9f914f353b4.c1" text="The first imported case of Middle East respiratory syndrome (MERS) in China recently occurred, allowing for the characterization of antibody titers in a series of the patient's sera using the following methods based on recombinant viral structural antigens: inactivated MERS coronavirus (MERS-CoV) enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA), recombinant MERS-CoV spike (S, or fragments of S) ELISA, nucleoprotein (NP) ELISA and MERS S pseudovirus particle-based neutralization test (ppNT). A longitudinal profile of the infection showed that seroconversion detected by ELISAs based on the recombinant extracellular domain, S, S1 and receptor-binding domain (RBD) antigens occurred as early as neutralizing antibodies were detected by the ppNT and earlier than antibodies were detected by the inactivated MERS-CoV and N-terminal domain (NTD) ELISAs. Antibodies detected by the NP ELISA occurred last. Strong correlations were found between the S1, RBD and NP ELISAs and the inactivated MERS-CoV ELISA. The S and RBD ELISAs were highly correlated with the commercial S1 ELISA. The S ELISA strongly correlated with the ppNT, although the MERS-CoV, S1, NTD and RBD ELISAs were also significantly correlated with the ppNT (Po0.001).">
    <entity charOffset="248-256" id="fc221d8af0a962a17778721217b1f9f914f353b4.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_59132" text="antigens" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="662-670" id="fc221d8af0a962a17778721217b1f9f914f353b4.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_59132" text="antigens" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
