<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="17334b138ba80214847f144ebc57ce27ff9c23cf">
  <chunk id="17334b138ba80214847f144ebc57ce27ff9c23cf.c0" text="Pulmonary melanoma and &quot;crazy paving&quot; patterns in chest images: a case report and literature review">
    <entity charOffset="10-18" id="17334b138ba80214847f144ebc57ce27ff9c23cf.c0.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002861" text="melanoma" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="17334b138ba80214847f144ebc57ce27ff9c23cf.c1" text="Background: In the lung, melanoma is mostly arranged as patterns of multiple nodules, solitary nodules, or miliary invasions. Very rarely, it also displays a &quot;crazy paving&quot; pattern (also described as a &quot;paving stone,&quot; &quot;flagstone,&quot; or &quot;slabstone&quot; pattern), which is rarer still in discrete bilateral nodules. This pattern is considered to be caused by pulmonary alveolar proteinosis, but its association with various diseases is unclear. Case presentation: A 60-year-old man was diagnosed with pulmonary melanoma. Computed tomography revealed discrete bilateral nodules surrounded by a &quot;paving&quot; pattern. A literature review found more than 40 types of diseases that have presented with &quot;paving&quot; patterns in the lung-predominantly pulmonary alveolar proteinosis, viral pneumonia, exogenous lipoid pneumonia, bacterial pneumonia, pulmonary alveolar microlithiasis, interstitial pneumonia, ARDS, squalene aspiration pneumonia, radiation pneumonitis, drug-induced pneumonitis, pulmonary leptospirosis, pulmonary hemorrhage, and pulmonary nocardiosis. Conclusions: We describe the first case of pulmonary melanoma in the form of discrete bilateral nodules accompanied with a computed tomography paving pattern. Although pulmonary paving patterns are rare, more than 40 diseases reportedly display them; clinicians should consider melanoma of the lung in differential diagnoses for patients who show such a pattern.">
    <entity charOffset="25-33" id="17334b138ba80214847f144ebc57ce27ff9c23cf.c1.e0" ontology_id="HP_0002861" text="melanoma" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="289-298" id="17334b138ba80214847f144ebc57ce27ff9c23cf.c1.e1" ontology_id="HP_0012832" text="bilateral" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="503-511" id="17334b138ba80214847f144ebc57ce27ff9c23cf.c1.e2" ontology_id="HP_0002861" text="melanoma" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="551-560" id="17334b138ba80214847f144ebc57ce27ff9c23cf.c1.e3" ontology_id="HP_0012832" text="bilateral" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="901-911" id="17334b138ba80214847f144ebc57ce27ff9c23cf.c1.e4" ontology_id="HP_0002835" text="aspiration" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1099-1107" id="17334b138ba80214847f144ebc57ce27ff9c23cf.c1.e5" ontology_id="HP_0002861" text="melanoma" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1132-1141" id="17334b138ba80214847f144ebc57ce27ff9c23cf.c1.e6" ontology_id="HP_0012832" text="bilateral" type="phenotype"/>
    <entity charOffset="1324-1332" id="17334b138ba80214847f144ebc57ce27ff9c23cf.c1.e7" ontology_id="HP_0002861" text="melanoma" type="phenotype"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
