<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="3d09812aba24146255e664c9ed4ed7d5dcd9e3b3">
  <chunk id="3d09812aba24146255e664c9ed4ed7d5dcd9e3b3.c0" text="Dengue research: a bibliometric analysis of worldwide and Arab publications during 1872-2015"/>
  <chunk id="3d09812aba24146255e664c9ed4ed7d5dcd9e3b3.c1" text="Background: Dengue is an important emerging and re-emerging arboviral infection globally as a rapidly growing and widespread public health problem, with transmission occurring in more than 128 countries in Asia, Americas, southeast Africa, western Pacific, and eastern Mediterranean regions. Therefore, the aim of this study was to characterize and quantify the scientific output of dengue research in Arab countries relative to that worldwide by using a bibliometric analysis. Methods: The standardized search approach based on the use of the the keyword &quot;dengue&quot; in the title, abstract, and keyword field was used to get research output related to dengue at a global level. All data related to dengue were collected from the past to December 31, 2015."/>
  <chunk id="3d09812aba24146255e664c9ed4ed7d5dcd9e3b3.c2" text="Results: A total of 19,581 dengue-related documents identified in the Scopus database. The results show that the study of dengue exhibits an overall upward trend from 1872 to 2015 with peak publications in 2014. The leading countries in dengue research were the USA (4,709; 24.05 %), India (1,942; 9.92 %), Brazil (1,530; 7.81 %), Thailand (1,260; 6.43 %), the UK (1,129; 5.77 %), and France (1,087; 5.55 %). Only 226 (1.16 % of the overall global research effort in the dengue field) articles were published from the Arab region. The total number of citations for all publications was 352,710, with an average of 18.0 citations per publication. Furthermore, the h-index for all extracted data related to dengue research was 186. Kingdom of Saudi Arabia (KSA) was the most productive country in Arab region with 102 documents representing 45.1 %. Furthermore, the h-index for all extracted data related to dengue research was 27. The USA was Arab's most main cooperative partner (46, 20.4 %), followed by India (36, 15.9 %). Conclusions: The amount of literature related to dengue research has considerably increased over the last decade. This bibliometric analysis has demonstrated the leading role that the USA, India, Brazil, Thailand, the UK, and France play in dengue research. The Arab world produced fewer publications related to dengue with lower quality than other world countries."/>
</document>
