<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="28876403_en">
  <chunk id="28876403_en.c0" text="Antimicrobial drug-related problems in a neonatal intensive care unit.">
    <entity charOffset="0-13" id="28876403_en.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33281" text="Antimicrobial" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="28876403_en.c1" text="The goal was to determine the main drug-related problems in neonates who were using antimicrobials.This was an observational, prospective and longitudinal study. Drug-related problems were classified according to version 6.2 of the Pharmaceutical Care Network Europe Foundation classification. A descriptive analysis was performed, in which the clinical and therapeutic variables were presented as absolute and relative frequencies or as the mean and standard deviation, as appropriate.In total, 152 neonates with a predominance of males (58.5%), gestational age of 32.7 ± 4.2 weeks and weight of 1,903.1 ± 846.9g were included. The main diagnostic hypothesis of infection was early sepsis (66.5%), and 71.7% of the neonates had some risk factor for infection. Among the neonates, 33.6% had at least one drug-related problem. Of these, 84.8% were related to treatment effectiveness and 15.2% to adverse reactions. The main cause of drug-related problems was the selected dose, particularly for aminoglycosides and cephalosporins.The use of antimicrobials in the neonatal intensive care is mainly associated with problems related to medication effectiveness, predominantly the prescription of subdoses of antimicrobials, especially aminoglycosides.">
    <entity charOffset="84-98" id="28876403_en.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33281" text="antimicrobials" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="232-246" id="28876403_en.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_52217" text="Pharmaceutical" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="994-1009" id="28876403_en.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_47779" text="aminoglycosides" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1040-1054" id="28876403_en.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_33281" text="antimicrobials" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1204-1218" id="28876403_en.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_33281" text="antimicrobials" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1231-1246" id="28876403_en.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_47779" text="aminoglycosides" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
