<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="30088524_en">
  <chunk id="30088524_en.c0" text="Experimental study of femoral vein reconstruction with sugarcane biopolymer tubular graft.">
    <entity charOffset="65-75" id="30088524_en.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33694" text="biopolymer" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="30088524_en.c1" text="to evaluate, through Doppler flowmetry, venography, histology and clinical evolution, the use of sugarcane biopolymer (BP) tubular grafts in the reconstruction of femoral veins in dogs.we submitted eight adult dogs to femoral vein reconstruction, on the left with BP tubular graft and on the right with autologous vein. In the postoperative period, the animals underwent clinical evaluation and femoral vein Doppler flowmetry. After 360 days, we reoperated the dogs and submitted them to femoral vein phlebography with iodinated contrast. We removed the segments of the femoral veins containing the grafts and sent them for histopathological evaluation.the dogs did not present hemorrhage, hematoma, surgical wound infection or operated limb edema. One animal had superficial venous dilatation in the left inguinal region. Phlebography performed 360 days after the first surgery showed that three (37.5%) BP grafts and seven (87.5%) grafts from the control group (C) were patent. In the histopathological evaluation, we found an inflammatory reaction, with neutrophils and lymphocytes on the external surface of both groups. In the intimal layer of the grafts and in the outer layer in the two groups, we observed fibrosis.based on the results obtained with the experimental model used, BP presents potential to be used as a tubular graft for venous revascularization. However, new research must be performed to confirm its efficacy in the revascularization of medium and large diameter veins, which could allow its use in clinical practice.">
    <entity charOffset="107-117" id="30088524_en.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33694" text="biopolymer" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
