<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="30156663_en">
  <chunk id="30156663_en.c0" text="Leprosy in individuals under the age of fifteen in priority cities, Mato Grosso, Brazil.">
    <entity charOffset="0-7" id="30156663_en.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_1024" text="Leprosy" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="30156663_en.c1" text="We aimed to compare the sociodemographic, clinical and epidemiological characteristics of individuals under the age of 15, reported to have leprosy, and who lived in priority and non-priority cities, as well as to compare the spatial distribution of these reported cases in such cities. This is a cross-sectional study of new leprosy cases in individuals under the age of 15 (n=429) registered in the Information System for Notifiable Diseases from the State of Mato Grosso, Brazil, between 2011 and 2013. The diagnosed cases were compared regarding sociodemographic, clinical and epidemiological aspects using the chi-square test at a 5% significance level. The spatial distribution was made through ArcGIS 10.2 software.Of the 141 assessed cities in the state, according to the spatial distribution, 58.1% (n=82) showed a high, very high and hyper-endemic mean incidence coefficient, and, of these, 34.1% (n=28) include the group of priority municipalities. Of the new cases included in the study, 73.9% (n=317) were reported in priority cities. We observed a difference in the proportion of cases registered among the cities, with a greater proportion in priority cities, in the age group from five to nine years old (χ²=4.09; p=0.043), in the white race (χ²=7.01; p=0.008) and in the tuberculoid clinical form (χ²=3.89; p=0.048). There was a greater proportion in non-priority cases with regard to non-urban areas (χ²=24.23; p&lt;0.001), two to five skin lesions (χ²=5.93; p=0.014) and spontaneous demand (χ²=6.16; p=0.013).The differences highlighted regarding clinical and epidemiological characteristics between the cities demonstrate the difficulty of endemic control in both municipality groups.">
    <entity charOffset="140-147" id="30156663_en.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_1024" text="leprosy" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="326-333" id="30156663_en.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_1024" text="leprosy" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
