<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="30328938_en">
  <chunk id="30328938_en.c0" text="Factors associated with underreporting of tuberculosis based on data from Sinan Aids and Sinan TB.">
    <entity charOffset="42-54" id="30328938_en.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_399" text="tuberculosis" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="80-84" id="30328938_en.c0.e1" ontology_id="DOID_635" text="Aids" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="30328938_en.c1" text="Tuberculosis (TB) is one of the world's major public health problems. Epidemiological surveillance has proved to be an important tool to assist in the control and prevention of communicable diseases such as TB and AIDS. This study aimed to estimate the rate and factors associated with the underreporting of TB among cases of coinfection with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)/AIDS in the state of Pernambuco, based on data from the TB and Aids Notifiable Diseases Information System (Sinan TB and Sinan AIDS).A cross-sectional study was carried out based on the records of the TB and AIDS Notification System to identify cases of TB underreporting in the study period. In order to identify underreporting, a probabilistic linkage was undertaken using RecLink III software.The rate of TB underreporting was 29%, and the factors associated were: presenting a clinical form of TB as cavitary or unspecified pulmonary TB or having both kinds of TB at the same time; being treated outside the municipality of Recife; and being treated at health services not specialized for HIV/AIDS.The proportion of underreporting found in our study was lower than that observed in other Brazilian studies that took into account underreporting from mortality data.The variables associated with underreporting of TB were mostly related to the healthcare system rather than to individual characteristics, which points to the need for training of health professionals in order to notify the information systems correctly.">
    <entity charOffset="0-12" id="30328938_en.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_399" text="Tuberculosis" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="214-218" id="30328938_en.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_635" text="AIDS" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="441-445" id="30328938_en.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_635" text="Aids" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="586-590" id="30328938_en.c1.e3" ontology_id="DOID_635" text="AIDS" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1075-1079" id="30328938_en.c1.e4" ontology_id="DOID_635" text="AIDS" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
