<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="32965375_en">
  <chunk id="32965375_en.c0" text="The experience with volunteer and collaborative work in mental health and psychosocial care during the COVID-19 pandemic.">
    <entity charOffset="103-111" id="32965375_en.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_0080600" text="COVID-19" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="32965375_en.c1" text="Brazil is the country of the world with the second most COVID-19 cases and deaths, and the pandemic's impacts pose multiple challenges for mental health. This paper reports on experience with the emergency organization of the volunteer and collaborative Working Group (GT, in Portuguese) on mental health and psychosocial care aimed at producing rapid responses for health services in the context of COVID-19. The study involved the identification and systematization of current evidence in the scientific literature on mental health and psychosocial care in public health emergencies and pandemics, with the establishment of a network involving 117 researchers and 25 institutions, and the organization of themes for the elaboration of materials, referenced on the response phases in public health emergencies and pandemics. In less than 60 days, 18 technical documents were produced, ranging from services organization and management for different vulnerable groups. The materials became references in health institutions and services. A national course on mental health and psychosocial care in COVID-19 was also organized, with more than 60,000 people registered. The experience provides food for thought and a contribution for future experiences involving knowledge translation in the current pandemic and in future public health emergencies and pandemics, with the following: (1) combination of volunteer and collaborative work involving professionals with experience in the organization of services and care in past events; (2) reliance on institutional support and resources; (3) speed and credibility of work involving the establishment of networks of professionals and institutions; and (4) responses to the urgent needs with the capacity to shape paths for care in mental health and psychosocial care.">
    <entity charOffset="56-64" id="32965375_en.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_0080600" text="COVID-19" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="400-408" id="32965375_en.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_0080600" text="COVID-19" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1098-1106" id="32965375_en.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_0080600" text="COVID-19" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1192-1196" id="32965375_en.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_33290" text="food" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="32965375_en.c1.e0" e2="32965375_en.c1.e3" id="32965375_en.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="32965375_en.c1.e1" e2="32965375_en.c1.e3" id="32965375_en.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="32965375_en.c1.e2" e2="32965375_en.c1.e3" id="32965375_en.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
