<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="0049ba8861864506e1e8559e7815f4de8b03dbed">
  <chunk id="0049ba8861864506e1e8559e7815f4de8b03dbed.c0" text="GPI-anchored single chain Fv -an effective way to capture transiently-exposed neutralization epitopes on HIV-1 envelope spike"/>
  <chunk id="0049ba8861864506e1e8559e7815f4de8b03dbed.c1" text="Background: Identification of broad neutralization epitopes in HIV-1 envelope spikes is paramount for HIV-1 vaccine development. A few broad neutralization epitopes identified so far are present on the surface of native HIV-1 envelope spikes whose recognition by antibodies does not depend on conformational changes of the envelope spikes. However, HIV-1 envelope spikes also contain transiently-exposed neutralization epitopes, which are more difficult to identify. Results: In this study, we constructed single chain Fvs (scFvs) derived from seven human monoclonal antibodies and genetically linked them with or without a glycosyl-phosphatidylinositol (GPI) attachment signal. We show that with a GPI attachment signal the scFvs are targeted to lipid rafts of plasma membranes. In addition, we demonstrate that four of the GPI-anchored scFvs, but not their secreted counterparts, neutralize HIV-1 with various degrees of breadth and potency. Among them, GPI-anchored scFv (X5) exhibits extremely potent and broad neutralization activity against multiple clades of HIV-1 strains tested. Moreover, we show that GPI-anchored scFv (4E10) also exhibited more potent neutralization activity than its secretory counterpart. Finally, we demonstrate that expression of GPI-anchored scFv (X5) in the lipid raft of plasma membrane of human CD4 + T cells confers longterm resistance to HIV-1 infection, HIV-1 envelope-mediated cell-cell fusion, and the infection of HIV-1 captured and transferred by human DCs.">
    <entity charOffset="655-658" id="0049ba8861864506e1e8559e7815f4de8b03dbed.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_36315" text="GPI" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="699-702" id="0049ba8861864506e1e8559e7815f4de8b03dbed.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_36315" text="GPI" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="747-752" id="0049ba8861864506e1e8559e7815f4de8b03dbed.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_18059" text="lipid" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1292-1297" id="0049ba8861864506e1e8559e7815f4de8b03dbed.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_18059" text="lipid" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="0049ba8861864506e1e8559e7815f4de8b03dbed.c2" text="Conclusions: Thus GPI-anchored scFv could be used as a general and effective way to identify antibodies that react with transiently-exposed neutralization epitopes in envelope proteins of HIV-1 and other enveloped viruses. The GPI-anchored scFv (X5), because of its breadth and potency, should have a great potential to be developed into anti-viral agent for HIV-1 prevention and therapy.">
    <entity charOffset="176-184" id="0049ba8861864506e1e8559e7815f4de8b03dbed.c2.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="338-354" id="0049ba8861864506e1e8559e7815f4de8b03dbed.c2.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_22587" text="anti-viral agent" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
