<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="03a158fb5fcbfccd841b4a9638e840a0302b9459">
  <chunk id="03a158fb5fcbfccd841b4a9638e840a0302b9459.c0" text="The DE and FG loops of the HPV major capsid protein contribute to the epitopes of vaccine-induced cross-neutralising antibodies OPEN">
    <entity charOffset="44-51" id="03a158fb5fcbfccd841b4a9638e840a0302b9459.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="03a158fb5fcbfccd841b4a9638e840a0302b9459.c1" text="The human papillomavirus (HPV) vaccines consist of major capsid protein (L1) virus-like particles (VLP) and are highly efficacious against the development of cervical cancer precursors attributable to oncogenic genotypes, HPV16 and HPV18. A degree of vaccine-induced cross-protection has also been demonstrated against genetically-related genotypes in the Alpha-7 (HPV18-like) and Alpha-9 (HPV16like) species groups which is coincident with the detection of L1 cross-neutralising antibodies. In this study the L1 domains recognised by inter-genotype cross-neutralising antibodies were delineated. L1 crystallographic homology models predicted a degree of structural diversity between the L1 loops of HPV16 and the non-vaccine Alpha-9 genotypes. These structural predictions informed the design of chimeric pseudovirions with inter-genotype loop swaps which demonstrated that the L1 domains recognised by inter-genotype cross-neutralising antibodies comprise residues within the DE loop and the late region of the FG loop. These data contribute to our understanding of the L1 domains recognised by vaccine-induced cross-neutralising antibodies. Such specificities may play a critical role in vaccineinduced cross-protection.">
    <entity charOffset="64-71" id="03a158fb5fcbfccd841b4a9638e840a0302b9459.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="158-173" id="03a158fb5fcbfccd841b4a9638e840a0302b9459.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_4362" text="cervical cancer" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="167-173" id="03a158fb5fcbfccd841b4a9638e840a0302b9459.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_162" text="cancer" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1183-1187" id="03a158fb5fcbfccd841b4a9638e840a0302b9459.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="03a158fb5fcbfccd841b4a9638e840a0302b9459.c1.e0" e2="03a158fb5fcbfccd841b4a9638e840a0302b9459.c1.e1" id="03a158fb5fcbfccd841b4a9638e840a0302b9459.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="03a158fb5fcbfccd841b4a9638e840a0302b9459.c1.e0" e2="03a158fb5fcbfccd841b4a9638e840a0302b9459.c1.e2" id="03a158fb5fcbfccd841b4a9638e840a0302b9459.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="03a158fb5fcbfccd841b4a9638e840a0302b9459.c1.e1" e2="03a158fb5fcbfccd841b4a9638e840a0302b9459.c1.e3" id="03a158fb5fcbfccd841b4a9638e840a0302b9459.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="03a158fb5fcbfccd841b4a9638e840a0302b9459.c1.e2" e2="03a158fb5fcbfccd841b4a9638e840a0302b9459.c1.e3" id="03a158fb5fcbfccd841b4a9638e840a0302b9459.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
