<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="066619641442d9c3f6a547301849bef0b8b12f2f">
  <chunk id="066619641442d9c3f6a547301849bef0b8b12f2f.c0" text="Perspectives of Australian policy-makers on the potential benefits and risks of technologically enhanced communicable disease surveillance -a modified Delphi survey">
    <entity charOffset="118-125" id="066619641442d9c3f6a547301849bef0b8b12f2f.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="066619641442d9c3f6a547301849bef0b8b12f2f.c1" text="Background: Event-based social media monitoring and pathogen whole genome sequencing (WGS) will enhance communicable disease surveillance research and systems. If linked electronically and scanned systematically, the information provided by these technologies could be mined to uncover new epidemiological patterns and associations much faster than traditional public health approaches. The benefits of earlier outbreak detection are significant, but implementation could be opposed in the absence of a social licence or if ethical and legal concerns are not addressed. Methods: A three-phase mixed-method Delphi survey with Australian policy-makers, health practitioners and lawyers (n = 44) was conducted to explore areas of consensus and disagreement over (1) key policy and practical issues raised by the introduction of novel communicable disease surveillance programmes; and (2) the most significant and likely risks from using social media content and WGS technologies in epidemiological research and outbreak investigations.">
    <entity charOffset="117-124" id="066619641442d9c3f6a547301849bef0b8b12f2f.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="844-851" id="066619641442d9c3f6a547301849bef0b8b12f2f.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="066619641442d9c3f6a547301849bef0b8b12f2f.c2" text="Results: Panellists agreed that the integration of social media monitoring and WGS technologies into communicable disease surveillance systems raised significant issues, including impacts on personal privacy, medicolegal risks and the potential for unintended consequences. Notably, their concerns focused on how these technologies should be used, rather than how the data was collected.">
    <entity charOffset="114-121" id="066619641442d9c3f6a547301849bef0b8b12f2f.c2.e0" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
