<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303">
  <chunk id="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c0" text="The 2 nd sialic acid-binding site of influenza A virus neuraminidase is an important determinant of the hemagglutinin- neuraminidase-receptor balance">
    <entity charOffset="37-46" id="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1" text="Influenza A virus (IAV) neuraminidase (NA) receptor-destroying activity and hemagglutinin (HA) receptor-binding affinity need to be balanced with the host receptor repertoire for optimal viral fitness. NAs of avian, but not human viruses, contain a functional 2 nd sialic acid (SIA)-binding site (2SBS) adjacent to the catalytic site, which contributes to sialidase activity against multivalent substrates. The receptor-binding specificity and potentially crucial contribution of the 2SBS to the HA-NA balance of virus particles is, however, poorly characterized. Here, we elucidated the receptor-binding specificity of the 2SBS of N2 NA and established an important role for this site in the virion HA-NA-receptor balance. NAs of H2N2/1957 pandemic virus with or without a functional 2SBS and viruses containing this NA were analysed. Avian-like N2, with a restored 2SBS due to an amino acid substitution at position 367, was more active than human N2 on multivalent substrates containing α2,3linked SIAs, corresponding with the pronounced binding-specificity of avian-like N2 for these receptors. When introduced into human viruses, avian-like N2 gave rise to altered plaque morphology and decreased replication compared to human N2. An opposite replication phenotype was observed when N2 was combined with avian-like HA. Specific bio-layer interferometry assays revealed a clear effect of the 2SBS on the dynamic interaction of virus particles with receptors. The absence or presence of a functional 2SBS affected virionreceptor binding and receptor cleavage required for particle movement on a receptor-coated surface and subsequent NA-dependent self-elution. The contribution of the 2SBS to virusreceptor interactions depended on the receptor-binding properties of HA and the identity of the receptors used. We conclude that the 2SBS is an important and underappreciated determinant of the HA-NA-receptor balance. The rapid loss of a functional 2SBS in pandemic viruses may have served to balance the novel host receptor-repertoire and altered receptorbinding properties of the corresponding HA protein.">
    <entity charOffset="0-9" id="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="Influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="265-276" id="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_26667" text="sialic acid" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="272-276" id="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_37527" text="acid" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="667-671" id="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="882-887" id="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_46882" text="amino" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="882-892" id="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_33704" text="amino acid" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="888-892" id="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.e6" ontology_id="CHEBI_37527" text="acid" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.e0" e2="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.e1" id="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.e0" e2="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.e2" id="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.e0" e2="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.e3" id="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.e0" e2="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.e4" id="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.e0" e2="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.e5" id="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.e0" e2="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.e6" id="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c1.p5" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c2" text="Influenza A viruses infect birds and mammals. They contain receptor-binding (HA) and receptor-destroying (NA) proteins, which are crucial determinants of host tropism and pathogenesis. It is generally accepted that the functional properties of HA and NA need to be well balanced to enable virion penetration of the receptor-rich mucus layer, binding to host cells, and release of newly assembled particles. This HA-NA-receptor balance is, however, poorly characterized resulting in part from a lack of suitable assays to measure this balance. In addition, NA is much less studied than HA. NA contains, besides its receptorcleavage site, a 2 nd receptor-binding site, which is functional in avian, but not in human viruses. We now show that this 2 nd receptor-binding site prefers binding to avian-type receptors and promotes cleavage of substrates carrying this receptor. Furthermore, by using novel assays, we established an important role for this site in the HA-NA-receptor balance of virus particles as it contributes to receptor binding and cleavage by virions, the latter of which is required for virion movement and self-elution from receptors. The results may provide an explanation for the rapid loss of a functional 2 nd receptor-binding site in human pandemic viruses.">
    <entity charOffset="0-9" id="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c2.e0" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="Influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="936-940" id="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c2.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c2.e0" e2="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c2.e1" id="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c2.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c3" text="Role for 2 nd SIA-binding site of IAV NA in HA-NA-receptor balance PLOS Pathogens | https://doi.org/10.">
    <entity charOffset="0-4" id="073bf7a5962595098cf9d08109b0db9ea1cb3303.c3.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="Role" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
