<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="075fc26a9bf29767e3e3e29e22121ce3980fcbf2">
  <chunk id="075fc26a9bf29767e3e3e29e22121ce3980fcbf2.c0" text="Viral communities associated with porcine respiratory disease complex in intensive commercial farms in Sichuan province, China">
    <entity charOffset="54-61" id="075fc26a9bf29767e3e3e29e22121ce3980fcbf2.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="075fc26a9bf29767e3e3e29e22121ce3980fcbf2.c1" text="Porcine respiratory disease complex (PRDC), a common piglet disease, causes substantive economic losses in pig farming. To investigate the viral diversity associated with PRDC, the viral communities in serum and nasal swabs from 26 PRDC-affected piglets were investigated using metagenomics. By deep sequencing and de novo assembly, 17 viruses were identified in two pooled libraries (16 viruses from serum, nine from nasal swabs). Porcine circovirus (PCV)-2, porcine reproductive and respiratory syndrome virus (PRRSV) and pseudorabies virus, all commonly associated with PRDC, were identified in the two pooled samples by metagenomics, but most viruses comprised small linear and circular DNAs (e.g. parvoviruses, bocaviruses and circoviruses). PCR was used to compare the detection rates of each virus in the serum samples from 36 PRDC-affected piglets versus 38 location-matched clinically healthy controls. The average virus category per sample was 6.81 for the PRDC-affected piglets and 4.09 for the controls. Single or co-infections with PCV-2 or PRRSV had very high detection rates in the PRDCaffected piglets. Interestingly, porcine parvovirus (PPV)-2, PPV-3, PPV-6 and torque teno sus virus 1a were significantly associated with PRDC. These results illustrate the complexity of viral communities in the PRDC-affected piglets and highlight the candidate viruses associated with it.">
    <entity charOffset="20-27" id="075fc26a9bf29767e3e3e29e22121ce3980fcbf2.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="60-67" id="075fc26a9bf29767e3e3e29e22121ce3980fcbf2.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="497-505" id="075fc26a9bf29767e3e3e29e22121ce3980fcbf2.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_225" text="syndrome" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1179-1185" id="075fc26a9bf29767e3e3e29e22121ce3980fcbf2.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_39294" text="torque" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="075fc26a9bf29767e3e3e29e22121ce3980fcbf2.c1.e0" e2="075fc26a9bf29767e3e3e29e22121ce3980fcbf2.c1.e3" id="075fc26a9bf29767e3e3e29e22121ce3980fcbf2.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="075fc26a9bf29767e3e3e29e22121ce3980fcbf2.c1.e1" e2="075fc26a9bf29767e3e3e29e22121ce3980fcbf2.c1.e3" id="075fc26a9bf29767e3e3e29e22121ce3980fcbf2.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="075fc26a9bf29767e3e3e29e22121ce3980fcbf2.c1.e2" e2="075fc26a9bf29767e3e3e29e22121ce3980fcbf2.c1.e3" id="075fc26a9bf29767e3e3e29e22121ce3980fcbf2.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
