<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="0910e151cd1fb8d455e54cd4e97f867627f934c8">
  <chunk id="0910e151cd1fb8d455e54cd4e97f867627f934c8.c0" text="Research Article Disparities in Spatial Prevalence of Feline Retroviruses due to Data Aggregation: A Case of the Modifiable Areal Unit Problem"/>
  <chunk id="0910e151cd1fb8d455e54cd4e97f867627f934c8.c1" text="The knowledge of the spatial distribution feline immunodeficiency virus and feline leukemia virus infections, which are untreatable, can inform on their risk factors and high-risk areas to enhance control. However, when spatial analysis involves aggregated spatial data, results may be influenced by the spatial scale of aggregation, an effect known as the modifiable areal unit problem (MAUP). In this study, area level risk factors for both infections in 28,914 cats tested with ELISA were investigated by multivariable spatial Poisson regression models along with MAUP effect on spatial clustering and cluster detection (for postal codes, counties, and states) by Moran's test and spatial scan test, respectively. The study results indicate that the significance and magnitude of the association of risk factors with both infections varied with aggregation scale. Further more, Moran's test only identified spatial clustering at postal code and county levels of aggregation. Similarly, the spatial scan test indicated that the number, size, and location of clusters varied over aggregation scales. In conclusion, the association between infection and area was influenced by the choice of spatial scale and indicates the importance of study design and data analysis with respect to specific research questions.">
    <entity charOffset="83-91" id="0910e151cd1fb8d455e54cd4e97f867627f934c8.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_1240" text="leukemia" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="605-612" id="0910e151cd1fb8d455e54cd4e97f867627f934c8.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33731" text="cluster" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1060-1068" id="0910e151cd1fb8d455e54cd4e97f867627f934c8.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_33731" text="clusters" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="0910e151cd1fb8d455e54cd4e97f867627f934c8.c1.e0" e2="0910e151cd1fb8d455e54cd4e97f867627f934c8.c1.e1" id="0910e151cd1fb8d455e54cd4e97f867627f934c8.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="0910e151cd1fb8d455e54cd4e97f867627f934c8.c1.e0" e2="0910e151cd1fb8d455e54cd4e97f867627f934c8.c1.e2" id="0910e151cd1fb8d455e54cd4e97f867627f934c8.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
