<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="0943374130f5f8474d6d480d4d038615a0e36de3">
  <chunk id="0943374130f5f8474d6d480d4d038615a0e36de3.c0" text="Interferon-a Improves Phosphoantigen-Induced Vc9Vd2 T-Cells Interferon-c Production during Chronic HCV Infection"/>
  <chunk id="0943374130f5f8474d6d480d4d038615a0e36de3.c1" text="In chronic HCV infection, treatment failure and defective host immune response highly demand improved therapy strategies. Vc9Vd2 T-cells may inhibit HCV replication in vitro through IFN-c release after Phosphoantigen (PhAg) stimulation. The aim of our work was to analyze Vc9Vd2 T-cell functionality during chronic HCV infection, studying the role of IFN-a on their function capability. IFN-c production by Vc9Vd2 T-cells was analyzed in vitro in 24 HCV-infected patients and 35 healthy donors (HD) after PhAg stimulation with or without IFN-a. The effect of in vivo PhAg/IFN-a administration on plasma IFN-c levels was analyzed in M. fascicularis monkeys. A quantitative analysis of IFN-c mRNA level and stability in Vc9Vd2 T-cells was also evaluated. During chronic HCV infection, Vc9Vd2 T-cells showed an effector/activated phenotype and were significantly impaired in IFN-c production. Interestingly, IFN-a was able to improve their IFN-c response to PhAg both in vitro in HD and HCV-infected patients, and in vivo in Macaca fascicularis primates. Finally, IFN-a increased IFN-c-mRNA transcription and stability in PhAg-activated Vc9Vd2 T-cells. Altogether our results show a functional impairment of Vc9Vd2 T-cells during chronic HCV infection that can be partially restored by using IFN-a. A study aimed to evaluate the antiviral impact of PhAg/IFN-a combination may provide new insight in designing possible combined strategies to improve HCV infection treatment outcome.">
    <entity charOffset="202-216" id="0943374130f5f8474d6d480d4d038615a0e36de3.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_59544" text="Phosphoantigen" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="343-347" id="0943374130f5f8474d6d480d4d038615a0e36de3.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="690-694" id="0943374130f5f8474d6d480d4d038615a0e36de3.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_33699" text="mRNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1326-1335" id="0943374130f5f8474d6d480d4d038615a0e36de3.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_22587" text="antiviral" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
