<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="12d7a96036ca9e861d3636d55d3841452e455c73">
  <chunk id="12d7a96036ca9e861d3636d55d3841452e455c73.c0" text="Infectious Complications during Tandem High-Dose Chemotherapy and Autologous Stem Cell Transplantation for Children with High-Risk or Recurrent Solid Tumors"/>
  <chunk id="12d7a96036ca9e861d3636d55d3841452e455c73.c1" text="We retrospectively analyzed infectious complications during tandem high-dose chemotherapy and autologous stem cell transplantation (HDCT/auto-SCT) in children and adolescents with high-risk or recurrent solid tumors. A total of 324 patients underwent their first HDCT/ auto-SCT between October 2004 and September 2014, and 283 of them proceeded to their second HDCT/auto-SCT (a total of 607 HDCT/auto-SCTs). During the early transplant period of 607 HDCT/auto-SCTs (from the beginning of HDCT to day 30 post-transplant), bacteremia, urinary tract infection (UTI), respiratory virus infection, and varicella zoster virus (VZV) reactivation occurred in 7.1%, 2.3%, 13.0%, and 2.5% of HDCT/auto-SCTs, respectively. The early transplant period of the second HDCT/auto-SCT had infectious complications similar to the first HDCT/auto-SCT. During the late transplant period of HDCT/ auto-SCT (from day 31 to 1 year post-transplant), bacteremia, UTI, and VZV reactivation occurred in 7.5%, 2.5%, and 3.9% of patients, respectively. Most infectious complications in the late transplant period occurred during the first 6 months post-transplant. There were no invasive fungal infections during the study period. Six patients died from infectious complications (4 from bacterial sepsis and 2 from respiratory virus infection). Our study suggests that infectious complications are similar following second and first HDCT/auto-SCT in children.">
    <entity charOffset="533-556" id="12d7a96036ca9e861d3636d55d3841452e455c73.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_13148" text="urinary tract infection" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="597-606" id="12d7a96036ca9e861d3636d55d3841452e455c73.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_8659" text="varicella" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1258-1274" id="12d7a96036ca9e861d3636d55d3841452e455c73.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_0040085" text="bacterial sepsis" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
