<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="154880a8053db7adb802ae5350656b649496b4a3">
  <chunk id="154880a8053db7adb802ae5350656b649496b4a3.c0" text="DC-SIGN (CD209) Promoter −336 A/G (rs4804803) Polymorphism Associated with Susceptibility of Kawasaki Disease">
    <entity charOffset="93-109" id="154880a8053db7adb802ae5350656b649496b4a3.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_13378" text="Kawasaki Disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="102-109" id="154880a8053db7adb802ae5350656b649496b4a3.c0.e1" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="Disease" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="154880a8053db7adb802ae5350656b649496b4a3.c1" text="Kawasaki disease (KD) is characterized by systemic vasculitis of unknown etiology. High-dose intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIG) is the most effective therapy for KD to reduce the prevalence of coronary artery lesion (CAL) formation. Recently, the α2, 6 sialylated IgG was reported to interact with a lectin receptor, specific intracellular adhesion molecule-3 grabbing nonintegrin homolog-related 1 (SIGN-R1) in mice and dendritic cell-specific intercellular adhesion molecule-3 grabbing nonintegrin (DC-SIGN) in human, and to trigger an anti-inflammatory cascade. This study was conducted to investigate whether the polymorphism of DC-SIGN (CD209) promoter −336 A/G (rs4804803) is responsible for susceptibility and CAL formation in KD patients using Custom TaqMan SNP Genotyping Assays. A total of 521 subjects (278 KD patients and 243 controls) were investigated to identify an SNP of rs4804803, and they were studied and showed a significant association between the genotypes and allele frequency of rs4804803 in control subjects and KD patients (P = 0.004 under the dominant model). However, the promoter variant of DC-SIGN gene was not associated with the occurrence of IVIG resistance, CAL formation in KD. The G allele of DC-SIGN promoter −336 (rs4804803) is a risk allele in the development of KD.">
    <entity charOffset="0-16" id="154880a8053db7adb802ae5350656b649496b4a3.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_13378" text="Kawasaki disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="9-16" id="154880a8053db7adb802ae5350656b649496b4a3.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="51-61" id="154880a8053db7adb802ae5350656b649496b4a3.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_865" text="vasculitis" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
