<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="15da0bac7ba69e867df1af947566ee74e80bdb0e">
  <chunk id="15da0bac7ba69e867df1af947566ee74e80bdb0e.c0" text="Emerging Microbes &amp; Infections (2017) 6, e74"/>
  <chunk id="15da0bac7ba69e867df1af947566ee74e80bdb0e.c1" text="Transmissible gastroenteritis virus (TGEV) is an infective coronavirus (CoV) that causes diarrhea-related morbidity and mortality in piglets. For the first time, a natural recombination strain of a TGEV Anhui Hefei (AHHF) virus between the Purdue and the Miller clusters was isolated from the small intestine content of piglets in China. A phylogenetic tree based on a complete genome sequence placed the TGEV AHHF strain between the Purdue and the Miller clusters. The results of a computational analysis of recombination showed that the TGEV AHHF strain is a natural recombinant strain between these clusters. Two breakpoints located in the open reading frame 1a (ORF1a) and spike (S) genes were identified. The pathogenicity of the TGEV AHHF strain was evaluated in piglets, and the results show that TGEV AHHF is an enteric pathogenic strain. These results provide valuable information about the recombination and evolution of CoVs and will facilitate future investigations of the molecular pathogenesis of TGEV.">
    <entity charOffset="14-29" id="15da0bac7ba69e867df1af947566ee74e80bdb0e.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_2326" text="gastroenteritis" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="262-270" id="15da0bac7ba69e867df1af947566ee74e80bdb0e.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33731" text="clusters" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="456-464" id="15da0bac7ba69e867df1af947566ee74e80bdb0e.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_33731" text="clusters" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="602-610" id="15da0bac7ba69e867df1af947566ee74e80bdb0e.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_33731" text="clusters" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="15da0bac7ba69e867df1af947566ee74e80bdb0e.c1.e0" e2="15da0bac7ba69e867df1af947566ee74e80bdb0e.c1.e1" id="15da0bac7ba69e867df1af947566ee74e80bdb0e.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="15da0bac7ba69e867df1af947566ee74e80bdb0e.c1.e0" e2="15da0bac7ba69e867df1af947566ee74e80bdb0e.c1.e2" id="15da0bac7ba69e867df1af947566ee74e80bdb0e.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="15da0bac7ba69e867df1af947566ee74e80bdb0e.c1.e0" e2="15da0bac7ba69e867df1af947566ee74e80bdb0e.c1.e3" id="15da0bac7ba69e867df1af947566ee74e80bdb0e.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
