<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="1f92a01ead66646392c85f3abe57d3ea5ef8125a">
  <chunk id="1f92a01ead66646392c85f3abe57d3ea5ef8125a.c0" text="Viral Phylogenomics Using an Alignment-Free Method: A Three- Step Approach to Determine Optimal Length of k-mer OPEN"/>
  <chunk id="1f92a01ead66646392c85f3abe57d3ea5ef8125a.c1" text="The development of rapid, economical genome sequencing has shed new light on the classification of viruses. As of October 2016, the National Center for Biotechnology Information (NCBI) database contained &gt;2 million viral genome sequences and a reference set of ~4000 viral genome sequences that cover a wide range of known viral families. Whole-genome sequences can be used to improve viral classification and provide insight into the viral &quot;tree of life&quot;. However, due to the lack of evolutionary conservation amongst diverse viruses, it is not feasible to build a viral tree of life using traditional phylogenetic methods based on conserved proteins. In this study, we used an alignment-free method that uses k-mers as genomic features for a large-scale comparison of complete viral genomes available in RefSeq. To determine the optimal feature length, k (an essential step in constructing a meaningful dendrogram), we designed a comprehensive strategy that combines three approaches: (1) cumulative relative entropy, (2) average number of common features among genomes, and (3) the Shannon diversity index. This strategy was used to determine k for all 3,905 complete viral genomes in RefSeq. The resulting dendrogram shows consistency with the viral taxonomy of the ICTV and the Baltimore classification of viruses.">
    <entity charOffset="68-73" id="1f92a01ead66646392c85f3abe57d3ea5ef8125a.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_30212" text="light" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="1f92a01ead66646392c85f3abe57d3ea5ef8125a.c2" text="Whole-genome sequencing of pathogens is now commonly used 1-3 , and was made possible by exponential reductions in the cost of sequencing 4 and computational advances in biological sequence analysis 5,6 . Viral taxonomy, in particular, has benefited from the availability of many new viral-genome sequences, enabling the improved classification of viruses. In support of viral genomics research, the NCBI Viral Genome Project 7 provides thousands of viral reference sequences, which cover a wide range of viral taxonomic families in the NCBI Reference Sequence Database. The classification of viruses is maintained by the International Committee on Taxonomy of Viruses (ICTV), which considers multiple viral properties and consensus data 8 , including similarities in genome structures, host ranges, and the presence of homologous genes and various phylogenetic features 9 . Although viral taxa have been continuously updated by the virus research community 10,11 , there are still many misclassifications in the ICTV viral taxonomy 12 , as well as many viral families currently not included in the RefSeq database. Further, the sequencing of viral metagenomic samples often results in many viral genomes that are of unknown origin 13,14 ."/>
  <chunk id="1f92a01ead66646392c85f3abe57d3ea5ef8125a.c3" text="Phylogenetic analysis is widely used for taxonomic classification, characterization, and revision 15,16 . However, for prokaryotic genomes, phylogenetic trees based on small subunit rRNAs often do not agree with those based on different genes. Conflicts among gene trees have increased as more genes and genomes are sequenced 17 . This incongruence can have many causes, including tree-building errors, incomplete lineage sorting, hidden paralogy, and horizontal gene transfer. As early as 1996, inconsistent phylogenetic trees were obtained for viruses when using different numbers of isolates, or when different lengths of aligned sequences were used (as in a study of hepatitis C viruses 18 ). Similar inconsistencies have been reported for human papillomaviruses 19 , SARS coronavirus 20 , and some plant viruses 21 .">
    <entity charOffset="671-680" id="1f92a01ead66646392c85f3abe57d3ea5ef8125a.c3.e0" ontology_id="DOID_2237" text="hepatitis" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="671-682" id="1f92a01ead66646392c85f3abe57d3ea5ef8125a.c3.e1" ontology_id="DOID_1883" text="hepatitis C" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="772-776" id="1f92a01ead66646392c85f3abe57d3ea5ef8125a.c3.e2" ontology_id="DOID_2945" text="SARS" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="1f92a01ead66646392c85f3abe57d3ea5ef8125a.c4" text="Phylogenomic dendograms constructed using whole-genome sequences are based on a more complete set of genomic information than phylogenies based on individual genes 22 . For large-scale comparisons of genome-scale sequences, especially highly diverse ones, alignment-free methods of phylogeny construction have been increasingly used in the past few years 23-26 . There are two categories of alignment-free methods for phylogenomic analysis: one based on the statistics of word frequency, the other on Kolmogorov complexity and chaos theory 27 . The primary advantage of these methods is that they enable quick genome-scale comparisons with linear time complexity (O(n)) 28 more efficiently than minimum likelihood or Bayesian alignment methods with subquadratic time complexity (o(n 2 )). Another advantage of alignment-free methods is that they can be used to compare sequences from draft genomes, with information loss proportional to the number of discontinuities in a genome. However, alignment-free methods do not capture the nuances of evolutionary models that incorporate site-dependent substitution patterns. Therefore, it is not possible to interpret branch lengths of alignment-free based trees in terms of mutation rates, even though alignment-free trees constructed from whole-genome sequences capture taxonomic classification (which reflects the evolutionary history of organisms) better than 16 S rRNA alignment-based trees for prokaryotes 28 .">
    <entity charOffset="666-669" id="1f92a01ead66646392c85f3abe57d3ea5ef8125a.c4.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_21547" text="naa" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1411-1415" id="1f92a01ead66646392c85f3abe57d3ea5ef8125a.c4.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_18111" text="rRNA" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="1f92a01ead66646392c85f3abe57d3ea5ef8125a.c5" text="Sims et al. 29 introduced an alignment-free method that uses a measure based on the Jensen-Shannon divergence between feature frequency profiles (FFPs), where the features, called k-mers, are short nucleotide or amino-acid sequences of length k. Applied in eukaryotic and prokaryotic systems, this approach shows great consistency with the taxonomic information accepted by the scientific community 30, 31 . For viruses, Wu et al. 32 applied the FFP method to whole-proteome sequences of 142 large dsDNA eukaryotic viruses, and Huang et al. used this approach when evaluating different methods for phylogenetic analysis of multiple-segmented viruses 33,34 . To date, however, relatively little work has been done using FFP to determine the phylogeny of virus genomes 35 , and there are only a few reports 36,37 on the construction of phylogenetic trees from the thousands of known viral genomes.">
    <entity charOffset="198-208" id="1f92a01ead66646392c85f3abe57d3ea5ef8125a.c5.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_36976" text="nucleotide" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="1f92a01ead66646392c85f3abe57d3ea5ef8125a.c6" text="In general, genome-scale phylogenetic trees can be built using either whole-genome sequences or whole-proteome sequences. However, some viruses have only one or two genes from which protein sequences can be predicted, and viral proteins tend to be very diverse. As a consequence, it is not feasible to build a viral &quot;tree of life&quot; based on conserved proteins. Therefore, we have used an FFP approach applied to complete viral genome sequences, and have built a dendogram of viruses.">
    <entity charOffset="182-189" id="1f92a01ead66646392c85f3abe57d3ea5ef8125a.c6.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="228-236" id="1f92a01ead66646392c85f3abe57d3ea5ef8125a.c6.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="350-358" id="1f92a01ead66646392c85f3abe57d3ea5ef8125a.c6.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="1f92a01ead66646392c85f3abe57d3ea5ef8125a.c7" text="A major challenge in using the FFP method for comparing whole genomes is determining the optimal k-mer length. In previous studies of dsDNA eukaryotic viruses 15,16,21 , the optimal feature length was based on cumulative relative entropy (CRE) and relative sequence divergence (RSD). For each individual genome and a value of k, the CRE (determined by a comparison of the observed FFP and the expected FFP from a second-order Markov model) captures how much information from the whole-genome sequence is encoded in the FFP. In other words, CRE indicates the power of the FFP to reconstruct the whole-genome sequence. Smaller CRE values, which result from longer k-mers, are indicative of the ability to better identify individual genomes. For a whole genome, the RSD for a value of k is a measure of the relatedness of the genome sequence (in terms of FFP) to a random sequence of the same length. According to Wu et al. 32 , the optimal value of k is the value when both CRE and RSD decrease to &lt; 10% of their maximum values as k is increased."/>
  <chunk id="1f92a01ead66646392c85f3abe57d3ea5ef8125a.c8" text="Determining RSD values becomes increasingly computationally complex as the number of genomes grows. This increase in complexity is due, in part, to an increase in the density of the k-mer feature space. We found that RSD cannot monotonically decrease when k increases, which is probably because this huge dimensional k-mer space can cover artificial k-mers (k-mers derived from random sequences), even though their probabilities are quite low."/>
  <chunk id="1f92a01ead66646392c85f3abe57d3ea5ef8125a.c9" text="In this study, we consider the 3,905 complete viral genomes that are available in the NCBI Reference Sequence Database (RefSeq) 38 . We show that CRE is significantly influenced by the genome size, as well as k-mer composition. Genomes of different sizes show different trend CRE curves. For small viral genomes (~3 kb), CRE values drop to zero around a k value of 6; for large viral genomes (1 Mb or more), the drop increases to a k value of 10. Consequently, CRE values for genomes of greatly varied sizes cannot simultaneously be decreased to &lt; 10% of maximum values at the fixed-feature length as suggested by Wu et al. 32 . Therefore, we first grouped viral genomes by genomic size. For each group, we proposed the optimal k-mer length by considering several genomic features, including the CRE value, the number of k-mers shared by genomes, and the total number of k-mers observed, and then we constructed a dendrogram at its optimal k-mer length. Finally, we derived a procedure to decide the optimal feature length to compare all 3,905 complete viral genomes. The tree of life for viral whole genomes constructed by our alignment-free method can be visualized using the optimal feature length for the global view."/>
</document>
