<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="219db23666b8e31245a5a93f4c8bda3606449296">
  <chunk id="219db23666b8e31245a5a93f4c8bda3606449296.c0" text="REVIEW Current progress in innovative engineered antibodies"/>
  <chunk id="219db23666b8e31245a5a93f4c8bda3606449296.c1" text="As of May 1, 2017, 74 antibody-based molecules have been approved by a regulatory authority in a major market. Additionally, there are 70 and 575 antibodybased molecules in phase III and phase I/II clinical trials, respectively. These total 719 antibody-based clinical stage molecules include 493 naked IgGs, 87 antibodydrug conjugates, 61 bispecific antibodies, 37 total Fc fusion proteins, 17 radioimmunoglobulins, 13 antibody fragments, and 11 immunocytokines. New uses for these antibodies are being discovered each year. For oncology, many of the exciting new approaches involve antibody modulation of T-cells. There are over 80 antibodies in clinical trials targeting T cell checkpoints, 26 T-cellredirected bispecific antibodies, and 145 chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) cell-based candidates (all currently in phase I or II clinical trials), totaling more than 250 T cell interacting clinical stage antibody-based candidates. Finally, significant progress has been made recently on routes of delivery, including delivery of proteins across the blood-brain barrier, oral delivery to the gut, delivery to the cellular cytosol, and gene-and viral-based delivery of antibodies. Thus, there are currently at least 864 antibody-based clinical stage molecules or cells, with incredible diversity in how they are constructed and what activities they impart. These are followed by a next wave of novel molecules, approaches, and new methods and routes of delivery, demonstrating that the field of antibody-based biologics is very innovative and diverse in its approaches to fulfill their promise to treat unmet medical needs.">
    <entity charOffset="37-46" id="219db23666b8e31245a5a93f4c8bda3606449296.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_25367" text="molecules" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="82-91" id="219db23666b8e31245a5a93f4c8bda3606449296.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_9339" text="authority" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="160-169" id="219db23666b8e31245a5a93f4c8bda3606449296.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_25367" text="molecules" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="275-284" id="219db23666b8e31245a5a93f4c8bda3606449296.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_25367" text="molecules" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="382-390" id="219db23666b8e31245a5a93f4c8bda3606449296.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="754-761" id="219db23666b8e31245a5a93f4c8bda3606449296.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_59132" text="antigen" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1031-1039" id="219db23666b8e31245a5a93f4c8bda3606449296.c1.e6" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1250-1259" id="219db23666b8e31245a5a93f4c8bda3606449296.c1.e7" ontology_id="CHEBI_25367" text="molecules" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1400-1409" id="219db23666b8e31245a5a93f4c8bda3606449296.c1.e8" ontology_id="CHEBI_25367" text="molecules" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
