<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="21da52646864c1ad3303daf10f0b3e4c9d12fa5c">
  <chunk id="21da52646864c1ad3303daf10f0b3e4c9d12fa5c.c0" text="Structural Proteomics of Herpesviruses"/>
  <chunk id="21da52646864c1ad3303daf10f0b3e4c9d12fa5c.c1" text="Herpesviruses are highly prevalent viruses associated with numerous pathologies both in animal and human populations. Until now, most of the strategies used to prevent or to cure these infections have been unsuccessful because these viruses have developed numerous immune evasion mechanisms. Therefore, a better understanding of their complex lifecycle is needed. In particular, while the genome of numerous herpesviruses has been sequenced, the exact composition of virions remains unknown for most of them. Mass spectrometry has recently emerged as a central method and has permitted fundamental discoveries in virology. Here, we review mass spectrometry-based approaches that have recently allowed a better understanding of the composition of the herpesvirus virion. In particular, we describe strategies commonly used for proper sample preparation and fractionation to allow protein localization inside the particle but also to avoid contamination by nonstructural proteins. A collection of other important data regarding post-translational modifications or the relative abundance of structural proteins is also described. This review also discusses the poorly studied importance of host proteins in herpesvirus structural proteins and the necessity to develop a quantitative workflow to better understand the dynamics of the structural proteome. In the future, we hope that this collaborative effort will assist in the development of new strategies to fight these infections.">
    <entity charOffset="879-886" id="21da52646864c1ad3303daf10f0b3e4c9d12fa5c.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="969-977" id="21da52646864c1ad3303daf10f0b3e4c9d12fa5c.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1099-1107" id="21da52646864c1ad3303daf10f0b3e4c9d12fa5c.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1192-1200" id="21da52646864c1ad3303daf10f0b3e4c9d12fa5c.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1227-1235" id="21da52646864c1ad3303daf10f0b3e4c9d12fa5c.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="21da52646864c1ad3303daf10f0b3e4c9d12fa5c.c2" text="2 of 17 infection, a description of the particle composition both in terms of viral and cellular proteins is also of major importance for a better characterization of infectious processes. In particular, characterization of the composition of complex enveloped viruses, such as poxviruses and herpesviruses, is of major importance to better understand their life cycle. Knowledge of the composition of the virion but also of the distribution of proteins in the capsid, tegument, and envelope are essential to understand virion assembly [6] or initiate functional characterization of structural proteins through targeted approaches such as interactomics [7] . Davison and Davison [8] published the first report of the use of mass spectrometry for determination of the structural proteome of a herpesvirus, Ictalurid herpesvirus 1 (IcHV-1), which is also known as channel catfish virus. Several other studies have since been performed to characterize the structural proteins of the virion of herpesviruses. It has been demonstrated that knowledge of the composition of virions can be highly useful for the development of improved vaccines and diagnostic tools for the control of herpesvirus infections [9] .">
    <entity charOffset="97-105" id="21da52646864c1ad3303daf10f0b3e4c9d12fa5c.c2.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="445-453" id="21da52646864c1ad3303daf10f0b3e4c9d12fa5c.c2.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="594-602" id="21da52646864c1ad3303daf10f0b3e4c9d12fa5c.c2.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="964-972" id="21da52646864c1ad3303daf10f0b3e4c9d12fa5c.c2.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="21da52646864c1ad3303daf10f0b3e4c9d12fa5c.c3" text="This review summarizes the different aspects of the study of the structural proteome focusing on the Herpesviridae family, notably the different proteomic workflow that has been successfully used and the importance of sample preparation. The review also discusses the status of host cellular proteins found in the virion and the interest in acquiring quantitative data.">
    <entity charOffset="292-300" id="21da52646864c1ad3303daf10f0b3e4c9d12fa5c.c3.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
