<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="22b6982820cdeb330dc2086ea69713f6e109a671">
  <chunk id="22b6982820cdeb330dc2086ea69713f6e109a671.c0" text="Recombinant Chimeric Transmissible Gastroenteritis Virus (TGEV)-Porcine Epidemic Diarrhea Virus (PEDV) Virus Provides Protection against Virulent PEDV">
    <entity charOffset="35-50" id="22b6982820cdeb330dc2086ea69713f6e109a671.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_2326" text="Gastroenteritis" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="81-89" id="22b6982820cdeb330dc2086ea69713f6e109a671.c0.e1" ontology_id="DOID_13250" text="Diarrhea" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="22b6982820cdeb330dc2086ea69713f6e109a671.c1" text="Porcine epidemic diarrhea virus (PEDV) is an enteric coronavirus causing high morbidity and mortality in porcine herds worldwide. Although both inactivated and live attenuated vaccines have been extensively used, the emergence of highly virulent strains and the recurrent outbreaks even in vaccinated farms highlight the need of effective vaccines. Engineering of genetically defined live attenuated vaccines is a rational approach for novel vaccine development. In this line, we engineered an attenuated virus based on the transmissible gastroenteritis virus (TGEV) genome, expressing a chimeric spike protein from a virulent United States (US) PEDV strain. This virus (rTGEV-RS-SPEDV) was attenuated in highly-sensitive five-day-old piglets, as infected animals did not lose weight and none of them died. In addition, the virus caused very minor tissue damage compared with a virulent virus. The rTGEV-RS-SPEDV vaccine candidate was also attenuated in three-week-old animals that were used to evaluate the protection conferred by this virus, compared with the protection induced by infection with a virulent PEDV US strain (PEDV-NVSL). The rTGEV-RS-SPEDV virus protected against challenge with a virulent PEDV strain, reducing challenge virus titers in jejunum and leading to undetectable challenge virus RNA levels in feces. The rTGEV-RS-SPEDV virus induced a humoral immune response specific for PEDV, including neutralizing antibodies. Altogether, the data indicated that rTGEV-RS-SPEDV is a promising vaccine candidate against virulent PEDV infection.">
    <entity charOffset="17-25" id="22b6982820cdeb330dc2086ea69713f6e109a671.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_13250" text="diarrhea" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="538-553" id="22b6982820cdeb330dc2086ea69713f6e109a671.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_2326" text="gastroenteritis" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="603-610" id="22b6982820cdeb330dc2086ea69713f6e109a671.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1307-1310" id="22b6982820cdeb330dc2086ea69713f6e109a671.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="22b6982820cdeb330dc2086ea69713f6e109a671.c1.e0" e2="22b6982820cdeb330dc2086ea69713f6e109a671.c1.e2" id="22b6982820cdeb330dc2086ea69713f6e109a671.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="22b6982820cdeb330dc2086ea69713f6e109a671.c1.e0" e2="22b6982820cdeb330dc2086ea69713f6e109a671.c1.e3" id="22b6982820cdeb330dc2086ea69713f6e109a671.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="22b6982820cdeb330dc2086ea69713f6e109a671.c1.e1" e2="22b6982820cdeb330dc2086ea69713f6e109a671.c1.e2" id="22b6982820cdeb330dc2086ea69713f6e109a671.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="22b6982820cdeb330dc2086ea69713f6e109a671.c1.e1" e2="22b6982820cdeb330dc2086ea69713f6e109a671.c1.e3" id="22b6982820cdeb330dc2086ea69713f6e109a671.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
