<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="281303193aa29253bb0b00328b48e892d0cf4f85">
  <chunk id="281303193aa29253bb0b00328b48e892d0cf4f85.c0" text="Low-Fidelity Polymerases of Alphaviruses Recombine at Higher Rates To Overproduce Defective Interfering Particles"/>
  <chunk id="281303193aa29253bb0b00328b48e892d0cf4f85.c1" text="Low-fidelity RNA-dependent RNA polymerases for many RNA virus mutators have been shown to confer attenuated phenotypes, presumably due to increased mutation rates. Additionally, for many RNA viruses, replication to high titers results in the production of defective interfering particles (DIs) that also attenuate infection. We hypothesized that fidelity, recombination, and DI production are tightly linked. We show that a Sindbis virus mutator replicating at a high multiplicity of infection manifests an earlier and greater accumulation of DIs than its wild-type counterpart. The isolated DIs interfere with the replication of full-length virus in a dose-dependent manner. Importantly, the ability of the mutator virus to overproduce DIs could be linked to an increased recombination frequency. These data confirm that RNA-dependent RNA polymerase fidelity and recombination are inversely correlated for this mutator. Our findings suggest that defective interference resulting from higher recombination rates may be more detrimental to RNA virus mutators than the increase in mutational burden.">
    <entity charOffset="27-30" id="281303193aa29253bb0b00328b48e892d0cf4f85.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="52-55" id="281303193aa29253bb0b00328b48e892d0cf4f85.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="187-190" id="281303193aa29253bb0b00328b48e892d0cf4f85.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="836-839" id="281303193aa29253bb0b00328b48e892d0cf4f85.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1039-1042" id="281303193aa29253bb0b00328b48e892d0cf4f85.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="281303193aa29253bb0b00328b48e892d0cf4f85.c2" text="IMPORTANCE"/>
  <chunk id="281303193aa29253bb0b00328b48e892d0cf4f85.c3" text="Citation Poirier EZ, Mounce BC, Rozen-Gagnon K, Hooikaas PJ, Stapleford KA, Moratorio G, Vignuzzi M. 2016. Low-fidelity polymerases of alphaviruses recombine at higher rates to overproduce defective interfering particles. J Virol"/>
</document>
