<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755">
  <chunk id="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c0" text="Mast cells and influenza A virus: association with allergic responses and beyond">
    <entity charOffset="15-24" id="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c1" text="Influenza A virus (IAV) is a widespread infectious agent commonly found in mammalian and avian species. In humans, IAV is a respiratory pathogen that causes seasonal infections associated with significant morbidity in young and elderly populations, and has a large economic impact. Moreover, IAV has the potential to cause both zoonotic spillover infection and global pandemics, which have significantly greater morbidity and mortality across all ages. The pathology associated with these pandemic and spillover infections appear to be the result of an excessive inflammatory response leading to severe lung damage, which likely predisposes the lungs for secondary bacterial infections. The lung is protected from pathogens by alveolar epithelial cells, endothelial cells, tissue resident alveolar macrophages, dendritic cells, and mast cells. The importance of mast cells during bacterial and parasitic infections has been extensively studied; yet, the role of these hematopoietic cells during viral infections is only beginning to emerge. Recently, it has been shown that mast cells can be directly activated in response to IAV, releasing mediators such histamine, proteases, leukotrienes, inflammatory cytokines, and antiviral chemokines, which participate in the excessive inflammatory and pathological response observed during IAV infections. In this review, we will examine the relationship between mast cells and IAV, and discuss the role of mast cells as a potential drug target during highly pathological IAV infections. Finally, we proposed an emerging role for mast cells in other viral infections associated with significant host pathology.">
    <entity charOffset="0-9" id="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="Influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="954-958" id="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1220-1229" id="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_22587" text="antiviral" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1441-1445" id="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1475-1479" id="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_23888" text="drug" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1563-1567" id="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c1.e0" e2="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c1.e1" id="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c1.e0" e2="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c1.e2" id="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c1.e0" e2="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c1.e3" id="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c1.e0" e2="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c1.e4" id="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c1.e0" e2="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c1.e5" id="29621887690af716dac0c244eeb95bce74fa8755.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
