<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="2db670e443cdceb7fb2ff63b6331df5d12efef99">
  <chunk id="2db670e443cdceb7fb2ff63b6331df5d12efef99.c0" text="A Quantitative Method for the Specific Assessment of Caspase-6 Activity in Cell Culture"/>
  <chunk id="2db670e443cdceb7fb2ff63b6331df5d12efef99.c1" text="Aberrant activation of caspase-6 has recently emerged as a major contributor to the pathogeneses of neurodegenerative disorders such as Alzheimer's and Huntington disease. Commercially available assays to measure caspase-6 activity commonly use the VEID peptide as a substrate. However these methods are not well suited to specifically assess caspase-6 activity in the presence of other, confounding protease activities, as often encountered in cell and tissue samples. Here we report the development of a method that overcomes this limitation by using a protein substrate, lamin A, which is highly specific for caspase-6 cleavage at amino acid 230. Using a neo-epitope antibody against cleaved lamin A, we developed an electrochemiluminescence-based ELISA assay that is suitable to specifically detect and quantify caspase-6 activity in highly apoptotic cell extracts. The method is more sensitive than VEID-based assays and can be adapted to a high-content imaging platform for high-throughput screening. This method should be useful to screen for and characterize caspase-6 inhibitor compounds and other interventions to decrease intracellular caspase-6 activity for applications in neurodegenerative disorders.">
    <entity charOffset="254-261" id="2db670e443cdceb7fb2ff63b6331df5d12efef99.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16670" text="peptide" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="555-562" id="2db670e443cdceb7fb2ff63b6331df5d12efef99.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="634-639" id="2db670e443cdceb7fb2ff63b6331df5d12efef99.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_46882" text="amino" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="634-644" id="2db670e443cdceb7fb2ff63b6331df5d12efef99.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_33704" text="amino acid" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="640-644" id="2db670e443cdceb7fb2ff63b6331df5d12efef99.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_37527" text="acid" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1077-1086" id="2db670e443cdceb7fb2ff63b6331df5d12efef99.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_35222" text="inhibitor" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
