<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="2e3d6708bedf2af3d3b900329871c910308b0b7a">
  <chunk id="2e3d6708bedf2af3d3b900329871c910308b0b7a.c0" text="Identification of Human Junctional Adhesion Molecule 1 as a Functional Receptor for the Hom-1 Calicivirus on Human Cells">
    <entity charOffset="44-52" id="2e3d6708bedf2af3d3b900329871c910308b0b7a.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_25367" text="Molecule" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="2e3d6708bedf2af3d3b900329871c910308b0b7a.c1" text="The Hom-1 vesivirus was reported in 1998 following the inadvertent transmission of the animal calicivirus San Miguel sea lion virus to a human host in a laboratory. We characterized the Hom-1 strain and investigated the mechanism by which human cells could be infected. An expression library of 3,559 human plasma membrane proteins was screened for reactivity with Hom-1 virus-like particles, and a single interacting protein, human junctional adhesion molecule 1 (hJAM1), was identified. Transient expression of hJAM1 conferred susceptibility to Hom-1 infection on nonpermissive Chinese hamster ovary (CHO) cells. Virus infection was markedly inhibited when CHO cells stably expressing hJAM were pretreated with anti-hJAM1 monoclonal antibodies. Cell lines of human origin were tested for growth of Hom-1, and efficient replication was observed in HepG2, HuH7, and SK-CO15 cells. The three cell lines (of hepatic or intestinal origin) were confirmed to express hJAM1 on their surface, and clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeats/Cas9-mediated knockout of the hJAM1 gene in each line abolished Hom-1 propagation. Taken together, our data indicate that entry of the Hom-1 vesivirus into these permissive human cell lines is mediated by the plasma membrane protein hJAM1 as a functional receptor.">
    <entity charOffset="323-331" id="2e3d6708bedf2af3d3b900329871c910308b0b7a.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="418-425" id="2e3d6708bedf2af3d3b900329871c910308b0b7a.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="453-461" id="2e3d6708bedf2af3d3b900329871c910308b0b7a.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_25367" text="molecule" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="615-630" id="2e3d6708bedf2af3d3b900329871c910308b0b7a.c1.e3" ontology_id="DOID_934" text="Virus infection" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1273-1280" id="2e3d6708bedf2af3d3b900329871c910308b0b7a.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="2e3d6708bedf2af3d3b900329871c910308b0b7a.c1.e0" e2="2e3d6708bedf2af3d3b900329871c910308b0b7a.c1.e3" id="2e3d6708bedf2af3d3b900329871c910308b0b7a.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="2e3d6708bedf2af3d3b900329871c910308b0b7a.c1.e1" e2="2e3d6708bedf2af3d3b900329871c910308b0b7a.c1.e3" id="2e3d6708bedf2af3d3b900329871c910308b0b7a.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="2e3d6708bedf2af3d3b900329871c910308b0b7a.c1.e2" e2="2e3d6708bedf2af3d3b900329871c910308b0b7a.c1.e3" id="2e3d6708bedf2af3d3b900329871c910308b0b7a.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="2e3d6708bedf2af3d3b900329871c910308b0b7a.c1.e3" e2="2e3d6708bedf2af3d3b900329871c910308b0b7a.c1.e4" id="2e3d6708bedf2af3d3b900329871c910308b0b7a.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
