<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="365ab3e4ca40537484abf16d4d33d88f63635404">
  <chunk id="365ab3e4ca40537484abf16d4d33d88f63635404.c0" text="A Bibliometric Analysis of PubMed Literature on Middle East Respiratory Syndrome">
    <entity charOffset="48-80" id="365ab3e4ca40537484abf16d4d33d88f63635404.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_0080642" text="Middle East Respiratory Syndrome" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="72-80" id="365ab3e4ca40537484abf16d4d33d88f63635404.c0.e1" ontology_id="DOID_225" text="Syndrome" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="365ab3e4ca40537484abf16d4d33d88f63635404.c1" text="Middle East Respiratory Syndrome (MERS), a pandemic threat to human beings, has aroused huge concern worldwide, but no bibliometric studies have been conducted on MERS research. The aim of this study was to map research productivity on the disease based on the articles indexed in PubMed. The articles related to MERS dated from 2012 to 2015 were retrieved from PubMed. The articles were classified into three categories according to their focus. Publication outputs were assessed and frequently used terms were mapped using the VOS viewer software. A total of 443 articles were included for analysis. They were published in 162 journals, with Journal of Virology being the most productive (44 articles; 9.9%) and by six types of organizations, with universities being the most productive (276 articles; 62.4%).The largest proportion of the articles focused on basic medical sciences and clinical studies (47.2%) and those on prevention and control ranked third (26.2%), with those on other focuses coming in between (26.6%). The articles on prevention and control had the highest mean rank for impact factor (IF) (226.34), followed by those on basic medical sciences and clinical studies (180.23) and those on other focuses (168.03). The mean rank differences were statistically significant (p = 0.000). Besides, &quot;conronavirus&quot;, &quot;case&quot;, &quot;transmission&quot; and &quot;detection&quot; were found to be the most frequently used terms. The findings of this first bibliometric study on MERS suggest that the prevention and control of the disease has become a big concern and related research should be strengthened.">
    <entity charOffset="0-32" id="365ab3e4ca40537484abf16d4d33d88f63635404.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_0080642" text="Middle East Respiratory Syndrome" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="24-32" id="365ab3e4ca40537484abf16d4d33d88f63635404.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_225" text="Syndrome" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="240-247" id="365ab3e4ca40537484abf16d4d33d88f63635404.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1519-1526" id="365ab3e4ca40537484abf16d4d33d88f63635404.c1.e3" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
