<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="40825b0106c7d8664276f75be3df4a75fb046c44">
  <chunk id="40825b0106c7d8664276f75be3df4a75fb046c44.c0" text="Protocol for development of a risk assessment tool for planning and management of religious mass-gathering events of India-a health system- strengthening initiative"/>
  <chunk id="40825b0106c7d8664276f75be3df4a75fb046c44.c1" text="Background: Religious mass gatherings (MGs) have always been an integral part of our society. At the outset, mass-gathering events provide challenging settings to plan a suitable emergency public health response. Published studies basically talk about retrospective reviews, case studies of the public health preparedness, or health care provided at individual events. Developing an understanding of the variables associated with MGs is the first step for public health managers. Risk assessment (RA) is a crucial part of pre-event planning as it helps foresee potential risks. Based on RA, one can develop preventive measures and ensure that the infrastructure to control the potential problems is in place. This study is an attempt to systemize RA process during MG events in a country that is culturally rich but with poor resources to handle such events. A RA tool will be developed for planning and management of religious MG events of India. Methods/design: Various strategies will be used to develop the risk assessment tool (RA tool). Extensive review of literature clubbed with key informant interviews will be done in order to identify the risk variables and decide the domains and items of the tool. Further, this tool will be developed as a mobile-based application. The feasibility of the mobile-based RA tool will be tested in real-time MG event in one part of the country. Concurrently in the same event, a community survey of residents and visitors will be done in order to assess public perceptions of public health and environmental risks associated with MG events. Discussion: The findings of this study will provide insights into the public health and environmental concerns that need to be considered if preventive strategies and intervention programs are to be designed for MG events. A &quot;RA Tool,&quot; which can be used in the planning and management of MG events by the public health managers will strengthen the existing health systems preparedness plans for MGs."/>
</document>
