<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="430903f42d10ae8f5729df9a61e75e2d6dc09f65">
  <chunk id="430903f42d10ae8f5729df9a61e75e2d6dc09f65.c0" text="Modeling the transboundary risk of feed ingredients contaminated with porcine epidemic diarrhea virus">
    <entity charOffset="87-95" id="430903f42d10ae8f5729df9a61e75e2d6dc09f65.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_13250" text="diarrhea" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="430903f42d10ae8f5729df9a61e75e2d6dc09f65.c1" text="Background: This study describes a model developed to evaluate the transboundary risk of PEDV-contaminated swine feed ingredients and the effect of two mitigation strategies during a simulated transport event from China to the US. Results: Ingredients imported to the USA from China, including organic &amp; conventional soybeans and meal, lysine hydrochloride, D-L methionine, tryptophan, Vitamins A, D &amp; E, choline, carriers (rice hulls, corn cobs) and feed grade tetracycline, were inoculated with PEDV. Control ingredients, and treatments (ingredients plus a liquid antimicrobial (SalCURB, Kemin Industries (LA) or a 2 % custom medium chain fatty acid blend (MCFA)) were tested. The model ran for 37 days, simulating transport of cargo from Beijing, China to Des Moines, IA, US from December 23, 2012 to January 28, 2013. To mimic conditions on land and sea, historical temperature and percent relative humidity (% RH) data were programmed into an environmental chamber which stored all containers. To evaluate PEDV viability over time, ingredients were organized into 1 of 4 batches of samples, each batch representing a specific segment of transport. Batch 1 (segment 1) simulated transport of contaminated ingredients from manufacturing plants in Beijing (day 1 post-contamination (PC)). Batch 2 (segments 1 and 2) simulated manufacturing and delivery to Shanghai, including time in Anquing terminal awaiting shipment (days 1-8 PC). Batch 3 (segments 1, 2 and 3) represented time in China, the crossing of the Pacific and entry to the US at the San Francisco, CA terminal (day 1-27 PC). Batch 4 (segments 1-4) represented the previous events, including transport to Des Moines, IA (days 1-37 PC). Across control (non-treated) ingredients, viable PEDV was detected in soybean meal (organic and conventional), Vitamin D, lysine hydrochloride and choline chloride. In contrast, viable PEDV was not detected in any samples treated with LA or MCFA. Conclusions: These results demonstrate the ability of PEDV to survive in a subset of feed ingredients using a model simulating shipment from China to the US. This is proof of concept suggesting that contaminated feed ingredients could serve as transboundary risk factors for PEDV, along with the identification of effective mitigation options.">
    <entity charOffset="336-342" id="430903f42d10ae8f5729df9a61e75e2d6dc09f65.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_18019" text="lysine" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="336-342" id="430903f42d10ae8f5729df9a61e75e2d6dc09f65.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_25094" text="lysine" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="343-356" id="430903f42d10ae8f5729df9a61e75e2d6dc09f65.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_17883" text="hydrochloride" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="386-394" id="430903f42d10ae8f5729df9a61e75e2d6dc09f65.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_33229" text="Vitamins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="405-412" id="430903f42d10ae8f5729df9a61e75e2d6dc09f65.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_15354" text="choline" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="414-422" id="430903f42d10ae8f5729df9a61e75e2d6dc09f65.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_78059" text="carriers" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="566-579" id="430903f42d10ae8f5729df9a61e75e2d6dc09f65.c1.e6" ontology_id="CHEBI_33281" text="antimicrobial" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="641-651" id="430903f42d10ae8f5729df9a61e75e2d6dc09f65.c1.e7" ontology_id="CHEBI_35366" text="fatty acid" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="647-651" id="430903f42d10ae8f5729df9a61e75e2d6dc09f65.c1.e8" ontology_id="CHEBI_37527" text="acid" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="759-762" id="430903f42d10ae8f5729df9a61e75e2d6dc09f65.c1.e9" ontology_id="CHEBI_34699" text="Des" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1669-1672" id="430903f42d10ae8f5729df9a61e75e2d6dc09f65.c1.e10" ontology_id="CHEBI_34699" text="Des" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1811-1818" id="430903f42d10ae8f5729df9a61e75e2d6dc09f65.c1.e11" ontology_id="CHEBI_33229" text="Vitamin" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1822-1828" id="430903f42d10ae8f5729df9a61e75e2d6dc09f65.c1.e12" ontology_id="CHEBI_18019" text="lysine" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1822-1828" id="430903f42d10ae8f5729df9a61e75e2d6dc09f65.c1.e13" ontology_id="CHEBI_25094" text="lysine" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1829-1842" id="430903f42d10ae8f5729df9a61e75e2d6dc09f65.c1.e14" ontology_id="CHEBI_17883" text="hydrochloride" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1847-1854" id="430903f42d10ae8f5729df9a61e75e2d6dc09f65.c1.e15" ontology_id="CHEBI_15354" text="choline" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
