<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="45670b1f604c315c742a23956615cd8ef7745f3a">
  <chunk id="45670b1f604c315c742a23956615cd8ef7745f3a.c0" text="Impact of a hospital-wide hand hygiene promotion strategy on healthcare-associated infections"/>
  <chunk id="45670b1f604c315c742a23956615cd8ef7745f3a.c1" text="Background: During the Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome (SARS) outbreak, high compliance in healthcare workers to hand hygiene was primarily driven by fear. However, the post-SARS period confirmed that this practice was not sustainable. At the Singapore General Hospital, a 1,600-bedded acute tertiary care hospital, the hand hygiene program was revised in early 2007 following Singapore's signing of the pledge to the World Health Organization (WHO) &quot;Clean Care is Safer Care&quot; program. Findings: A multi-prong approach was used in designing the hand hygiene program. This included system change; training and education; evaluation and feedback; reminders in the workplace; and institutional safety climate. Hand hygiene compliance rate improved from 20% (in January 2007) to 61% (2010). Improvement was also seen annually in the compliance to each of the 5 moments as well as in all staff categories. Healthcareassociated MRSA infections were reduced from 0.6 (2007) to 0.3 (2010) per 1000 patient-days. Conclusions: Leadership's support of the program evidenced through visible leadership presence, messaging and release of resources is the key factor in helping to make the program a true success. The hospital was recognised as a Global Hand Hygiene Expert Centre in January 2011. The WHO multi-prong interventions work in improving compliance and reducing healthcare associated infections.">
    <entity charOffset="23-56" id="45670b1f604c315c742a23956615cd8ef7745f3a.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_2945" text="Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="48-56" id="45670b1f604c315c742a23956615cd8ef7745f3a.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_225" text="Syndrome" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="58-62" id="45670b1f604c315c742a23956615cd8ef7745f3a.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_2945" text="SARS" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
