<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="4631d1a1d9384ce4aa9d96d6695417357855ce84">
  <chunk id="4631d1a1d9384ce4aa9d96d6695417357855ce84.c0" text="Population-based surveys and interventions for mental health literacy in China during 1997-2018: a scoping review"/>
  <chunk id="4631d1a1d9384ce4aa9d96d6695417357855ce84.c1" text="Background: This scoping review maps population-based surveys and mental health literacy (MHL) interventions undertaken in China during 1997-2018 in order to identify research gaps. Method: Following Arksey and O'Malley's framework for a scoping review, five English databases (Medline, PsycINFO, Cochrane library, Web of Science and CINAHL) and two Chinese ones (CNKI and WanFang) were systematically searched, identifying both reports of surveys and evaluation of interventions from Jan 1997 to Oct 2018. Results: MHL research has developed rapidly in China in terms of numbers of studies and geographic coverage over the past two decades. There were 350 peer-reviewed publications included in this review, covering diverse settings and participants. Of these publications, 313 (89.4%) were published in Chinese-language journals and 37 in English-language journals; 303 (86.6%) reported on survey findings and 47 reported on the evaluation of MHL interventions. MHL research in China has mainly focused on the assessment of mental health-related knowledge and beliefs. Much less attention has been given to developing and evaluating relevant interventions. MHL related to general mental health and suicide were most commonly studied, with less focus on specific disorders, although some studies covered depression, psychosis and anxiety disorders. The majority of MHL tools utilized in the studies reported in this review were developed in China (n = 97, 80.2% ) and almost half of these studies (57.8%) did not provide enough details concerning psychometrics. Conclusions: More interventions targeting the general public and aiming to improve MHL and promote behaviour change, are needed in China. These should be evaluated with high-quality study designs, such as randomised controlled trials. Proper validation of tools used for measuring MHL should also be addressed in future studies.">
    <entity charOffset="1332-1339" id="4631d1a1d9384ce4aa9d96d6695417357855ce84.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_2030" text="anxiety" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
