<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="48106886ec5b19e6cc62abf552ff3529f1d8aca3">
  <chunk id="48106886ec5b19e6cc62abf552ff3529f1d8aca3.c0" text="The presence of fever in adults with influenza and other viral respiratory infections">
    <entity charOffset="37-46" id="48106886ec5b19e6cc62abf552ff3529f1d8aca3.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="48106886ec5b19e6cc62abf552ff3529f1d8aca3.c1" text="We compared the rates of fever in adult subjects with laboratory-confirmed influenza and other respiratory viruses and examined the factors that predict fever in adults. Symptom data on 158 healthcare workers (HCWs) with a laboratory-confirmed respiratory virus infection were collected using standardized data collection forms from three separate studies. Overall, the rate of fever in confirmed viral respiratory infections in adult HCWs was 23·4% (37/158). Rates varied by virus: human rhinovirus (25·3%, 19/75), influenza A virus (30%, 3/10), coronavirus (28·6%, 2/7), human metapneumovirus (28·6%, 2/7), respiratory syncytial virus (14·3%, 4/28) and parainfluenza virus (8·3%, 1/12). Smoking [relative risk (RR) 4·65, 95% confidence interval (CI) 1·33-16·25] and coinfection with two or more viruses (RR 4·19, 95% CI 1·21-14·52) were significant predictors of fever. Fever is less common in adults with confirmed viral respiratory infections, including influenza, than described in children. More than 75% of adults with a viral respiratory infection do not have fever, which is an important finding for clinical triage of adult patients with respiratory infections. The accepted definition of 'influenza-like illness' includes fever and may be insensitive for surveillance when high case-finding is required. A more sensitive case definition could be used to identify adult cases, particularly in event of an emerging viral infection.">
    <entity charOffset="75-84" id="48106886ec5b19e6cc62abf552ff3529f1d8aca3.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="256-271" id="48106886ec5b19e6cc62abf552ff3529f1d8aca3.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_934" text="virus infection" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="516-525" id="48106886ec5b19e6cc62abf552ff3529f1d8aca3.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="958-967" id="48106886ec5b19e6cc62abf552ff3529f1d8aca3.c1.e3" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
