<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="492ae848b7e2b20047ac406af1c7712ea6255461">
  <chunk id="492ae848b7e2b20047ac406af1c7712ea6255461.c0" text="Three-Dimensional Normal Human Neural Progenitor Tissue-Like Assemblies: A Model of Persistent Varicella- Zoster Virus Infection">
    <entity charOffset="113-128" id="492ae848b7e2b20047ac406af1c7712ea6255461.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_934" text="Virus Infection" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="492ae848b7e2b20047ac406af1c7712ea6255461.c1" text="Varicella-zoster virus (VZV) is a neurotropic human alphaherpesvirus that causes varicella upon primary infection, establishes latency in multiple ganglionic neurons, and can reactivate to cause zoster. Live attenuated VZV vaccines are available; however, they can also establish latent infections and reactivate. Studies of VZV latency have been limited to the analyses of human ganglia removed at autopsy, as the virus is strictly a human pathogen. Recently, terminally differentiated human neurons have received much attention as a means to study the interaction between VZV and human neurons; however, the short life-span of these cells in culture has limited their application. Herein, we describe the construction of a model of normal human neural progenitor cells (NHNP) in tissue-like assemblies (TLAs), which can be successfully maintained for at least 180 days in three-dimensional (3D) culture, and exhibit an expression profile similar to that of human trigeminal ganglia. Infection of NHNP TLAs with cell-free VZV resulted in a persistent infection that was maintained for three months, during which the virus genome remained stable. Immediate-early, early and late VZV genes were transcribed, and low-levels of infectious VZV were recurrently detected in the culture supernatant. Our data suggest that NHNP TLAs are an effective system to investigate long-term interactions of VZV with complex assemblies of human neuronal cells. Citation: Goodwin TJ, McCarthy M, Osterrieder N, Cohrs RJ, Kaufer BB (2013) Three-Dimensional Normal Human Neural Progenitor Tissue-Like Assemblies: A Model of Persistent Varicella-Zoster Virus Infection. PLoS Pathog 9(8): e1003512.">
    <entity charOffset="81-90" id="492ae848b7e2b20047ac406af1c7712ea6255461.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_8659" text="varicella" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
