<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="49ef14fbeee682057ed14674f623ca36c6d954cc">
  <chunk id="49ef14fbeee682057ed14674f623ca36c6d954cc.c0" text="RNA and DNA Bacteriophages as Molecular Diagnosis Controls in Clinical Virology: A Comprehensive Study of More than 45,000 Routine PCR Tests">
    <entity charOffset="0-3" id="49ef14fbeee682057ed14674f623ca36c6d954cc.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="8-11" id="49ef14fbeee682057ed14674f623ca36c6d954cc.c0.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="49ef14fbeee682057ed14674f623ca36c6d954cc.c1" text="Real-time PCR techniques are now commonly used for the detection of viral genomes in various human specimens and require for validation both external and internal controls (ECs and ICs). In particular, ICs added to clinical samples are necessary to monitor the extraction, reverse transcription, and amplification steps in order to detect false-negative results resulting from PCR-inhibition or errors in the technical procedure. Here, we performed a large scale evaluation of the use of bacteriophages as ICs in routine molecular diagnosis. This allowed to propose simple standardized procedures (i) to design specific ECs for both DNA and RNA viruses and (ii) to use T4 (DNA) or MS2 (RNA) phages as ICs in routine diagnosis. Various technical formats for using phages as ICs were optimised and validated. Subsequently, T4 and MS2 ICs were evaluated in routine real-time PCR or RT-PCR virological diagnostic tests, using a series of 8,950 clinical samples (representing 36 distinct specimen types) sent to our laboratory for the detection of a variety of DNA and RNA viruses. The frequency of inefficient detection of ICs was analyzed according to the nature of the sample. Inhibitors of enzymatic reactions were detected at high frequency in specific sample types such as heparinized blood and bone marrow (.70%), broncho-alveolar liquid (41%) and stools (36%). The use of T4 and MS2 phages as ICs proved to be cost-effective, flexible and adaptable to various technical procedures of real-time PCR detection in virology. It represents a valuable strategy for enhancing the quality of routine molecular diagnosis in laboratories that use in-house designed diagnostic systems, which can conveniently be associated to the use of specific synthetic ECs. The high rate of inhibitors observed in a variety of specimen types should stimulate the elaboration of improved technical protocols for the extraction and amplification of nucleic acids. Citation: Ninove L, Nougairede A, Gazin C, Thirion L, Delogu I, et al. (2011) RNA and DNA Bacteriophages as Molecular Diagnosis Controls in Clinical Virology: A Comprehensive Study of More than 45,000 Routine PCR Tests. PLoS ONE 6(2): e16142.">
    <entity charOffset="633-636" id="49ef14fbeee682057ed14674f623ca36c6d954cc.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="641-644" id="49ef14fbeee682057ed14674f623ca36c6d954cc.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="673-676" id="49ef14fbeee682057ed14674f623ca36c6d954cc.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="686-689" id="49ef14fbeee682057ed14674f623ca36c6d954cc.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1056-1059" id="49ef14fbeee682057ed14674f623ca36c6d954cc.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1064-1067" id="49ef14fbeee682057ed14674f623ca36c6d954cc.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1175-1185" id="49ef14fbeee682057ed14674f623ca36c6d954cc.c1.e6" ontology_id="CHEBI_35222" text="Inhibitors" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1770-1780" id="49ef14fbeee682057ed14674f623ca36c6d954cc.c1.e7" ontology_id="CHEBI_35222" text="inhibitors" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="2019-2022" id="49ef14fbeee682057ed14674f623ca36c6d954cc.c1.e8" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="2027-2030" id="49ef14fbeee682057ed14674f623ca36c6d954cc.c1.e9" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="2166-2169" id="49ef14fbeee682057ed14674f623ca36c6d954cc.c1.e10" ontology_id="CHEBI_58972" text="ONE" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
