<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="4cc3f3b34e4353ec33df7c231e22112232ae7218">
  <chunk id="4cc3f3b34e4353ec33df7c231e22112232ae7218.c0" text="Hijacking the Supplies: Metabolism as a Novel Facet of Virus-Host Interaction"/>
  <chunk id="4cc3f3b34e4353ec33df7c231e22112232ae7218.c1" text="Viral replication is a process that involves an extremely high turnover of cellular molecules. Since viruses depend on the host cell to obtain the macromolecules needed for their proper replication, they have evolved numerous strategies to shape cellular metabolism and the biosynthesis machinery of the host according to their specific needs. Technologies for the rigorous analysis of metabolic alterations in cells have recently become widely available and have greatly expanded our knowledge of these crucial host-pathogen interactions. We have learned that most viruses enhance specific anabolic pathways and are highly dependent on these alterations. Since uninfected cells are far more plastic in their metabolism, targeting of the virus-induced metabolic alterations is a promising strategy for specific antiviral therapy and has gained great interest recently. In this review, we summarize the current advances in our understanding of metabolic adaptations during viral infections, with a particular focus on the utilization of this information for therapeutic application.">
    <entity charOffset="147-161" id="4cc3f3b34e4353ec33df7c231e22112232ae7218.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33839" text="macromolecules" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="811-820" id="4cc3f3b34e4353ec33df7c231e22112232ae7218.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_22587" text="antiviral" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="4cc3f3b34e4353ec33df7c231e22112232ae7218.c2" text="Viruses depend on the host cell to obtain the macromolecules and biosynthesis machinery required for their replication. In order to ensure the undisturbed supply of these elements, viruses have evolved a plethora of strategies to shape host-cell metabolism according to their specific needs. The simultaneous course of both the activation of host cell defense mechanisms and the high biomolecular turnover associated with virion production results in a highly anabolic cellular state. This is often accompanied by upregulation of the ingestion of an extracellular carbon source (e.g., glucose or glutamine) and a redirection of these carbon supplies to metabolic pathways crucial for viral replication, such as lipogenesis and nucleotide synthesis. However, not only do viruses shape host-cell metabolism in order to obtain supplies for virion production, but they also induce a reorganization of the cellular membrane and biosynthesis machinery, which is accompanied by alterations in lipid metabolism, as we shall explain later.">
    <entity charOffset="46-60" id="4cc3f3b34e4353ec33df7c231e22112232ae7218.c2.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33839" text="macromolecules" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="564-570" id="4cc3f3b34e4353ec33df7c231e22112232ae7218.c2.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_27594" text="carbon" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="585-592" id="4cc3f3b34e4353ec33df7c231e22112232ae7218.c2.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_17234" text="glucose" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="596-605" id="4cc3f3b34e4353ec33df7c231e22112232ae7218.c2.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_18050" text="glutamine" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="596-605" id="4cc3f3b34e4353ec33df7c231e22112232ae7218.c2.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_28300" text="glutamine" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="634-640" id="4cc3f3b34e4353ec33df7c231e22112232ae7218.c2.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_27594" text="carbon" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="727-737" id="4cc3f3b34e4353ec33df7c231e22112232ae7218.c2.e6" ontology_id="CHEBI_36976" text="nucleotide" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="986-991" id="4cc3f3b34e4353ec33df7c231e22112232ae7218.c2.e7" ontology_id="CHEBI_18059" text="lipid" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="4cc3f3b34e4353ec33df7c231e22112232ae7218.c3" text="The first insights into the dependence of viruses on certain carbon sources were gained decades ago, when researchers focused on investigating the consequences of glucose or glutamine deprivation on viral replication (1-6). However, it was the availability of mass spectrometry (MS)-based analysis of the metabolome that enabled fast progress toward an in-depth understanding of the interaction between viruses and host-cell metabolism. Munger et al. pioneered the field in 2006, when">
    <entity charOffset="61-67" id="4cc3f3b34e4353ec33df7c231e22112232ae7218.c3.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_27594" text="carbon" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="163-170" id="4cc3f3b34e4353ec33df7c231e22112232ae7218.c3.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_17234" text="glucose" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="174-183" id="4cc3f3b34e4353ec33df7c231e22112232ae7218.c3.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_18050" text="glutamine" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="174-183" id="4cc3f3b34e4353ec33df7c231e22112232ae7218.c3.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_28300" text="glutamine" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
