<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="512ad31f56a7be38e686f3864431191b0b9f659e">
  <chunk id="512ad31f56a7be38e686f3864431191b0b9f659e.c0" text="Punica granatum L. Leaf Extract Attenuates Lung Inflammation in Mice with Acute Lung Injury"/>
  <chunk id="512ad31f56a7be38e686f3864431191b0b9f659e.c1" text="The hydroalcoholic extract of Punica granatum (pomegranate) leaves was previously demonstrated to be anti-inflammatory in a rat model of lipopolysaccharide-(LPS-) induced acute peritonitis. Here, we investigated the anti-inflammatory effects of the ethyl acetate fraction obtained from the pomegranate leaf hydroalcoholic extract (EAFPg) on the LPS-induced acute lung injury (ALI) mouse model. Male Swiss mice received either EAFPg at different doses or dexamethasone (per os) prior to LPS intranasal instillation. Vehicle-treated mice were used as controls. Animals were culled at 4 h after LPS challenge, and the bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) and lung samples were collected for analysis. EAFPg and kaempferol effects on NO and cytokine production by LPS-stimulated RAW 264.7 macrophages were also investigated. Pretreatment with EAFPg (100-300 mg/kg) markedly reduced cell accumulation (specially neutrophils) and collagen deposition in the lungs of ALI mice. The same animals presented with reduced lung and BALF TNF-α and IL-1β expression in comparison with vehicle controls (p &lt; 0 05). Additionally, incubation with either EAFPg or kaempferol (100 μg/ml) reduced NO production and cytokine gene expression in cultured LPS-treated RAW 264.7 macrophages. Overall, these results demonstrate that the prophylactic treatment with EAFPg attenuates acute lung inflammation. We suggest this fraction may be useful in treating ALI.">
    <entity charOffset="249-254" id="512ad31f56a7be38e686f3864431191b0b9f659e.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_37807" text="ethyl" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="249-262" id="512ad31f56a7be38e686f3864431191b0b9f659e.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_27750" text="ethyl acetate" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="255-262" id="512ad31f56a7be38e686f3864431191b0b9f659e.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_30089" text="acetate" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="394-398" id="512ad31f56a7be38e686f3864431191b0b9f659e.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_30780" text="Male" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="454-467" id="512ad31f56a7be38e686f3864431191b0b9f659e.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_41879" text="dexamethasone" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="486-489" id="512ad31f56a7be38e686f3864431191b0b9f659e.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_16412" text="LPS" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="592-595" id="512ad31f56a7be38e686f3864431191b0b9f659e.c1.e6" ontology_id="CHEBI_16412" text="LPS" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="707-717" id="512ad31f56a7be38e686f3864431191b0b9f659e.c1.e7" ontology_id="CHEBI_28499" text="kaempferol" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="923-931" id="512ad31f56a7be38e686f3864431191b0b9f659e.c1.e8" ontology_id="CHEBI_3815" text="collagen" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1144-1154" id="512ad31f56a7be38e686f3864431191b0b9f659e.c1.e9" ontology_id="CHEBI_28499" text="kaempferol" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
