<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="5535ed240ab00c780ce2aa42f1fbe13ef24b9120">
  <chunk id="5535ed240ab00c780ce2aa42f1fbe13ef24b9120.c0" text="viruses Reliable and Standardized Animal Models to Study the Pathogenesis of Bluetongue and Schmallenberg Viruses in Ruminant Natural Host Species with Special Emphasis on Placental Crossing"/>
  <chunk id="5535ed240ab00c780ce2aa42f1fbe13ef24b9120.c1" text="Starting in 2006, bluetongue virus serotype 8 (BTV8) was responsible for a major epizootic in Western and Northern Europe. The magnitude and spread of the disease were surprisingly high and the control of BTV improved significantly with the marketing of BTV8 inactivated vaccines in 2008. During late summer of 2011, a first cluster of reduced milk yield, fever, and diarrhoea was reported in the Netherlands. Congenital malformations appeared in March 2012 and Schmallenberg virus (SBV) was identified, becoming one of the very few orthobunyaviruses distributed in Europe. At the start of both epizootics, little was known about the pathogenesis and epidemiology of these viruses in the European context and most assumptions were extrapolated based on other related viruses and/or other regions of the World. Standardized and repeatable models potentially mimicking clinical signs observed in the field are required to study the pathogenesis of these infections, and to clarify their ability to cross the placental barrier. This review presents some of the latest experimental designs for infectious disease challenges with BTV or SBV. Infectious doses, routes of infection, inoculum preparation, and origin are discussed. Particular emphasis is given to the placental crossing associated with these two viruses.">
    <entity charOffset="155-162" id="5535ed240ab00c780ce2aa42f1fbe13ef24b9120.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="325-332" id="5535ed240ab00c780ce2aa42f1fbe13ef24b9120.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33731" text="cluster" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="367-376" id="5535ed240ab00c780ce2aa42f1fbe13ef24b9120.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_13250" text="diarrhoea" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1090-1108" id="5535ed240ab00c780ce2aa42f1fbe13ef24b9120.c1.e3" ontology_id="DOID_0050117" text="infectious disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1101-1108" id="5535ed240ab00c780ce2aa42f1fbe13ef24b9120.c1.e4" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <pair e1="5535ed240ab00c780ce2aa42f1fbe13ef24b9120.c1.e0" e2="5535ed240ab00c780ce2aa42f1fbe13ef24b9120.c1.e1" id="5535ed240ab00c780ce2aa42f1fbe13ef24b9120.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5535ed240ab00c780ce2aa42f1fbe13ef24b9120.c1.e1" e2="5535ed240ab00c780ce2aa42f1fbe13ef24b9120.c1.e2" id="5535ed240ab00c780ce2aa42f1fbe13ef24b9120.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5535ed240ab00c780ce2aa42f1fbe13ef24b9120.c1.e1" e2="5535ed240ab00c780ce2aa42f1fbe13ef24b9120.c1.e3" id="5535ed240ab00c780ce2aa42f1fbe13ef24b9120.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5535ed240ab00c780ce2aa42f1fbe13ef24b9120.c1.e1" e2="5535ed240ab00c780ce2aa42f1fbe13ef24b9120.c1.e4" id="5535ed240ab00c780ce2aa42f1fbe13ef24b9120.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
