<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="567cbbb719b238bcd46a7c4de309537911ea42a4">
  <chunk id="567cbbb719b238bcd46a7c4de309537911ea42a4.c0" text="Canine respiratory coronavirus employs caveolin-1-mediated pathway for internalization to HRT-18G cells">
    <entity charOffset="59-66" id="567cbbb719b238bcd46a7c4de309537911ea42a4.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_34922" text="pathway" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="567cbbb719b238bcd46a7c4de309537911ea42a4.c1" text="Canine respiratory coronavirus (CRCoV), identified in 2003, is a member of the Coronaviridae family. The virus is a betacoronavirus and a close relative of human coronavirus OC43 and bovine coronavirus. Here, we examined entry of CRCoV into human rectal tumor cells (HRT-18G cell line) by analyzing co-localization of single virus particles with cellular markers in the presence or absence of chemical inhibitors of pathways potentially involved in virus entry. We also targeted these pathways using siRNA. The results show that the virus hijacks caveolin-dependent endocytosis to enter cells via endocytic internalization. © The Author(s) 2018. This article is distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License (http://creat iveco mmons .org/licen ses/by/4.0/), which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons license, and indicate if changes were made. The Creative Commons Public Domain Dedication waiver">
    <entity charOffset="247-259" id="567cbbb719b238bcd46a7c4de309537911ea42a4.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_1984" text="rectal tumor" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="402-412" id="567cbbb719b238bcd46a7c4de309537911ea42a4.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_35222" text="inhibitors" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="567cbbb719b238bcd46a7c4de309537911ea42a4.c1.e0" e2="567cbbb719b238bcd46a7c4de309537911ea42a4.c1.e1" id="567cbbb719b238bcd46a7c4de309537911ea42a4.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
