<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="57e168131391d871fa93444a1741f3f2b4403d45">
  <chunk id="57e168131391d871fa93444a1741f3f2b4403d45.c0" text="Development of pooled testing system for porcine epidemic diarrhoea using real-time fluorescent reverse-transcription loop- mediated isothermal amplification assay">
    <entity charOffset="58-67" id="57e168131391d871fa93444a1741f3f2b4403d45.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_13250" text="diarrhoea" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="57e168131391d871fa93444a1741f3f2b4403d45.c1" text="Background: Porcine epidemic diarrhoea (PED) is an emerging disease in pigs that causes massive economic losses in the swine industry, with high mortality in suckling piglets. Early identification of PED virus (PEDV)-infected herd through surveillance or monitoring strategies is necessary for mass control of PED. However, a common working diagnosis system involves identifying PEDV-infected animals individually, which is a costly and time-consuming approach. Given the above information, the thrusts of this study were to develop a real-time fluorescent reverse transcription loop-mediated isothermal amplification (RtF-RT-LAMP) assay and establish a pooled testing system using faecal sample to identify PEDV-infected herd. Results: In this study, we developed an accurate, rapid, cost-effective, and simple RtF-RT-LAMP assay for detecting the PEDV genome targeting M gene. The pooled testing system using the RtF-RT-LAMP assay was optimized such that a pool of at least 15 individual faecal samples could be analysed. Conclusions: The developed RtF-RT-LAMP assay in our study could support the design and implementation of largescaled epidemiological surveys as well as active surveillance and monitoring programs for effective control of PED.">
    <entity charOffset="29-38" id="57e168131391d871fa93444a1741f3f2b4403d45.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_13250" text="diarrhoea" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="60-67" id="57e168131391d871fa93444a1741f3f2b4403d45.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
