<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="5a6e220c6796a02e36a272103dd39dd62c9311eb">
  <chunk id="5a6e220c6796a02e36a272103dd39dd62c9311eb.c0" text="Antibody Engineering for Pursuing a Healthier Future"/>
  <chunk id="5a6e220c6796a02e36a272103dd39dd62c9311eb.c1" text="Since the development of antibody-production techniques, a number of immunoglobulins have been developed on a large scale using conventional methods. Hybridoma technology opened a new horizon in the production of antibodies against target antigens of infectious pathogens, malignant diseases including autoimmune disorders, and numerous potent toxins. However, these clinical humanized or chimeric murine antibodies have several limitations and complexities. Therefore, to overcome these difficulties, recent advances in genetic engineering techniques and phage display technique have allowed the production of highly specific recombinant antibodies. These engineered antibodies have been constructed in the hunt for novel therapeutic drugs equipped with enhanced immunoprotective abilities, such as engaging immune effector functions, effective development of fusion proteins, efficient tumor and tissue penetration, and high-affinity antibodies directed against conserved targets. Advanced antibody engineering techniques have extensive applications in the fields of immunology, biotechnology, diagnostics, and therapeutic medicines. However, there is limited knowledge regarding dynamic antibody development approaches. Therefore, this review extends beyond our understanding of conventional polyclonal and monoclonal antibodies. Furthermore, recent advances in antibody engineering techniques together with antibody fragments, display technologies, immunomodulation, and broad applications of antibodies are discussed to enhance innovative antibody production in pursuit of a healthier future for humans.">
    <entity charOffset="239-247" id="5a6e220c6796a02e36a272103dd39dd62c9311eb.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_59132" text="antigens" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="735-740" id="5a6e220c6796a02e36a272103dd39dd62c9311eb.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_23888" text="drugs" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="816-824" id="5a6e220c6796a02e36a272103dd39dd62c9311eb.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_35224" text="effector" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
