<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2">
  <chunk id="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c0" text="Analysis of Transmission and Control of Tuberculosis in Mainland China, 2005-2016, Based on the Age-Structure Mathematical Model">
    <entity charOffset="40-52" id="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_399" text="Tuberculosis" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1" text="Tuberculosis (TB), an air-borne infectious disease, is a major public-health problem in China. The reported number of the active tuberculosis cases is about one million each year. The morbidity data for 2005-2012 reflect that the difference in morbidity based on age group is significant, thus the role of age-structure on the transmission of TB needs to be further developed. In this work, based on the reported data and the observed morbidity characteristics, we propose a susceptible-exposed-infectious-recovered (SEIR) epidemic model with age groupings, involving three categories: children, the middle-aged, and senior to investigate the role of age on the transmission of tuberculosis in Mainland China from 2005 to 2016. Then, we evaluated the parameters by the Least Square method and simulated the model and it had good alignment with the reported infected TB data in Mainland China. Furthermore, we estimated the basic reproduction number R 0 of 1.7858, with an obtained 95% confidence interval for R 0 of (1.7752, 1.7963) by Latin hypercube sampling, and we completed a sensitivity analysis of R 0 in terms of some parameters. Our study demonstrates that diverse age groups have different effects on TB. Two effective measures were found that would help reach the goals of the World Health Organization (WHO) End TB Strategy: an increase in the recovery rate and the reduction in the infectious rate of the senior age group. and the WHO's short course chemotherapy strategy, TB remains a major cause of illness and death in most high-incidence countries.">
    <entity charOffset="0-12" id="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_399" text="Tuberculosis" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="129-141" id="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_399" text="tuberculosis" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="298-302" id="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="643-647" id="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="678-690" id="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1.e4" ontology_id="DOID_399" text="tuberculosis" type="disease"/>
    <pair e1="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1.e0" e2="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1.e2" id="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1.e0" e2="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1.e3" id="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1.e1" e2="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1.e2" id="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1.e1" e2="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1.e3" id="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1.e2" e2="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1.e4" id="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1.e3" e2="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1.e4" id="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c1.p5" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c2" text="As in many high-TB burden countries, TB is a major public health problem in China. Attributed to the emergence of drug-resistant strains of Mtb and the spread of HIV/AIDS, the TB burden in China has increased over the past two decades [3] . Meanwhile, according to the United Nations, as a result of the one-child policy and low mortality, China is ageing more rapidly than almost any other country [4] . From the morbidity statistics from 2005 to 2012, shown in Figure 1 , we know that the difference in morbidity between different age groups is remarkable: the morbidity of the 0-14 age group is the lowest and that of the 60 and older age group is the highest, while the morbidity of the 15-59 age group is in between. However, the role of this age grouping pattern in the transmission of TB in China is not yet clear. Therefore, we wanted to identify the potential effect of age on the morbidity for the transmission of TB in China, which could help provide effective control strategies for diverse sub-populations.">
    <entity charOffset="735-739" id="5a7988cd92e05a8bca504b5f1a467e2c8d3976d2.c2.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
