<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="60bb4454a34fb7642d6805ff6261abc91809a135">
  <chunk id="60bb4454a34fb7642d6805ff6261abc91809a135.c0" text="Drainage systems, an occluded source of sanitation related outbreaks"/>
  <chunk id="60bb4454a34fb7642d6805ff6261abc91809a135.c1" text="Background: Drainage systems and its role in sanitation related outbreaks are evident but still occluded once it has been installed. This current review evaluates if drainage systems can cause infections and thus be of clinical concern.">
    <entity charOffset="37-41" id="60bb4454a34fb7642d6805ff6261abc91809a135.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="60bb4454a34fb7642d6805ff6261abc91809a135.c2" text="Method: A review of the literature was analyzed. Papers, guidelines, and quality management systems have been considered. Results: Adequate sanitation is fundamental and a prerequisite for safe life and productivity. In contrast, malfunctioning sanitation has been reported to cause outbreaks all over the world. In areas with no sanitation, diarrheal mortality is high and has been shown to decrease by 36% after interventions to improve sanitation. Often, infections are faeces associated and when present in wastewater and sewage sludge poses a high risk of infection upon exposure. Hence, there are working safety guidelines and in industries where infection reduction is essential strict quality assurance systems, i.e. HACCP (hazard analysis critical control points) and GMP (Good Manufacturing Practice) must be complied. Healthcare has recently taken interest in the HACCP system in their efforts to reduce healthcare associated infections as a response to increasing number of ineffective antibiotics and the threat of mortality rate like the pre-antibiotic era. The last few years have called for immediate action to contain the emergence of increasing resistant microorganisms. Resistance is obtained as a result of overuse and misuse of antibiotics in both healthcare and agriculture. Also, by the discharge of antibiotics from manufacturers, healthcare and society. One mechanism of development of novel resistant pathogens has been shown to be by effortless sharing of genetic mobile elements coding for resistance from microbes in the environment to human microbes. These pathogens have been sampled from the drainage systems. These were noticed owing to their possession of an unusual antibiotic resistance profile linking them to the outbreak. Often the cause of sanitation related outbreaks is due to inadequate sanitation and maintenance. However, in general these infections probably go unnoticed.">
    <entity charOffset="777-780" id="60bb4454a34fb7642d6805ff6261abc91809a135.c2.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_17345" text="GMP" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="998-1009" id="60bb4454a34fb7642d6805ff6261abc91809a135.c2.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33281" text="antibiotics" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1117-1123" id="60bb4454a34fb7642d6805ff6261abc91809a135.c2.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_5133" text="action" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1249-1260" id="60bb4454a34fb7642d6805ff6261abc91809a135.c2.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_33281" text="antibiotics" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1323-1334" id="60bb4454a34fb7642d6805ff6261abc91809a135.c2.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_33281" text="antibiotics" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1498-1506" id="60bb4454a34fb7642d6805ff6261abc91809a135.c2.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_33250" text="elements" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1701-1711" id="60bb4454a34fb7642d6805ff6261abc91809a135.c2.e6" ontology_id="CHEBI_33281" text="antibiotic" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="60bb4454a34fb7642d6805ff6261abc91809a135.c3" text="Conclusion: Drainage systems and its maintenance, if neglected, could pose a threat in both community and healthcare causing infections as well as emergence of multi-resistant bacteria that could cause unpredictable clinical manifestations."/>
</document>
