<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="659220e080e623e34f3efe2ce84e63fb2cefdd8e">
  <chunk id="659220e080e623e34f3efe2ce84e63fb2cefdd8e.c0" text="Phylodynamic applications in 21 st century global infectious disease research">
    <entity charOffset="50-68" id="659220e080e623e34f3efe2ce84e63fb2cefdd8e.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_0050117" text="infectious disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="61-68" id="659220e080e623e34f3efe2ce84e63fb2cefdd8e.c0.e1" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="659220e080e623e34f3efe2ce84e63fb2cefdd8e.c1" text="Background: Phylodynamics, the study of the interaction between epidemiological and pathogen evolutionary processes within and among populations, was originally defined in the context of rapidly evolving viruses and used to characterize transmission dynamics. The concept of phylodynamics has evolved since the early 21 st century, extending its reach to slower-evolving pathogens, including bacteria and fungi, and to the identification of influential factors in disease spread and pathogen population dynamics. Results: The phylodynamic approach has now become a fundamental building block for the development of comparative phylogenetic tools capable of incorporating epidemiological surveillance data with molecular sequences into a single statistical framework. These innovative tools have greatly enhanced scientific investigations of the temporal and geographical origins, evolutionary history, and ecological risk factors associated with the growth and spread of viruses such as human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), Zika, and dengue and bacteria such as Methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus. Conclusions: Capitalizing on an extensive review of the literature, we discuss the evolution of the field of infectious disease epidemiology and recent accomplishments, highlighting the advancements in phylodynamics, as well as the challenges and limitations currently facing researchers studying emerging pathogen epidemics across the globe.">
    <entity charOffset="464-471" id="659220e080e623e34f3efe2ce84e63fb2cefdd8e.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1215-1233" id="659220e080e623e34f3efe2ce84e63fb2cefdd8e.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_0050117" text="infectious disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1226-1233" id="659220e080e623e34f3efe2ce84e63fb2cefdd8e.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
