<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="6673835e81ea115480bd68bc4e2d90c742bb77c1">
  <chunk id="6673835e81ea115480bd68bc4e2d90c742bb77c1.c0" text="Susceptibility of Chickens to Porcine Deltacoronavirus Infection"/>
  <chunk id="6673835e81ea115480bd68bc4e2d90c742bb77c1.c1" text="Porcine deltacoronavirus (PDCoV) is a novel swine enteropathogenic coronavirus with worldwide distribution. PDCoV belongs to the Deltacoronavirus (DCoV) genus, which mainly includes avian coronaviruses (CoVs). PDCoV has the potential to infect human and chicken cells in vitro, and also has limited infectivity in calves. However, the origin of PDCoV in pigs, the host range, and cross-species infection of PDCoV still remain unclear. To determine whether PDCoV really has the ability to infect chickens in vivo, the three lines of chicken embryos and specific pathogen free (SPF) chickens were inoculated with PDCoV HNZK-02 strain to investigate PDCoV infection in the current study. Our results indicated that PDCoV can infect chicken embryos and could be continuously passaged on them. Furthermore, we observed that PDCoV-inoculated chickens showed mild diarrhea symptoms and low fecal viral RNA shedding. PDCoV RNA could also be detected in multiple organs (lung, kidney, jejunum, cecum, and rectum) and intestinal contents of PDCoV-inoculated chickens until 17 day post-inoculation by real-time quantitative PCR (qRT-PCR). A histology analysis indicated that PDCoV caused mild lesions in the lung, kidney, and intestinal tissues. These results prove the susceptibility of chickens to PDCoV infection, which might provide more insight about the cross-species transmission of PDCoV.">
    <entity charOffset="576-579" id="6673835e81ea115480bd68bc4e2d90c742bb77c1.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_88542" text="SPF" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="857-865" id="6673835e81ea115480bd68bc4e2d90c742bb77c1.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_13250" text="diarrhea" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="895-898" id="6673835e81ea115480bd68bc4e2d90c742bb77c1.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="915-918" id="6673835e81ea115480bd68bc4e2d90c742bb77c1.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="6673835e81ea115480bd68bc4e2d90c742bb77c1.c1.e0" e2="6673835e81ea115480bd68bc4e2d90c742bb77c1.c1.e1" id="6673835e81ea115480bd68bc4e2d90c742bb77c1.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="6673835e81ea115480bd68bc4e2d90c742bb77c1.c1.e1" e2="6673835e81ea115480bd68bc4e2d90c742bb77c1.c1.e2" id="6673835e81ea115480bd68bc4e2d90c742bb77c1.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="6673835e81ea115480bd68bc4e2d90c742bb77c1.c1.e1" e2="6673835e81ea115480bd68bc4e2d90c742bb77c1.c1.e3" id="6673835e81ea115480bd68bc4e2d90c742bb77c1.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
