<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="6bb112bc662ab0ff3a6f44b4f28873c12228c641">
  <chunk id="6bb112bc662ab0ff3a6f44b4f28873c12228c641.c0" text="molecules Advanced Nanobiomaterials: Vaccines, Diagnosis and Treatment of Infectious Diseases">
    <entity charOffset="0-9" id="6bb112bc662ab0ff3a6f44b4f28873c12228c641.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_25367" text="molecules" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="6bb112bc662ab0ff3a6f44b4f28873c12228c641.c1" text="The use of nanoparticles has contributed to many advances due to their important properties such as, size, shape or biocompatibility. The use of nanotechnology in medicine has great potential, especially in medical microbiology. Promising data show the possibility of shaping immune responses and fighting severe infections using synthetic materials. Different studies have suggested that the addition of synthetic nanoparticles in vaccines and immunotherapy will have a great impact on public health. On the other hand, antibiotic resistance is one of the major concerns worldwide; a recent report of the World Health Organization (WHO) states that antibiotic resistance could cause 300 million deaths by 2050. Nanomedicine offers an innovative tool for combating the high rates of resistance that we are fighting nowadays, by the development of both alternative therapeutic and prophylaxis approaches and also novel diagnosis methods. Early detection of infectious diseases is the key to a successful treatment and the new developed applications based on nanotechnology offer an increased sensibility and efficiency of the diagnosis. The aim of this review is to reveal and discuss the main advances made on the science of nanomaterials for the prevention, diagnosis and treatment of infectious diseases. Highlighting innovative approaches utilized to: (i) increasing the efficiency of vaccines; (ii) obtaining shuttle systems that require lower antibiotic concentrations; (iii) developing coating devices that inhibit microbial colonization and biofilm formation.">
    <entity charOffset="11-24" id="6bb112bc662ab0ff3a6f44b4f28873c12228c641.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_50803" text="nanoparticles" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="163-171" id="6bb112bc662ab0ff3a6f44b4f28873c12228c641.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_23888" text="medicine" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="415-428" id="6bb112bc662ab0ff3a6f44b4f28873c12228c641.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_50803" text="nanoparticles" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="521-531" id="6bb112bc662ab0ff3a6f44b4f28873c12228c641.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_33281" text="antibiotic" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="650-660" id="6bb112bc662ab0ff3a6f44b4f28873c12228c641.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_33281" text="antibiotic" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1448-1458" id="6bb112bc662ab0ff3a6f44b4f28873c12228c641.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_33281" text="antibiotic" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
