<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="6c3d20fd2c5c86c813cddcaef028a3c5f6d7cf34">
  <chunk id="6c3d20fd2c5c86c813cddcaef028a3c5f6d7cf34.c0" text="molecules iPPBS-Opt: A Sequence-Based Ensemble Classifier for Identifying Protein-Protein Binding Sites by Optimizing Imbalanced Training Datasets">
    <entity charOffset="0-9" id="6c3d20fd2c5c86c813cddcaef028a3c5f6d7cf34.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_25367" text="molecules" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="6c3d20fd2c5c86c813cddcaef028a3c5f6d7cf34.c1" text="Knowledge of protein-protein interactions and their binding sites is indispensable for in-depth understanding of the networks in living cells. With the avalanche of protein sequences generated in the postgenomic age, it is critical to develop computational methods for identifying in a timely fashion the protein-protein binding sites (PPBSs) based on the sequence information alone because the information obtained by this way can be used for both biomedical research and drug development. To address such a challenge, we have proposed a new predictor, called iPPBS-Opt, in which we have used: (1) the K-Nearest Neighbors Cleaning (KNNC) and Inserting Hypothetical Training Samples (IHTS) treatments to optimize the training dataset; (2) the ensemble voting approach to select the most relevant features; and (3) the stationary wavelet transform to formulate the statistical samples. Cross-validation tests by targeting the experiment-confirmed results have demonstrated that the new predictor is very promising, implying that the aforementioned practices are indeed very effective. Particularly, the approach of using the wavelets to express protein/peptide sequences might be the key in grasping the problem's essence, fully consistent with the findings that many important biological functions of proteins can be elucidated with their low-frequency internal motions. To maximize the convenience of most experimental scientists, we have provided a step-by-step guide on how to use the predictor's web server (http://www.jci-bioinfo.cn/iPPBS-Opt) to get the desired results without the need to go through the complicated mathematical equations involved.">
    <entity charOffset="165-172" id="6c3d20fd2c5c86c813cddcaef028a3c5f6d7cf34.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="473-477" id="6c3d20fd2c5c86c813cddcaef028a3c5f6d7cf34.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_23888" text="drug" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="837-846" id="6c3d20fd2c5c86c813cddcaef028a3c5f6d7cf34.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_133305" text="transform" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1144-1151" id="6c3d20fd2c5c86c813cddcaef028a3c5f6d7cf34.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1301-1309" id="6c3d20fd2c5c86c813cddcaef028a3c5f6d7cf34.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
