<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="6e94aa9c37dd7be5b553090717c59992005d114b">
  <chunk id="6e94aa9c37dd7be5b553090717c59992005d114b.c0" text="Operational Programme of the Autonomous Region of Sardinia"/>
  <chunk id="6e94aa9c37dd7be5b553090717c59992005d114b.c1" text="The activation of astrocytes and microglia is often associated with diseases of the central nervous system (CNS). Understanding how activation alters the transcriptome of these cells may offer valuable insight regarding how activation of these cells mediate neurological damage. Furthermore, identifying common and unique pathways of gene expression during activation may provide new insight into the distinct roles these cells have in the CNS during infection and inflammation. Since recent studies indicate that TLR7 recognizes not only viral RNA but also microRNAs that are released by damaged neurons and elevated during neurological diseases, we first examined the response of glial cells to TLR7 stimulation using microarray analysis. Microglia were found to generate a much stronger response to TLR7 activation than astrocytes, both in the number of genes induced as well as fold induction. Although the primary pathways induced by both cell types were directly linked to immune responses, microglia also induced pathways associated with cellular proliferation, while astrocytes did not. Targeted analysis of a subset of the upregulated genes identified unique mRNA, including Ifi202b which was only upregulated by microglia and was found to be induced during both retroviral and bunyavirus infections in the CNS. In addition, other genes including Birc3 and Gpr84 as well as two expressed sequences AW112010 and BC023105 were found to be induced in both microglia and astrocytes and were upregulated in the CNS following virus infection. Thus, expression of these genes may a useful measurement of glial activation during insult or injury to the CNS.">
    <entity charOffset="545-548" id="6e94aa9c37dd7be5b553090717c59992005d114b.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="6e94aa9c37dd7be5b553090717c59992005d114b.c2" text="Astrocyte and microglia cultures were prepared from the brain cortex of 1-2 day old Inbred Rocky Mountain White (IRW) mice as previously described [20] . In brief, brain tissue was removed from multiple animals at 2 days of age and placed in ice cold phosphate buffered saline (PBS). Hind brains, mid brains, and meninges were dissected out. Cerebral cortices were TLR-Induced Transcriptome Changes in Glial Cells PLOS ONE |">
    <entity charOffset="246-250" id="6e94aa9c37dd7be5b553090717c59992005d114b.c2.e0" ontology_id="DOID_3083" text="cold" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="251-260" id="6e94aa9c37dd7be5b553090717c59992005d114b.c2.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_18367" text="phosphate" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="419-422" id="6e94aa9c37dd7be5b553090717c59992005d114b.c2.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_58972" text="ONE" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="6e94aa9c37dd7be5b553090717c59992005d114b.c2.e0" e2="6e94aa9c37dd7be5b553090717c59992005d114b.c2.e1" id="6e94aa9c37dd7be5b553090717c59992005d114b.c2.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="6e94aa9c37dd7be5b553090717c59992005d114b.c2.e0" e2="6e94aa9c37dd7be5b553090717c59992005d114b.c2.e2" id="6e94aa9c37dd7be5b553090717c59992005d114b.c2.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
