<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="71b9d32718c8ba343468da22dc28314f84b852ec">
  <chunk id="71b9d32718c8ba343468da22dc28314f84b852ec.c0" text="A Lattice Model for Influenza Spreading">
    <entity charOffset="20-29" id="71b9d32718c8ba343468da22dc28314f84b852ec.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="Influenza" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="71b9d32718c8ba343468da22dc28314f84b852ec.c1" text="We construct a stochastic SIR model for influenza spreading on a D-dimensional lattice, which represents the dynamic contact network of individuals. An age distributed population is placed on the lattice and moves on it. The displacement from a site to a nearest neighbor empty site, allows individuals to change the number and identities of their contacts. The dynamics on the lattice is governed by an attractive interaction between individuals belonging to the same age-class. The parameters, which regulate the pattern dynamics, are fixed fitting the data on the age-dependent daily contact numbers, furnished by the Polymod survey. A simple SIR transmission model with a nearest neighbors interaction and some very basic adaptive mobility restrictions complete the model. The model is validated against the age-distributed Italian epidemiological data for the influenza A(H1N1) during the 2009=2010 season, with sensible predictions for the epidemiological parameters. For an appropriate topology of the lattice, we find that, whenever the accordance between the contact patterns of the model and the Polymod data is satisfactory, there is a good agreement between the numerical and the experimental epidemiological data. This result shows how rich is the information encoded in the average contact patterns of individuals, with respect to the analysis of the epidemic spreading of an infectious disease. Citation: Liccardo A, Fierro A (2013) A Lattice Model for Influenza Spreading. PLoS ONE 8(5): e63935.">
    <entity charOffset="40-49" id="71b9d32718c8ba343468da22dc28314f84b852ec.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="865-874" id="71b9d32718c8ba343468da22dc28314f84b852ec.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1468-1477" id="71b9d32718c8ba343468da22dc28314f84b852ec.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="Influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1494-1497" id="71b9d32718c8ba343468da22dc28314f84b852ec.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_58972" text="ONE" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="71b9d32718c8ba343468da22dc28314f84b852ec.c1.e0" e2="71b9d32718c8ba343468da22dc28314f84b852ec.c1.e3" id="71b9d32718c8ba343468da22dc28314f84b852ec.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="71b9d32718c8ba343468da22dc28314f84b852ec.c1.e1" e2="71b9d32718c8ba343468da22dc28314f84b852ec.c1.e3" id="71b9d32718c8ba343468da22dc28314f84b852ec.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="71b9d32718c8ba343468da22dc28314f84b852ec.c1.e2" e2="71b9d32718c8ba343468da22dc28314f84b852ec.c1.e3" id="71b9d32718c8ba343468da22dc28314f84b852ec.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
