<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="7266d5a2b588f4bd08e301590247156d59a7f227">
  <chunk id="7266d5a2b588f4bd08e301590247156d59a7f227.c0" text="A Rapid Method to Characterize Mouse IgG Antibodies and Isolate Native Antigen Binding IgG B Cell Hybridomas">
    <entity charOffset="71-78" id="7266d5a2b588f4bd08e301590247156d59a7f227.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_59132" text="Antigen" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="7266d5a2b588f4bd08e301590247156d59a7f227.c1" text="B cell hybridomas are an important source of monoclonal antibodies. In this paper, we developed a high-throughput method to characterize mouse IgG antibodies using surface plasmon resonance technology. This assay rapidly determines their sub-isotypes, whether they bind native antigen and their approximate affinities for the antigen using only 50 μl of hybridoma cell culture supernatant. Moreover, we found that mouse hybridomas secreting IgG antibodies also have membrane form IgG expression without Igα. Based on this surface IgG, we used flow cytometry to isolate rare γ2a isotype switched variants from a γ2b antibody secreting hybridoma cell line. Also, we used fluorescent antigen to single cell sort antigen binding hybridoma cells from bulk mixture of fused hybridoma cells instead of the traditional multi-microwell plate screening and limiting dilution sub-cloning thus saving time and labor. The IgG monoclonal antibodies specific for the native antigen identified with these methods are suitable for in vivo therapeutic uses, but also for sandwich ELISA assays, histology, flow cytometry, immune precipitation and x-ray crystallography. Fig 5. Isolation of IgG ɣ2a antibody secreting cells from an IgG ɣ2b hybridoma cell line. (A) Detection of IgG ɣ2a antibody secreting hybridoma cells in S212, an IgG ɣ2b hybridoma cell line with ELISPOT. (B) Cell surface IgG staining of S212 cells. (C) Enrichment of IgG ɣ2a secreting cells by MACS and single cell sorting of these heavy chain switched cells. (D) Biacore testing of S212 IgG ɣ2b antibody and the switched IgG ɣ2a antibody.">
    <entity charOffset="277-284" id="7266d5a2b588f4bd08e301590247156d59a7f227.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_59132" text="antigen" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="326-333" id="7266d5a2b588f4bd08e301590247156d59a7f227.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_59132" text="antigen" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="681-688" id="7266d5a2b588f4bd08e301590247156d59a7f227.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_59132" text="antigen" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="709-716" id="7266d5a2b588f4bd08e301590247156d59a7f227.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_59132" text="antigen" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="751-758" id="7266d5a2b588f4bd08e301590247156d59a7f227.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_60004" text="mixture" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="959-966" id="7266d5a2b588f4bd08e301590247156d59a7f227.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_59132" text="antigen" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="7266d5a2b588f4bd08e301590247156d59a7f227.c2" text="Fig 6. Sorting of native antigen binding IgG hybridomas from a fusion bulk mixture. (A) Staining of OVA specific hybridoma cell line with fluorescent OVA. (B) Sorting of OVA specific hybridoma clls from a fusion bulk mixture.">
    <entity charOffset="25-32" id="7266d5a2b588f4bd08e301590247156d59a7f227.c2.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_59132" text="antigen" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
