<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="74af665d4b129e0ed662f50fa0d215f4ff2c2c52">
  <chunk id="74af665d4b129e0ed662f50fa0d215f4ff2c2c52.c0" text="Microbiome-transcriptome interactions Related to Severity of Respiratory Syncytial Virus infection">
    <entity charOffset="83-98" id="74af665d4b129e0ed662f50fa0d215f4ff2c2c52.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_934" text="Virus infection" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="74af665d4b129e0ed662f50fa0d215f4ff2c2c52.c1" text="microbial species in the respiratory tract is only partially known. We aimed to understand the impact of interactions between the nasal microbiome and host transcriptome on the severity and clinical outcomes of RSV infection. We used 16 S rRNA sequencing to characterize the nasal microbiome of infants with RSV infection. We used RNA sequencing to interrogate the transcriptome of CD4 + t cells obtained from the same set of infants. After dimension reduction through principal component (pc) analysis, we performed an integrative analysis to identify significant co-variation between microbial clade and gene expression pcs. We then employed LioneSS (Linear interpolation to obtain network estimates for Single Samples) to estimate the clade-gene association patterns for each infant. our network-based integrative analysis identified several clade-gene associations significantly related to the severity of RSV infection. the microbial taxa with the highest loadings in the implicated clade pcs included Moraxella, Corynebacterium, Streptococcus, Haemophilus influenzae, and Staphylococcus. interestingly, many of the genes with the highest loadings in the implicated gene pcs are encoded in mitochondrial DnA, while others are involved in the host immune response. this study on microbiometranscriptome interactions provides insights into how the host immune system mounts a response against RSV and specific infectious agents in nasal microbiota.">
    <entity charOffset="239-243" id="74af665d4b129e0ed662f50fa0d215f4ff2c2c52.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_18111" text="rRNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="331-334" id="74af665d4b129e0ed662f50fa0d215f4ff2c2c52.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="74af665d4b129e0ed662f50fa0d215f4ff2c2c52.c2" text="Respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) is a major cause of lower respiratory tract infections and hospital visits during infancy and childhood 1-3 . Almost all children will have been infected with RSV by age two, with about 3% requiring hospitalization. A recent report estimated that in 2015 about 33.1 million children worldwide under age 5 had RSV-related acute lower respiratory infection; of those, approximately 10% required hospitalization with 59,000 in-hospital fatalities 1 . The incidence and mortality of RSV vary between geographic locations, with children from developing countries considered to be at higher risk 4 . In the United States, 20% of infants require outpatient treatment for RSV-related illnesses, with an associated economic burden of $1.9 billion 5 ; around 3% of these cases are associated with serious bronchiolitis and viral pneumonia-the most common forms of severe RSV infection.">
    <entity charOffset="829-842" id="74af665d4b129e0ed662f50fa0d215f4ff2c2c52.c2.e0" ontology_id="DOID_2942" text="bronchiolitis" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="74af665d4b129e0ed662f50fa0d215f4ff2c2c52.c3" text="Analysis of sample-specific networks. We separated the sample-specific LIONESS networks based on their severity class and compared the distribution of each edge's weight between mild and severe groups using limma (version 3.34.9) correcting for sex and race. All edges with p-value &lt; 0.05 were considered nominally significant."/>
  <chunk id="74af665d4b129e0ed662f50fa0d215f4ff2c2c52.c4" text="The Institutional Review Boards of the University of Rochester and Rochester General Hospital approved the study. For each infant, one parent provided written informed consent at enrollment. All methods were performed in accordance with the relevant guidelines and regulations. The data analyzed in the manuscript are available on dbGap (phs001201.v1.p1)."/>
</document>
