<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="75622daf6a8bde4809687a432c5bd991d8a849ea">
  <chunk id="75622daf6a8bde4809687a432c5bd991d8a849ea.c0" text="ARTICLE Junctional and allele-specific residues are critical for MERS-CoV neutralization by an exceptionally potent germline-like antibody"/>
  <chunk id="75622daf6a8bde4809687a432c5bd991d8a849ea.c1" text="The MERS-CoV is an emerging virus, which already infected more than 1,300 humans with high (B36%) mortality. Here, we show that m336, an exceptionally potent human anti-MERS-CoV antibody, is almost germline with only one somatic mutation in the heavy chain. The structure of Fab m336 in complex with the MERS-CoV receptor-binding domain reveals that its IGHV1-69-derived heavy chain provides more than 85% binding surface and that its epitope almost completely overlaps with the receptor-binding site. Analysis of antibodies from 69 healthy humans suggests an important role of the V(D)J recombination-generated junctional and allele-specific residues for achieving high affinity of binding at such low levels of somatic hypermutation. Our results also have important implications for development of vaccine immunogens based on the newly identified m336 epitope as well as for elucidation of mechanisms of neutralization by m336-like antibodies and their elicitation in vivo. Figure 1 | Crystal structures of Fab m336 in complex with MERS-CoV RBD. (a) Complex structure in cartoon representation. Heavy and light chains of m336 are coloured light green and light blue, respectively. The receptor-binding subdomain on MERS-CoV RBD is coloured orange with Trp535 shown in shticks representation. (b) Sequences of m336 heavy chain and light chain with residues that interact with the MERS-CoV RBD highlighted with orange dots. Antibody residues are numbered according to the Kabat nomenclature. (c) Interaction between CDRs of m336 and the MERS-CoV RBD. m336 CDRs are shown in cartoon representation and the MERS-CoV RBD is depicted in semitransparent surface and cartoon. (d) Detailed interactions between m336 and patches 1 and 2 of the MERS-CoV RBD. Key residues are highlighted in stick representation. Hydrogen bonds and salt bridges are displayed with dotted lines connecting interacting atoms. The non-canonical disulphide bond between HCDR3 residues Cys98 and Cys100c is in yellow sticks. Both panels (c,d) are shown as different 90°views from panel (a).">
    <entity charOffset="435-442" id="75622daf6a8bde4809687a432c5bd991d8a849ea.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_53000" text="epitope" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="570-574" id="75622daf6a8bde4809687a432c5bd991d8a849ea.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="854-861" id="75622daf6a8bde4809687a432c5bd991d8a849ea.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_53000" text="epitope" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1107-1112" id="75622daf6a8bde4809687a432c5bd991d8a849ea.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_30212" text="light" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1141-1146" id="75622daf6a8bde4809687a432c5bd991d8a849ea.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_30212" text="light" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1141-1152" id="75622daf6a8bde4809687a432c5bd991d8a849ea.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_87065" text="light green" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1157-1162" id="75622daf6a8bde4809687a432c5bd991d8a849ea.c1.e6" ontology_id="CHEBI_30212" text="light" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1332-1337" id="75622daf6a8bde4809687a432c5bd991d8a849ea.c1.e7" ontology_id="CHEBI_30212" text="light" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1804-1812" id="75622daf6a8bde4809687a432c5bd991d8a849ea.c1.e8" ontology_id="CHEBI_18276" text="Hydrogen" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1804-1812" id="75622daf6a8bde4809687a432c5bd991d8a849ea.c1.e9" ontology_id="CHEBI_49637" text="Hydrogen" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1823-1827" id="75622daf6a8bde4809687a432c5bd991d8a849ea.c1.e10" ontology_id="CHEBI_24866" text="salt" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
