<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="7c8f40872fb6e8d5289fec4b0573cc22e15fa180">
  <chunk id="7c8f40872fb6e8d5289fec4b0573cc22e15fa180.c0" text="Military-civilian cooperative emergency response to infectious disease prevention and control in China">
    <entity charOffset="52-70" id="7c8f40872fb6e8d5289fec4b0573cc22e15fa180.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_0050117" text="infectious disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="63-70" id="7c8f40872fb6e8d5289fec4b0573cc22e15fa180.c0.e1" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="7c8f40872fb6e8d5289fec4b0573cc22e15fa180.c1" text="In recent years, the incidence of severe infectious diseases has increased, and the number of emerging infectious diseases continues to increase. The Chinese government and military forces have paid a great deal of attention to infectious disease prevention and control, and using military-civilian cooperation, they have successfully prevented numerous severe epidemic situations, such as severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS), influenza A (H1N1), avian influenza H5N1 and H7N9, and Ebola hemorrhagic fever, while actively maintained public health, economic development, and national construction. This paper focuses on the mechanisms of the military-cooperative emergency response to infectious diseases-the joint working mechanism, the information-sharing mechanism, the research collaboration mechanism, and the joint disposal mechanism-and presents a sorted summary of the practices and experiences of cooperative emergency responses to infectious diseases. In the future, the Chinese military and the civilian sector will further strengthen the cooperative joint command system and emergency rescue force and will reinforce their collaborative information-sharing platform and technical equipment system to further improve military-civilian collaborative emergency infectious diseases disposal, advance the level of infectious disease prevention and control, and maintain public health.">
    <entity charOffset="228-246" id="7c8f40872fb6e8d5289fec4b0573cc22e15fa180.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_0050117" text="infectious disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="239-246" id="7c8f40872fb6e8d5289fec4b0573cc22e15fa180.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="390-423" id="7c8f40872fb6e8d5289fec4b0573cc22e15fa180.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_2945" text="severe acute respiratory syndrome" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="415-423" id="7c8f40872fb6e8d5289fec4b0573cc22e15fa180.c1.e3" ontology_id="DOID_225" text="syndrome" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="432-441" id="7c8f40872fb6e8d5289fec4b0573cc22e15fa180.c1.e4" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="452-467" id="7c8f40872fb6e8d5289fec4b0573cc22e15fa180.c1.e5" ontology_id="DOID_4492" text="avian influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="458-467" id="7c8f40872fb6e8d5289fec4b0573cc22e15fa180.c1.e6" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="487-510" id="7c8f40872fb6e8d5289fec4b0573cc22e15fa180.c1.e7" ontology_id="DOID_4325" text="Ebola hemorrhagic fever" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1325-1343" id="7c8f40872fb6e8d5289fec4b0573cc22e15fa180.c1.e8" ontology_id="DOID_0050117" text="infectious disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1336-1343" id="7c8f40872fb6e8d5289fec4b0573cc22e15fa180.c1.e9" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
