<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="7fb385f3c0c5ce04f1c3d3c4f20678c0ae3a7031">
  <chunk id="7fb385f3c0c5ce04f1c3d3c4f20678c0ae3a7031.c0" text="Development and validation of knowledge, attitude and practice questionnaire for prevention of respiratory tract infections among Malaysian Hajj pilgrims"/>
  <chunk id="7fb385f3c0c5ce04f1c3d3c4f20678c0ae3a7031.c1" text="Background: Hajj pilgrimage faces numerous challenges including a high prevalence of respiratory tract infection as well as its prevention strategies. The aim of this study was to develop and validate a questionnaire to evaluate knowledge, attitude and practice (KAP) towards respiratory tract infections (RTIs) prevention among Malaysian Hajj pilgrims. Methods: This study was conducted among Malaysian Umrah pilgrims in Malaysia from Kuala Lumpur and Kelantan. The questionnaire then underwent a series of validation process that included content, face validity and exploratory part. Item response theory (IRT) analysis was utilized for the validation of the knowledge domain. The attitude and practice were validated using the exploratory factor analysis (EFA). Results: The validation process resulted in a questionnaire that comprised of four main sections: demography, knowledge, attitude, and practice. Following IRT analysis of the knowledge domain, all items analyzed were within the acceptable range of difficulty and discrimination. The Kaiser-Meyer-Olkin measure of sampling adequacy (KMO) was 0.72 and 0.84 for attitude and practice domain respectively and Bartlett's test of Sphericity for both domains were highly significant (P &lt; 0.001). The factor analysis resulted in two factors with total of 12 items in attitude domain, and 2 factors with total of 13 items in the practice domain with satisfactory factor loading (&gt; 0.3). The Cronbach's alpha for reliability of the knowledge, attitude and practice domains all showed acceptable values of &gt; 0.6 (0.92, 0.77 and 0.85). Conclusion: The findings of this validation and reliability study showed that the developed questionnaire had a satisfactory psychometric property for measuring KAP of Malaysian Hajj pilgrims.">
    <entity charOffset="550-554" id="7fb385f3c0c5ce04f1c3d3c4f20678c0ae3a7031.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_0111084" text="face" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1458-1463" id="7fb385f3c0c5ce04f1c3d3c4f20678c0ae3a7031.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_30216" text="alpha" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="7fb385f3c0c5ce04f1c3d3c4f20678c0ae3a7031.c1.e0" e2="7fb385f3c0c5ce04f1c3d3c4f20678c0ae3a7031.c1.e1" id="7fb385f3c0c5ce04f1c3d3c4f20678c0ae3a7031.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
