<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="808eb805948a72da00d370c274656653679536b5">
  <chunk id="808eb805948a72da00d370c274656653679536b5.c0" text="Epitope Mapping of M36, a Human Antibody Domain with Potent and Broad HIV-1 Inhibitory Activity">
    <entity charOffset="0-7" id="808eb805948a72da00d370c274656653679536b5.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_53000" text="Epitope" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="808eb805948a72da00d370c274656653679536b5.c1" text="M36 is the first member of a novel class of potent HIV-1 entry inhibitors based on human engineered antibody domains (eAds). It exhibits broad inhibitory activity suggesting that its CD4-induced epitope is highly conserved. Here, we describe fine mapping of its epitope by using several approaches. First, a panel of mimotopes was affinity-selected from a random peptide library and potential m36-binding residues were computationally predicted. Second, homology modeling of m36 and molecular docking of m36 onto gp120 revealed potentially important residues in gp120-m36 interactions. Third, the predicted contact residues were verified by site-directed mutagenesis. Taken together, m36 epitope comprising three discontinuous sites including six key gp120 residues (Site C1: Thr123 and Pro124; Site C3: Glu370 and Ile371; Site C4: Met426 and Trp427) were identified. In the 3D structure of gp120, the sites C1 and C4 are located in the bridging sheet and the site C3 is within the b15-a3 excursion, which play essential roles for the receptor-and coreceptor-binding and are major targets of neutralizing antibodies. Based on these results we propose a precise localization of the m36 epitope and suggest a mechanism of its broad inhibitory activity which could help in the development of novel HIV-1 therapeutics based on eAds.">
    <entity charOffset="63-73" id="808eb805948a72da00d370c274656653679536b5.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_35222" text="inhibitors" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="195-202" id="808eb805948a72da00d370c274656653679536b5.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_53000" text="epitope" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="262-269" id="808eb805948a72da00d370c274656653679536b5.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_53000" text="epitope" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="363-370" id="808eb805948a72da00d370c274656653679536b5.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_16670" text="peptide" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="688-695" id="808eb805948a72da00d370c274656653679536b5.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_53000" text="epitope" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1185-1192" id="808eb805948a72da00d370c274656653679536b5.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_53000" text="epitope" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
