<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="80f244134084f44bfc86bbe102f338d18e219dbc">
  <chunk id="80f244134084f44bfc86bbe102f338d18e219dbc.c0" text="Molecular Sciences Bioactivities of Phenolics by Focusing on Suppression of Chronic Diseases: A Review"/>
  <chunk id="80f244134084f44bfc86bbe102f338d18e219dbc.c1" text="Phenolics, which are secondary metabolites of plants, exhibit remarkable bioactivities. In this contribution, we have focused on their protective effect against chronic diseases rather than their antioxidant activities, which have been widely discussed in the literature. A large body of epidemiological studies has proven the bioactivities of phenolics in both standard compounds and natural extracts: namely, anticancer, anti-inflammatory, and antibacterial activities as well as reducing diabetes, cardiovascular disease, and neurodegenerative disease. Phenolics also display anti-analgesic, anti-allergic, and anti-Alzheimer's properties. Thus, this review provides crucial information for better understanding the bioactivities of phenolics in foods and fills a gap in the existing collective and overall knowledge in the field. which decide the individual differences of each phenolic acid. The ingested phenolic acids are absorbed in the gastrointestinal tract and then circulate in the blood system after methylation, sulfation, and glucuronidation in the liver [2] . For example, hydroxycinnamic acids in wines are absorbed in the gastrointestinal tract after ingestion and transformed into glucuronide and sulfate conjugates, followed by circulation in the blood [3] . This conjugation process increases the hydrophilicity of the phenolic compounds and helps remove them via the biliary or the urinary route.">
    <entity charOffset="21-42" id="80f244134084f44bfc86bbe102f338d18e219dbc.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_25212" text="secondary metabolites" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="31-42" id="80f244134084f44bfc86bbe102f338d18e219dbc.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_25212" text="metabolites" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="196-207" id="80f244134084f44bfc86bbe102f338d18e219dbc.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_22586" text="antioxidant" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="749-754" id="80f244134084f44bfc86bbe102f338d18e219dbc.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_33290" text="foods" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="919-924" id="80f244134084f44bfc86bbe102f338d18e219dbc.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_37527" text="acids" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1089-1110" id="80f244134084f44bfc86bbe102f338d18e219dbc.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_24689" text="hydroxycinnamic acids" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1105-1110" id="80f244134084f44bfc86bbe102f338d18e219dbc.c1.e6" ontology_id="CHEBI_37527" text="acids" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1200-1211" id="80f244134084f44bfc86bbe102f338d18e219dbc.c1.e7" ontology_id="CHEBI_15341" text="glucuronide" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1216-1223" id="80f244134084f44bfc86bbe102f338d18e219dbc.c1.e8" ontology_id="CHEBI_16189" text="sulfate" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
