<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="8142d13b88328405d5302f1e899e5c2a8c1df196">
  <chunk id="8142d13b88328405d5302f1e899e5c2a8c1df196.c0" text="Roles of aminoacyl-tRNA synthetases in immune regulation and immune diseases">
    <entity charOffset="9-23" id="8142d13b88328405d5302f1e899e5c2a8c1df196.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_2651" text="aminoacyl-tRNA" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="8142d13b88328405d5302f1e899e5c2a8c1df196.c1" text="Aminoacyl-tRNA synthetases (ARSs) play a vital role in protein synthesis by linking amino acids to their cognate transfer RNAs (tRNAs). This typical function has been well recognized over the past few decades. However, accumulating evidence reveals that ARSs are involved in a wide range of physiological and pathological processes apart from translation. Strikingly, certain ARSs are closely related to different types of immune responses. In this review, we address the infection and immune responses induced by pathogen ARSs, as well as the potential anti-infective compounds that target pathogen ARSs. Meanwhile, we describe the functional mechanisms of ARSs in the development of immune cells. In addition, we focus on the roles of ARSs in certain immune diseases, such as autoimmune diseases, infectious diseases, and tumor immunity. Although our knowledge of ARSs in the immunological context is still in its infancy, research in this field may provide new ideas for the treatment of immunerelated diseases.">
    <entity charOffset="0-14" id="8142d13b88328405d5302f1e899e5c2a8c1df196.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_2651" text="Aminoacyl-tRNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="47-51" id="8142d13b88328405d5302f1e899e5c2a8c1df196.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="55-62" id="8142d13b88328405d5302f1e899e5c2a8c1df196.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="84-89" id="8142d13b88328405d5302f1e899e5c2a8c1df196.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_46882" text="amino" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="84-95" id="8142d13b88328405d5302f1e899e5c2a8c1df196.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_33704" text="amino acids" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="90-95" id="8142d13b88328405d5302f1e899e5c2a8c1df196.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_37527" text="acids" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
