<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0">
  <chunk id="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c0" text="Altered Thymic Function during Interferon Therapy in HCV-Infected Patients">
    <entity charOffset="31-41" id="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_52999" text="Interferon" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1" text="Interferon alpha (IFNa) therapy, despite good efficacy in curing HCV infection, leads to major side effects, in particular inducement of a strong peripheral T-cell lymphocytopenia. We here analyze the early consequences of IFNa therapy on both thymic function and peripheral T-cell homeostasis in patients in the acute or chronic phase of HCV-infection as well as in HIV/HCV co-infected patients. The evolution of T-cell subsets and T-cell homeostasis were estimated by flow cytometry while thymic function was measured through quantification of T-cell receptor excision circles (TREC) and estimation of intrathymic precursor T-cell proliferation during the first four months following the initiation of IFNa therapy. Beginning with the first month of therapy, a profound lymphocytopenia was observed for all T-cell subsets, including naïve T-cells and recent thymic emigrants (RTE), associated with inhibition of intrathymic precursor T-cell proliferation. Interleukin (IL)-7 plasma concentration rapidly dropped while lymphocytopenia progressed. This was neither a consequence of higher consumption of the cytokine nor due to its neutralization by soluble CD127. Decrease in IL-7 plasma concentration under IFNa therapy correlated with the decline in HCV viral load, thymic activity and RTE concentration in blood. These data demonstrate that IFNa-based therapy rapidly impacts on thymopoiesis and, consequently, perturbs T-cell homeostasis. Such a side effect might be detrimental for the continuation of IFNa therapy and may lead to an increased level of infectious risk, in particular in HIV/HCV co-infected patients. Altogether, this study suggests the therapeutic potential of IL-7 in the maintenance of peripheral T-cell homeostasis in IFNa-treated patients.">
    <entity charOffset="0-10" id="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_52999" text="Interferon" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="11-16" id="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_30216" text="alpha" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="164-179" id="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_614" text="lymphocytopenia" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="772-787" id="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1.e3" ontology_id="DOID_614" text="lymphocytopenia" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1020-1035" id="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1.e4" ontology_id="DOID_614" text="lymphocytopenia" type="disease"/>
    <pair e1="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1.e0" e2="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1.e2" id="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1.e0" e2="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1.e3" id="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1.e0" e2="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1.e4" id="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1.e1" e2="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1.e2" id="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1.e1" e2="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1.e3" id="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1.e1" e2="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1.e4" id="83d77dc0616b9b240d13a844c7135dc250773fe0.c1.p5" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
