<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="850be0ae2ae61513057e7b44b0b2e7b2f326746c">
  <chunk id="850be0ae2ae61513057e7b44b0b2e7b2f326746c.c0" text="Best practices for standardized performance testing of infrared thermographs intended for fever screening"/>
  <chunk id="850be0ae2ae61513057e7b44b0b2e7b2f326746c.c1" text="Infrared (IR) modalities represent the only currently viable mass fever screening approaches for outbreaks of infectious disease pandemics such as Ebola virus disease and severe acute respiratory syndrome. Non-contact IR thermometers (NCITs) and IR thermographs (IRTs) have been used for fever screening in public areas such as airports. While NCITs remain a more popular choice than IRTs, there has been increasing evidences in the literature that IRTs can provide great accuracy in estimating body temperature if qualified systems are used and appropriate procedures are consistently applied. In this study, we addressed the issue of IRT qualification by implementing and evaluating a battery of test methods for objective, quantitative assessment of IRT performance based on a recent international standard (IEC 80601-2-59). We tested two commercial IRTs to evaluate their stability and drift, image uniformity, minimum resolvable temperature difference, and radiometric temperature laboratory accuracy. Based on these tests, we illustrated how experimental and data processing procedures could affect results, and suggested methods for clarifying and optimizing test methods. Overall, the insights into thermograph standardization and acquisition methods provided by this study may improve the utility of IR thermography and aid in comparing IRT performance, thus improving the potential for producing high quality disease pandemic countermeasures. a The data for uniformity, accuracy, stability and drift were based on worst-case scenarios. b Uniformity values were for a ±1˚C step from ambient temperature at 80% of the central area. For other temperature, multiply by ΔT (the difference between the ambient and the blackbody temperatures). c Calculated based on the standard uncertainty value of uniformity, stability and drift. Assuming ambient temperature of 20˚C and blackbody temperature of 35˚C.">
    <entity charOffset="110-128" id="850be0ae2ae61513057e7b44b0b2e7b2f326746c.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_0050117" text="infectious disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="121-128" id="850be0ae2ae61513057e7b44b0b2e7b2f326746c.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="147-166" id="850be0ae2ae61513057e7b44b0b2e7b2f326746c.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_4325" text="Ebola virus disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="159-166" id="850be0ae2ae61513057e7b44b0b2e7b2f326746c.c1.e3" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="171-204" id="850be0ae2ae61513057e7b44b0b2e7b2f326746c.c1.e4" ontology_id="DOID_2945" text="severe acute respiratory syndrome" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1419-1426" id="850be0ae2ae61513057e7b44b0b2e7b2f326746c.c1.e5" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
