<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="86e3f31b72109395a9dd02071bf83aeb7fa6803c">
  <chunk id="86e3f31b72109395a9dd02071bf83aeb7fa6803c.c0" text="Lethal Nipah Virus Infection Induces Rapid Overexpression of CXCL10">
    <entity charOffset="13-28" id="86e3f31b72109395a9dd02071bf83aeb7fa6803c.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_934" text="Virus Infection" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="61-67" id="86e3f31b72109395a9dd02071bf83aeb7fa6803c.c0.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_138157" text="CXCL10" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="86e3f31b72109395a9dd02071bf83aeb7fa6803c.c0.e0" e2="86e3f31b72109395a9dd02071bf83aeb7fa6803c.c0.e1" id="86e3f31b72109395a9dd02071bf83aeb7fa6803c.c0.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="86e3f31b72109395a9dd02071bf83aeb7fa6803c.c1" text="Nipah virus (NiV) is a recently emerged zoonotic Paramyxovirus that causes regular outbreaks in East Asia with mortality rate exceeding 75%. Major cellular targets of NiV infection are endothelial cells and neurons. To better understand virus-host interaction, we analyzed the transcriptome profile of NiV infection in primary human umbilical vein endothelial cells. We further assessed some of the obtained results by in vitro and in vivo methods in a hamster model and in brain samples from NiV-infected patients. We found that NiV infection strongly induces genes involved in interferon response in endothelial cells. Among the top ten upregulated genes, we identified the chemokine CXCL10 (interferon-induced protein 10, IP-10), an important chemoattractant involved in the generation of inflammatory immune response and neurotoxicity. In NiV-infected hamsters, which develop pathology similar to what is seen in humans, expression of CXCL10 mRNA was induced in different organs with kinetics that followed NiV replication. Finally, we showed intense staining for CXCL10 in the brain of patients who succumbed to lethal NiV infection during the outbreak in Malaysia, confirming induction of this chemokine in fatal human infections. This study sheds new light on NiV pathogenesis, indicating the role of CXCL10 during the course of infection and suggests that this chemokine may serve as a potential new marker for lethal NiV encephalitis.">
    <entity charOffset="579-589" id="86e3f31b72109395a9dd02071bf83aeb7fa6803c.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_52999" text="interferon" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="686-692" id="86e3f31b72109395a9dd02071bf83aeb7fa6803c.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_138157" text="CXCL10" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="713-720" id="86e3f31b72109395a9dd02071bf83aeb7fa6803c.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="939-945" id="86e3f31b72109395a9dd02071bf83aeb7fa6803c.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_138157" text="CXCL10" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="946-950" id="86e3f31b72109395a9dd02071bf83aeb7fa6803c.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_33699" text="mRNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1068-1074" id="86e3f31b72109395a9dd02071bf83aeb7fa6803c.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_138157" text="CXCL10" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1258-1263" id="86e3f31b72109395a9dd02071bf83aeb7fa6803c.c1.e6" ontology_id="CHEBI_30212" text="light" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1300-1304" id="86e3f31b72109395a9dd02071bf83aeb7fa6803c.c1.e7" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1308-1314" id="86e3f31b72109395a9dd02071bf83aeb7fa6803c.c1.e8" ontology_id="CHEBI_138157" text="CXCL10" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
