<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="880359b9dd6158ec31280e45a077f9d59b68e22f">
  <chunk id="880359b9dd6158ec31280e45a077f9d59b68e22f.c0" text="Whole-genome Sequencing for Tracing the Transmission Link between Two ARD Outbreaks Caused by a Novel HAdV Serotype 7 Variant, China OPEN"/>
  <chunk id="880359b9dd6158ec31280e45a077f9d59b68e22f.c1" text="two outbreaks of acute respiratory disease caused by HAdV-7 were reported in China. We investigated possible transmission links between these two seemingly unrelated outbreaks by integration of epidemiological and whole-genome sequencing (WGS) data. WGS analyses showed that the HAdV-7 isolates from the two outbreaks were genetically indistinguishable; however, a 12 bp deletion in the virus-associated RNA gene distinguished the outbreak isolates from other HAdV-7 isolates. Outbreak HAdV-7 isolates demonstrated increased viral replication compared to non-outbreak associated HAdV-7 isolate. Epidemiological data supported that the first outbreak was caused by introduction of the novel HAdV-7 virus by an infected recruit upon arrival at the training base. Nosocomial transmission by close contacts was the most likely source leading to onset of the second HAdV-7 outbreak, establishing the apparent transmission link between the outbreaks. Our findings imply that in-hospital contact investigations should be encouraged to reduce or interrupt further spread of infectious agents when treating outbreak cases, and WGS can provide useful information guiding infection-control interventions.">
    <entity charOffset="35-42" id="880359b9dd6158ec31280e45a077f9d59b68e22f.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="404-407" id="880359b9dd6158ec31280e45a077f9d59b68e22f.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="880359b9dd6158ec31280e45a077f9d59b68e22f.c1.e0" e2="880359b9dd6158ec31280e45a077f9d59b68e22f.c1.e1" id="880359b9dd6158ec31280e45a077f9d59b68e22f.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="880359b9dd6158ec31280e45a077f9d59b68e22f.c2" text="Human adenoviruses (HAdVs) are non-enveloped, icosahedral, double-stranded DNA viruses that are classified into seven species (A-G) based on their nucleotide homology, haemagglutination, biochemical and biological properties; at least 51 serotypes are recognized 1-3 . HAdV can cause a wide range of clinical syndromes, including respiratory tract illnesses, conjunctivitis, cystitis, gastroenteritis, neurological diseases; in some cases infection directly results in death 1,4 . HAdV is reported to be one of the primary causes of acute respiratory disease (ARD) worldwide, which is responsible for 5-10% of lower respiratory tract infections in children throughout the world 2,5 . Serotype 7 (HAdV-7) accounts for nearly 20% of all HAdV infections reported to the World Health Organization 4,6 , and is more frequently associated with severe illnesses, particularly in children aged &lt; 7 years and persons with underlying health conditions 7,8 .">
    <entity charOffset="59-78" id="880359b9dd6158ec31280e45a077f9d59b68e22f.c2.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_4705" text="double-stranded DNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="75-78" id="880359b9dd6158ec31280e45a077f9d59b68e22f.c2.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="147-157" id="880359b9dd6158ec31280e45a077f9d59b68e22f.c2.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_36976" text="nucleotide" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="551-558" id="880359b9dd6158ec31280e45a077f9d59b68e22f.c2.e3" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <pair e1="880359b9dd6158ec31280e45a077f9d59b68e22f.c2.e0" e2="880359b9dd6158ec31280e45a077f9d59b68e22f.c2.e3" id="880359b9dd6158ec31280e45a077f9d59b68e22f.c2.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="880359b9dd6158ec31280e45a077f9d59b68e22f.c2.e1" e2="880359b9dd6158ec31280e45a077f9d59b68e22f.c2.e3" id="880359b9dd6158ec31280e45a077f9d59b68e22f.c2.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="880359b9dd6158ec31280e45a077f9d59b68e22f.c2.e2" e2="880359b9dd6158ec31280e45a077f9d59b68e22f.c2.e3" id="880359b9dd6158ec31280e45a077f9d59b68e22f.c2.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
