<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="88e8809f280ef47d36f3e56b7f8558c303f36742">
  <chunk id="88e8809f280ef47d36f3e56b7f8558c303f36742.c0" text="An educational programme for nursing college staff and students during a MERS-coronavirus outbreak in Saudi Arabia"/>
  <chunk id="88e8809f280ef47d36f3e56b7f8558c303f36742.c1" text="Background: The Middle Eastern Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus is a serious and emerging issue in Saudi Arabia and the world. A response was required to reduce possible disease transmission between the hospital and university. College of Nursing academic staff developed a programme in response to the educational and emotional needs of participants. Methods: A MERS-CoV Task Force responded to the rapidly unfolding epidemic. The aim was to find out what nursing staff and nursing students in the college knew about MERS-CoV. While most gaps in knowledge were addressed after an intense information seminar, other learning needs were identified and responded to. The Task Force developed mandatory information sessions for all nursing faculty, students and staff. All staff were informed by email, letters and posters. There are 28 faculty staff, 84 support staff and 480 students in the College of Nursing. The information settings all took place within the College of Nursing, Princess Nourah University, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia. Questionnaires were given to faculty, students and staff to understand their baseline knowledge. After the sessions, faculty, students and staff were asked about what was learned through the sessions, and what educational needs still needed to be addressed. Approval was sought and received by the Ethics Committee for the College of Nursing. Participants completed informed consent forms and the voluntary nature of the study was explained. Results: The total number of people attending the education sessions was133, including 65 students. 18 faculty members attended and 57 support staff. Data was gathered on gaps in participant knowledge and a plan was developed to address the gaps. Policies were established around student participation in clinical and return to work practices for staff with any symptoms. Conclusion: In hospitals there is above average risk for exposure to infectious diseases. Student nurses travel between hospital and university, with the capacity to act as a conduit of pathogens to large, susceptible populations. Nursing colleges must respond thoroughly to protect students and staff and prevent spread of disease into the university community in the midst of an epidemic.">
    <entity charOffset="43-51" id="88e8809f280ef47d36f3e56b7f8558c303f36742.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_225" text="Syndrome" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="170-177" id="88e8809f280ef47d36f3e56b7f8558c303f36742.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="2172-2179" id="88e8809f280ef47d36f3e56b7f8558c303f36742.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
