<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9">
  <chunk id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c0" text="Aerosol emission and superemission during human speech increase with voice loudness"/>
  <chunk id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1" text="Mechanistic hypotheses about airborne infectious disease transmission have traditionally emphasized the role of coughing and sneezing, which are dramatic expiratory events that yield both easily visible droplets and large quantities of particles too small to see by eye. Nonetheless, it has long been known that normal speech also yields large quantities of particles that are too small to see by eye, but are large enough to carry a variety of communicable respiratory pathogens. Here we show that the rate of particle emission during normal human speech is positively correlated with the loudness (amplitude) of vocalization, ranging from approximately 1 to 50 particles per second (0.06 to 3 particles per cm 3 ) for low to high amplitudes, regardless of the language spoken (english, spanish, Mandarin, or Arabic). Furthermore, a small fraction of individuals behaves as &quot;speech superemitters,&quot; consistently releasing an order of magnitude more particles than their peers. our data demonstrate that the phenomenon of speech superemission cannot be fully explained either by the phonic structures or the amplitude of the speech. these results suggest that other unknown physiological factors, varying dramatically among individuals, could affect the probability of respiratory infectious disease transmission, and also help explain the existence of superspreaders who are disproportionately responsible for outbreaks of airborne infectious disease.">
    <entity charOffset="38-56" id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_0050117" text="infectious disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="49-56" id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="104-108" id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1280-1298" id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.e3" ontology_id="DOID_0050117" text="infectious disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1291-1298" id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.e4" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1432-1450" id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.e5" ontology_id="DOID_0050117" text="infectious disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1443-1450" id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.e6" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <pair e1="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.e0" e2="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.e2" id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.e1" e2="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.e2" id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.e2" e2="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.e3" id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.e2" e2="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.e4" id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.e2" e2="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.e5" id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.e2" e2="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.e6" id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c1.p5" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c2" text="It has long been recognized that particles expelled during human expiratory events, such as sneezing, coughing, talking, and breathing, serve as vehicles for respiratory pathogen transmission 1-6 . The relative contribution of each expiratory activity in transmitting infectious microorganisms, however, remains unclear 4 . Much previous research has focused on coughing 7-12 and sneezing 11,13,14 activities that yield relatively large droplets (approximately 50 μm or larger) easily visible to the naked eye. Less noticeable, but arguably more infectious for some diseases, are the smaller particles emitted during sneezing and coughing as well as during breathing 15-17 and talking 16, 18, 19 . These small particles are believed to be generated during breathing and talking from the mucosal layers coating the respiratory tract via a combination of a &quot;fluid-film burst&quot; mechanism within the bronchioles and from vocal folds adduction and vibration within the larynx 6,20,21 . The particles emitted during breathing and typical speech predominantly average only 1 μm in diameter 15-17 and are thus too small to see without specialized equipment; most people outside of the community of bioaerosol researchers are less aware of them."/>
  <chunk id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c3" text="Despite their small size, however, these micron-scale particles are sufficiently large to carry a variety of respiratory pathogens such as measles virus (50-500 nm) 22 , influenza virus (100 nm-1 µm) 23 , and Mycobacterium tuberculosis (1-3 µm) 24 . Indeed, recent work by Yan et al. has confirmed that significant amounts of influenza viral RNA are present in small particles (&lt;5 μm) emitted by influenza-infected individuals during natural breathing, without coughing or sneezing 25 . These small particles are potentially more infectious than larger sneeze-or">
    <entity charOffset="139-146" id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c3.e0" ontology_id="DOID_8622" text="measles" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="170-179" id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c3.e1" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="223-235" id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c3.e2" ontology_id="DOID_399" text="tuberculosis" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="326-335" id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c3.e3" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="342-345" id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c3.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c3.e0" e2="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c3.e4" id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c3.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c3.e1" e2="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c3.e4" id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c3.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c3.e2" e2="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c3.e4" id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c3.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c3.e3" e2="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c3.e4" id="8954feaa230060999c4f698c1582ffadfd79b0b9.c3.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
