<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411">
  <chunk id="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c0" text="Evaluation of the efficacy of a trivalent vaccine mixture against a triple challenge with Mycoplasma hyopneumoniae, PCV2, and PRRSV and the efficacy comparison of the respective monovalent vaccines against a single challenge">
    <entity charOffset="50-57" id="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_60004" text="mixture" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1" text="Background: The objective of this study was to assess the efficacy of a trivalent vaccine mixture and compare it to the respective monovalent vaccines against Mycoplasma hyopneumoniae, porcine circovirus type 2 (PCV2), and porcine reproductive and respiratory syndrome virus (PRRSV). Results: Pigs that were triple challenged with M. hyopneumoniae, PCV2, and PRRSV following vaccination with the trivalent vaccine mixture exhibited a significantly better growth performance when compared to unvaccinated and challenged pigs. A statistical difference was not found when comparing pig populations which were vaccinated with the trivalent vaccine followed by a triple challenge and pigs vaccinated with monovalent M hyopneumoniae vaccine followed by mycoplasmal single challenge in the following areas: M. hyopneumoniae nasal shedding, the number of M. hyopneumoniae-specific interferon-γ secreting cells (IFN-γ-SC), and mycoplasmal lung lesion scores. Pigs vaccinated with the trivalent vaccine mixture followed by a triple challenge resulted in a similar reduction of PCV2 viremia, an increase in the number of PCV2-specific IFN-γ-SC and reduction in interstitial lung lesion scores when compared to pigs vaccinated with a PCV-2 vaccine and challenged with PCV2 only. Lastly, there was a significant difference in the reduction of PRRSV viremia, an increase in PRRSV-specific IFN-γ-SC and a reduction of interstitial lung lesion scores between pigs vaccinated with the trivalent vaccine mixture followed by a triple challenge and pigs vaccinated with a monovalent PRRSV vaccine followed by PRRSV challenge only. Conclusion: The trivalent vaccine mixture was efficacious against a triple challenge of M. hyopneumoniae, PCV2, and PRRSV. The trivalent vaccine mixture, however, did not result in equal protection when compared against each respective monovalent vaccine, with the largest vaccine occurring within PRRSV.">
    <entity charOffset="90-97" id="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_60004" text="mixture" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="260-268" id="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_225" text="syndrome" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="414-421" id="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_60004" text="mixture" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="993-1000" id="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_60004" text="mixture" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1486-1493" id="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_60004" text="mixture" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1645-1652" id="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_60004" text="mixture" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1756-1763" id="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.e6" ontology_id="CHEBI_60004" text="mixture" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.e0" e2="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.e1" id="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.e1" e2="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.e2" id="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.e1" e2="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.e3" id="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.e1" e2="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.e4" id="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.e1" e2="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.e5" id="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.e1" e2="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.e6" id="8d67e5c1683885f28d8b023224e65998d8e73411.c1.p5" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
