<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="8fc0e17fe32585f3e3216b48c7beba4b15221e57">
  <chunk id="8fc0e17fe32585f3e3216b48c7beba4b15221e57.c0" text="NAR Breakthrough Article Generating genomic platforms to study Candida albicans pathogenesis"/>
  <chunk id="8fc0e17fe32585f3e3216b48c7beba4b15221e57.c1" text="The advent of the genomic era has made elucidating gene function on a large scale a pressing challenge. ORFeome collections, whereby almost all ORFs of a given species are cloned and can be subsequently leveraged in multiple functional genomic approaches, represent valuable resources toward this endeavor. Here we provide novel, genome-scale tools for the study of Candida albicans, a commensal yeast that is also responsible for frequent superficial and disseminated infections in humans. We have generated an ORFeome collection composed of 5099 ORFs cloned in a Gateway™ donor vector, representing 83% of the currently annotated coding sequences of C. albicans. Sequencing data of the cloned ORFs are available in the CandidaOrfDB database at http: //candidaorfeome.eu. We also engineered 49 expression vectors with a choice of promoters, tags and selection markers and demonstrated their applicability to the study of target ORFs transferred from the C. albicans ORFeome. In addition, the use of the OR-Feome in the detection of protein-protein interaction was demonstrated. Mating-compatible strains as well as Gateway™-compatible two-hybrid vectors were en-gineered, validated and used in a proof of concept experiment. These unique and valuable resources should greatly facilitate future functional studies in C. albicans and the elucidation of mechanisms that underlie its pathogenicity.">
    <entity charOffset="26-29" id="8fc0e17fe32585f3e3216b48c7beba4b15221e57.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_51451" text="era" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="574-579" id="8fc0e17fe32585f3e3216b48c7beba4b15221e57.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_17499" text="donor" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="574-579" id="8fc0e17fe32585f3e3216b48c7beba4b15221e57.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_17891" text="donor" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
