<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="943491914a5f52c713070accbde7e0e868771e91">
  <chunk id="943491914a5f52c713070accbde7e0e868771e91.c0" text="Evaluation of Mucosal and Systemic Immune Responses Elicited by GPI-0100-Adjuvanted Influenza Vaccine Delivered by Different Immunization Strategies">
    <entity charOffset="84-93" id="943491914a5f52c713070accbde7e0e868771e91.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="Influenza" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="943491914a5f52c713070accbde7e0e868771e91.c1" text="Vaccines for protection against respiratory infections should optimally induce a mucosal immune response in the respiratory tract in addition to a systemic immune response. However, current parenteral immunization modalities generally fail to induce mucosal immunity, while mucosal vaccine delivery often results in poor systemic immunity. In order to find an immunization strategy which satisfies the need for induction of both mucosal and systemic immunity, we compared local and systemic immune responses elicited by two mucosal immunizations, given either by the intranasal (IN) or the intrapulmonary (IPL) route, with responses elicited by a mucosal prime followed by a systemic boost immunization. The study was conducted in BALB/c mice and the vaccine formulation was an influenza subunit vaccine supplemented with GPI-0100, a saponin-derived adjuvant. While optimal mucosal antibody titers were obtained after two intrapulmonary vaccinations, optimal systemic antibody responses were achieved by intranasal prime followed by intramuscular boost. The latter strategy also resulted in the best T cell response, yet, it was ineffective in inducing nose or lung IgA. Successful induction of secretory IgA, IgG and T cell responses was only achieved with prime-boost strategies involving intrapulmonary immunization and was optimal when both immunizations were given via the intrapulmonary route. Our results underline that immunization via the lungs is particularly effective for priming as well as boosting of local and systemic immune responses. Citation: Liu H, Patil HP, de Vries-Idema J, Wilschut J, Huckriede A (2013) Evaluation of Mucosal and Systemic Immune Responses Elicited by GPI-0100-Adjuvanted Influenza Vaccine Delivered by Different Immunization Strategies. PLoS ONE 8(7): e69649.">
    <entity charOffset="778-787" id="943491914a5f52c713070accbde7e0e868771e91.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1712-1721" id="943491914a5f52c713070accbde7e0e868771e91.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="Influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1783-1786" id="943491914a5f52c713070accbde7e0e868771e91.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_58972" text="ONE" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="943491914a5f52c713070accbde7e0e868771e91.c1.e0" e2="943491914a5f52c713070accbde7e0e868771e91.c1.e2" id="943491914a5f52c713070accbde7e0e868771e91.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="943491914a5f52c713070accbde7e0e868771e91.c1.e1" e2="943491914a5f52c713070accbde7e0e868771e91.c1.e2" id="943491914a5f52c713070accbde7e0e868771e91.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
