<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="94d2ebfc7a2a0ffc00b05ce8031fdfef3255af4a">
  <chunk id="94d2ebfc7a2a0ffc00b05ce8031fdfef3255af4a.c0" text="Emerging Microbes &amp; Infections (2017) 6, e4"/>
  <chunk id="94d2ebfc7a2a0ffc00b05ce8031fdfef3255af4a.c1" text="We report the first imported case of Rift Valley fever (RVF) in China. The patient returned from Angola, a non-epidemic country, with an infection of a new reassortant from different lineages of Rift Valley fever viruses (RVFVs). The patient developed multiorgan dysfunction and gradually recovered with continuous renal replacement therapy and a short regimen of methylprednisolone treatment. The disordered cytokines and chemokines in the plasma of the patient revealed hypercytokinemia, but the levels of protective cytokines were low upon admission and fluctuated as the disease improved. Whole-genome sequencing and phylogenetic analysis revealed that the imported strain was a reassortant comprising the L and M genes from lineage E and the S gene from lineage A. This case highlights that RVFV had undergone genetic reassortment, which could potentially alter its biological properties, cause large outbreaks and pose a serious threat to global public health as well as the livestock breeding industry.">
    <entity charOffset="37-54" id="94d2ebfc7a2a0ffc00b05ce8031fdfef3255af4a.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_1328" text="Rift Valley fever" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="195-212" id="94d2ebfc7a2a0ffc00b05ce8031fdfef3255af4a.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_1328" text="Rift Valley fever" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="364-382" id="94d2ebfc7a2a0ffc00b05ce8031fdfef3255af4a.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_6888" text="methylprednisolone" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="575-582" id="94d2ebfc7a2a0ffc00b05ce8031fdfef3255af4a.c1.e3" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <pair e1="94d2ebfc7a2a0ffc00b05ce8031fdfef3255af4a.c1.e0" e2="94d2ebfc7a2a0ffc00b05ce8031fdfef3255af4a.c1.e2" id="94d2ebfc7a2a0ffc00b05ce8031fdfef3255af4a.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="94d2ebfc7a2a0ffc00b05ce8031fdfef3255af4a.c1.e1" e2="94d2ebfc7a2a0ffc00b05ce8031fdfef3255af4a.c1.e2" id="94d2ebfc7a2a0ffc00b05ce8031fdfef3255af4a.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="94d2ebfc7a2a0ffc00b05ce8031fdfef3255af4a.c1.e2" e2="94d2ebfc7a2a0ffc00b05ce8031fdfef3255af4a.c1.e3" id="94d2ebfc7a2a0ffc00b05ce8031fdfef3255af4a.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
