<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="9728dc7174668523338b32a9608f43a91e8b797d">
  <chunk id="9728dc7174668523338b32a9608f43a91e8b797d.c0" text="Detection of Novel duck reovirus (NDRV) using visual reverse transcription loop-mediated isothermal amplification (RT-LAMP)"/>
  <chunk id="9728dc7174668523338b32a9608f43a91e8b797d.c1" text="for detecting the gene encoding the σB major outer-capsid protein of novel duck reovirus (NDRV). A set of primers, composed of two outer primers, two inner primers and two loop primers, was designed based on the gene of interest. The LAMP reaction was conducted in a traditional laboratory water bath at 65 °C for 50 min. We compared the performance of calcein/Mn 2+ and SYBR Green I dyes, as well as electrophoresis on agarose gel stained with GoldView nucleic acid dye to detect the RT-LAMP-amplified products and all assays could be employed to discriminate between positive and negative specimens in visible or UV light. Our data showed that there is no cross-reaction with other viruses and the RT-LAMP technique displayed high sensitivity for detecting NDRV with a minimal detection limit of 200 fg RNA input. This assay was more sensitive than conventional PCR in detecting NDRV both in natural and experimental infection. In conclusion, the RT-LAMP technique was remarkably sensitive, specific, rapid, simple and profitable for the identification of NDRV.">
    <entity charOffset="58-65" id="9728dc7174668523338b32a9608f43a91e8b797d.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="290-295" id="9728dc7174668523338b32a9608f43a91e8b797d.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_15377" text="water" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="371-383" id="9728dc7174668523338b32a9608f43a91e8b797d.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_51461" text="SYBR Green I" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="420-427" id="9728dc7174668523338b32a9608f43a91e8b797d.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_2511" text="agarose" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="454-466" id="9728dc7174668523338b32a9608f43a91e8b797d.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_33696" text="nucleic acid" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="462-466" id="9728dc7174668523338b32a9608f43a91e8b797d.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_37527" text="acid" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="467-470" id="9728dc7174668523338b32a9608f43a91e8b797d.c1.e6" ontology_id="CHEBI_37958" text="dye" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="805-808" id="9728dc7174668523338b32a9608f43a91e8b797d.c1.e7" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
