<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8">
  <chunk id="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c0" text="Characterization of Ribosomal Frameshifting in Theiler's Murine Encephalomyelitis Virus">
    <entity charOffset="64-81" id="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_640" text="Encephalomyelitis" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c1" text="Theiler's murine encephalomyelitis virus (TMEV) is a member of the genus Cardiovirus in the Picornaviridae, a family of positive-sense single-stranded RNA viruses. Previously, we demonstrated that in the related cardiovirus, Encephalomyocarditis virus, a programmed ؊1 ribosomal frameshift (؊1 PRF) occurs at a conserved G_GUU_UUU sequence within the 2B-encoding region of the polyprotein open reading frame (ORF). Here we show that ؊1 PRF occurs at a similar site during translation of the TMEV genome. In addition, we demonstrate that a predicted 3= RNA stem-loop structure at a noncanonical spacing downstream of the shift site is required for efficient frameshifting in TMEV and that frameshifting also requires virus infection. Mutating the G_GUU_UUU shift site to inhibit frameshifting results in an attenuated virus with reduced growth kinetics and a small-plaque phenotype. Frameshifting in the virus context was found to be extremely efficient at 74 to 82%, which, to our knowledge, is the highest frameshifting efficiency recorded to date for any virus. We propose that highly efficient ؊1 PRF in TMEV provides a mechanism to escape the confines of equimolar expression normally inherent in the single-polyprotein expression strategy of picornaviruses.">
    <entity charOffset="17-34" id="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_640" text="encephalomyelitis" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="151-154" id="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="552-555" id="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c1.e0" e2="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c1.e1" id="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c1.e0" e2="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c1.e2" id="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c2" text="Many viruses utilize programmed ؊1 ribosomal frameshifting (؊1 PRF) to produce different protein products at a defined ratio, or to translate overlapping ORFs to increase coding capacity. With few exceptions, ؊1 PRF occurs on specific &quot;slippery&quot; heptanucleotide sequences and is stimulated by RNA structure beginning 5 to 9 nucleotides (nt) downstream of the slippery site. Here we describe an unusual case of ؊1 PRF in Theiler's murine encephalomyelitis virus (TMEV) that is extraordinarily efficient (74 to 82% of ribosomes shift into the alternative reading frame) and, in stark contrast to other examples of ؊1 PRF, is dependent upon a stem-loop structure beginning 14 nt downstream of the slippery site. Furthermore, in TMEV-based reporter constructs in transfected cells, efficient frameshifting is critically dependent upon virus infection. We suggest that TMEV evolved frameshifting as a novel mechanism for removing ribosomes from the message (a &quot;ribosome sink&quot;) to downregulate synthesis of the 3=-encoded replication proteins.">
    <entity charOffset="89-96" id="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c2.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="293-296" id="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c2.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="324-335" id="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c2.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_36976" text="nucleotides" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="437-454" id="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c2.e3" ontology_id="DOID_640" text="encephalomyelitis" type="disease"/>
    <pair e1="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c2.e0" e2="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c2.e3" id="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c2.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c2.e1" e2="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c2.e3" id="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c2.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c2.e2" e2="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c2.e3" id="975a7b5f0f9a7f9a03195cb5cd1a633ecd4e36f8.c2.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
