<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="9809fd94325b39bffb3a2414a3d7f3e1429fa539">
  <chunk id="9809fd94325b39bffb3a2414a3d7f3e1429fa539.c0" text="Global toxocariasis research trends from 1932 to 2015: a bibliometric analysis">
    <entity charOffset="7-19" id="9809fd94325b39bffb3a2414a3d7f3e1429fa539.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_9790" text="toxocariasis" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="9809fd94325b39bffb3a2414a3d7f3e1429fa539.c1" text="Background: Toxocariasis is a highly prevalent parasitic disease in the tropical regions of the world, with its impact on public health being typically underestimated. To better recognise the trends and characteristics of toxocariasis research, this study is a bibliometric analysis of the global toxocariasis research. Methods: Searches were completed on April 5, 2016, using the Scopus database. A search without any language restriction was performed to extract publications dealing with toxocariasis. Terms related to toxocariasis were used to perform a title keyword search. Results: A total of 2765 publications comprising 11 document types and published between 1932 and 2015 were included in the analysis. Articles were the most popular document form, accounting for 83.62% of all publications, followed by letters (3.80%) and reviews (3.4%). The annual number of research publications increased from 30 in 1980 to 111 in 2015, indicating that the number of publications on toxocariasis has increased slowly over the past 35 years. The United States of America and Japan are the predominant countries of origin, with 303 articles and 207 articles, respectively, followed by Brazil and the United Kingdom, with 180 (6.5%) each. The h-index for all the publications was 60. The highest h-index were for publications from the United Kingdom (h-index value = 43) and the United States (h-index value = 39); these two countries were also involved with the highest number of international collaborations, with 27 and 28 countries, respectively. Conclusions: Developed countries, including the United States, Japan, the United Kingdom, France, Germany and Italy, are the world's leaders in toxocariasis research, contributing to more than 34% of the total published literature. In addition, developing countries, such as Brazil, Poland, Argentina and India, showed a noticeable increase in published papers on toxocariasis research in recent years. A push for more collaboration is needed to achieve a superior research strategy related to toxocariasis at the global level from the viewpoint of epidemiological data, clinical aspects, medical ecology, molecular aspects and treatment practices associated with toxocariasis.">
    <entity charOffset="12-24" id="9809fd94325b39bffb3a2414a3d7f3e1429fa539.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_9790" text="Toxocariasis" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="57-64" id="9809fd94325b39bffb3a2414a3d7f3e1429fa539.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="222-234" id="9809fd94325b39bffb3a2414a3d7f3e1429fa539.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_9790" text="toxocariasis" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="297-309" id="9809fd94325b39bffb3a2414a3d7f3e1429fa539.c1.e3" ontology_id="DOID_9790" text="toxocariasis" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="491-503" id="9809fd94325b39bffb3a2414a3d7f3e1429fa539.c1.e4" ontology_id="DOID_9790" text="toxocariasis" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="522-534" id="9809fd94325b39bffb3a2414a3d7f3e1429fa539.c1.e5" ontology_id="DOID_9790" text="toxocariasis" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="982-994" id="9809fd94325b39bffb3a2414a3d7f3e1429fa539.c1.e6" ontology_id="DOID_9790" text="toxocariasis" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1691-1703" id="9809fd94325b39bffb3a2414a3d7f3e1429fa539.c1.e7" ontology_id="DOID_9790" text="toxocariasis" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1911-1923" id="9809fd94325b39bffb3a2414a3d7f3e1429fa539.c1.e8" ontology_id="DOID_9790" text="toxocariasis" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="2041-2053" id="9809fd94325b39bffb3a2414a3d7f3e1429fa539.c1.e9" ontology_id="DOID_9790" text="toxocariasis" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="2211-2223" id="9809fd94325b39bffb3a2414a3d7f3e1429fa539.c1.e10" ontology_id="DOID_9790" text="toxocariasis" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
