<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="9976bf51302bf33a5384a30c73231d4077c63ffe">
  <chunk id="9976bf51302bf33a5384a30c73231d4077c63ffe.c0" text="Genotyping and pathobiologic characterization of canine parvovirus circulating in Nanjing, China"/>
  <chunk id="9976bf51302bf33a5384a30c73231d4077c63ffe.c1" text="Background: Canine parvovirus (CPV) is an important pathogen that causes acute enteric disease in dogs. It has mutated and spread throughout the world in dog populations. We provide an update on the molecular characterization of CPV that circulated in Nanjing, a provincial capital in China between 2009 and 2012. Results: Seventy rectal swab samples were collected from the dogs diagnosed with CPV infection in 8 animal hospitals of Nanjing. Sequence analysis of VP2 genes of 31 samples revealed that 29 viral strains belonged to CPV-2a subtype, while other two strains were classified into CPV-2b. To investigate the pathogenicity of the prevalent virus, we isolated CPV-2a and performed the animal experiment. Nine beagles were inoculated with 10 5.86 of 50% tissue culture infectious doses (TCID 50 ) of the virus. All the experimentally infected beagles exhibited mild to moderate mucoid or watery diarrhea on day 4 post-infection (p.i.). On day 9 p.i., characteristic histopathological lesions were clearly observed in multiple organs of infected dogs, including liver, spleen, kidney, brain and all segments of the small and large intestines, while viral DNA and antigen staining could be detected in the sampled tissues. It is notable that canine parvovirus was isolated in one from two brain samples processed. Conclusion: Our results indicated that CPV-2a is the predominant subtype in Nanjing of China. And this virus caused extensive lesions in a variety of tissues, including the brain.">
    <entity charOffset="87-94" id="9976bf51302bf33a5384a30c73231d4077c63ffe.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="903-911" id="9976bf51302bf33a5384a30c73231d4077c63ffe.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_13250" text="diarrhea" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1162-1165" id="9976bf51302bf33a5384a30c73231d4077c63ffe.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1170-1177" id="9976bf51302bf33a5384a30c73231d4077c63ffe.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_59132" text="antigen" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="9976bf51302bf33a5384a30c73231d4077c63ffe.c1.e0" e2="9976bf51302bf33a5384a30c73231d4077c63ffe.c1.e2" id="9976bf51302bf33a5384a30c73231d4077c63ffe.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="9976bf51302bf33a5384a30c73231d4077c63ffe.c1.e0" e2="9976bf51302bf33a5384a30c73231d4077c63ffe.c1.e3" id="9976bf51302bf33a5384a30c73231d4077c63ffe.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="9976bf51302bf33a5384a30c73231d4077c63ffe.c1.e1" e2="9976bf51302bf33a5384a30c73231d4077c63ffe.c1.e2" id="9976bf51302bf33a5384a30c73231d4077c63ffe.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="9976bf51302bf33a5384a30c73231d4077c63ffe.c1.e1" e2="9976bf51302bf33a5384a30c73231d4077c63ffe.c1.e3" id="9976bf51302bf33a5384a30c73231d4077c63ffe.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
