<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1">
  <chunk id="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c0" text="Quantifying the value of surveillance data for improving model predictions of lymphatic filariasis elimination">
    <entity charOffset="78-98" id="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_12211" text="lymphatic filariasis" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="88-98" id="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c0.e1" ontology_id="DOID_1080" text="filariasis" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c1" text="Mathematical models are increasingly being used to evaluate strategies aiming to achieve the control or elimination of parasitic diseases. Recently, owing to growing realization that process-oriented models are useful for ecological forecasts only if the biological processes are well defined, attention has focused on data assimilation as a means to improve the predictive performance of these models. Data Availability Statement: Code for running the models EPIFIL, LYMFASIM, and TRANSFIL are available at www.ntdmodelling.org/diseases/ lymphatic-filariasis. All the custom codes for analyzing model outputs are freely available in Github (https://github.com/EdwinMichaelLab/ EPIFIL_LFData.git). The relevant data used for running the models and analyses conducted in this study are provided within the paper and its Supplementary Information files. more accurate predictions of the durations of drug interventions required to achieve parasite elimination.">
    <entity charOffset="898-902" id="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_23888" text="drug" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c2" text="Knowledge of relative information contributions of model only versus data-informed models is valuable for improving the usefulness of LF model predictions in management decision making, learning system dynamics, and for supporting the design of parasite monitoring programmes. The present results further pinpoint the crucial need for longitudinal infection surveillance data for enhancing the precision and accuracy of model predictions of the intervention durations required to achieve parasite elimination in an endemic location."/>
  <chunk id="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c3" text="Although parasite transmission models offer powerful tools for predicting the impacts of interventions, there is growing realization that these models can be useful for this purpose only if their governing biological processes are well defined. Recently, model-data assimilation has been applied to address this problem and improve the performance of processoriented models for ecological forecasting. Here, we developed an analytical framework that allowed the sequential coupling of the three existing lymphatic filariasis (LF) models with longitudinal infection monitoring data collected in field sites undergoing mass drug administrations (MDAs) to examine the relative value of such data for parameterizing these models and for improving their predictions of the required durations of drug interventions to break parasite transmission. We found that data-informed models provided more precise and reliable forecasts of elimination timelines in the study sites compared to model-only predictions, and that data collected up to 5 years post-MDA reduced each model's predictive uncertainty most. We also found that this improved performance may be intriguingly related to temporal changes in system dynamics. Our results underscore the significance of sequential model-data fusion for enhancing the understanding of LF transmission dynamics, design of surveillance, and generation of reliable model predictions for management decision making.">
    <entity charOffset="504-524" id="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c3.e0" ontology_id="DOID_12211" text="lymphatic filariasis" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="514-524" id="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c3.e1" ontology_id="DOID_1080" text="filariasis" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="622-626" id="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c3.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_23888" text="drug" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="790-794" id="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c3.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_23888" text="drug" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c3.e0" e2="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c3.e2" id="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c3.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c3.e0" e2="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c3.e3" id="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c3.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c3.e1" e2="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c3.e2" id="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c3.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c3.e1" e2="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c3.e3" id="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c3.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="9abc1a92424ffc51803613392c22320da59ebfb1.c4" text="Data assimilation in filarial model predictions PLOS Neglected Tropical Diseases | https://doi."/>
</document>
