<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d">
  <chunk id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c0" text="The 17th Rocky Mountain Virology Association Meeting"/>
  <chunk id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c1" text="Since 2000, scientists and students from the greater Rocky Mountain region, along with invited speakers, both national and international, have gathered at the Mountain Campus of Colorado State University to discuss their area of study, present recent findings, establish or strengthen collaborations, and mentor the next generation of virologists and prionologists through formal presentations and informal discussions concerning science, grantsmanship and network development. This year, approximately 100 people attended the 17th annual Rocky Mountain Virology Association meeting, that began with a keynote presentation, and featured 29 oral and 35 poster presentations covering RNA and DNA viruses, prions, virus-host interactions and guides to successful mentorship. Since the keynote address focused on the structure and function of Zika and related flaviviruses, a special session was held to discuss RNA control. The secluded meeting at the foot of the Colorado Rocky Mountains gave ample time for in-depth discussions amid the peak of fall colors in the aspen groves while the random bear provided excitement. On behalf of the Rocky Mountain Virology Association, this report summarizes the &gt;50 reports.">
    <entity charOffset="682-685" id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="690-693" id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="908-911" id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c2" text="Viruses 2017, 9, 333 2 of 26 a virus and prion themed performance during the formal poster session. Taken together, the 17th annual RMVA meeting ( Figure 2 ) upheld the tradition of presenting novel findings, summarized below, that spanned the fields of bio-informatics, host-pathogen interactions, immunology, therapeutics, replication of DNA and RNA viruses along with prion detection and disease propagation. ) who described his team's high resolution anatomical study of flaviviruses. Zika virus emerged in 2015-2016 in the Americas, with rapid spread and substantial impact. His team solved the structure of this flavivirus virion to near atomic resolution, and this revealed the similarity with previous flavivirus structures such as dengue virus and West Nile virus. Despite strong overall structural similarity, regions of the envelope (E) glycoprotein revealed differences that suggested sequences that might be involved in the unique cell and tissue tropism that Zika has displayed. Together with dengue virus, his team continued to probe the structure and composition of these viruses and their assembly intermediates using the tools of cryo-electron microscopy and mass spectrometry. In particular, they probed the process of virus particle maturation examining the immature virus particle and the conversion of prM by cellular furin to the mature M form of the protein. This process in dengue virus is very inefficient and they determined the stoichiometry of prM/M proteins in the Zika virion, and evaluated the implications of the maturation state on virus biology. Antibody binding to the particle has also been examined and has revealed insights into the process of virus maturation as well as entry of the virion into target host cells. The ability to compare virus particles from multiple members of the flavivirus genus in terms of structure and function serves as a powerful strategy to discern common processes and distinct features that contribute to virus biology.">
    <entity charOffset="340-343" id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c2.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="348-351" id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c2.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="391-398" id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c2.e2" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="848-860" id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c2.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_17089" text="glycoprotein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1043-1048" id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c2.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_50406" text="probe" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1479-1487" id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c2.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c2.e0" e2="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c2.e2" id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c2.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c2.e1" e2="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c2.e2" id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c2.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c2.e2" e2="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c2.e3" id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c2.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c2.e2" e2="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c2.e4" id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c2.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c2.e2" e2="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c2.e5" id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c2.p4" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c3" text="2.1. RNA Viruses described his work on the impact of environmental conditions on defining the population diversity of Zika virus in Aedes mosquitoes. The emergence of arthropod-borne viruses (arboviruses) has become an ever-growing public concern, highlighted by the recent emergence of Chikungunya virus and Zika virus (ZIKV) in the Americas. The conditions that lead to the emergence of new virus genotypes are poorly understood. In mosquitoes, temperature profoundly impacts virus transmission via replication rate and the likelihood that virus will disseminate from the midgut and ultimately be transmitted. Accordingly, they sought to define the impact of temperature on transmission dynamics of ZIKV and determine whether temperature affects virus population structure during extrinsic incubation (EI) in the mosquito. In particular, they exposed Aedes aegypti and Aedes albopictus mosquito vectors to a bloodmeal containing a Puerto-Rican strain of Zika virus (ZIKV, Flaviviridae, Flavivirus) and held the mosquitoes for 7 and 14 days at 25 • C, 28 • C and 35 • C. They also exposed the infected mosquitoes to fluctuating temperatures that varied from 25 to 35 • C diurnally. They found that transmission of ZIKV in both Aedes mosquitoes was most efficient at 28 • C (p &lt; 0.05). However, viral load in the midgut and hemolymph was highest at 35 • C (p &lt; 0.05). Using RNA deep sequencing (RNAseq) to characterize virus genetic diversity, they described that ZIKV populations in the midgut, hemolymph, and saliva were shaped by the EI temperature. Collectively, their data indicated that temperature has multiple impacts on ZIKV biology.">
    <entity charOffset="5-8" id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c3.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="287-298" id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c3.e1" ontology_id="DOID_0050012" text="Chikungunya" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1374-1377" id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c3.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c3.e0" e2="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c3.e1" id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c3.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c3.e1" e2="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c3.e2" id="9b5a336dab77072af21829b37a7b8318ae1dec6d.c3.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
