<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="9bbe789148466f6667a673885d4adddedf6b74e4">
  <chunk id="9bbe789148466f6667a673885d4adddedf6b74e4.c0" text="viruses Isolation of a Divergent Strain of Bovine Parainfluenza Virus Type 3 (BPIV3) Infecting Cattle in China"/>
  <chunk id="9bbe789148466f6667a673885d4adddedf6b74e4.c1" text="Bovine parainfluenza virus type 3 (BPIV3) is one of the most important known viral respiratory pathogens of both young and adult cattle. It is also named &quot;heat stress in transport&quot;, causing morbidity and mass death. New variants of BPIV3 have been detected or isolated in China since 2008. Here, we isolate one BPIV3 strain (named BPIV3 BJ) in Madin-Darby bovine kidney (MDBK) cells from nasal samples collected in China. Phylogenetic analysis showed that our isolate is related to BPIV3 of the genotype A. The comparison of BPIV3-BJ and the reference Chinese isolate NM09 showed that these strains are highly divergent. We found many differences in the amino acid composition in the nucleocapsid (NP) protein among these genotype A strains. Since the NP protein has been implicated in immunization studies, our BPIV3 isolate will be useful for the development of immune assays and vaccine studies. The diversity of BPIV3 lineages that we found in China indicated ongoing evolution for immune escape. Our study highlights the importance of genetic surveillance for determining the effect of BPIV3 variability on pathogen evolution and population-scale immunity.">
    <entity charOffset="654-659" id="9bbe789148466f6667a673885d4adddedf6b74e4.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_46882" text="amino" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="654-664" id="9bbe789148466f6667a673885d4adddedf6b74e4.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33704" text="amino acid" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="660-664" id="9bbe789148466f6667a673885d4adddedf6b74e4.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_37527" text="acid" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="702-709" id="9bbe789148466f6667a673885d4adddedf6b74e4.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="755-762" id="9bbe789148466f6667a673885d4adddedf6b74e4.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
