<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="a5fdb40f1b5bddf4ab24efaddedc40d441e3a130">
  <chunk id="a5fdb40f1b5bddf4ab24efaddedc40d441e3a130.c0" text="A retrospective study of factors associated with treatment decision for nontuberculous mycobacterial lung disease in adults without altered systemic immunity">
    <entity charOffset="101-113" id="a5fdb40f1b5bddf4ab24efaddedc40d441e3a130.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_850" text="lung disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="106-113" id="a5fdb40f1b5bddf4ab24efaddedc40d441e3a130.c0.e1" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="a5fdb40f1b5bddf4ab24efaddedc40d441e3a130.c1" text="Background: Nontuberculous mycobacteria (NTM) lung diseases are increasingly recognized as chronic opportunistic infections, occurring in individuals with a wide variety of underlying conditions. In the absence of systemic immunodeficiency, decision of NTM lung disease treatment must relies on a careful risk/benefit assessment, given the requirement of long-term administration of multidrug therapies supported by limited evidence. The primary objective was to identify the factors associated with anti-NTM treatment initiation. Clinical and radiological outcome upon treatment were studied. Methods: This retrospective, single center study (2013)(2014)(2015)(2016) 45 months) addressed the criteria supporting treatment decision among adults with NTM lung disease without systemic immunodeficiency at our institution, with the assigned goal to harmonize the practice. All patients matched the current international definitions of NTM lung disease according to the American Thoracic Society criteria. Factors associated with anti-NTM treatment were investigated by conditional logistic regression. Clinical and radiological outcomes of treated and untreated NTMdisease cases were examined. Mortality rate was assessed. An expert radiologist conducted a blinded computed tomography (CT)-scan review of the treated and untreated patients.">
    <entity charOffset="257-269" id="a5fdb40f1b5bddf4ab24efaddedc40d441e3a130.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_850" text="lung disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="262-269" id="a5fdb40f1b5bddf4ab24efaddedc40d441e3a130.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="754-766" id="a5fdb40f1b5bddf4ab24efaddedc40d441e3a130.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_850" text="lung disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="759-766" id="a5fdb40f1b5bddf4ab24efaddedc40d441e3a130.c1.e3" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="937-949" id="a5fdb40f1b5bddf4ab24efaddedc40d441e3a130.c1.e4" ontology_id="DOID_850" text="lung disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="942-949" id="a5fdb40f1b5bddf4ab24efaddedc40d441e3a130.c1.e5" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
