<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="a70d334286efa96684bd35e383175063c285ab8b">
  <chunk id="a70d334286efa96684bd35e383175063c285ab8b.c0" text="Molecular characterization of type 1 porcine reproductive and respiratory syndrome viruses (PRRSV) isolated in the Netherlands from 2014 to 2016">
    <entity charOffset="74-82" id="a70d334286efa96684bd35e383175063c285ab8b.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_225" text="syndrome" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="a70d334286efa96684bd35e383175063c285ab8b.c1" text="Porcine reproductive and respiratory syndrome virus (PRRSV) is the causative agent of a devastating pig disease present all over the world. The remarkable genetic variation of PRRSV, makes epidemiological and molecular analysis of circulating viruses highly important to review current diagnostic tools and vaccine efficacy. Monitoring PRRS viruses supports modern herd management by explaining the source of found viruses, either internally or externally from the herd. No epidemiological or molecular study has been published on circulating PRRS-viruses in the Netherlands, since the early nineties. Therefore, the objective of this study is to investigate circulating PRRS-viruses in the Netherlands in 2014, 2015 and 2016 on a molecular level by sequencing ORF2, ORF3, ORF4, ORF5, ORF6 and ORF7. The results demonstrate that the 74 PRRSV strains belong to PRRSV-1, but the diversity among strains is high, based on nucleotide identity, individual ORF length and phylogenetic trees of individual ORFs. Furthermore, the data presented here show that the phylogenetic topology of some viruses is ORF dependent and suggests recombination. The identity of the strain of interest might be misinterpreted and wrong conclusions may be drawn in a diagnostic and epidemiological perspective, when only ORF5 is analyzed, as performed in many routine sequencing procedures.">
    <entity charOffset="37-45" id="a70d334286efa96684bd35e383175063c285ab8b.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_225" text="syndrome" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="104-111" id="a70d334286efa96684bd35e383175063c285ab8b.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="919-929" id="a70d334286efa96684bd35e383175063c285ab8b.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_36976" text="nucleotide" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="951-954" id="a70d334286efa96684bd35e383175063c285ab8b.c1.e3" ontology_id="DOID_8771" text="ORF" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1097-1100" id="a70d334286efa96684bd35e383175063c285ab8b.c1.e4" ontology_id="DOID_8771" text="ORF" type="disease"/>
    <pair e1="a70d334286efa96684bd35e383175063c285ab8b.c1.e0" e2="a70d334286efa96684bd35e383175063c285ab8b.c1.e2" id="a70d334286efa96684bd35e383175063c285ab8b.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="a70d334286efa96684bd35e383175063c285ab8b.c1.e1" e2="a70d334286efa96684bd35e383175063c285ab8b.c1.e2" id="a70d334286efa96684bd35e383175063c285ab8b.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="a70d334286efa96684bd35e383175063c285ab8b.c1.e2" e2="a70d334286efa96684bd35e383175063c285ab8b.c1.e3" id="a70d334286efa96684bd35e383175063c285ab8b.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="a70d334286efa96684bd35e383175063c285ab8b.c1.e2" e2="a70d334286efa96684bd35e383175063c285ab8b.c1.e4" id="a70d334286efa96684bd35e383175063c285ab8b.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
