<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="a714dc2983f4139a10c0222d8816654277e72965">
  <chunk id="a714dc2983f4139a10c0222d8816654277e72965.c0" text="Attitudes of consumers and live-poultry workers to central slaughtering in controlling H7N9: a cross-sectional study"/>
  <chunk id="a714dc2983f4139a10c0222d8816654277e72965.c1" text="Background: Guangdong Province in the Pearl River Delta of Southeast China is among the areas in the country with the highest rates of avian flu cases. In order to control the outbreak of human-infected H7N9 cases, Guangdong launched a new policy on the central slaughtering of live poultry in 2015. This study aims to evaluate attitudes of consumers and live-poultry workers toward the policy. The live-poultry workers consisted of two sub-groups: live-poultry traders and poultry farm workers. Methods: Consumers and live-poultry workers from Guangdong were enrolled by stratified multi-stage random sampling. Online and field surveys were conducted to investigate participants' attitudes on policy implementation. Questionnaires were developed to quantify participant demographics, to collect information about attitudes toward the policy, and to identify influential factors of policy acceptability. Proportional odds logistics regression was used in the univariate and multivariate analyses. A total of 1449 consumers, 181 live-poultry traders, and 114 poultry farm workers completed the study. Results: Policy acceptability percentages among consumers, live-poultry traders, and poultry farm workers were 57. 1, 37.9, and 62.6%, respectively. Logistics regression shows that consumers tended not to support the policy if they were males, if they were concerned with the food safety of chilled products, and if they preferred purchasing live poultry. Live-poultry traders tended not to support if they were subsidized by the government, if they were males, if they experienced a drop in trading volume, and if they were unclear whether avian flu was a preventable disease. Finally, poultry farm workers tended not to support if they experienced a drop in trading volume, if they operated a poultry farm on a small to medium scale, and if they experienced inconvenience in their work due to the policy.">
    <entity charOffset="135-144" id="a714dc2983f4139a10c0222d8816654277e72965.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_4492" text="avian flu" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="141-144" id="a714dc2983f4139a10c0222d8816654277e72965.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="flu" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1376-1380" id="a714dc2983f4139a10c0222d8816654277e72965.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_33290" text="food" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1641-1650" id="a714dc2983f4139a10c0222d8816654277e72965.c1.e3" ontology_id="DOID_4492" text="avian flu" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1647-1650" id="a714dc2983f4139a10c0222d8816654277e72965.c1.e4" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="flu" type="disease"/>
    <pair e1="a714dc2983f4139a10c0222d8816654277e72965.c1.e0" e2="a714dc2983f4139a10c0222d8816654277e72965.c1.e2" id="a714dc2983f4139a10c0222d8816654277e72965.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="a714dc2983f4139a10c0222d8816654277e72965.c1.e1" e2="a714dc2983f4139a10c0222d8816654277e72965.c1.e2" id="a714dc2983f4139a10c0222d8816654277e72965.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="a714dc2983f4139a10c0222d8816654277e72965.c1.e2" e2="a714dc2983f4139a10c0222d8816654277e72965.c1.e3" id="a714dc2983f4139a10c0222d8816654277e72965.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="a714dc2983f4139a10c0222d8816654277e72965.c1.e2" e2="a714dc2983f4139a10c0222d8816654277e72965.c1.e4" id="a714dc2983f4139a10c0222d8816654277e72965.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="a714dc2983f4139a10c0222d8816654277e72965.c2" text="The study reveals a substantial refusal or slowness to accept the policy. Failure to accept the policy results from varying reasons. Among consumers, concern about food safety and dietary preference are two major causes of disapproval. Policy acceptability among live-poultry workers diverges within the two sub-groups. While a large percentage of poultry farm workers accept the policy, the drop in trading and an insufficient subsidy hamper acceptance by live-poultry traders. We recommend that policy-makers promote health education and alleviate the policy impact on trading with a reformed subsidy policy to increase acceptability. These findings are crucial for the prevention of human-infected H7N9 cases in Guangdong.">
    <entity charOffset="164-168" id="a714dc2983f4139a10c0222d8816654277e72965.c2.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33290" text="food" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
