<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="aa1eaad52d7a7827850cecf3d6b582e728e7e543">
  <chunk id="aa1eaad52d7a7827850cecf3d6b582e728e7e543.c0" text="Haemorrhagic pneumonia in sled dogs caused by Streptococcus equi subsp. zooepidemicus -one fatality and two full recoveries: a case report">
    <entity charOffset="13-22" id="aa1eaad52d7a7827850cecf3d6b582e728e7e543.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_552" text="pneumonia" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="aa1eaad52d7a7827850cecf3d6b582e728e7e543.c1" text="In spite of yearly vaccination, outbreaks of canine infectious respiratory disease are periodically seen amongst domestic dogs. These infections compromise host defense mechanisms, and, when combined with other stressful events, allow opportunistic pathogens like Streptococcus equi subsp. zooepidemicus to create serious disease. Early recognition and treatment are tremendously important for a successful outcome in these cases. A polyvalent vaccine was given to 22 racing dogs three days after a competition, followed by two days of rest, and then the dogs were returned to regular training. Coughing was noticed among the dogs four days after immunisation. Three days after this outbreak one of the dogs was unusually silent and was found dead the next morning. Simultaneously two other dogs developed haemorrhagic expectorate, depression and dyspnea and were brought in to the veterinary hospital. Streptococcus equi subsp. zooepidemicus was isolated in pure culture from all three cases. They were treated and rehabilitated successfully, and won a sledge race three months later. This paper discusses the necropsy results, treatment regime, rehabilitation and the chronology of vaccination, stressful events and disease.">
    <entity charOffset="75-82" id="aa1eaad52d7a7827850cecf3d6b582e728e7e543.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="322-329" id="aa1eaad52d7a7827850cecf3d6b582e728e7e543.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1218-1225" id="aa1eaad52d7a7827850cecf3d6b582e728e7e543.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
