<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e">
  <chunk id="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c0" text="Protective Efficacy of Cross-Reactive CD8 + T Cells Recognising Mutant Viral Epitopes Depends on Peptide-MHC-I Structural Interactions and T Cell Activation Threshold"/>
  <chunk id="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1" text="Emergence of a new influenza strain leads to a rapid global spread of the virus due to minimal antibody immunity. Preexisting CD8 + T-cell immunity directed towards conserved internal viral regions can greatly ameliorate the disease. However, mutational escape within the T cell epitopes is a substantial issue for virus control and vaccine design. Although mutations can result in a loss of T cell recognition, some variants generate cross-reactive T cell responses. In this study, we used reverse genetics to modify the influenza NP 336-374 peptide at a partially-solvent exposed residue (N-.A, NPN3A mutation) to assess the availability, effectiveness and mechanism underlying influenza-specific cross-reactive T cell responses. The engineered virus induced a diminished CD8 + T cell response and selected a narrowed T cell receptor (TCR) repertoire within two Vb regions (Vb8.3 and Vb9). This can be partially explained by the H-2D b NPN3A structure that showed a loss of several contacts between the NPN3A peptide and H-2D b , including a contact with His155, a position known to play an important role in mediating TCR-pMHC-I interactions. Despite these differences, common cross-reactive TCRs were detected in both the naïve and immune NPN3A-specific TCR repertoires. However, while the NPN3A epitope primes memory T-cells that give an equivalent recall response to the mutant or wild-type (wt) virus, both are markedly lower than wt-.wt challenge. Such decreased CD8 + responses elicited after heterologous challenge resulted in delayed viral clearance from the infected lung. Furthermore, mice first exposed to the wt virus give a poor, low avidity response following secondary infection with the mutant. Thus, the protective efficacy of cross-reactive CD8 + T cells recognising mutant viral epitopes depend on peptide-MHC-I structural interactions and functional avidity. Our study does not support vaccine strategies that include immunization against commonly selected cross-reactive variants with mutations at partially-solvent exposed residues that have characteristics comparable to NPN3A.">
    <entity charOffset="19-28" id="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="522-531" id="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="543-550" id="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_16670" text="peptide" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1011-1018" id="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_16670" text="peptide" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1103-1107" id="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1300-1307" id="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_53000" text="epitope" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.e0" e2="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.e2" id="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.e0" e2="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.e3" id="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.e0" e2="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.e4" id="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.e0" e2="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.e5" id="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.e1" e2="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.e2" id="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.e1" e2="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.e3" id="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.p5" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.e1" e2="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.e4" id="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.p6" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.e1" e2="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.e5" id="aa1f783a1af8b14cdbee5ea50cc0a78c56d7442e.c1.p7" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
