<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="aa6d90b5eb890db486db2e09d3b28db343a7d48c">
  <chunk id="aa6d90b5eb890db486db2e09d3b28db343a7d48c.c0" text="Bureau of Health Policy, Ministry of Health and Welfare"/>
  <chunk id="aa6d90b5eb890db486db2e09d3b28db343a7d48c.c1" text="This study examined the public's preventive behavioral responses during the 2015 Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus (MERS-CoV) outbreak in Korea and the influencing factors. Two cross-sectional telephone surveys were conducted by Gallup Korea using random digit dialing in June 2015 (n = 2004). The main outcome variables were nonpharmaceutical preventive measures (survey (1): Measures for reducing transmission (handwashing, face masks); and survey (2): Measures for avoiding contact with others). Multiple logistic regression was used to identify the factors influencing preventive behaviors. In survey (1), 60.3% of respondents reported more frequent handwashing and 15.5% reported wearing face masks at least once due to the MERS-CoV epidemic. In survey (2), 41-56% of respondents reported practicing avoidance measures. The concerned group was more likely to practice reducing transmission measures (odds ratio (OR) 4.5; 95% confidence interval (CI) 3.3-6.1) and avoidance measures (OR = 9.6; 95% CI, 6.4-14.4). The respondents who had low trust in president or ruling party had a higher practice rate of reducing transmission measures (OR = 1.7; 95% CI, 1.2-2.6) and avoidance measures (OR = 2.1; 95% CI, 1.2-3.5). Cooperative prevention measures need appropriated public concern based on effective risk communication.">
    <entity charOffset="81-113" id="aa6d90b5eb890db486db2e09d3b28db343a7d48c.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_0080642" text="Middle East respiratory syndrome" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="105-113" id="aa6d90b5eb890db486db2e09d3b28db343a7d48c.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_225" text="syndrome" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="437-441" id="aa6d90b5eb890db486db2e09d3b28db343a7d48c.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_0111084" text="face" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="704-708" id="aa6d90b5eb890db486db2e09d3b28db343a7d48c.c1.e3" ontology_id="DOID_0111084" text="face" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
