<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="aca7762f80af606fe3c6d2614096db74f1398368">
  <chunk id="aca7762f80af606fe3c6d2614096db74f1398368.c0" text="Development of VHH Antibodies against Dengue Virus Type 2 NS1 and Comparison with Monoclonal Antibodies for Use in Immunological Diagnosis"/>
  <chunk id="aca7762f80af606fe3c6d2614096db74f1398368.c1" text="The possibility of using variable domain heavy-chain antibodies (VHH antibodies) as diagnostic tools for dengue virus (DENV) type 2 NS1 protein was investigated and compared with the use of conventional monoclonal antibodies. After successful expression of DENV type 2 NS1 protein, the genes of VHH antibodies against NS1 protein were biopanned from a non-immune llama library by phage display. VHH antibodies were then expressed and purified from Escherichia coli. Simultaneously, monoclonal antibodies were obtained by the conventional route. Sequence analysis of the VHH antibodies revealed novel and long complementarity determining regions 3 (CDR3). Epitope mapping was performed via a phage display peptide library using purified VHH and monoclonal antibodies as targets. Interestingly, the same region of NS1, which comprises amino acids 224 HWPKPHTLW 232 , was conserved for both kinds of antibodies displaying the consensus motif histidine-tryptophan-tryptophan or tryptophan-proline-tryptophan. The two types of antibodies were used to prepare rapid diagnostic kits based on immunochromatographic assay. The VHH antibody immobilized rapid diagnostic kit showed better sensitivity and specificity than the monoclonal antibody immobilized rapid diagnostic kit, which might be due to the long CDR3 regions of the VHH antibodies and their ability to bind to the pocket and cleft of the targeted antigen. This demonstrates that VHH antibodies are likely to be an option for developing point-of-care tests against DENV infection.">
    <entity charOffset="136-143" id="aca7762f80af606fe3c6d2614096db74f1398368.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="273-280" id="aca7762f80af606fe3c6d2614096db74f1398368.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="322-329" id="aca7762f80af606fe3c6d2614096db74f1398368.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="655-662" id="aca7762f80af606fe3c6d2614096db74f1398368.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_53000" text="Epitope" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="705-712" id="aca7762f80af606fe3c6d2614096db74f1398368.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_16670" text="peptide" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="833-838" id="aca7762f80af606fe3c6d2614096db74f1398368.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_46882" text="amino" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="833-844" id="aca7762f80af606fe3c6d2614096db74f1398368.c1.e6" ontology_id="CHEBI_33704" text="amino acids" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="839-844" id="aca7762f80af606fe3c6d2614096db74f1398368.c1.e7" ontology_id="CHEBI_37527" text="acids" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
