<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="b4a0898920270c599908b3efbf4f7342a8b56c8e">
  <chunk id="b4a0898920270c599908b3efbf4f7342a8b56c8e.c0" text="Nod2 is required for antigen-specific humoral responses against antigens orally delivered using a recombinant Lactobacillus vaccine platform">
    <entity charOffset="64-72" id="b4a0898920270c599908b3efbf4f7342a8b56c8e.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_59132" text="antigens" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="b4a0898920270c599908b3efbf4f7342a8b56c8e.c1" text="Safe and efficacious orally-delivered mucosal vaccine platforms are desperately needed to combat the plethora of mucosally transmitted pathogens. Lactobacillus spp. have emerged as attractive candidates to meet this need and are known to activate the host innate immune response in a species-and strain-specific manner. For selected bacterial isolates and mutants, we investigated the role of key innate immune pathways required for induction of innate and subsequent adaptive immune responses. Co-culture of murine macrophages with L. gasseri (strain NCK1785), L. acidophilus (strain NCFM), or NCFM-derived mutants-NCK2025 and NCK2031-elicited an M2b-like phenotype associated with TH2 skewing and immune regulatory function. For NCFM, this M2b phenotype was dependent on expression of lipoteichoic acid and S layer proteins. Through the use of macrophage genetic knockouts, we identified Toll-like receptor 2 (TLR2), the cytosolic nucleotide-binding oligomerization domain containing 2 (NOD2) receptor, and the inflammasome-associated caspase-1 as contributors to macrophage activation, with NOD2 cooperating with caspase-1 to induce inflammasome derived interleukin (IL)-1β in a pyroptosis-independent fashion. Finally, utilizing an NCFM-based mucosal vaccine platform with surface expression of human immunodeficiency virus type 1 (HIV-1) Gag or membrane proximal external region (MPER), we demonstrated that NOD2 signaling is required for antigen-specific mucosal and systemic humoral responses. We show that lactobacilli differentially utilize innate immune pathways and highlight NOD2 as a key mediator of macrophage function and antigen-specific humoral responses to a Lactobacillus acidophilus mucosal vaccine platform.">
    <entity charOffset="385-389" id="b4a0898920270c599908b3efbf4f7342a8b56c8e.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="787-804" id="b4a0898920270c599908b3efbf4f7342a8b56c8e.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_28640" text="lipoteichoic acid" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="800-804" id="b4a0898920270c599908b3efbf4f7342a8b56c8e.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_37527" text="acid" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1343-1346" id="b4a0898920270c599908b3efbf4f7342a8b56c8e.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_143889" text="Gag" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
