<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="b5e924927b31aface620ada453f904e6e9ebb203">
  <chunk id="b5e924927b31aface620ada453f904e6e9ebb203.c0" text="Bid Regulates the Pathogenesis of Neurotropic Reovirus"/>
  <chunk id="b5e924927b31aface620ada453f904e6e9ebb203.c1" text="Reovirus infection leads to apoptosis in both cultured cells and the murine central nervous system (CNS). NF-kB-driven transcription of proapoptotic cellular genes is required for the effector phase of the apoptotic response. Although both extrinsic death-receptor signaling pathways and intrinsic pathways involving mitochondrial injury are implicated in reovirusinduced apoptosis, mechanisms by which either of these pathways are activated and their relationship to NF-kB signaling following reovirus infection are unknown. The proapoptotic Bcl-2 family member, Bid, is activated by proteolytic cleavage following reovirus infection. To understand how reovirus integrates host signaling circuits to induce apoptosis, we examined proapoptotic signaling following infection of Bid-deficient cells. Although reovirus growth was not affected by the absence of Bid, cells lacking Bid failed to undergo apoptosis. Furthermore, we found that NF-kB activation is required for Bid cleavage and subsequent proapoptotic signaling. To examine the functional significance of Bid-dependent apoptosis in reovirus disease, we monitored fatal encephalitis caused by reovirus in the presence and absence of Bid. Survival of Biddeficient mice was significantly enhanced in comparison to wild-type mice following either peroral or intracranial inoculation of reovirus. Decreased reovirus virulence in Bid-null mice was accompanied by a reduction in viral yield. These findings define a role for NF-kB-dependent cleavage of Bid in the cell death program initiated by viral infection and link Bid to viral virulence.">
    <entity charOffset="184-192" id="b5e924927b31aface620ada453f904e6e9ebb203.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_35224" text="effector" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1128-1140" id="b5e924927b31aface620ada453f904e6e9ebb203.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_9588" text="encephalitis" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1468-1472" id="b5e924927b31aface620ada453f904e6e9ebb203.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1548-1563" id="b5e924927b31aface620ada453f904e6e9ebb203.c1.e3" ontology_id="DOID_934" text="viral infection" type="disease"/>
    <pair e1="b5e924927b31aface620ada453f904e6e9ebb203.c1.e0" e2="b5e924927b31aface620ada453f904e6e9ebb203.c1.e1" id="b5e924927b31aface620ada453f904e6e9ebb203.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="b5e924927b31aface620ada453f904e6e9ebb203.c1.e0" e2="b5e924927b31aface620ada453f904e6e9ebb203.c1.e3" id="b5e924927b31aface620ada453f904e6e9ebb203.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="b5e924927b31aface620ada453f904e6e9ebb203.c1.e1" e2="b5e924927b31aface620ada453f904e6e9ebb203.c1.e2" id="b5e924927b31aface620ada453f904e6e9ebb203.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="b5e924927b31aface620ada453f904e6e9ebb203.c1.e2" e2="b5e924927b31aface620ada453f904e6e9ebb203.c1.e3" id="b5e924927b31aface620ada453f904e6e9ebb203.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
