<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="b691523206f8c2fc150e5939b3136d361d193815">
  <chunk id="b691523206f8c2fc150e5939b3136d361d193815.c0" text="Distributed under Creative Commons CC-BY 4.0 Exploring the psychological health of emergency dispatch centre operatives: a systematic review and narrative synthesis"/>
  <chunk id="b691523206f8c2fc150e5939b3136d361d193815.c1" text="Background. The study objective was to investigate and synthesize available evidence relating to the psychological health of Emergency Dispatch Centre (EDC) operatives, and to identify key stressors experienced by EDC operatives. Methods. Eight electronic databases (Embase, PubMed, Medline, CINAHL, PsycInfo, PsycArticles, The Psychology and Behavioural Sciences Collection, and Google Scholar) were searched. All study designs were included, and no date limits were set. Studies were included if they were published in English, and explored the psychological health of any EDC operatives, across fire, police, and emergency medical services. Studies were excluded if they related solely to other emergency workers, such as police officers or paramedics. Methodological quality of included studies was assessed using checklists adapted from the Critical Appraisal Skills Programme. A narrative synthesis was conducted, using thematic analysis. Results. A total of 16 articles were included in the review. Two overarching themes were identified during the narrative synthesis: 'Organisational and Operational Factors' and 'Interactions with Others'. Stressors identified included being exposed to traumatic calls, lacking control over high workload, and working in under-resourced and pressured environments. Lack of support from management and providing an emotionally demanding service were additional sources of stress. Peer support and social support from friends and family were helpful in managing work-related stress. Discussion. EDC operatives experience stress as a result of their work, which appears to be related to negative psychological health outcomes. Future research should explore the long-term effects of this stress, and the potential for workplace interventions to alleviate the negative impacts on psychological health. PROSPERO Registration Number. CRD42014010806. How to cite this article Golding et al. (2017), Exploring the psychological health of emergency dispatch centre operatives: a systematic review and narrative synthesis. PeerJ 5:e3735; DOI 10.7717/peerj.3735 Subjects Emergency and Critical Care, Psychiatry and Psychology . Dean AM, Rainnie A. 2009. Frontline employees' views on organizational factors that affect the delivery of service quality in call centers. Journal of Services Marketing 23(5):326-337. Deery S, Iverson R, Walsh J. 2002. Work relationships in telephone call centres: understanding emotional exhaustion and employee withdrawal. Journal of Management Studies 39(4):471-496 M. 2012. Stress amongst nurses working in a healthcare telephone-advice service: relationship with job satisfaction, intention to leave, sickness absence, and performance. Journal of Advanced Nursing 68(7):">
    <entity charOffset="152-155" id="b691523206f8c2fc150e5939b3136d361d193815.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_27789" text="EDC" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="214-217" id="b691523206f8c2fc150e5939b3136d361d193815.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_27789" text="EDC" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="575-578" id="b691523206f8c2fc150e5939b3136d361d193815.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_27789" text="EDC" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1537-1540" id="b691523206f8c2fc150e5939b3136d361d193815.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_27789" text="EDC" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="2161-2165" id="b691523206f8c2fc150e5939b3136d361d193815.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_63877" text="Dean" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
