<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="ba29366173f97f54a22e5c410b3d05e9a9649d28">
  <chunk id="ba29366173f97f54a22e5c410b3d05e9a9649d28.c0" text="Foodborne Transmission of Deformed Wing Virus to Ants (Myrmica rubra)"/>
  <chunk id="ba29366173f97f54a22e5c410b3d05e9a9649d28.c1" text="Virus host shifts occur frequently, but the whole range of host species and the actual transmission pathways are often poorly understood. Deformed wing virus (DWV), an RNA virus described from honeybees (Apis mellifera), has been shown to have a broad host range. Since ants are often scavenging on dead honeybees, foodborne transmission of these viruses may occur. However, the role of the ant Myrmica rubra as an alternative host is not known and foodborne transmission to ants has not been experimentally addressed yet. Here, we show with a 16-week feeding experiment that foodborne transmission enables DWV type-A and -B to infect M. rubra and that these ants may serve as a virus reservoir. However, the titers of both plus-and minus-sense viral RNA strands decreased over time. Since the ants were fed with highly virus-saturated honeybee pupae, this probably resulted in initial viral peaks, then approaching lower equilibrium titers in infected individuals later. Since DWV infections were also found in untreated field-collected M. rubra colonies, our results support the wide host range of DWV and further suggest foodborne transmission as a so far underestimated spread mechanism. of honeybee viruses frequently happens, although it is not fully understood why and when pathogens jump between some species and not others [4, 15] .">
    <entity charOffset="168-171" id="ba29366173f97f54a22e5c410b3d05e9a9649d28.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="379-383" id="ba29366173f97f54a22e5c410b3d05e9a9649d28.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="751-754" id="ba29366173f97f54a22e5c410b3d05e9a9649d28.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="ba29366173f97f54a22e5c410b3d05e9a9649d28.c2" text="The deformed wing virus (DWV) is a prevalent virus in honeybees with a broad host range spanning at least eight insect orders and three orders of Arachnida [17] [18] [19] [20] [21] . This virus is a positive sense single-stranded RNA virus and a harmful honeybee pathogen [22] , of which at least three distinct genotypes or master variants-type A, B, and C-are known [21] . DWV can cause clinical symptoms such as crippled wings, a shortened abdomen, and a reduced host lifespan [22] [23] [24] . Driven by efficient vector transmission via ectoparasitic mites Varroa destructor, DWV has become ubiquitous [25] [26] [27] [28] .">
    <entity charOffset="230-233" id="ba29366173f97f54a22e5c410b3d05e9a9649d28.c2.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="ba29366173f97f54a22e5c410b3d05e9a9649d28.c3" text="Foodborne virus transmission appears to be less important in honeybees, but may be relevant for transmission to other species [21], especially for predators and scavengers [29] [30] [31] [32] . However, data on foodborne DWV transmission between honeybees and insect predators/scavengers are scarce."/>
  <chunk id="ba29366173f97f54a22e5c410b3d05e9a9649d28.c4" text="Since virus-infected brood and adults are often expelled from honeybee colonies [33-36] and ants are often seen foraging such bees in apiaries (personal observations), it appears as if ants are very likely to consume DWV-infected food. However, there are only few studies on virus transmission between honeybees and ants. DWV and Kashmir Bee Virus (KBV) presence plus replication was detected in invasive argentine ants (Linepithema humile) as well as presence of Black queen cell virus (BQCV) in Linepithema humile and Anoplolepis gracilipes [37] [38] [39] . Further, DWV and other honeybee viruses (BQCV, Israeli acute paralysis virus and Sacbrood virus) were detected in Camponotus sp. ants [19] . Similarly, chronic bee paralysis virus seems to be able to replicate in ants Camponotus vagus [29] . So far, no study has yet experimentally addressed the efficacy of foodborne virus transmission between honeybees and predators/scavengers. Since ants are ubiquitous and play essential roles in terrestrial ecosystem functioning [40] [41] [42] [43] , virus transmission from managed honeybees might pose a considerable threat, given the virus is able to exploit the novel hosts. On the other hand, viruses and other pathogens may help limiting the spread of invasive M. rubra populations [37, 44] . Novel hosts can be biological vectors that support virus replication or reservoirs and mechanical vectors without virus replication [4] . Further, spillover events can also be bidirectional, from the novel host back to the initial host [1], possibly resulting in altered virulence and respective consequences as e.g., for influenza [45] .">
    <entity charOffset="405-414" id="ba29366173f97f54a22e5c410b3d05e9a9649d28.c4.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_2819" text="argentine" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1621-1630" id="ba29366173f97f54a22e5c410b3d05e9a9649d28.c4.e1" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <pair e1="ba29366173f97f54a22e5c410b3d05e9a9649d28.c4.e0" e2="ba29366173f97f54a22e5c410b3d05e9a9649d28.c4.e1" id="ba29366173f97f54a22e5c410b3d05e9a9649d28.c4.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="ba29366173f97f54a22e5c410b3d05e9a9649d28.c5" text="Here, we empirically test for the first time whether ants, Myrmica rubra, which are common in Europe [46] and an invasive species in North America [47], can be alternative hosts of DWV and if foodborne transmission is feasible. Monitoring of viral loads after consumption of virus-infected food will shed light on the fate of the viruses. If negative-sense strands of the RNA viruses can be found, this would suggest virus replication [48, 49] .">
    <entity charOffset="290-294" id="ba29366173f97f54a22e5c410b3d05e9a9649d28.c5.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33290" text="food" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="305-310" id="ba29366173f97f54a22e5c410b3d05e9a9649d28.c5.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_30212" text="light" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="372-375" id="ba29366173f97f54a22e5c410b3d05e9a9649d28.c5.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
