<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="bcd61a98bcf6ab96b5e65dd3f7bfe288e6f9153a">
  <chunk id="bcd61a98bcf6ab96b5e65dd3f7bfe288e6f9153a.c0" text="Stimulation of Dectin-1 and Dectin-2 during Parenteral Immunization, but Not Mincle, Induces Secretory IgA in Intestinal Mucosa"/>
  <chunk id="bcd61a98bcf6ab96b5e65dd3f7bfe288e6f9153a.c1" text="Induction of a robust and long-lived mucosal immune response during vaccination is critical to achieve protection against numerous pathogens. However, traditional injected vaccines are generally poor inducers of mucosal immunity. One of the effective strategies to improve vaccine efficacy is incorporation of adjuvant molecules that enhance and polarize adaptive immune reactions. Effects of Syk-coupled lectin receptor agonists as adjuvants to induce mucosal immune reactions during parenteral immunization are not fully studied. We now report that the agonists trehalose-6,6-dibehenate (TDB), curdlan, and furfurman, which stimulate Dectin-1, Dectin-2, and Mincle, respectively, activate transcription factors (NF-κB, NFAT, and AP-1) to various extents in murine RAW 264.7 macrophages, even though similar pathways are activated. The agonists also elicit differential expression of maturation markers in bone marrow-derived dendritic cells, as well as differential cytokine secretion from these cells and from splenic mononuclear cells. In vivo assays also show that agonists of Dectin-1 and Dectin-2, but not Mincle, induce heavy IgA secretion in intestinal mucosa even when delivered parenterally. Strikingly, this effect appears to be formulation-independent. Collectively, the data suggest that adjuvants based on Dectin-1 and Dectin-2 agonists may significantly improve the efficacy of parenteral vaccines by inducing robust local immune reactions in intestinal mucosa.">
    <entity charOffset="310-318" id="bcd61a98bcf6ab96b5e65dd3f7bfe288e6f9153a.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_60809" text="adjuvant" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="319-328" id="bcd61a98bcf6ab96b5e65dd3f7bfe288e6f9153a.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_25367" text="molecules" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="421-429" id="bcd61a98bcf6ab96b5e65dd3f7bfe288e6f9153a.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_48705" text="agonists" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="433-442" id="bcd61a98bcf6ab96b5e65dd3f7bfe288e6f9153a.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_60809" text="adjuvants" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="555-563" id="bcd61a98bcf6ab96b5e65dd3f7bfe288e6f9153a.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_48705" text="agonists" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="837-845" id="bcd61a98bcf6ab96b5e65dd3f7bfe288e6f9153a.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_48705" text="agonists" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1070-1078" id="bcd61a98bcf6ab96b5e65dd3f7bfe288e6f9153a.c1.e6" ontology_id="CHEBI_48705" text="agonists" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1302-1311" id="bcd61a98bcf6ab96b5e65dd3f7bfe288e6f9153a.c1.e7" ontology_id="CHEBI_60809" text="adjuvants" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1343-1351" id="bcd61a98bcf6ab96b5e65dd3f7bfe288e6f9153a.c1.e8" ontology_id="CHEBI_48705" text="agonists" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
