<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="bd1d9c526a0194d356d7a65ebcebc322dd872a36">
  <chunk id="bd1d9c526a0194d356d7a65ebcebc322dd872a36.c0" text="Seronegative Celiac Disease and Immunoglobulin Deficiency: Where to Look in the Submerged Iceberg?">
    <entity charOffset="13-27" id="bd1d9c526a0194d356d7a65ebcebc322dd872a36.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_10608" text="Celiac Disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="20-27" id="bd1d9c526a0194d356d7a65ebcebc322dd872a36.c0.e1" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="Disease" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="bd1d9c526a0194d356d7a65ebcebc322dd872a36.c1" text="In the present narrative review, we analyzed the relationship between seronegative celiac disease (SNCD) and immunoglobulin deficiencies. For this purpose, we conducted a literature search on the main medical databases. SNCD poses a diagnostic dilemma. Villous blunting, intraepithelial lymphocytes (IELs) count and gluten &quot;challenge&quot; are the most reliable markers. Immunohistochemistry/immunofluorescence tissue transglutaminase (tTG)-targeted mucosal immunoglobulin A (IgA) immune complexes in the intestinal mucosa of SNCD patients may be useful. In our experience, tTG-mRNA was similarly increased in seropositive celiac disease (CD) and suspected SNCD, and strongly correlated with the IELs count. This increase is found even in the IELs' range of 15-25/100 enterocytes, suggesting that there may be a &quot;grey zone&quot; of gluten-related disorders. An immune deregulation (severely lacking B-cell differentiation) underlies the association of SNCD with immunoglobulin deficiencies. Therefore, CD may be linked to autoimmune disorders and immune deficits (common variable immunodeficiency (CVID)/IgA selective deficiency). CVID is a heterogeneous group of antibodies dysfunction, whose association with CD is demonstrated only by the response to a gluten-free diet (GFD). We hypothesized a familial inheritance between CD and CVID. Selective IgA deficiency, commonly associated with CD,">
    <entity charOffset="83-97" id="bd1d9c526a0194d356d7a65ebcebc322dd872a36.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_10608" text="celiac disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="90-97" id="bd1d9c526a0194d356d7a65ebcebc322dd872a36.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="618-632" id="bd1d9c526a0194d356d7a65ebcebc322dd872a36.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_10608" text="celiac disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="625-632" id="bd1d9c526a0194d356d7a65ebcebc322dd872a36.c1.e3" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1054-1086" id="bd1d9c526a0194d356d7a65ebcebc322dd872a36.c1.e4" ontology_id="DOID_12177" text="common variable immunodeficiency" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1121-1125" id="bd1d9c526a0194d356d7a65ebcebc322dd872a36.c1.e5" ontology_id="DOID_12177" text="CVID" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1324-1328" id="bd1d9c526a0194d356d7a65ebcebc322dd872a36.c1.e6" ontology_id="DOID_12177" text="CVID" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
