<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="bf5c0b8c4f555f2af2ff41bc32faeb9c991dcafa">
  <chunk id="bf5c0b8c4f555f2af2ff41bc32faeb9c991dcafa.c0" text="Microarray analysis of long non-coding RNA expression profiles uncovers a Toxoplasma- induced negative regulation of host immune signaling">
    <entity charOffset="39-42" id="bf5c0b8c4f555f2af2ff41bc32faeb9c991dcafa.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="bf5c0b8c4f555f2af2ff41bc32faeb9c991dcafa.c1" text="Background: Toxoplasma gondii is an obligate intracellular protozoan parasite that can infect mammalian cells and thereby regulate host gene expression. The long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) have been demonstrated to be an important class of RNA molecules that regulate many biological processes, including host-pathogen interactions. However, the role of host lncRNAs in the response to T. gondii infection remains largely unknown. Methods: We applied a microarray approach to determine the differential expression profiles of both lncRNAs and mRNAs in the human foreskin fibroblast (HFF) cells after T. gondii infection. The Gene Ontology and Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes (KEGG) pathway analyses were performed to reveal the potential functions of T. gondii-induced genes. Based on the co-expression networks of lncRNAs and immune-related genes, the role of NONSHAT022487 on the regulation of UNC93B1 related immune signaling was investigated by the knockdown and over-expression of lncRNA in human macrophage derived from the PMA-induced promonocytic cell line THP-1. Results: Our data showed that 996 lncRNAs and 109 mRNAs in HFF cells were significantly and differentially expressed following T. gondii infection (fold change ≥ 5, P &lt; 0.05). The results from the GO and KEGG pathway analyses indicated that the mRNAs with differential expression were mainly involved in the host immune response. Remarkably, we identified a novel lncRNA, NONSHAT022487, which suppresses the expression of the immunerelated molecule UNC93B1. After T. gondii infection, NONSHAT022487 impaired the secretion of the cytokines IL-12, TNF-α, IL-1β and IFN-γ by downregulating UNC93B1 expression in human macrophage cells. Conclusions: Our study identified infection-induced lncRNA expression as a novel mechanism by which the Toxoplasma parasite regulates host immune signaling, which advances our understanding of the interaction of T. gondii parasites and host cells.">
    <entity charOffset="239-242" id="bf5c0b8c4f555f2af2ff41bc32faeb9c991dcafa.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="243-252" id="bf5c0b8c4f555f2af2ff41bc32faeb9c991dcafa.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_25367" text="molecules" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="345-349" id="bf5c0b8c4f555f2af2ff41bc32faeb9c991dcafa.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="689-696" id="bf5c0b8c4f555f2af2ff41bc32faeb9c991dcafa.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_34922" text="pathway" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="860-864" id="bf5c0b8c4f555f2af2ff41bc32faeb9c991dcafa.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1288-1295" id="bf5c0b8c4f555f2af2ff41bc32faeb9c991dcafa.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_34922" text="pathway" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1519-1527" id="bf5c0b8c4f555f2af2ff41bc32faeb9c991dcafa.c1.e6" ontology_id="CHEBI_25367" text="molecule" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
