<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="bfdf1cc025285b3c20fdde66f5de3be60b46930e">
  <chunk id="bfdf1cc025285b3c20fdde66f5de3be60b46930e.c0" text="Locally Produced IL-10 Limits Cutaneous Vaccinia Virus Spread">
    <entity charOffset="40-48" id="bfdf1cc025285b3c20fdde66f5de3be60b46930e.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_3298" text="Vaccinia" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="bfdf1cc025285b3c20fdde66f5de3be60b46930e.c1" text="Skin infection with the poxvirus vaccinia (VV) elicits a powerful, inflammatory cellular response that clears virus infection in a coordinated, spatially organized manner. Given the high concentration of pro-inflammatory effectors at areas of viral infection, it is unclear how tissue pathology is limited while virus-infected cells are being eliminated. To better understand the spatial dynamics of the anti-inflammatory response to a cutaneous viral infection, we first screened cytokine mRNA expression levels after epicutaneous (ec.) VV infection and found a large increase the anti-inflammatory cytokine IL-10. Ex vivo analyses revealed that T cells in the skin were the primary IL-10-producing cells. To understand the distribution of IL-10-producing T cells in vivo, we performed multiphoton intravital microscopy (MPM) of VV-infected mice, assessing the location and dynamic behavior of IL-10 producing cells. Although virus-specific T cells were distributed throughout areas of the inflamed skin lacking overt virus-infection, IL-10 + cells closely associated with large keratinocytic foci of virus replication where they exhibited similar motility patterns to bulk antigen-specific CD8 + T cells. Paradoxically, neutralizing secreted IL-10 in vivo with an anti-IL-10 antibody increased viral lesion size and viral replication. Additional analyses demonstrated that IL-10 antibody administration decreased recruitment of CCR2 + inflammatory monocytes, which were important for reducing viral burden in the infected skin. Based upon these findings, we conclude that spatially concentrated IL-10 production limits cutaneous viral replication and dissemination, likely through modulation of the innate immune repertoire at the site of viral growth.">
    <entity charOffset="33-41" id="bfdf1cc025285b3c20fdde66f5de3be60b46930e.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_3298" text="vaccinia" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="110-125" id="bfdf1cc025285b3c20fdde66f5de3be60b46930e.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_934" text="virus infection" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="490-494" id="bfdf1cc025285b3c20fdde66f5de3be60b46930e.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_33699" text="mRNA" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="bfdf1cc025285b3c20fdde66f5de3be60b46930e.c1.e0" e2="bfdf1cc025285b3c20fdde66f5de3be60b46930e.c1.e2" id="bfdf1cc025285b3c20fdde66f5de3be60b46930e.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="bfdf1cc025285b3c20fdde66f5de3be60b46930e.c1.e1" e2="bfdf1cc025285b3c20fdde66f5de3be60b46930e.c1.e2" id="bfdf1cc025285b3c20fdde66f5de3be60b46930e.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
