<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="c1a54ec890c135c78fb0c2b0b9c1b96ac2b945eb">
  <chunk id="c1a54ec890c135c78fb0c2b0b9c1b96ac2b945eb.c0" text="Oncolytic Reovirus Infection Is Facilitated by the Autophagic Machinery"/>
  <chunk id="c1a54ec890c135c78fb0c2b0b9c1b96ac2b945eb.c1" text="Mammalian reovirus is a double-stranded RNA virus that selectively infects and lyses transformed cells, making it an attractive oncolytic agent. Despite clinical evidence for anti-tumor activity, its efficacy as a stand-alone therapy remains to be improved. The success of future trials can be greatly influenced by the identification and the regulation of the cellular pathways that are important for reovirus replication and oncolysis. Here, we demonstrate that reovirus induces autophagy in several cell lines, evident from the formation of Atg5-Atg12 complexes, microtubule-associated protein 1 light chain 3 (LC3) lipidation, p62 degradation, the appearance of acidic vesicular organelles, and LC3 puncta. Furthermore, in electron microscopic images of reovirus-infected cells, autophagosomes were observed without evident association with viral factories. Using UV-inactivated reovirus, we demonstrate that a productive reovirus infection facilitates the induction of autophagy. Importantly, knock-out cell lines for specific autophagy-related genes revealed that the expression of Atg3 and Atg5 but not Atg13 facilitates reovirus replication. These findings highlight a central and Atg13-independent role for the autophagy machinery in facilitating reovirus infection and contribute to a better understanding of reovirus-host interactions. ), and were previously described in literature [18] . All MEFs were cultured in DMEM plus pen-strep and 10% FBS. The Atg3wt, Atg3−/−, and Atg3+/+ MEFs were cultured at 32 • C, and all other MEFs at 37 • C. All cell lines were maintained in a 5% CO 2 atmosphere.">
    <entity charOffset="24-43" id="c1a54ec890c135c78fb0c2b0b9c1b96ac2b945eb.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_67208" text="double-stranded RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="40-43" id="c1a54ec890c135c78fb0c2b0b9c1b96ac2b945eb.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="589-596" id="c1a54ec890c135c78fb0c2b0b9c1b96ac2b945eb.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="599-604" id="c1a54ec890c135c78fb0c2b0b9c1b96ac2b945eb.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_30212" text="light" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="727-735" id="c1a54ec890c135c78fb0c2b0b9c1b96ac2b945eb.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_10545" text="electron" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1207-1211" id="c1a54ec890c135c78fb0c2b0b9c1b96ac2b945eb.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
