<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="c49e3b42331dd3c65340f486f5b6067df16cbbd4">
  <chunk id="c49e3b42331dd3c65340f486f5b6067df16cbbd4.c0" text="Open Access E-Predict: a computational strategy for species identification based on observed DNA microarray hybridization patterns">
    <entity charOffset="5-11" id="c49e3b42331dd3c65340f486f5b6067df16cbbd4.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_34922" text="Access" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="93-96" id="c49e3b42331dd3c65340f486f5b6067df16cbbd4.c0.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="c49e3b42331dd3c65340f486f5b6067df16cbbd4.c1" text="E-Predict: microarray-based species identification &lt;p&gt;An algorithm, E-Predict, for microarray-based species identification is presented. E-Predict compares an observed hybridization pat-tern with a set of theoretical energy profiles. Each profile represents a species that may be identified.&lt;/p&gt; Abstract DNA microarrays may be used to identify microbial species present in environmental and clinical samples. However, automated tools for reliable species identification based on observed microarray hybridization patterns are lacking. We present an algorithm, E-Predict, for microarraybased species identification. E-Predict compares observed hybridization patterns with theoretical energy profiles representing different species. We demonstrate the application of the algorithm to viral detection in a set of clinical samples and discuss its relevance to other metagenomic applications. Genome Biology 2005, Volume 6, Issue 9, Article R78 Urisman et al. R78.3 comment reviews reports refereed research deposited research interactions information Genome Biology 2005, 6:R78 R78.4 Genome Biology 2005, Volume 6, Issue 9, Article R78 Urisman et al. food and water [24], and detection of agents involved in potential cases of bioterrorism [26]. http://genomebiology.com/2005/6/9/R78 Genome Biology 2005, Volume 6, Issue 9, Article R78 Urisman et al. R78.11 comment reviews reports refereed research deposited research interactions information Genome Biology 2005, 6:R78 http://genomebiology.com/2005/6/9/R78 Genome Biology 2005, Volume 6, Issue 9, Article R78 Urisman et al. R78.13 comment reviews reports refereed research deposited research interactions information Genome Biology 2005, 6:R78">
    <entity charOffset="305-308" id="c49e3b42331dd3c65340f486f5b6067df16cbbd4.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1148-1152" id="c49e3b42331dd3c65340f486f5b6067df16cbbd4.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33290" text="food" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1157-1162" id="c49e3b42331dd3c65340f486f5b6067df16cbbd4.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_15377" text="water" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
