<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="c5c2bc7a07670d6fb970d84a59aab3832752a3f1">
  <chunk id="c5c2bc7a07670d6fb970d84a59aab3832752a3f1.c0" text="Role of the ERK1/2 Signaling Pathway in the Replication of Junín and Tacaribe Viruses">
    <entity charOffset="0-4" id="c5c2bc7a07670d6fb970d84a59aab3832752a3f1.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="Role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="29-36" id="c5c2bc7a07670d6fb970d84a59aab3832752a3f1.c0.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_34922" text="Pathway" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="c5c2bc7a07670d6fb970d84a59aab3832752a3f1.c1" text="We have previously shown that the infection of cell cultures with the arenaviruses Junín (JUNV), Tacaribe (TCRV), and Pichindé promotes the phosphorylation of mitogen-activated protein kinases (MAPKs) extracellular signal-regulated kinases 1 and 2 (ERK1/2) and that this activation is required for the achievement of a productive infection. Here we examined the contribution of ERK1/2 in early steps of JUNV and TCRV multiplication. JUNV adsorption, internalization, and uncoating were not affected by treatment of cultured cells with U0126, an inhibitor of the ERK1/2 signaling pathway. In contrast, U0126 caused a marked reduction in viral protein expression and RNA synthesis, while JUNV RNA synthesis was significantly augmented in the presence of an activator of the ERK1/2 pathway. Moreover, U0126 impaired the expression of a reporter gene in a TCRV-based replicon system, confirming the ability of the compound to hinder arenavirus macromolecular synthesis. By using a cell-based assay, we determined that the inhibitor did not affect the translation of a synthetic TCRV-like mRNA. No changes in the phosphorylation pattern of the translation factor eIF2α were found in U0126-treated cells. Our results indicate that U0126 impairs viral RNA synthesis, thereby leading to a subsequent reduction in viral protein expression. Thus, we conclude that ERK1/2 signaling activation is required for an efficient arenavirus RNA synthesis.">
    <entity charOffset="177-184" id="c5c2bc7a07670d6fb970d84a59aab3832752a3f1.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="545-554" id="c5c2bc7a07670d6fb970d84a59aab3832752a3f1.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_35222" text="inhibitor" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="642-649" id="c5c2bc7a07670d6fb970d84a59aab3832752a3f1.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="665-668" id="c5c2bc7a07670d6fb970d84a59aab3832752a3f1.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="691-694" id="c5c2bc7a07670d6fb970d84a59aab3832752a3f1.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1018-1027" id="c5c2bc7a07670d6fb970d84a59aab3832752a3f1.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_35222" text="inhibitor" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1245-1248" id="c5c2bc7a07670d6fb970d84a59aab3832752a3f1.c1.e6" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1311-1318" id="c5c2bc7a07670d6fb970d84a59aab3832752a3f1.c1.e7" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1422-1425" id="c5c2bc7a07670d6fb970d84a59aab3832752a3f1.c1.e8" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
