<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="c5df32e01e9583e1b4430418e8f8f58c8a85021c">
  <chunk id="c5df32e01e9583e1b4430418e8f8f58c8a85021c.c0" text="Establishment and application of a real-time loop-mediated isothermal amplification system for the detection of CYP2C19 polymorphisms OPEN"/>
  <chunk id="c5df32e01e9583e1b4430418e8f8f58c8a85021c.c1" text="Single-nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) represent the most widespread type of genetic variation (approximately 90%) in the human genome, and the demand to overcome such variation has received more attention now than ever before. The capacity to rapidly assess SNPs that correlate with disease predisposition, drug efficacy and drug toxicity is a key step for the development of personalized medicine. In this work, a rapid one-step SNP detection method, real-time loop-mediated isothermal amplification (RT-LAMP), was first applied for CYP2C19 polymorphisms testing. The optimized method was established with specifically designed primers for target amplification by real-time detection in approximately 30 min under isothermal conditions. RT-LAMP amplified few copies of template to produce significant amounts of product and quantitatively detected human DNA with compatible specificity and sensitivity. The success in the establishment of this RT-LAMP protocol for CYP2C19 polymorphism testing is significant for the extension of this technique for the detection of other SNPs, which will further facilitate the development of personalized medicine. OPEN www.nature.com/scientificreports/ Evaluation of RT-LAMP using peripheral blood samples. To evaluate the feasibility of RT-LAMP in clinical applications, 100 peripheral blood samples were tested with Tris-EDTA buffer as the negative control. All of the samples were also further verified by conventional PCR and direct sequencing.">
    <entity charOffset="284-291" id="c5df32e01e9583e1b4430418e8f8f58c8a85021c.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="308-312" id="c5df32e01e9583e1b4430418e8f8f58c8a85021c.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_23888" text="drug" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="326-330" id="c5df32e01e9583e1b4430418e8f8f58c8a85021c.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_23888" text="drug" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="856-859" id="c5df32e01e9583e1b4430418e8f8f58c8a85021c.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1366-1372" id="c5df32e01e9583e1b4430418e8f8f58c8a85021c.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_35225" text="buffer" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="c5df32e01e9583e1b4430418e8f8f58c8a85021c.c1.e0" e2="c5df32e01e9583e1b4430418e8f8f58c8a85021c.c1.e1" id="c5df32e01e9583e1b4430418e8f8f58c8a85021c.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="c5df32e01e9583e1b4430418e8f8f58c8a85021c.c1.e0" e2="c5df32e01e9583e1b4430418e8f8f58c8a85021c.c1.e2" id="c5df32e01e9583e1b4430418e8f8f58c8a85021c.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="c5df32e01e9583e1b4430418e8f8f58c8a85021c.c1.e0" e2="c5df32e01e9583e1b4430418e8f8f58c8a85021c.c1.e3" id="c5df32e01e9583e1b4430418e8f8f58c8a85021c.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="c5df32e01e9583e1b4430418e8f8f58c8a85021c.c1.e0" e2="c5df32e01e9583e1b4430418e8f8f58c8a85021c.c1.e4" id="c5df32e01e9583e1b4430418e8f8f58c8a85021c.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
