<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="c7b980605c4ba138f35378e5f56b95e677cc87c5">
  <chunk id="c7b980605c4ba138f35378e5f56b95e677cc87c5.c0" text="Ubiquitin-specific Protease 15 Negatively Regulates Virus- induced Type I Interferon Signaling via Catalytically-dependent and -independent Mechanisms OPEN">
    <entity charOffset="74-84" id="c7b980605c4ba138f35378e5f56b95e677cc87c5.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_52999" text="Interferon" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="c7b980605c4ba138f35378e5f56b95e677cc87c5.c1" text="Although not fully characterized, these innate antiviral responses are fine-tuned by dynamic ubiquitination and deubiquitination processes. In this study, we report ubiquitin-specific protease (USP) 15 is involved in regulation of the retinoic acid-inducible gene I (RIG-I)-dependent type I IFN induction pathway. Knockdown of endogenous USP15 augmented cellular antiviral responses. Overexpression of USP15 inhibited the transcription of IFN-β. Further analyses identified histidine 862 as a critical residue for USP15's catalytic activity. Interestingly, USP15 specifically removed lysine 63-linked polyubiquitin chains from RIG-I among the essential components in RIG-I-like receptor-dependent pathway. In addition, we demonstrated that in contrast to USP15 de-ubiquitinating (DUB) activity, USP15-mediated inhibition of IFN signaling was not abolished by mutations eliminating the catalytic activity, indicating that a fraction of USP15-mediated IFN antagonism was independent of the DUB activity. Catalytically inactive USP15 mutants, as did the wild-type protein, disrupted virus-induced interaction of RIG-I and IFN-β promoter stimulator 1. Taken together, our data demonstrate that USP15 acts as a negative regulator of RIG-I signaling via DUB-dependent and independent mechanisms.">
    <entity charOffset="47-56" id="c7b980605c4ba138f35378e5f56b95e677cc87c5.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_22587" text="antiviral" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="363-372" id="c7b980605c4ba138f35378e5f56b95e677cc87c5.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_22587" text="antiviral" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="474-483" id="c7b980605c4ba138f35378e5f56b95e677cc87c5.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_15971" text="histidine" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="474-483" id="c7b980605c4ba138f35378e5f56b95e677cc87c5.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_27570" text="histidine" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="584-590" id="c7b980605c4ba138f35378e5f56b95e677cc87c5.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_18019" text="lysine" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="584-590" id="c7b980605c4ba138f35378e5f56b95e677cc87c5.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_25094" text="lysine" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
