<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="cb56f2e5caa4992c01aedc47943146ee81cac007">
  <chunk id="cb56f2e5caa4992c01aedc47943146ee81cac007.c0" text="Intrathecal Humoral Immunity to Encephalitic RNA Viruses">
    <entity charOffset="45-48" id="cb56f2e5caa4992c01aedc47943146ee81cac007.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="cb56f2e5caa4992c01aedc47943146ee81cac007.c1" text="The nervous system is the target for acute encephalitic viral infections, as well as a reservoir for persisting viruses. Intrathecal antibody (Ab) synthesis is well documented in humans afflicted by infections associated with neurological complications, as well as the demyelinating disease, multiple sclerosis. This review focuses on the origin, recruitment, maintenance, and biological relevance of Ab-secreting cells (ASC) found in the central nervous system (CNS) following experimental neurotropic RNA virus infections. We will summarize evidence for a highly dynamic, evolving humoral response characterized by temporal alterations in B cell subsets, proliferation, and differentiation. Overall local Ab plays a beneficial role via complement-independent control of virus replication, although cross or self-reactive Ab to CNS antigens may contribute to immune-mediated pathogenesis during some infections. Importantly, protective Ab exert anti-viral activity not only by direct neutralization, but also by binding to cell surface-expressed viral glycoproteins. Ab engagement of viral glycoproteins blocks budding and mediates intracellular signaling leading to restored homeostatic and innate functions. The sustained Ab production by local ASC, as well as chemokines and cytokines associated with ASC recruitment and retention, are highlighted as critical components of immune control.">
    <entity charOffset="503-506" id="cb56f2e5caa4992c01aedc47943146ee81cac007.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="729-733" id="cb56f2e5caa4992c01aedc47943146ee81cac007.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="833-841" id="cb56f2e5caa4992c01aedc47943146ee81cac007.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_59132" text="antigens" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1053-1066" id="cb56f2e5caa4992c01aedc47943146ee81cac007.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_17089" text="glycoproteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1091-1104" id="cb56f2e5caa4992c01aedc47943146ee81cac007.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_17089" text="glycoproteins" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
