<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f">
  <chunk id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c0" text="The Long Noncoding RNA NEAT1 Exerts Antihantaviral Effects by Acting as Positive Feedback for RIG-I Signaling">
    <entity charOffset="19-22" id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c1" text="Hantavirus infection, which causes zoonotic diseases with a high mortality rate in humans, has long been a global public health concern. Over the past decades, accumulating evidence suggests that long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) play key regulatory roles in innate immunity. However, the involvement of host lncRNAs in hantaviral control remains uncharacterized. In this study, we identified the lncRNA NEAT1 as a vital antiviral modulator. NEAT1 was dramatically upregulated after Hantaan virus (HTNV) infection, whereas its downregulation in vitro or in vivo delayed host innate immune responses and aggravated HTNV replication. Ectopic expression of NEAT1 enhanced beta interferon (IFN-␤) production and suppressed HTNV infection. Further investigation suggested that NEAT1 served as positive feedback for RIG-I signaling. HTNV infection activated NEAT1 transcription through the RIG-I-IRF7 pathway, whereas NEAT1 removed the transcriptional inhibitory effects of the splicing factor proline-and glutamine-rich protein (SFPQ) by relocating SFPQ to paraspeckles, thus promoting the expression of RIG-I and DDX60. RIG-I and DDX60 had synergic effects on IFN production. Taken together, our findings demonstrate that NEAT1 modulates the innate immune response against HTNV infection, providing another layer of information about the role of lncRNAs in controlling viral infections. IMPORTANCE Hantaviruses have attracted worldwide attention as archetypal emerging pathogens. Recently, increasing evidence has highlighted long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) as key regulators of innate immunity; however, their roles in hantavirus infection remain unknown. In the present work, a new unexplored function of lncRNA NEAT1 in controlling HTNV replication was found. NEAT1 promoted interferon (IFN) responses by acting as positive feedback for RIG-I signaling. This lncRNA was induced by HTNV through the RIG-I-IRF7 pathway in a time-and dose-dependent manner and promoted HTNV-induced IFN production by facilitating RIG-I and DDX60 expression. Intriguingly, NEAT1 relocated SFPQ and formed paraspeckles after HTNV infection, which might reverse inhibitive effects of SFPQ on the transcription of RIG-I and DDX60. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first study to address the regulatory role of the lncRNA NEAT1 in host innate immunity after HTNV infection. In summary, our findings provide additional insights regarding the role of lncRNAs in controlling viral infections. KEYWORDS long noncoding RNA, NEAT1, Hantaan virus, RIG-I, DDX60, beta interferon, SFPQ, interferons, innate immunity H antaviruses belong to the family Bunyaviridae and genus Hantavirus, and they have attracted worldwide attention as archetypal emerging pathogens (1). Hantaviruses contain a tripartite negative-sense single-stranded RNA (ssRNA) genome, including small (S), medium (M), and large (L) genes, which encode nucleocapsid protein (NP), F. 2017. The long noncoding RNA NEAT1 exerts antihantaviral effects by acting as positive feedback for RIG-I signaling. J Virol 91:e02250-16. Volume 91 Issue 9 e02250-16 jvi.asm.org 1 Journal of Virology">
    <entity charOffset="417-426" id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_22587" text="antiviral" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="665-669" id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_10545" text="beta" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="670-680" id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_52999" text="interferon" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="891-898" id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_34922" text="pathway" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1011-1018" id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1330-1334" id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1768-1778" id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c1.e6" ontology_id="CHEBI_52999" text="interferon" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1902-1909" id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c1.e7" ontology_id="CHEBI_34922" text="pathway" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="2280-2284" id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c1.e8" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="2418-2422" id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c1.e9" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="2491-2494" id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c1.e10" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="2532-2536" id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c1.e11" ontology_id="CHEBI_10545" text="beta" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="2537-2547" id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c1.e12" ontology_id="CHEBI_52999" text="interferon" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="2801-2804" id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c1.e13" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="2901-2908" id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c1.e14" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="2943-2946" id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c1.e15" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c2" text="FIG 1 NEAT1 expression is induced by HTNV in a time-and dose-dependent manner. (A)"/>
  <chunk id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c3" text="The design for detecting and disrupting NEAT1 transcription, as well as the paraspeckle entities, is shown schematically. (B) RNA isolated from HUVECs, which were either mock infected or treated with live or 60 Co-inactivated HTNV at an MOI of 1 for 24 h, was sequenced on an Illumina platform. More than 3.4 million reads per sample were obtained. Sequence analysis identified lncRNA NEAT1 as a significantly upregulated transcript after HTNV infection (indicated by arrows). (C) HUVECs were either mock infected or infected with HTNV or 60 Co-inactivated HTNV, followed by qRT-PCR at 6, 12, 24, or 48 h to measure NEAT1-2. Values are means Ϯ standard deviation (SD) (n ϭ 5; *, P Ͻ 0.01; **, P Ͻ 0.001; ***, P Ͻ 0.0001; Student's t test, compared with the 60 Co-inactivated HTNV group). (D) HUVECs were either mock infected or infected with HTNV or 60 Co-inactivated HTNV, followed by FISH staining and immunostaining (left). NEAT1 (red), NP (green), and nuclei stained with DAPI (blue). The NEAT1-2-positive cell percentage was calculated based on four randomized fields in each group and analyzed using the Student t test (right). Values are means Ϯ SD (n ϭ 5; *, P Ͻ 0.01; **, P Ͻ 0.001; ***, P Ͻ 0.0001; compared with the mock group). (E) The expression levels of HTNV S segment in HUVECs or HEK293, HeLa, or A549 cells by qRT-PCR at 0, 2, 6, 12, 24, 48, 72, 96, and 120 hpi (infection MOI ϭ 1, n ϭ 5; replicates shown in the following data are biological). (F) Different cell lines were infected with HTNV and followed by immunostaining at 48 hpi. NP (shown as green in HUVECs and HEK293 cells and as red in HeLa and A549 cells) and nuclei stained with DAPI (blue). (G) The propagated HTNV in different cells was acquired at 72 hpi, and viral titers were detected by TCID 50 with ELISA (n ϭ 3). (H) The expression levels of NEAT1 were assessed in HUVECs or HEK293, HeLa, or A549 cells by qRT-PCR at different infection time intervals (MOI ϭ 1, n ϭ 5). (I) The expression levels of NEAT1 were assessed in HUVECs or HEK293, HeLa, or A549 cells by qRT-PCR at different infection MOIs (72 hpi, n ϭ 5). At least three independent experiments were performed with similar results.">
    <entity charOffset="126-129" id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c3.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="956-962" id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c3.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33252" text="nuclei" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="976-980" id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c3.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_51231" text="DAPI" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1639-1645" id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c3.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_33252" text="nuclei" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1659-1663" id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c3.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_51231" text="DAPI" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c4" text="Journal of Virology"/>
  <chunk id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c5" text="MATERIALS AND METHODS"/>
  <chunk id="d18636f47e3c7dd93da309d556ba464d964fd24f.c6" text="HTNV strain 76-118 was propagated in Vero E6 cells (a green monkey kidney epithelial cell line; ATCC no. CRL-1586), and the titers were measured by ELISA as previously described (43). For infection, cells with a confluence of 70 to 80% in 6, 24, or 96 wells or 35-mm dishes were rinsed twice with Dulbecco's phosphate-buffered saline (DPBS; HyClone, Logan City, UT), followed by the addition of HTNV that had been diluted to the desired MOI. After incubation for 90 min at 37°C, the supernatant was discarded. The cells were then washed twice with DPBS, and complete medium was added. As a control, cells were incubated with culture supernatant from uninfected Vero E6 cells, which were referred to as mock-infected cells."/>
</document>
