<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="d92d00ed95878f5a37061b76e848fda5b11d21da">
  <chunk id="d92d00ed95878f5a37061b76e848fda5b11d21da.c0" text="Type I Interferon Reaction to Viral Infection in Interferon-Competent, Immortalized Cell Lines from the African Fruit Bat Eidolon helvum">
    <entity charOffset="7-17" id="d92d00ed95878f5a37061b76e848fda5b11d21da.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_52999" text="Interferon" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="30-45" id="d92d00ed95878f5a37061b76e848fda5b11d21da.c0.e1" ontology_id="DOID_934" text="Viral Infection" type="disease"/>
    <pair e1="d92d00ed95878f5a37061b76e848fda5b11d21da.c0.e0" e2="d92d00ed95878f5a37061b76e848fda5b11d21da.c0.e1" id="d92d00ed95878f5a37061b76e848fda5b11d21da.c0.p0" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="d92d00ed95878f5a37061b76e848fda5b11d21da.c1" text="Bats harbor several highly pathogenic zoonotic viruses including Rabies, Marburg, and henipaviruses, without overt clinical symptoms in the animals. It has been suspected that bats might have evolved particularly effective mechanisms to suppress viral replication. Here, we investigated interferon (IFN) response, -induction, -secretion and -signaling in epithelial-like cells of the relevant and abundant African fruit bat species, Eidolon helvum (E. helvum). Immortalized cell lines were generated; their potential to induce and react on IFN was confirmed, and biological assays were adapted to application in bat cell cultures, enabling comparison of landmark IFN properties with that of common mammalian cell lines. E. helvum cells were fully capable of reacting to viral and artificial IFN stimuli. E. helvum cells showed highest IFN mRNA induction, highly productive IFN protein secretion, and evidence of efficient IFN stimulated gene induction. In an Alphavirus infection model, O'nyong-nyong virus exhibited strong IFN induction but evaded the IFN response by translational rather than transcriptional shutoff, similar to other Alphavirus infections. These novel IFN-competent cell lines will allow comparative research on zoonotic, bat-borne viruses in order to model mechanisms of viral maintenance and emergence in bat reservoirs.">
    <entity charOffset="287-297" id="d92d00ed95878f5a37061b76e848fda5b11d21da.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_52999" text="interferon" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="839-843" id="d92d00ed95878f5a37061b76e848fda5b11d21da.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33699" text="mRNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="877-884" id="d92d00ed95878f5a37061b76e848fda5b11d21da.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
