<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="dad72c9c3422ef1c9b9149e8dd567de494d46a8a">
  <chunk id="dad72c9c3422ef1c9b9149e8dd567de494d46a8a.c0" text="Nasal Delivery of an Adenovirus-Based Vaccine Bypasses Pre-Existing Immunity to the Vaccine Carrier and Improves the Immune Response in Mice">
    <entity charOffset="92-99" id="dad72c9c3422ef1c9b9149e8dd567de494d46a8a.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_78059" text="Carrier" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="dad72c9c3422ef1c9b9149e8dd567de494d46a8a.c1" text="Pre-existing immunity to human adenovirus serotype 5 (Ad5) is common in the general population. Bypassing pre-existing immunity could maximize Ad5 vaccine efficacy. Vaccination by the intramuscular (I.M.), nasal (I.N.) or oral (P.O.) route with Ad5 expressing Ebola Zaire glycoprotein (Ad5-ZGP) fully protected naïve mice against lethal challenge with Ebola. In the presence of pre-existing immunity, only mice vaccinated I.N. survived. The frequency of IFN-c+ CD8+ T cells was reduced by 80% and by 15% in animals vaccinated by the I.M. and P.O. routes respectively. Neutralizing antibodies could not be detected in serum from either treatment group. Pre-existing immunity did not compromise the frequency of IFN-c+ CD8+ T cells (3.961% naïve vs. 3.661% pre-existing immunity, PEI) nor anti-Ebola neutralizing antibody (NAB, 40610 reciprocal dilution, both groups). The number of INF-c+ CD8+ cells detected in bronchioalveolar lavage fluid (BAL) after I.N. immunization was not compromised by pre-existing immunity to Ad5 (146614, naïve vs. 120616 SFC/million MNCs, PEI). However, pre-existing immunity reduced NAB levels in BAL by ,25% in this group. To improve the immune response after oral vaccination, the Ad5-based vaccine was PEGylated. Mice given the modified vaccine did not survive challenge and had reduced levels of IFN-c+ CD8+ T cells 10 days after administration (0.360.3% PEG vs. 1.760.5% unmodified). PEGylation did increase NAB levels 2-fold. These results provide some insight about the degree of T and B cell mediated immunity necessary for protection against Ebola virus and suggest that modification of the virus capsid can influence the type of immune response elicited by an Ad5-based vaccine.">
    <entity charOffset="272-284" id="dad72c9c3422ef1c9b9149e8dd567de494d46a8a.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_17089" text="glycoprotein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="778-781" id="dad72c9c3422ef1c9b9149e8dd567de494d46a8a.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_144613" text="PEI" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="942-945" id="dad72c9c3422ef1c9b9149e8dd567de494d46a8a.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_64198" text="BAL" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1126-1129" id="dad72c9c3422ef1c9b9149e8dd567de494d46a8a.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_64198" text="BAL" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1388-1391" id="dad72c9c3422ef1c9b9149e8dd567de494d46a8a.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_46793" text="PEG" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
