<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="dd673a8892d7431842f691147b9d4b1e6206b912">
  <chunk id="dd673a8892d7431842f691147b9d4b1e6206b912.c0" text="Utility of massive open online courses (MOOCs) concerning outbreaks of emerging and reemerging diseases [version 2; referees: 2 approved]"/>
  <chunk id="dd673a8892d7431842f691147b9d4b1e6206b912.c1" text="The emergence and re-emergence of infectious diseases such as Ebola, chikungunya, and Zika increase the necessity of knowledgeable and skilled health professionals. Massive open online courses (MOOCs) arise as opportunities that allow people around the world to participate in higher education courses. A search was conducted on specialized MOOC platforms to find courses related to outbreaks, using terms included in the list of the WHO disease outbreaks from January 1st to December 31 , 2016. We found seven courses about Ebola, two about Zika, three about the dynamics of epidemics and pandemics, and only one course about dengue, chikungunya, and malaria. Most of the courses were conducted in English. The courses on Ebola, Zika and chikungunya were released after their last outbreak. MOOCs could be used to learn about health issues of global relevance, and with the necessity of fast divulgation of knowledge and skills. Translating the courses into more languages could give these courses more traction, and allow participation of professionals in regions affected by these outbreaks. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text | Free Full Text 2. Weaver SC, Lecuit M: Chikungunya virus and the global spread of a mosquitoborne disease. N Engl J Med. 2015; 372(13): 1231-9. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 3. Gulland A: Zika virus is a global public health emergency, declares WHO. BMJ. 2016; 352: i657. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 4. Lupiáñez-Villanueva F, Mayer MA, Torrent J: Opportunities and challenges of Web 2.0 within the health care systems: an empirical exploration. Inform Health Soc Care. 2009; 34(3): 117-26. PubMed Abstract | Publisher Full Text 5. Hew KF: Promoting engagement in online courses: What strategies can we learn from three highly rated MOOCS. Br J Educ Technol. 2016; 47(2): 320-41. Publisher Full Text 6. Bendezu-Quispe G, Torres-Roman JS, Salinas-Ochoa B, et al.: Dataset 1 in: Utility of massive open online courses (MOOCs) concerning outbreaks of emerging and reemerging diseases. F1000Research. 2017. Data Source">
    <entity charOffset="69-80" id="dd673a8892d7431842f691147b9d4b1e6206b912.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_0050012" text="chikungunya" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="438-445" id="dd673a8892d7431842f691147b9d4b1e6206b912.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="635-646" id="dd673a8892d7431842f691147b9d4b1e6206b912.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_0050012" text="chikungunya" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="739-750" id="dd673a8892d7431842f691147b9d4b1e6206b912.c1.e3" ontology_id="DOID_0050012" text="chikungunya" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1174-1185" id="dd673a8892d7431842f691147b9d4b1e6206b912.c1.e4" ontology_id="DOID_0050012" text="Chikungunya" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1233-1240" id="dd673a8892d7431842f691147b9d4b1e6206b912.c1.e5" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
