<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="e50473adb66bac4a176d80051d63f415d2dbd5a8">
  <chunk id="e50473adb66bac4a176d80051d63f415d2dbd5a8.c0" text="Integrin b3 Is Required in Infection and Proliferation of Classical Swine Fever Virus"/>
  <chunk id="e50473adb66bac4a176d80051d63f415d2dbd5a8.c1" text="Classical Swine Fever (CSF) is a highly infectious fatal pig disease, resulting in huge economic loss to the swine industry. Integrins are membrane-bound signal mediators, expressed on a variety of cell surfaces and are known as receptors or coreceptors for many viruses. However, the role of integrin b3 in CSFV infection is unknown. Here, through quantitive PCR, immunofluorescence (IFC) and immunocytohistochemistry (ICC), we revealed that ST (swine testicles epithelial) cells have a prominent advantage in CSFV proliferation as compared to EC (swine umbilical vein endothelial cell), IEC (swine intestinal epithelial cell) and PK (porcine kidney epithelial) cells. Meanwhile, ST cells had remarkably more integrin b3 expression as compared to EC, IEC and PK cells, which was positively correlated with CSFV infection and proliferation. Integrin b3 was upregulated post CSFV infection in all the four cell lines, while the CSFV proliferation rate was decreased in integrin b3 function-blocked cells. ShRNA1755 dramatically decreased integrin b3, with a deficiency of 96% at the mRNA level and 80% at the protein level. CSFV proliferation was dramatically reduced in integrin b3 constantly-defected cells (ICDC), with the deficiencies of 92.6%, 99% and 81.7% at 24 h, 48 h and 72 h post CSFV infection, respectively. These results demonstrate that integrin b3 is required in CSFV infection and proliferation, which provide a new insight into the mechanism of CSFV infection.">
    <entity charOffset="285-289" id="e50473adb66bac4a176d80051d63f415d2dbd5a8.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="385-388" id="e50473adb66bac4a176d80051d63f415d2dbd5a8.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_82035" text="IFC" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1082-1086" id="e50473adb66bac4a176d80051d63f415d2dbd5a8.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_33699" text="mRNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1108-1115" id="e50473adb66bac4a176d80051d63f415d2dbd5a8.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
