<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="e5a10a7f2c9bb07f74fcce076a62f63f859cf3a4">
  <chunk id="e5a10a7f2c9bb07f74fcce076a62f63f859cf3a4.c0" text="Resource-Limited Settings"/>
  <chunk id="e5a10a7f2c9bb07f74fcce076a62f63f859cf3a4.c1" text="Critical care is an important component of health care systems around the world (Figure 1) . Caring for critically ill patients in resource-rich settings typically involves treatment in intensive care units (ICUs) staffed with highly specialized health care professionals, systematic monitoring and use of high-cost technology [1]. Unfortunately, these components are not always available in resource-limited settings [2, 3], where the burden of disease is greater [4], outcomes are poorer [5, 6], and local characteristics require context-specific approaches to the organization of critical care services.">
    <entity charOffset="446-453" id="e5a10a7f2c9bb07f74fcce076a62f63f859cf3a4.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="e5a10a7f2c9bb07f74fcce076a62f63f859cf3a4.c2" text="Critical care delivery, education, and research require a global perspective based on epidemiologic considerations. The burden of critical illness in resource-limited settings is not well described, but the best available estimates suggest that it may be greater than in resource-rich settings [7, 8] due to deficiencies in access to health care, emergency triage, and lack of early recognition [9][10][11]. Mortality for adults with sepsis [5, 12, 13] and acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) [14] [15] [16] in resource-limited settings is higher than in resource-rich settings, and decedents are usually young (mean age 35 years vs. 61 years in United States) [12, 17] , which contributes to a greater negative downstream social and economic impact. Similarly, there is a higher burden of sepsis and respiratory infection mortality among children [18] [19] [20] [21] . Recent epidemiological changes in global health have created a ' double burden of disease' to resource-limited settings [9, 22] due to an increase in the prevalence of non-communicable diseases combined with lack of improvement in the long-recognized higher burden of communicable diseases, maternal and child mortality, malnutrition, and human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)-related complications.">
    <entity charOffset="484-492" id="e5a10a7f2c9bb07f74fcce076a62f63f859cf3a4.c2.e0" ontology_id="DOID_225" text="syndrome" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="494-498" id="e5a10a7f2c9bb07f74fcce076a62f63f859cf3a4.c2.e1" ontology_id="DOID_11394" text="ARDS" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="e5a10a7f2c9bb07f74fcce076a62f63f859cf3a4.c3" text="Health care professionals from resource-rich and resource-limited settings should take a global perspective on critical care for both ethical and practical reasons. Ethically, health care professionals, trainees, professional societies, non-governmental organizations (NGOs), and international organizations from resource-rich settings have the capacity of deploying resources to improve outcomes for critically ill patients in resource-limited settings [11, 23, 24] . Assistance can include financial help, knowledge exchange in the form of research and educational partnerships, and capacity building in operations and implementation science. From a practical point of view, supporting resource-limited settings is also important given that inter-related economies, Caring for critically ill patients is challenging in resource-limited settings, where the burden of disease and mortality from potentially treatable illnesses is higher than in resource-rich areas. Barriers to delivering quality critical care in these settings include lack of epidemiologic data and context-specific evidence for medical decision-making, deficiencies in health systems organization and resources, and institutional obstacles to implementation of life-saving interventions. Potential solutions include the development of common definitions for intensive care unit (ICU), intensivist, and intensive care to create a universal ICU organization framework; development of educational programs for capacity building of health care professionals working in resource-limited settings; global prioritization of epidemiologic and clinical research in resource-limited settings to conduct timely and ethical studies in response to emerging threats; adaptation of international guidelines to promote implementation of evidence-based care; and strengthening of health systems that integrates these interventions. This manuscript reviews the field of global critical care, barriers to safe high-quality care, and potential solutions to existing challenges. We also suggest a roadmap for improving the treatment of critically ill patients in resource-limited settings.">
    <entity charOffset="868-875" id="e5a10a7f2c9bb07f74fcce076a62f63f859cf3a4.c3.e0" ontology_id="DOID_4" text="disease" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
