<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da">
  <chunk id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c0" text="Selection of reference genes for expression analysis using RT-qPCR in the dissemination system of Heliothis virescens ascovirus 3 h (HvAV-3h) OPEN"/>
  <chunk id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c1" text="Ascoviruses are double-stranded DNA viruses that mainly infect noctuid larvae, and are transmitted by the parasitoid wasp Microplitis similis Lyle. Ascovirus-parasitoids wasp-noctuid insects constitute the dissemination system. Selection of suitable reference genes for the dissemination system could play an important role in elucidating the pathogenic molecular mechanisms of ascovirus. Unfortunately, such studies on potential reference genes in the dissemination system of ascoviruses are lacking. In the present study, we evaluated 11 candidate reference genes: β-actin1 (ACT1), β-actin2 (ACT2), elongation factor 1 (EF1), elongation factor 2 (EF2), ribosomal protein L10 (L10), ribosomal protein L17A (L17A), superoxide dismutase (SOD), 28S ribosome (28S), Tubulin (TUB) and 18S ribosome (18S). The samples were originally from various virus concentrations and points-in-time of experimental treatments using RefFinder and four algorithms. The results showed that EF1 was the most stable internal gene in S. exigua and M. similis and that EF2 was the most stable in the IOZCAS-Spex-II-A cell line, and the stability of reference genes were confirmed via the expression levels of two inhibitor of apoptosis-like (iap-like) genes from Heliothis virescens ascovirus 3 h (HvAV-3h). This study provides a crucial basis for future research that explores the molecular mechanisms of the pathogenesis of ascoviruses.">
    <entity charOffset="16-35" id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_4705" text="double-stranded DNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="32-35" id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="319-323" id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="665-672" id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="694-701" id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="715-725" id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_18421" text="superoxide" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1189-1198" id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c1.e6" ontology_id="CHEBI_35222" text="inhibitor" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2" text="Ascoviruses (Ascoviridae) are circular double-stranded DNA viruses of insects that attack the most common lepidopteran species of the Noctuidae, Crambidae and Plutellidae families 1-3 . Heliothis virescens ascovirus 3h genome length is 190, 519 bp and is a strain of the species Heliothis virescens ascovirus 3a 4, 5 . HvAV-3h has strong pathogenicity to S. exigua, Spodoptera litura and Helicoverpa armigera 6-8 . However, ascoviruses must be transmitted by parasitoid wasps in the field. A potential application value of ascoviruses for bio-control was predicted because of the dissemination system and acute pathogenic features of ascoviruses, which was different from other insect viruses, e.g., nucleopolyhedrovirus (NPV). Research on the pathogenic molecular mechanisms is relatively deficient for ascoviruses, and research on implementing a stabile reference gene for ascoviruses has not been performed. RT-qPCR is usually used in research on pathogenic molecular mechanisms. To achieve RNA quantitation and data normalization with different samples, we selected an optimal reference gene to correct the reliability and accuracy of quantitative results. Due to its simple operation, high sensitivity, low pollution and good repeatability, RT-qPCR is widely used in basic science research 9 . However, diverse samples have different RNA efficiencies of extraction, RNA quality, and reverse transcription efficiency of the product 10 . Therefore, it is important to ensure a high quality of RNA in RT-qPCR 11 . Generally, housekeeping genes are considered to be relatively stable expressed in all cell types and physiological states 12 . However, some studies have indicated that the expression quantity of housekeeping genes in different cell types, tissues, experimental conditions and under different physiological states is inconsistent 13, 14 . For example, ACT was unsuitable as a reference gene when human cell lines were infected by cytomegalovirus, human herpesvirus-6, camelpox virus, SARS coronavirus or yellow">
    <entity charOffset="39-58" id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_4705" text="double-stranded DNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="55-58" id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="994-997" id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1339-1342" id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1371-1374" id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1496-1499" id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="2000-2004" id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.e6" ontology_id="DOID_2945" text="SARS" type="disease"/>
    <pair e1="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.e0" e2="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.e6" id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.e1" e2="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.e6" id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.e2" e2="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.e6" id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.e3" e2="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.e6" id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.e4" e2="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.e6" id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.e5" e2="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.e6" id="e8be80485fdee7344e970941c62ca23fb3eed4da.c2.p5" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
