<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="f2f841111913d49cbbd17e0988fc4f49b06c4945">
  <chunk id="f2f841111913d49cbbd17e0988fc4f49b06c4945.c0" text="Modeling [ 18 F]-FDG lymphoid tissue kinetics to characterize nonhuman primate immune response to Middle East respiratory syndrome-coronavirus aerosol challenge"/>
  <chunk id="f2f841111913d49cbbd17e0988fc4f49b06c4945.c1" text="Background: The pathogenesis and immune response to Middle East respiratory syndrome (MERS) caused by a recently discovered coronavirus, MERS-CoV, have not been fully characterized because a suitable animal model is currently not available. 18 F-Fluorodeoxyglucose ([ 18 F]-FDG)-positron emission tomography/computed tomography (PET/CT) as a longitudinal noninvasive approach can be beneficial in providing biomarkers for host immune response.">
    <entity charOffset="52-84" id="f2f841111913d49cbbd17e0988fc4f49b06c4945.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_0080642" text="Middle East respiratory syndrome" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="76-84" id="f2f841111913d49cbbd17e0988fc4f49b06c4945.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_225" text="syndrome" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="f2f841111913d49cbbd17e0988fc4f49b06c4945.c2" text="[ 18 F]-FDG uptake is increased in activated immune cells in response to virus entry and can be localized by PET imaging. We used [ 18 F]-FDG-PET/CT to investigate the host response developing in nonhuman primates after MERS-CoV exposure and applied kinetic modeling to monitor the influx rate constant (K i ) in responsive lymphoid tissue. Methods: Multiple [ 18 F]-FDG-PET and CT images were acquired on a PET/CT clinical scanner modified to operate in a biosafety level 4 environment prior to and up to 29 days after MERS-CoV aerosol exposure. Time activity curves of various lymphoid tissues were reconstructed to follow the [ 18 F]-FDG uptake for approximately 60 min (3,600 s). Image-derived input function was used to calculate K i for lymphoid tissues by Patlak plot. Results: Two-way repeated measures analysis of variance revealed alterations in K i that was associated with the time point (p &lt; 0.001) after virus exposure and the location of lymphoid tissue (p = 0.0004). As revealed by a statistically significant interaction (p &lt; 0.0001) between these two factors, the pattern of K i changes over time differed between three locations but not between subjects. A distinguished pattern of statistically significant elevation in K i was observed in mediastinal lymph nodes (LNs) that correlated to K i changes in axillary LNs. Changes in LNs K i were concurrent with elevations of monocytes in peripheral blood. Conclusions: [ 18 F]-FDG-PET is able to detect subtle changes in host immune response to contain a subclinical virus infection. Full quantitative analysis is the preferred approach rather than semiquantitative analysis using standardized uptake value for detection of the immune response to the virus.">
    <entity charOffset="109-112" id="f2f841111913d49cbbd17e0988fc4f49b06c4945.c2.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_131701" text="PET" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="408-411" id="f2f841111913d49cbbd17e0988fc4f49b06c4945.c2.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_131701" text="PET" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1285-1288" id="f2f841111913d49cbbd17e0988fc4f49b06c4945.c2.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_137262" text="LNs" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1333-1336" id="f2f841111913d49cbbd17e0988fc4f49b06c4945.c2.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_137262" text="LNs" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1349-1352" id="f2f841111913d49cbbd17e0988fc4f49b06c4945.c2.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_137262" text="LNs" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
