<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="f5ff89ebfdd0375d034c112c6c1c7e163fa69a0c">
  <chunk id="f5ff89ebfdd0375d034c112c6c1c7e163fa69a0c.c0" text="Etiology of Influenza-Like Illnesses from Sentinel Network Practitioners in Réunion Island, 2011-2012"/>
  <chunk id="f5ff89ebfdd0375d034c112c6c1c7e163fa69a0c.c1" text="In Ré union Island, despite an influenza surveillance established since 1996 by the sentinel general practitioner's network, little is known about the etiology of Influenza like-illness (ILI) that differs from influenza viruses in a tropical area. We set up a retrospective study using nasal swabs collected by sentinel GPs from ILI patients in 2011 and 2012. A total of 250 swabs were randomly selected and analyzed by multiplex reverse transcriptase polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) including research of 18 viruses and 4 bacteria. We detected respiratory viruses in 169/222 (76.1%) samples, mostly rhinovirus (23.4%), influenza A virus (21.2%), influenza B virus (12.6%), coronavirus (4.9%) and Human metapneumovirus (3.6%). Nine swabs (5.3% of positive swabs) revealed co-infections with two viruses identified, among which six concerned co-infections with influenza viruses. We observed important seasonal differences, with circulation of Human Metapneumoviruses, RSV A and B and coronavirus only during summer; whereas parainfluenza viruses were identified only during winter. In conclusion, this study highlights a substantial circulation of multiple respiratory pathogens in Ré union Island throughout the year. It shows that ILI are not only attributable to influenza and underlines the need for biological surveillance. As the use of multiplex RT-PCR showed its efficacy, it is now used routinely in the surveillance of ILI.">
    <entity charOffset="31-40" id="f5ff89ebfdd0375d034c112c6c1c7e163fa69a0c.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="163-172" id="f5ff89ebfdd0375d034c112c6c1c7e163fa69a0c.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="Influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="210-219" id="f5ff89ebfdd0375d034c112c6c1c7e163fa69a0c.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="320-323" id="f5ff89ebfdd0375d034c112c6c1c7e163fa69a0c.c1.e3" ontology_id="DOID_0111044" text="GPs" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="623-632" id="f5ff89ebfdd0375d034c112c6c1c7e163fa69a0c.c1.e4" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="650-659" id="f5ff89ebfdd0375d034c112c6c1c7e163fa69a0c.c1.e5" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="863-872" id="f5ff89ebfdd0375d034c112c6c1c7e163fa69a0c.c1.e6" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1269-1278" id="f5ff89ebfdd0375d034c112c6c1c7e163fa69a0c.c1.e7" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
