<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="f6d2afb2ec44d8656972ea79f8a833143bbeb42b">
  <chunk id="f6d2afb2ec44d8656972ea79f8a833143bbeb42b.c0" text="Virus-Vectored Influenza Virus Vaccines">
    <entity charOffset="15-24" id="f6d2afb2ec44d8656972ea79f8a833143bbeb42b.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="Influenza" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="f6d2afb2ec44d8656972ea79f8a833143bbeb42b.c1" text="Despite the availability of an inactivated vaccine that has been licensed for &gt;50 years, the influenza virus continues to cause morbidity and mortality worldwide. Constant evolution of circulating influenza virus strains and the emergence of new strains diminishes the effectiveness of annual vaccines that rely on a match with circulating influenza strains. Thus, there is a continued need for new, efficacious vaccines conferring cross-clade protection to avoid the need for biannual reformulation of seasonal influenza vaccines. Recombinant virus-vectored vaccines are an appealing alternative to classical inactivated vaccines because virus vectors enable native expression of influenza antigens, even from virulent influenza viruses, while expressed in the context of the vector that can improve immunogenicity. In addition, a vectored vaccine often enables delivery of the vaccine to sites of inductive immunity such as the respiratory tract enabling protection from influenza virus infection. Moreover, the ability to readily manipulate virus vectors to produce novel influenza vaccines may provide the quickest path toward a universal vaccine protecting against all influenza viruses. This review will discuss experimental virus-vectored vaccines for use in humans, comparing them to licensed vaccines and the hurdles faced for licensure of these next-generation influenza virus vaccines.">
    <entity charOffset="93-102" id="f6d2afb2ec44d8656972ea79f8a833143bbeb42b.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="197-206" id="f6d2afb2ec44d8656972ea79f8a833143bbeb42b.c1.e1" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="340-349" id="f6d2afb2ec44d8656972ea79f8a833143bbeb42b.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="512-521" id="f6d2afb2ec44d8656972ea79f8a833143bbeb42b.c1.e3" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="681-690" id="f6d2afb2ec44d8656972ea79f8a833143bbeb42b.c1.e4" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="720-729" id="f6d2afb2ec44d8656972ea79f8a833143bbeb42b.c1.e5" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="973-982" id="f6d2afb2ec44d8656972ea79f8a833143bbeb42b.c1.e6" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1075-1084" id="f6d2afb2ec44d8656972ea79f8a833143bbeb42b.c1.e7" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1174-1183" id="f6d2afb2ec44d8656972ea79f8a833143bbeb42b.c1.e8" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1371-1380" id="f6d2afb2ec44d8656972ea79f8a833143bbeb42b.c1.e9" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
