<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="f7f482ba4aaa3ef0d620d9aad8c9635f88806d8e">
  <chunk id="f7f482ba4aaa3ef0d620d9aad8c9635f88806d8e.c0" text="The autophagy elongation complex (ATG5-12/16L1) positively regulates HCV replication and is required for wild-type membranous web formation OPEN"/>
  <chunk id="f7f482ba4aaa3ef0d620d9aad8c9635f88806d8e.c1" text="The autophagy machinery has been proposed to participate in the formation of such vesicles. However, no clear evidence has been found linking autophagy to the formation of these DMVs. In this study, we evaluated the role of the autophagy elongation complex (ATG5-12/16L1) in HCV replication and MW formation. Using a dominant negative form of ATG12 and an siRNA approach, we demonstrated that the ATG5-12 conjugate, but not LC3-II formation, is crucial for efficient viral replication. Furthermore, purification of HCV MW revealed the presence of ATG5-12 and ATG16L1 along with HCV nonstructural proteins. Interestingly, LC3 was not recruited along with the elongation complex to the site of viral replication. Finally, inhibition of the elongation complex, but not LC3, greatly impaired the formation of the wildtype MW phenotype. To our knowledge, this study provides the first evidence of the involvement of autophagy proteins in the formation of wild-type MWs.">
    <entity charOffset="216-220" id="f7f482ba4aaa3ef0d620d9aad8c9635f88806d8e.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="596-604" id="f7f482ba4aaa3ef0d620d9aad8c9635f88806d8e.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="921-929" id="f7f482ba4aaa3ef0d620d9aad8c9635f88806d8e.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="f7f482ba4aaa3ef0d620d9aad8c9635f88806d8e.c2" text="During the early steps of autophagosome biogenesis, ATG5, ATG12, and ATG16L1 form a stoichiometric complex known as the autophagy elongation complex (ATG5-12/16L1). The elongation complex has been shown to determine the site of LC3 lipidation 11 , a process required for the association of LC3 with the autophagosomal membrane. The membrane-associated LC3 allows the completion of autophagosome formation 12 ."/>
  <chunk id="f7f482ba4aaa3ef0d620d9aad8c9635f88806d8e.c3" text="Although autophagy can act as an anti-viral mechanism, many reports have shown that positive-strand RNA viruses, including HCV, can hijack the autophagy machinery for virion morphogenesis and viral replication [13] [14] [15] [16] [17] . Several studies have shown that HCV induces autophagosome formation in vitro 9,18-21 . This finding has also been confirmed in liver biopsies obtained from patients chronically infected with HCV 22 . In addition, HCV infection has been shown to induce mitophagy, the selective removal of mitochondria, through the induction of phosphatase and tensin homolog (PTEN)-induced putative kinase 1 (PINK1) and Parkin on the outer surface of the mitochondria. It has been proposed that degradation of mitochondria enhances HCV replication and suppresses cellular apoptosis 23 . Although several studies have shown that HCV infection induces autophagy by ER-stress via induction of the unfolded protein response (UPR) 20,24-27 , other studies have shown that HCV induces autophagy in a manner independent of ER-stress, through the direct interaction of viral proteins with autophagy proteins 28, 29 . Moreover, HCV-induced autophagy has been found to play a crucial role in evading host microbial defense mechanisms at the level of innate and adaptive immune responses 30 . The induction of autophagy promotes HCV replication either by enhancing protein translation 31 or via viral maturation 32 . Owing to the morphological similarities between HCV-induced DMVs and the double-membrane nature of autophagosomes, it has been proposed that autophagy plays a role in the biogenesis of viral replication compartments 7 . Importantly, Atg5 induces the formation of DMVs in embryonic stem cells 33 . In addition, a previous study conducted by our lab has shown that ATG5 interacts with the viral polymerase (NS5B) and co-localizes with NS4B, a MW-associated viral protein 34 . Another group has shown that ATG12, Beclin 1, and ATG4B are required for the establishment of viral replication 31 . However, studies on the involvement of autophagy proteins in the assembly of the MW remain elusive. In this study, we investigated the putative role of the ATG5-12/16L1 complex in the HCV replication-cycle. We found that the autophagy elongation complex (ATG5-12/16L1) is recruited at the MW, where it promotes HCV replication in an LC3-independent manner. Surprisingly, knock-down of one component of the elongation complex, ATG12, led to an aberrant MW phenotype, thus suggesting a novel role of autophagy proteins in the formation of the MW.">
    <entity charOffset="100-103" id="f7f482ba4aaa3ef0d620d9aad8c9635f88806d8e.c3.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="923-930" id="f7f482ba4aaa3ef0d620d9aad8c9635f88806d8e.c3.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1087-1095" id="f7f482ba4aaa3ef0d620d9aad8c9635f88806d8e.c3.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1111-1119" id="f7f482ba4aaa3ef0d620d9aad8c9635f88806d8e.c3.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1194-1198" id="f7f482ba4aaa3ef0d620d9aad8c9635f88806d8e.c3.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1374-1381" id="f7f482ba4aaa3ef0d620d9aad8c9635f88806d8e.c3.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1585-1589" id="f7f482ba4aaa3ef0d620d9aad8c9635f88806d8e.c3.e6" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1887-1894" id="f7f482ba4aaa3ef0d620d9aad8c9635f88806d8e.c3.e7" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="2066-2074" id="f7f482ba4aaa3ef0d620d9aad8c9635f88806d8e.c3.e8" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="2161-2165" id="f7f482ba4aaa3ef0d620d9aad8c9635f88806d8e.c3.e9" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="2507-2511" id="f7f482ba4aaa3ef0d620d9aad8c9635f88806d8e.c3.e10" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="2525-2533" id="f7f482ba4aaa3ef0d620d9aad8c9635f88806d8e.c3.e11" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
