<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="fae8f01ff5ef7b1737b60dfba0e183bdf482aaba">
  <chunk id="fae8f01ff5ef7b1737b60dfba0e183bdf482aaba.c0" text="Species-specific vulnerability of RanBP2 shaped the evolution of SIV as it transmitted in African apes"/>
  <chunk id="fae8f01ff5ef7b1737b60dfba0e183bdf482aaba.c1" text="HIV-1 arose as the result of spillover of simian immunodeficiency viruses (SIVs) from great apes in Africa, namely from chimpanzees and gorillas. Chimpanzees and gorillas were, themselves, infected with SIV after virus spillover from African monkeys. During spillover events, SIV is thought to require adaptation to the new host species. The host barriers that drive viral adaptation have predominantly been attributed to restriction factors, rather than cofactors (host proteins exploited to promote viral replication). Here, we consider the role of one cofactor, RanBP2, in providing a barrier that drove viral genome evolution during SIV spillover events. RanBP2 (also known as Nup358) is a component of the nuclear pore complex known to facilitate nuclear entry of HIV-1. Our data suggest that transmission of SIV from monkeys to chimpanzees, and then from chimpanzees to gorillas, both coincided with changes in the viral capsid that allowed interaction with RanBP2 of the new host species. However, human RanBP2 subsequently provided no barrier to the zoonotic transmission of SIV from chimpanzees or gorillas, indicating that chimpanzee-and gorilla-adapted SIVs are pre-adapted to humans in this regard. Our observations are in agreement with RanBP2 driving virus evolution during cross-species transmissions of SIV, particularly in the transmissions to and between great ape species.">
    <entity charOffset="455-464" id="fae8f01ff5ef7b1737b60dfba0e183bdf482aaba.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_23357" text="cofactors" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="471-479" id="fae8f01ff5ef7b1737b60dfba0e183bdf482aaba.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="543-547" id="fae8f01ff5ef7b1737b60dfba0e183bdf482aaba.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_50906" text="role" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="fae8f01ff5ef7b1737b60dfba0e183bdf482aaba.c2" text="Multiple times, HIV-1 has entered the human population after emerging from a viral reservoir that exists in African primates. First, simian immunodeficiency virus (SIV) made the jump from monkeys into African great apes, and then from apes (namely, chimpanzees and gorillas) into humans. It is well appreciated that restriction factors, which are specialized proteins of the innate immune system, acted as host-specific barriers that drove virus adaptation during these spillover events. Here, we present data showing that a major constituent of the nuclear pore complex, RanBP2, was also a barrier to the spillover of SIVs, particularly in great ape species. Spillover of SIV into chimpanzee and gorilla PLOS Pathogens | https://doi.populations required that the SIV capsid mutate to establish interaction with RanBP2 in the new host species. Our study highlights how essential housekeeping proteins, despite being generally more evolutionarily conserved than restriction factors, can also drive virus evolution during spillover events. Fig 4. Cyclophilin-binding loops from gorilla-derived viruses interact with gorilla RanCyp. Cell lines stably expressing TRIM-RanCyp (as indicated across the bottom) were infected with HIV-1 bearing the indicated cyclophilin-binding loop (top) and a GFP reporter. The percentage of cells infected in each sample was normalized to the empty vector control. Infections were performed in triplicate and error bars represent twice the standard error of the mean.">
    <entity charOffset="359-367" id="fae8f01ff5ef7b1737b60dfba0e183bdf482aaba.c2.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="892-900" id="fae8f01ff5ef7b1737b60dfba0e183bdf482aaba.c2.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_36080" text="proteins" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
