<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="fbaaee7a5ac9ab3324e82bc7b8706edc5bd1524e">
  <chunk id="fbaaee7a5ac9ab3324e82bc7b8706edc5bd1524e.c0" text="Immunization by Replication-Competent Controlled Herpesvirus Vectors"/>
  <chunk id="fbaaee7a5ac9ab3324e82bc7b8706edc5bd1524e.c1" text="Replication-competent controlled virus vectors were derived from the virulent herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1) wild-type strain 17synϩ by placing one or two replication-essential genes under the stringent control of a gene switch that is coactivated by heat and an antiprogestin. Upon activation of the gene switch, the vectors replicate in infected cells with an efficacy that approaches that of the wildtype virus from which they were derived. Essentially no replication occurs in the absence of activation. When administered to mice, localized application of a transient heat treatment in the presence of systemic antiprogestin results in efficient but limited virus replication at the site of administration. The immunogenicity of these viral vectors was tested in a mouse footpad lethal challenge model. Unactivated viral vectors-which may be regarded as equivalents of inactivated vaccines-induced detectable protection against lethality caused by wild-type virus challenge. Single activation of the viral vectors at the site of administration (rear footpads) greatly enhanced protective immune responses, and a second immunization resulted in complete protection. Once activated, vectors also induced far better neutralizing antibody and HSV-1-specific cellular immune responses than unactivated vectors. To find out whether the immunogenicity of a heterologous antigen was also enhanced in the context of efficient transient vector replication, a virus vector constitutively expressing an equine influenza virus hemagglutinin was constructed. Immunization of mice with this recombinant induced detectable antibody-mediated neutralization of equine influenza virus, as well as a hemagglutinin-specific cellular immune response. Single activation of viral replication resulted in a severalfold enhancement of these immune responses.">
    <entity charOffset="78-92" id="fbaaee7a5ac9ab3324e82bc7b8706edc5bd1524e.c1.e0" ontology_id="DOID_8566" text="herpes simplex" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1367-1374" id="fbaaee7a5ac9ab3324e82bc7b8706edc5bd1524e.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_59132" text="antigen" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1502-1511" id="fbaaee7a5ac9ab3324e82bc7b8706edc5bd1524e.c1.e2" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <entity charOffset="1654-1663" id="fbaaee7a5ac9ab3324e82bc7b8706edc5bd1524e.c1.e3" ontology_id="DOID_8469" text="influenza" type="disease"/>
    <pair e1="fbaaee7a5ac9ab3324e82bc7b8706edc5bd1524e.c1.e0" e2="fbaaee7a5ac9ab3324e82bc7b8706edc5bd1524e.c1.e1" id="fbaaee7a5ac9ab3324e82bc7b8706edc5bd1524e.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="fbaaee7a5ac9ab3324e82bc7b8706edc5bd1524e.c1.e1" e2="fbaaee7a5ac9ab3324e82bc7b8706edc5bd1524e.c1.e2" id="fbaaee7a5ac9ab3324e82bc7b8706edc5bd1524e.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="fbaaee7a5ac9ab3324e82bc7b8706edc5bd1524e.c1.e1" e2="fbaaee7a5ac9ab3324e82bc7b8706edc5bd1524e.c1.e3" id="fbaaee7a5ac9ab3324e82bc7b8706edc5bd1524e.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
