<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="fbb13d5bcfe0597fc854533fa1637fd4c415bb5a">
  <chunk id="fbb13d5bcfe0597fc854533fa1637fd4c415bb5a.c0" text="A Recombinant Avian Infectious Bronchitis Virus Expressing a Heterologous Spike Gene Belonging to the 4/91 Serotype">
    <entity charOffset="31-41" id="fbb13d5bcfe0597fc854533fa1637fd4c415bb5a.c0.e0" ontology_id="DOID_6132" text="Bronchitis" type="disease"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="fbb13d5bcfe0597fc854533fa1637fd4c415bb5a.c1" text="We have shown previously that replacement of the spike (S) gene of the apathogenic IBV strain Beau-R with that from the pathogenic strain of the same serotype, M41, resulted in an apathogenic virus, BeauR-M41(S), that conferred protection against challenge with M41 [1]. We have constructed a recombinant IBV, BeauR-4/91(S), with the genetic backbone of Beau-R but expressing the spike protein of the pathogenic IBV strain 4/91(UK), which belongs to a different serogroup as Beaudette or M41. Similar to our previous findings with BeauR-M41(S), clinical signs observations showed that the S gene of the pathogenic 4/91 virus did not confer pathogenicity to the rIBV BeauR-4/91(S). Furthermore, protection studies showed there was homologous protection; BeauR-4/91(S) conferred protection against challenge with wild type 4/91 virus as shown by the absence of clinical signs, IBV RNA assessed by qRT-PCR and the fact that no virus was isolated from tracheas removed from birds primarily infected with BeauR-4/91(S) and challenged with IBV 4/91(UK). A degree of heterologous protection against M41 challenge was observed, albeit at a lower level. Our results confirm and extend our previous findings and conclusions that swapping of the ectodomain of the S protein is a precise and effective way of generating genetically defined candidate IBV vaccines.">
    <entity charOffset="386-393" id="fbb13d5bcfe0597fc854533fa1637fd4c415bb5a.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="879-882" id="fbb13d5bcfe0597fc854533fa1637fd4c415bb5a.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33697" text="RNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1255-1262" id="fbb13d5bcfe0597fc854533fa1637fd4c415bb5a.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_16541" text="protein" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
