<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="ff77d5ebc39274bb7729f2b5261bca574bdfd6a8">
  <chunk id="ff77d5ebc39274bb7729f2b5261bca574bdfd6a8.c0" text="Prevalence and Genetic Diversity Analysis of Human Coronavirus OC43 among Adult Patients with Acute Respiratory Infections in Beijing"/>
  <chunk id="ff77d5ebc39274bb7729f2b5261bca574bdfd6a8.c1" text="To determine the prevalence, epidemiology and genetic diversity of human coronavirus OC43 (HCoV-OC43) among adult patients with acute respiratory infections (ARI) in Beijing,five hundred and fifty-nine nasopharyngeal swab samples were collected from adult patients with ARI in Beijing. The prevalence of HCoV-OC43 infection among these patients was assessed using two different OneStep reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) assays. The epidemiological profiles of the patients with HCoV-OC43 infection were described. Partial S and N genes of HCoV-OC43 circulating strains were sequenced followed by phylogenetic analysis and amino acid alignment. Our results showed that the prevalence of HCoV-OC43 infection was 12.52% (95% CI: 9.78-15.26%), and the epidemic peak occurred in autumn. Fifty partial S and 40 partial N fragments were obtained from these patients. Phylogenetic analysis based on neighbour-joining method showed that at least three distinct clusters (A, B, C/D) of HCoV-OC43 strains were circulating among adult patients with ARI in Beijing. In addition, some novel unique clusters (UNT) of HCoV-OC43 were found in the S-and N-based phylogenetic trees. Furthermore, consensus amino acids substitutes for each cluster were also found after alignment of partial S or N sequence coding region in this study. In conclusion, we herein describe the prevalence of HCoV-OC43 among adult patients and provide substantial evidence for the genetic diversity of HCoV-OC43 circulating in Beijing.">
    <entity charOffset="158-161" id="ff77d5ebc39274bb7729f2b5261bca574bdfd6a8.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_35640" text="ARI" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="270-273" id="ff77d5ebc39274bb7729f2b5261bca574bdfd6a8.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_35640" text="ARI" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="645-650" id="ff77d5ebc39274bb7729f2b5261bca574bdfd6a8.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_46882" text="amino" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="645-655" id="ff77d5ebc39274bb7729f2b5261bca574bdfd6a8.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_33704" text="amino acid" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="651-655" id="ff77d5ebc39274bb7729f2b5261bca574bdfd6a8.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_37527" text="acid" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="975-983" id="ff77d5ebc39274bb7729f2b5261bca574bdfd6a8.c1.e5" ontology_id="CHEBI_33731" text="clusters" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1060-1063" id="ff77d5ebc39274bb7729f2b5261bca574bdfd6a8.c1.e6" ontology_id="CHEBI_35640" text="ARI" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1107-1115" id="ff77d5ebc39274bb7729f2b5261bca574bdfd6a8.c1.e7" ontology_id="CHEBI_33731" text="clusters" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1117-1120" id="ff77d5ebc39274bb7729f2b5261bca574bdfd6a8.c1.e8" ontology_id="CHEBI_33397" text="UNT" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1210-1215" id="ff77d5ebc39274bb7729f2b5261bca574bdfd6a8.c1.e9" ontology_id="CHEBI_46882" text="amino" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1210-1221" id="ff77d5ebc39274bb7729f2b5261bca574bdfd6a8.c1.e10" ontology_id="CHEBI_33704" text="amino acids" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1216-1221" id="ff77d5ebc39274bb7729f2b5261bca574bdfd6a8.c1.e11" ontology_id="CHEBI_37527" text="acids" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1243-1250" id="ff77d5ebc39274bb7729f2b5261bca574bdfd6a8.c1.e12" ontology_id="CHEBI_33731" text="cluster" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
