<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="27759780_en">
  <chunk id="27759780_en.c0" text="ANTIBIOTIC PROPHYLAXIS IN LAPAROSCOPIC CHOLECISTECTOMY: IS IT WORTH DOING?">
    <entity charOffset="0-10" id="27759780_en.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33281" text="ANTIBIOTIC" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="27759780_en.c1" text="Elective laparoscopic cholecystectomy has very low risk for infectious complications, ranging the infection rate from 0.4% to 1.1%. Many surgeons still use routine antibiotic prophylaxis.Evaluate the real impact of antibiotic prophylaxis in elective laparoscopic cholecystectomies in low risk patients.Prospective, randomized and double-blind study. Were evaluated 100 patients that underwent elective laparoscopic cholecystectomy divided in two groups: group A (n=50), patients that received prophylaxis using intravenous Cephazolin (2 g) during anesthetic induction and group B (n=50), patients that didn't receive any antibiotic prophylaxis. The outcome evaluated were infeccious complications at surgical site. The patients were reviewed seven and 30 days after surgery.There was incidence of 2% in infection complications in group A and 2% in group B. There was no statistical significant difference of infectious complications (p=0,05) between the groups. The groups were homogeneous and comparable.The use of the antibiotic prophylaxis in laparoscopic cholecystectomy in low risk patients doesn't provide any significant benefit in the decrease of surgical wound infection.">
    <entity charOffset="164-174" id="27759780_en.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33281" text="antibiotic" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="215-225" id="27759780_en.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33281" text="antibiotic" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="523-533" id="27759780_en.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_474053" text="Cephazolin" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="621-631" id="27759780_en.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_33281" text="antibiotic" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1020-1030" id="27759780_en.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_33281" text="antibiotic" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="27759780_en.c1.e0" e2="27759780_en.c1.e2" id="27759780_en.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="27759780_en.c1.e1" e2="27759780_en.c1.e2" id="27759780_en.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="27759780_en.c1.e2" e2="27759780_en.c1.e3" id="27759780_en.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="27759780_en.c1.e2" e2="27759780_en.c1.e4" id="27759780_en.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
