<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="29069186_en">
  <chunk id="29069186_en.c0" text="Evaluation of data quality, timeliness and acceptability of the tuberculosis surveillance system in Brazil's micro-regions."/>
  <chunk id="29069186_en.c1" text="This study aimed to evaluate quality, acceptability and timeliness of the data in the tuberculosis surveillance system in Brazilian micro-regions. An ecological cross-sectional study was carried out, after a qualitative stage for selecting indicators. All 558 Brazilian micro-regions were used as units of analysis. Data available in the National Notifiable Diseases Information System (SINAN), from 2012 to 2014, were used to calculate 14 indicators relating to four attributes: completeness, consistency, timeliness and acceptability. The study made use of cluster analysis to group micro-regions according to acceptability and timeliness. Three clusters were identified among the 473 micro-regions with optimal or regular completeness (70% to 100%) and with over five notifications. Cluster 1 (n = 109) presented mean timeliness of notification and treatment equal to 62.8% and 24.9%, respectively. Cluster 2 (n = 143) had a mean percentage of cases tested for HIV equal to 55.9%. Cluster 3 (n = 221) had the best performing tuberculosis indicators. Results suggest priority areas for improving surveillance of tuberculosis, predominantly in the central-north part of the country. They also point to the need to increase the timeliness of treatment and the percentage of cases tested for HIV.">
    <entity charOffset="559-566" id="29069186_en.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_33731" text="cluster" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="648-656" id="29069186_en.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_33731" text="clusters" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="786-793" id="29069186_en.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_33731" text="Cluster" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="902-909" id="29069186_en.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_33731" text="Cluster" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="984-991" id="29069186_en.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_33731" text="Cluster" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="29069186_en.c1.e0" e2="29069186_en.c1.e1" id="29069186_en.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="29069186_en.c1.e0" e2="29069186_en.c1.e2" id="29069186_en.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="29069186_en.c1.e0" e2="29069186_en.c1.e3" id="29069186_en.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="29069186_en.c1.e0" e2="29069186_en.c1.e4" id="29069186_en.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="29069186_en.c1.e1" e2="29069186_en.c1.e2" id="29069186_en.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="29069186_en.c1.e1" e2="29069186_en.c1.e3" id="29069186_en.c1.p5" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="29069186_en.c1.e1" e2="29069186_en.c1.e4" id="29069186_en.c1.p6" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
