<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="30328937_en">
  <chunk id="30328937_en.c0" text="Moderate endemicity of the human T-lymphotropic virus infection in the metropolitan region of Belém, Pará, Brazil."/>
  <chunk id="30328937_en.c1" text="The spread of the HTLV infection in families living in the metropolitan area of Belém, Pará, Brazil, and the lack of studies in the general population requires studies to better understand its prevalence in the region.An anti-HTLV-1/HTLV-2 antibodies test was carried out on random adults in public places in Belém between November 2014 and November 2015. A proviral DNA test detected if the person was infected, and then a clinical evaluation and an intrafamilial investigation were carried out.Of the 1059 individuals being investigated, 21 (2.0%) had seroreagent samples, 15 (1.4%) had HTLV-1, 5 (0.5%) had HTLV-2, and proviral DNA was undetectable in one case. The mean age of the infected people (57.2) was higher than that of those that were uninfected (46.2) (p = 0.0010). The prevalence of infection increased with age, especially in individuals with a family income equal to or less than a minimum wage. Intrafamilial transmission seems to have occurred in all of the families being studied. Among the patients with HTLV-1, 30% (3/10) already had some symptom related to the infection.The increase in prevalence rates according to age may be due to late seroconversion of a previously acquired infection, or the cumulative risk of new infections, especially in women.There was a moderate prevalence of the HTLV infection among adult individuals from the metropolitan area of Belém, with a predominance of HTLV-1. This infection was associated with low income and increasingly older women. It also presented intrafamily spread and negligence in the diagnosis of associated diseases.">
    <entity charOffset="367-370" id="30328937_en.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="631-634" id="30328937_en.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
