<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="30726307_en">
  <chunk id="30726307_en.c0" text="Comparative analysis of glutathione transferase genetic polymorphism, Helicobacter pylori and Epstein-Barr virus between the tumor area and the proximal and distal resection margins of gastric cancer.">
    <entity charOffset="24-35" id="30726307_en.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16856" text="glutathione" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="30726307_en.c1" text="to compare the polymorphism of the Glutathione S-transferase theta 1 (GSTT1) and Glutathione S-transferase mu 1 (GSTM1) genes from the tumor area with the proximal and distal margins of stomach specimens resected from patients with gastric cancer, and to investigate the presence of Epstein-Barr virus (EBV) DNA and Helicobacter pylori.we prospectively collected tissue specimens from the tumor area and from the proximal and distal resection margins of the stomachs of ten patients with gastric adenocarcinoma who underwent gastrectomy with D2 lymphadenectomy, and submitted these specimens to DNA extraction. We compared the tumor area with the proximal and distal margins of the resected stomachs for polymorphism of GSTT1 and GSTM1 genes and investigated the presence of EBV-DNA and H. pylori. We used the p53 exon 5 gene as an internal control of the multiplex PCR reaction.in one patient, we detected null GSTT1 and GSTM1 genotypes in the tumor area, in contrast to the presence of both genes in the proximal and distal margins. We found EBV-DNA and H. pylori in the tumor area and also in the proximal and distal margins. In another patient, the proximal margin was negative for GSTT1, and EBV-DNA was negative in the distal margin. In three patients, EBV-DNA was negative only in the distal margin.this is the first report where different genotypes, EBV-DNA and H. pylori infection were observed in the same patient, indicating a probable deletion of these genes in response to tumor progression and intratumoral heterogeneity.">
    <entity charOffset="35-46" id="30726307_en.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_16856" text="Glutathione" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="61-66" id="30726307_en.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_138143" text="theta" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="81-92" id="30726307_en.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_16856" text="Glutathione" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="308-311" id="30726307_en.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="595-598" id="30726307_en.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_16991" text="DNA" type="chemical"/>
    <pair e1="30726307_en.c1.e0" e2="30726307_en.c1.e1" id="30726307_en.c1.p0" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="30726307_en.c1.e0" e2="30726307_en.c1.e3" id="30726307_en.c1.p1" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="30726307_en.c1.e0" e2="30726307_en.c1.e4" id="30726307_en.c1.p2" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="30726307_en.c1.e1" e2="30726307_en.c1.e2" id="30726307_en.c1.p3" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="30726307_en.c1.e1" e2="30726307_en.c1.e3" id="30726307_en.c1.p4" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="30726307_en.c1.e1" e2="30726307_en.c1.e4" id="30726307_en.c1.p5" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="30726307_en.c1.e2" e2="30726307_en.c1.e3" id="30726307_en.c1.p6" relation="true"/>
    <pair e1="30726307_en.c1.e2" e2="30726307_en.c1.e4" id="30726307_en.c1.p7" relation="true"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
