<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<document id="32049128_en">
  <chunk id="32049128_en.c0" text="Prevalence of induced abortion and associated factors in a cohort of women living with HIV/AIDS, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, 1996-2016.">
    <entity charOffset="59-65" id="32049128_en.c0.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_34935" text="cohort" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
  <chunk id="32049128_en.c1" text="The aim of this study was to verify the prevalence of induced abortion and associated factors at the time of inclusion in a cohort of women living with HIV/AIDS in the city of Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, from 1996 to 2016. Eligibility criteria for inclusion in the cohort were female sex at birth, age 18 years and older, and confirmed HIV infection. At the baseline visit, data on sexual, reproductive, and behavioral aspects and HIV infection were obtained through a face-to-face interview with the attending physician. Lifetime prevalence of induced abortion was calculated, and factors associated with induced abortion were verified by multiple logistic regression for all the women and for those with previous pregnancy. In the entire cohort of women, 30.4% reported a history of induced abortion, compared to 33.5% in women with previous pregnancy. Frequency of reported induced abortion showed a significant reduction during the period (41.7% in 1996-2000 versus 22.5% in 2011-2016, p &lt; 0.001). Factors associated with induced abortion, both for the entire cohort and for the women with previous pregnancy, were age, schooling, ≥ 5 lifetime sexual partners, teenage pregnancy, lifetime use of any illicit drug, and inclusion in the cohort after the year 2005. Changes in the socioeconomic, sexual, reproductive, and HIV infection profile are possible explanations for the reduction in abortions during the period. Studies that use direct methods to measure abortion should be conducted in other populations to confirm the downward trend in induced abortion and its determinants in Brazil.">
    <entity charOffset="124-130" id="32049128_en.c1.e0" ontology_id="CHEBI_34935" text="cohort" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="261-267" id="32049128_en.c1.e1" ontology_id="CHEBI_34935" text="cohort" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="736-742" id="32049128_en.c1.e2" ontology_id="CHEBI_34935" text="cohort" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1060-1066" id="32049128_en.c1.e3" ontology_id="CHEBI_34935" text="cohort" type="chemical"/>
    <entity charOffset="1235-1241" id="32049128_en.c1.e4" ontology_id="CHEBI_34935" text="cohort" type="chemical"/>
  </chunk>
</document>
